{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84425/amnesty-international-urges-sri-lankan-govt-to-stop-using-pta-against-protesters",
  "time_ut": 1660997640,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Amnesty International urges Sri Lankan govt to stop using PTA against protesters",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Amnesty International urges Sri Lankan govt to stop using PTA against protesters",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Amnesty International has urged the Sri Lankan government to not use the draconian anti-terror law, the Prevention of Terrorism Act (PTA) against protesters for their acts of civil disobedience.",
        "In a Twitter thread, the international rights organization said it is “deeply concerned by reports that Wasantha Mudalige, the Convener of the Inter-University Students’ Federation, is currently being held at the Terrorism Investigation Division by the authorities.”",
        "Urging to refrain from using the PTA against protesters, Amnesty International called on the government to repeal the anti-terror law instead.",
        "“Arbitrarily detaining protesters and charging them with serious criminal offences that are not justified by their actions, such as terrorism-related charges, is against international law,” the organization said further.",
        "Sri Lanka: We are deeply concerned by reports that Wasantha Mudalige, the Convener of the Inter University Students' Federation, is currently being held at the Terrorism Investigation Division by the authorities.— Amnesty International South Asia (@amnestysasia) August 19, 2022"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Amnesty International",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "PTA",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Amnesty International",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Prevention of Terrorism Act",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Twitter",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wasantha Mudalige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Inter-University Students’ Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Terrorism Investigation Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amnesty International",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wasantha Mudalige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Inter University Students' Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Terrorism Investigation Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amnesty International South Asia",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 19, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට එරෙහිව ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත භාවිතා කිරීම නවත්වන ලෙස ජාත්‍යන්තර ක්ෂමා සංවිධානය ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සිවිල් අකීකරු ක්‍රියාවන් සඳහා විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට එරෙහිව ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත (PTA) කුරිරු ත්‍රස්ත විරෝධී නීතිය භාවිතා නොකරන ලෙස ජාත්‍යන්තර ක්ෂමා සංවිධානය ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා තිබේ.",
        "“අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බලමණ්ඩලයේ කැඳවුම්කරු වසන්ත මුදලිගේ මේ වන විට බලධාරීන් විසින් ත්‍රස්ත විමර්ශන කොට්ඨාශයේ රඳවා සිටින බවට පළවන වාර්තා සම්බන්ධයෙන් තමන් දැඩි කනස්සල්ලට පත්ව සිටින” බව ට්විටර් ත්‍රෙඩ් එකක ජාත්‍යන්තර අයිතිවාසිකම් සංවිධානය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට එරෙහිව ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත භාවිතා කිරීමෙන් වළකින ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටි ඇම්නෙස්ටි ඉන්ටර්නැෂනල්, ඒ වෙනුවට ත්‍රස්ත විරෝධී නීතිය ඉවත් කරන ලෙස රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "\"විරෝධතාකරුවන් අත්තනෝමතික ලෙස රඳවා තබා ගැනීම සහ ත්‍රස්තවාදය සම්බන්ධ චෝදනා වැනි ඔවුන්ගේ ක්‍රියාවන් මගින් යුක්ති සහගත නොවන බරපතල සාපරාධී වැරදි සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඔවුන්ට චෝදනා කිරීම ජාත්‍යන්තර නීතියට පටහැනියි\" යනුවෙන් එම සංවිධානය වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව: අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බලමණ්ඩලයේ කැඳවුම්කරු වසන්ත මුදලිගේ මේ වන විට බලධාරීන් විසින් ත්‍රස්ත විමර්ශන කොට්ඨාශයේ රඳවා සිටින බවට පළ වන වාර්තා පිළිබඳව අපි දැඩි කනස්සල්ලට පත්ව සිටිමු.— Amnesty International South Asia (@amnestysasia) අගෝස්තු 19, 2022"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඇම්නෙස්ටි ඉන්ටර්නැෂනල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "PTA",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇම්නෙස්ටි ඉන්ටර්නැෂනල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ට්විටර්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසන්ත මුදලිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රස්ත විමර්ශන අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇම්නෙස්ටි ඉන්ටර්නැෂනල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "වසන්ත මුදලිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රස්ත විමර්ශන අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇම්නෙස්ටි ඉන්ටර්නැෂනල් දකුණු ආසියාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "போராட்டக்காரர்களுக்கு எதிராக பயங்கரவாத தடைச்சட்டத்தைப் பயன்படுத்துவதை நிறுத்துமாறு இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தை சர்வதேச மன்னிப்புச் சபை வலியுறுத்துகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சிவில் ஒத்துழையாமைக்கு எதிராக ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களுக்கு எதிராக கொடூரமான பயங்கரவாத எதிர்ப்புச் சட்டம், பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டம் (PTA) ஆகியவற்றைப் பயன்படுத்த வேண்டாம் என்று சர்வதேச மன்னிப்புச் சபை இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தை வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் சம்மேளனத்தின் அழைப்பாளர் வசந்த முதலிகே தற்போது பயங்கரவாத புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவில் அதிகாரிகளால் தடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக வெளியாகியுள்ள தகவல்களால் கவலையடைவதாக சர்வதேச உரிமைகள் அமைப்பு ட்விட்டரில் பதிவிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "போராட்டக்காரர்களுக்கு எதிராக பயங்கரவாத தடைச்சட்டத்தைப் பயன்படுத்துவதைத் தவிர்க்க வலியுறுத்தி, சர்வதேச மன்னிப்புச் சபை, அதற்குப் பதிலாக பயங்கரவாத எதிர்ப்புச் சட்டத்தை ரத்து செய்யுமாறு அரசாங்கத்தைக் கேட்டுக் கொண்டது.",
        "\"எதிரித்தனமாக எதிர்ப்பாளர்களை தடுத்து வைப்பது மற்றும் பயங்கரவாதம் தொடர்பான குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் போன்ற அவர்களின் நடவடிக்கைகளால் நியாயப்படுத்தப்படாத கடுமையான கிரிமினல் குற்றங்களில் குற்றம் சாட்டுவது சர்வதேச சட்டத்திற்கு எதிரானது\" என்று அந்த அமைப்பு மேலும் கூறியது.",
        "இலங்கை: பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் சம்மேளனத்தின் அழைப்பாளர் வசந்த முதலிகே தற்போது பயங்கரவாத விசாரணைப் பிரிவில் அதிகாரிகளால் தடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார் என்ற செய்திகளால் நாங்கள் மிகவும் கவலையடைந்துள்ளோம்.— Amnesty International South Asia (@amnestysasia) ஆகஸ்ட் 19, 2022"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சர்வதேச மன்னிப்புச் சபை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "PTA",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச மன்னிப்புச் சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ட்விட்டர்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "வசந்த முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பயங்கரவாத விசாரணைப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச மன்னிப்புச் சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "வசந்த முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பயங்கரவாத விசாரணைப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்னெஸ்டி இன்டர்நேஷனல் தெற்காசியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 19, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}