{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Dankotuwa-Group-posts-impressive-1Q/34-738775",
  "time_ut": 1660688300,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Dankotuwa Group posts impressive 1Q",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dankotuwa Group posts impressive 1Q",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Group achieves 81% revenue growth, 122% GP growth and Rs. 268 m PBT",
        "Dankotuwa Porcelain PLC, said yesterday it has posted remarkable results for the Q1 of the financial year 2022/2023.",
        "As a company, Dankotuwa Porcelain, recorded a revenue of Rs. 788.4 million for the Q1 of the financial year 2022/23, a 56% growth when compared to Rs. 504.4 million achieved during the corresponding period.",
        "Further, the company achieved a Gross Profit (GP) of Rs. 374.1 million, which was an 86% growth compared to Rs. 201.46 million achieved for the same period of the last financial year. The Profit before Tax (PBT) for Dankotuwa, as a company, was Rs. 207.52 million, a commendable achievement when compared to the Rs. 55.81 million made during the first quarter of the previous Financial Year 2021/22.",
        "Dankotuwa Porcelain as a Group (which includes its subsidiary Royal Fernwood Porcelain Ltd.) posted a revenue of Rs. 1.42 billion, an 81% growth compared to Rs. 787.67 million achieved last year for the same period.",
        "The Group further achieved a Gross Profit (GP) of Rs. 610.55 million, a 122% growth compared to Rs. 275.5 million and Profit before Tax (PBT) of Rs. 367.77 million, an increase compared to Rs. 60.26 million and Profit after Tax (PAT) of Rs. 298million impressive increase of 491% compared to the Rs. 50 million achieved in the corresponding period in the last financial year.",
        "Royal Fernwood Porcelain Ltd., its subsidiary, recorded a gross profit of Rs. 236.46 million for Q1 of the financial year 2022/23 which contributed positively towards the overall performance of the Group. The company underwent restructuring and realigned business verticals enabling the convergence of resources which has definitely contributed to the positive results during the last quarter.",
        "Dankotuwa Porcelain CEO Channa Gunawardana said: “We’ve navigated through turbulent phases over the past years and are very pleased to announce the commendable performance of the organisation. It has been a tough journey paved by the pandemic, lockdowns, economic and political distress, and disruptions. Amidst all these difficulties, we have emerged strong and positive, demonstrating our resilience and our willingness to accept challenges and forge ahead with commitment and determination.”",
        "“As an organisation, we continued to adapt to the changes imposed by the pandemic and faced the macro-economic challenges with resilience. During this period, one of our most effective concepts, Collective Leadership, enabled the employees of our organisation to identify their true potential and showcase their best performance within an unfavourable macro-economic environment,” Gunawardana added.",
        "The Board of Directors of Dankotuwa Porcelain comprises of eminent key business personalities such as Chairman Yudy Kanagasabai, Deputy Chairman Ranil Pathirana, Revantha Devasurendra, Rohan Peris, Niranjan Wijesekera, Shalike Karunasena and Dr. Sajeeva Narangoda."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dankotuwa Group",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "1Q",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "81%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "122%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "268",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "PBT",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dankotuwa Porcelain PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022/2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dankotuwa Porcelain",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "788.4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022/23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "56%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "504.4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "374.1 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "86%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "201.46 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last financial year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Profit before Tax",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PBT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dankotuwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "207.52 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "55.81 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first quarter",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Royal Fernwood Porcelain Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.42 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "81%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "787.67 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "610.55 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "122%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "275.5 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Profit before Tax",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PBT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "367.77 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60.26 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Profit after Tax (PAT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "298million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "491%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last financial year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Royal Fernwood Porcelain Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "236.46 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last quarter",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gunawardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Collective Leadership",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunawardana",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yudy Kanagasabai",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Pathirana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Revantha Devasurendra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rohan Peris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Niranjan Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shalike Karunasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajeeva Narangoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දංකොටුව සමූහ පළ කිරීම් ආකර්ෂණීය 1Q",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සමූහය 81% ආදායම් වර්ධනයක්, 122% GP වර්ධනයක් සහ රු. මීටර් 268 PBT",
        "2022/2023 මූල්‍ය වර්ෂයේ Q1 සඳහා විශිෂ්ට ප්‍රතිඵල නිකුත් කර ඇති බව දංකොටුව පෝසිලේන් පීඑල්සී ඊයේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "සමාගමක් ලෙස දංකොටුව පෝසිලේන් ආදායම රු. 2022/23 මුල්‍ය වර්ෂයේ පළමු කාර්තුව සඳහා රුපියල් මිලියන 788.4ක් වූ අතර එය රු. මිලියන 504.4ක් අනුරූප කාලපරිච්ඡේදය තුළ අත්පත් කර ගෙන ඇත.",
        "තවද, සමාගම රු. මිලියන 374.1 ක් වූ අතර එය රු. මිලියන 201.46ක් පසුගිය මූල්‍ය වර්ෂයේ එම කාලසීමාව සඳහා ලබාගෙන ඇත. සමාගමක් ලෙස දංකොටුව සඳහා බදු ගෙවීමට පෙර ලාභය (PBT) රු. මිලියන 207.52 ක් වූ අතර එය රු. 2021/22 පෙර මූල්‍ය වර්ෂයේ පළමු කාර්තුව තුළ රුපියල් මිලියන 55.81ක් උපයා ඇත.",
        "දංකොටුව පෝසිලේන් සමූහයක් ලෙස (එහි අනුබද්ධ Royal Fernwood Porcelain Ltd. ඇතුළුව) ආදායම රු. බිලියන 1.42, 81% ක වර්ධනයක් රු. මිලියන 787.67ක් පසුගිය වසරේ එම කාලසීමාව සඳහා අත්පත් කර ගෙන ඇත.",
        "සමූහය තවදුරටත් දළ ලාභය (GP) රු. මිලියන 610.55, 122% ක වර්ධනයක් රු. මිලියන 275.5 ක් සහ බදු වලට පෙර ලාභය (PBT) රු. මිලියන 367.77 ට සාපේක්ෂව වැඩි වීමකි. මිලියන 60.26 ක් සහ බදු ගෙවීමෙන් පසු ලාභය (PAT) රු. රුපියල් මිලියන 298 ට සාපේක්ෂව 491% ක ආකර්ෂණීය වර්ධනයකි. පසුගිය මූල්‍ය වර්ෂයේ අනුරූප කාලපරිච්ඡේදය තුළ රුපියල් මිලියන 50ක් ලබාගෙන ඇත.",
        "එහි අනුබද්ධිත Royal Fernwood Porcelain Ltd. හි දළ ලාභය රු. 2022/23 මූල්‍ය වර්ෂයේ පළමු කාර්තුව සඳහා රුපියල් මිලියන 236.46 ක් වූ අතර එය සමූහයේ සමස්ත කාර්ය සාධනය සඳහා ධනාත්මක ලෙස දායක විය. සමාගම ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම සහ ප්‍රතිනිර්මාණය කරන ලද ව්‍යාපාර සිරස්තලවලට භාජනය වී ඇති අතර එය සම්පත් අභිසාරී වීමට ඉඩ සලසයි, එය පසුගිය කාර්තුව තුළ ධනාත්මක ප්‍රතිඵල සඳහා නිසැකවම දායක වී ඇත.",
        "දංකොටුව පෝසිලේන් හි ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී චන්න ගුණවර්ධන මහතා මෙසේ පැවසීය: “පසුගිය වසර කිහිපය තුළ අපි කැළඹිලි සහිත අවධීන් හරහා ගමන් කළ අතර සංවිධානයේ ප්‍රශංසනීය ක්‍රියාකාරිත්වය නිවේදනය කිරීමට ලැබීම ගැන අපි ඉතා සතුටු වෙමු. එය වසංගතය, අගුලු දැමීම්, ආර්ථික හා දේශපාලන දුක්ඛිත තත්වයන් සහ කඩාකප්පල් කිරීම් මගින් සකස් කරන ලද දුෂ්කර ගමනකි. මෙම සියලු දුෂ්කරතා මධ්‍යයේ, අපගේ ඔරොත්තු දීමේ හැකියාව සහ අභියෝග භාර ගැනීමට සහ කැපවීමෙන් සහ අධිෂ්ඨානයෙන් ඉදිරියට යාමට ඇති කැමැත්ත පෙන්නුම් කරමින් අපි ශක්තිමත් සහ ධනාත්මකව මතු වී සිටිමු.",
        "“සංවිධානයක් ලෙස, අපි වසංගතය විසින් පනවන ලද වෙනස්කම් වලට අනුවර්තනය වූ අතර සාර්ව ආර්ථික අභියෝගවලට ඔරොත්තු දීමේ හැකියාවෙන් යුතුව මුහුණ දුන්නෙමු. මෙම කාල පරිච්ෙඡ්දය තුළ අපගේ වඩාත් ඵලදායී සංකල්පයක් වන සාමූහික නායකත්වය, අපගේ ආයතනයේ සේවකයින්ට ඔවුන්ගේ සැබෑ හැකියාවන් හඳුනා ගැනීමට සහ අවාසිදායක සාර්ව ආර්ථික පරිසරයක් තුළ ඔවුන්ගේ හොඳම කාර්ය සාධනය පෙන්වීමට හැකි විය.",
        "දංකොටුව පෝසිලේන් හි අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය සභාපති යූඩි කනගසබායි, උප සභාපති රනිල් පතිරණ, රේවන්ත දේවසුරේන්ද්‍ර, රොහාන් පීරිස්, නිරංජන් විජේසේකර, ශාලිකේ කරුණාසේන සහ වෛද්‍ය සජීව නාරංගොඩ වැනි ප්‍රකට ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්ගෙන් සමන්විත වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දංකොටුව සමූහ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "1Q",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "81%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "122%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "268",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "PBT",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දංකොටුව පෝසිලේන් පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022/2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දංකොටුව පෝසිලේන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 788.4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022/23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "56%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 504.4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 374.1 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "86%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 201.46 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මූල්ය වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බද්දට පෙර ලාභය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PBT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දන්කොටුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 207.52 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 55.81 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමු කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෝයල් ෆර්න්වුඩ් පෝසිලේන් ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 1.42 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "81%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 787.67 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය අවුරුද්දේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 610.55 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "122%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 275.5 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදු වලට පෙර ලාභය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PBT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 367.77 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 60.26 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදු පසු ලාභය (PAT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 298 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "491%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 50 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මූල්ය වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රෝයල් ෆර්න්වුඩ් පෝසිලේන් ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 236.46 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසාන කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාමූහික නායකත්වය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යූඩි කනගසබායි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් පතිරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රේවන්ත දේවසුරේන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොහාන් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිරංජන් විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශාලිකේ කරුණාසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජීව නාරංගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தங்கொடுவ குழும இடுகைகள் ஈர்க்கக்கூடிய 1Q",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "குழு 81% வருவாய் வளர்ச்சி, 122% GP வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் ரூ. 268 மீ பிபிடி",
        "2022/2023 நிதியாண்டின் Q1 இல் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க முடிவுகளைப் பதிவு செய்துள்ளதாக தங்கொடுவ Porcelain PLC, நேற்று தெரிவித்தது.",
        "ஒரு நிறுவனமாக, தங்கொடுவ பீங்கான், ரூ. 2022/23 நிதியாண்டின் முதல் காலாண்டில் 788.4 மில்லியன், ரூ. உடன் ஒப்பிடும்போது 56% வளர்ச்சி. இதே காலத்தில் 504.4 மில்லியன் ஈட்டப்பட்டது.",
        "மேலும், நிறுவனம் மொத்த லாபம் (GP) ரூ. 374.1 மில்லியன், இது 86% வளர்ச்சியுடன் ஒப்பிடுகையில் ரூ. கடந்த நிதியாண்டின் இதே காலப்பகுதியில் 201.46 மில்லியன் ஈட்டப்பட்டுள்ளது. ஒரு நிறுவனமாக தங்கொடுவைக்கான வரிக்கு முந்தைய லாபம் (PBT) ரூ. 207.52 மில்லியன், ஒரு பாராட்டத்தக்க சாதனையை ஒப்பிடும் போது ரூ. முந்தைய நிதியாண்டின் 2021/22 முதல் காலாண்டில் 55.81 மில்லியன் ஈட்டப்பட்டது.",
        "Dankotuwa Porcelain ஒரு குழுவாக (அதன் துணை நிறுவனமான Royal Fernwood Porcelain Ltd ஐ உள்ளடக்கியது) ரூ. 1.42 பில்லியன், 81% வளர்ச்சியுடன் ஒப்பிடுகையில் ரூ. கடந்த ஆண்டு இதே காலத்தில் 787.67 மில்லியன் ஈட்டப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "குழுமத்தின் மொத்த லாபம் (GP) ரூ. 610.55 மில்லியன், 122% வளர்ச்சி ரூ. 275.5 மில்லியன் மற்றும் வரிக்கு முந்தைய லாபம் (PBT) ரூ. 367.77 மில்லியன், இது ரூ. 60.26 மில்லியன் மற்றும் வரிக்குப் பிந்தைய லாபம் (PAT) ரூ. 298 மில்லியனுடன் ஒப்பிடுகையில் 491% இன் ஈர்க்கக்கூடிய அதிகரிப்பு. கடந்த நிதியாண்டில் இதே காலத்தில் 50 மில்லியன் ஈட்டப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அதன் துணை நிறுவனமான Royal Fernwood Porcelain Ltd. மொத்த லாபம் ரூ. 2022/23 நிதியாண்டின் Q1 க்கு 236.46 மில்லியன், இது குழுமத்தின் ஒட்டுமொத்த செயல்திறனுக்கு சாதகமாக பங்களித்தது. நிறுவனம் மறுசீரமைப்பு மற்றும் வணிக செங்குத்துகளை மறுசீரமைத்தது, இது வளங்களின் ஒருங்கிணைப்பை செயல்படுத்துகிறது, இது கடந்த காலாண்டில் நேர்மறையான முடிவுகளுக்கு நிச்சயமாக பங்களித்தது.",
        "தங்கொடுவ பீங்கான் நிறுவனத்தின் பிரதம நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரி சன்ன குணவர்தன கூறினார்: “கடந்த வருடங்களில் நாங்கள் கொந்தளிப்பான கட்டங்களில் பயணித்துள்ளோம் மற்றும் நிறுவனத்தின் பாராட்டத்தக்க செயல்திறனை அறிவிப்பதில் மிகவும் மகிழ்ச்சியடைகிறோம். தொற்றுநோய், பூட்டுதல்கள், பொருளாதார மற்றும் அரசியல் நெருக்கடிகள் மற்றும் இடையூறுகளால் இது ஒரு கடினமான பயணமாக உள்ளது. இந்த அனைத்து சிரமங்களுக்கும் மத்தியில், நாங்கள் வலிமையாகவும் நேர்மறையாகவும் வெளிப்பட்டுள்ளோம், எங்களின் பின்னடைவு மற்றும் சவால்களை ஏற்று அர்ப்பணிப்பு மற்றும் உறுதியுடன் முன்னேறுவதற்கான எங்கள் விருப்பத்தை வெளிப்படுத்துகிறோம்.",
        "\"ஒரு அமைப்பாக, தொற்றுநோயால் திணிக்கப்பட்ட மாற்றங்களை நாங்கள் தொடர்ந்து மாற்றியமைத்தோம் மற்றும் மேக்ரோ-பொருளாதார சவால்களை பின்னடைவுடன் எதிர்கொண்டோம். இந்தக் காலப்பகுதியில், எங்களுடைய மிகவும் பயனுள்ள கருத்துக்களில் ஒன்றான கூட்டுத் தலைமைத்துவமானது, எமது நிறுவன ஊழியர்களுக்கு அவர்களின் உண்மையான திறனைக் கண்டறிந்து, சாதகமற்ற பொருளாதாரச் சூழலுக்குள் அவர்களின் சிறந்த செயல்திறனை வெளிப்படுத்த உதவியது, ”என்று குணவர்தன மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "தங்கொடுவ பீங்கான் நிறுவனத்தின் பணிப்பாளர் சபையில் தலைவர் யூடி கனகசபை, பிரதித் தலைவர் ரணில் பத்திரன, ரேவந்த தேவசுரேந்திர, ரொஹான் பெரிஸ், நிரஞ்சன் விஜேசேகர, ஷாலிகே கருணாசேன மற்றும் கலாநிதி சஜீவ நாரங்கொட போன்ற பிரபல வர்த்தக பிரமுகர்கள் உள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தங்கொடுவ குழு",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "1Q",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "81%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "122%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "268",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "PBT",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தங்கொடுவ பீங்கான் பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022/2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தங்கொடுவ பீங்கான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "788.4 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022/23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "56%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "504.4 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "374.1 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "86%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "201.46 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த நிதியாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரிக்கு முந்தைய லாபம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PBT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தங்கொடுவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "207.52 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "55.81 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதல் காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராயல் ஃபெர்ன்வுட் பீங்கான் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.42 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "81%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "787.67 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "610.55 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "122%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "275.5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரிக்கு முந்தைய லாபம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PBT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "367.77 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60.26 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரிக்குப் பிந்தைய லாபம் (PAT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "298 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "491%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த நிதியாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராயல் ஃபெர்ன்வுட் பீங்கான் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "236.46 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடைசி காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கூட்டுத் தலைமை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யூடி கனகசபை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் பத்திரன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரேவந்த தேவசுரேந்திரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோஹன் பெரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிரஞ்சன் விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷாலிகே கருணாசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜீவ நாரங்கொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}