{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Litro-procures-100-000MT-LP-Gas-for-next-4-months/108-240107",
  "time_ut": 1656577965,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Litro procures 100,000MT LP Gas for next 4 months",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Litro procures 100,000MT LP Gas for next 4 months",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Litro Gas said today that it has successfully procured 100,000MT of LP Gas which will be enough to supply the country it's gas requirements for next four months.",
        "The total consignment costs of the 100,000MT of LP Gas is $90 million and the World Bank has provided funding of $70 million, while the remaining $20 million has been provided by Litro.",
        "Litro said 70% of the consignment will be provided to domestic consumers. An estimated 5 million 12.5kg cylinders, 1 million 5kg cylinders and 1 million 2.5kg cylinders will be obtained from this. The remaining 30% will be provided for commercial use.",
        "An initial consignment of 33,000 tons of LPG procured by Litro at a cost of $20 million will reach Sri Lanka by the first week of July and distribution will commence immediately.(DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "next 4 months",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next four months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 100,000MT of LP Gas",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$90 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$70 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$20 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "70%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "An estimated 5 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.5kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "30%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "33,000 tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "LPG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "$20 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first week of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉදිරි මාස 4 සඳහා ලිට්‍රෝ මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 100,000 LP ගෑස් ලබා ගනී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් සමාගම අද ප්‍රකාශ කළේ තමන් එල්පී ගෑස් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 100,000ක් සාර්ථකව මිලදී ගෙන ඇති බවත් එය ඉදිරි මාස හතර සඳහා රටට අවශ්‍ය ගෑස් සැපයීමට ප්‍රමාණවත් වනු ඇති බවත්ය.",
        "LP ගෑස් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 100,000ක මුළු තොගයේ පිරිවැය ඩොලර් මිලියන 90ක් වන අතර ලෝක බැංකුව ඩොලර් මිලියන 70ක අරමුදල් සපයා ඇති අතර ඉතිරි ඩොලර් මිලියන 20 ලිට්‍රෝ සමාගම විසින් ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "එම තොගවලින් 70%ක් ගෘහස්ථ පාරිභෝගිකයන් වෙත ලබාදෙන බව Litro සමාගම පවසයි. මෙයින් කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 12.5 සිලින්ඩර මිලියන 5 ක්, කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 5 සිලින්ඩර මිලියන 1 ක් සහ කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 2.5 සිලින්ඩර මිලියන 1 ක් ලබා ගැනීමට ඇස්තමේන්තු කර ඇත. ඉතිරි 30% වාණිජමය භාවිතය සඳහා ලබා දෙනු ඇත.",
        "ඩොලර් මිලියන 20 ක වියදමින් ලිට්‍රෝ සමාගම විසින් ලබාගන්නා ලද LPG ටොන් 33,000 ක මූලික තොගයක් ජූලි මස මුල් සතිය වන විට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙන අතර බෙදා හැරීම වහාම ආරම්භ කෙරේ.(DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉදිරි මාස 4",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ ගෑස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි මාස හතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100,000MT LP ගෑස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 90 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 70 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 20 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "70%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 5ක් යැයි ගණන් බලා ඇත",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1 ක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1 ක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.5kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "30%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 33,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්.පී.ජී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 20 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි පළමු සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "Litro அடுத்த 4 மாதங்களுக்கு 100,000MT LP எரிவாயுவை வாங்குகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் நிறுவனம் 100,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் எல்பி எரிவாயுவை வெற்றிகரமாக கொள்முதல் செய்துள்ளதாக, இது அடுத்த நான்கு மாதங்களுக்கு நாட்டிற்கு தேவையான எரிவாயுவை வழங்க போதுமானதாக இருக்கும் என்று தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "100,000MT LP எரிவாயுவின் மொத்தச் செலவு $90 மில்லியன் மற்றும் உலக வங்கி $70 மில்லியன் நிதியுதவி அளித்துள்ளது, மீதமுள்ள $20 மில்லியனை Litro வழங்கியது.",
        "சரக்குகளில் 70% உள்நாட்டு நுகர்வோருக்கு வழங்கப்படும் என்று லிட்ரோ தெரிவித்துள்ளது. இதன் மூலம் 5 மில்லியன் 12.5 கிலோ சிலிண்டர்கள், 1 மில்லியன் 5 கிலோ சிலிண்டர்கள் மற்றும் 1 மில்லியன் 2.5 கிலோ சிலிண்டர்கள் பெறப்படும். மீதமுள்ள 30% வணிக பயன்பாட்டிற்கு வழங்கப்படும்.",
        "லிட்ரோவினால் 20 மில்லியன் டொலர்கள் செலவில் கொள்வனவு செய்யப்பட்ட 33,000 தொன் எல்பிஜி ஆரம்ப சரக்கு ஜூலை முதல் வாரத்தில் இலங்கையை வந்தடையும் மற்றும் விநியோகம் உடனடியாக ஆரம்பிக்கப்படும்.(DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அடுத்த 4 மாதங்கள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த நான்கு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100,000MT LP எரிவாயு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$90 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$70 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$20 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "70%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 மில்லியன் என மதிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.5 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "30%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "33,000 டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்.பி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "$20 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை முதல் வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}