{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83476/dhananjaya-and-vandersay-also-test-covid-19-positive",
  "time_ut": 1657162560,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Dhananjaya and Vandersay also test Covid-19 positive",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dhananjaya and Vandersay also test Covid-19 positive",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lankan cricketers Dhananjaya de Silva and Jeffrey Vandersay have been ruled out of 2nd Test against Australia as both players have tested positive for Covid-19, according to Sri Lanka Cricket (SLC).",
        "This brings the total number of Sri Lankan national team players to test positive for the virus to four.",
        "Previously, star all-rounder, Angelo Mathews tested positive late on Day 2 of the first Test, and was subsequently ruled out of the contest; Oshada Fernando was called in as his replacement.",
        "Mathews had returned a positive rapid antigen test after feeling unwell. Sri Lanka Cricket had said he has since been isolated from other team members.",
        "On July 04, Praveen Jayawickrama had also tested positive for Covid-19 and was isolated immediately for five days.",
        "The player was found to be Covid positive when he was tested (Rapid Antigen Test) on the morning of July 04, as he complained of feeling ‘unwell’, the SLC had said.",
        "Jayawickrama was immediately isolated from the rest of the team members and will remain in room isolation for 5 days, it said.",
        "SLC had said that upon identification of Jayawickrama, as Covid Positive, the rest of the team members (players and support staff) were subjected to a Rapid Antigen Test, however all of them had returned negative results then.",
        "Sri Lanka are hoping for Mathews’ return, should he recover in time for the second Test, which starts on Friday, 8 July.",
        "Australia are leading the two-match series 1-0, after sealing a convincing win in the first Test by 10 wickets."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dhananjaya",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Vandersay",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhananjaya de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jeffrey Vandersay",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2nd Test",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Cricket",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Angelo Mathews",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oshada Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Cricket",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 04",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Praveen Jayawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "five days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the morning of July 04",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayawickrama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayawickrama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Covid Positive",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mathews",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Test",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ධනංජය සහ වැන්ඩර්සේ ද කොවිඩ්-19 ධනාත්මක බව පරීක්‍ෂා කරති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් ක්‍රීඩකයින් දෙදෙනෙකු වන ධනංජය ද සිල්වා සහ ජෙෆ්රි වැන්ඩර්සේ ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවට එරෙහි 2 වන ටෙස්ට් තරඟයෙන් ඉවත් කර ඇති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් (SLC) පවසයි.",
        "මේ අනුව වෛරසය සඳහා ධනාත්මක බව පරීක්‍ෂා කළ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජාතික කණ්ඩායමේ මුළු ක්‍රීඩකයින් සංඛ්‍යාව 4 දක්වා ගෙන එයි.",
        "මීට පෙර, තරු තුන් ඉරියව් ක්‍රීඩක, ඇන්ජලෝ මැතිව්ස් පළමු ටෙස්ට් තරගයේ 2 වන දින ප්‍රමාද වී ධනාත්මක බව පරීක්‍ෂා කළ අතර පසුව තරගයෙන් ඉවත් විය. ඔහු වෙනුවට ඕෂද ප්‍රනාන්දු කැඳවා තිබුණි.",
        "මැතිව්ස් අසනීප වූ පසු ධනාත්මක වේගවත් ප්‍රතිදේහජනක පරීක්ෂණයක් නැවත ලබා දී ඇත. ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබුණේ එතැන් සිට ඔහු සෙසු කණ්ඩායම් සාමාජිකයන්ගෙන් හුදෙකලා වී ඇති බවයි.",
        "ජූලි 04 වන දින ප්‍රවීන් ජයවික්‍රම ද කොවිඩ් -19 සඳහා ධනාත්මක බව පරීක්‍ෂා කර දින පහක් වහාම හුදකලා විය.",
        "ජුලි 04 වැනි දින උදෑසන ‘සනීප නොවන’ බවක් දැනුණු බවට පැමිණිලි කිරීම නිසා ක්‍රීඩකයා (Rapid Antigen Test) පරීක්‍ෂා කළ විට ඔහුට Covid ධනාත්මක බව පෙනී ගිය බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් ආයතනය පවසා ඇත.",
        "ජයවික්‍රම වහාම කණ්ඩායමේ සෙසු සාමාජිකයින්ගෙන් හුදකලා වූ අතර දින 5 ක් කාමර හුදකලාවේ සිටිනු ඇත.",
        "ජයවික්‍රම කොවිඩ් පොසිටිව් ලෙස හඳුනාගැනීමත් සමඟ කණ්ඩායමේ සෙසු සාමාජිකයන් (ක්‍රීඩකයන් සහ සහායක කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය) වේගවත් ප්‍රතිදේහජනක පරීක්ෂණයකට භාජනය කළ නමුත් ඔවුන් සියලු දෙනාම ඒ වන විට ඍණාත්මක ප්‍රතිඵල ලබා දුන් බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් ආයතනය පවසා තිබුණි.",
        "ජූලි 8 සිකුරාදා ආරම්භ වන දෙවන ටෙස්ට් තරගයට නියමිත වේලාවට ඔහු සුවය ලබා ගතහොත් මැතිව්ස්ගේ නැවත පැමිණීම ශ්‍රී ලංකාව බලාපොරොත්තු වේ.",
        "පළමු ටෙස්ට් තරගයෙන් කඩුලු 10කින් විශිෂ්ට ජයක් අත්කරගත් ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාව තරග දෙකකින් සමන්විත තරගාවලිය 1-0ක් ලෙස ඉදිරියෙන් සිටී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ධනංජය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "වැන්ඩර්සේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධනංජය ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෙෆ්රි වැන්ඩර්සේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 වැනි ටෙස්ට්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇන්ජලෝ මැතිව්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕෂද ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 04",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රවීන් ජයවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින පහක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 04 උදේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයවික්‍රම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 5 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයවික්‍රම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොවිඩ් පොසිටිව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැතිව්ස්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පරීක්ෂණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தனஞ்சயா மற்றும் வாண்டர்சே ஆகியோரும் கோவிட்-19 பாசிட்டிவ் சோதனையில் உள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை கிரிக்கெட் வீரர்கள் தனஞ்சய டி சில்வா மற்றும் ஜெஃப்ரி வான்டர்சே ஆகியோர் ஆஸ்திரேலியாவுக்கு எதிரான 2 வது டெஸ்டில் இருந்து விலக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர், ஏனெனில் இரு வீரர்களும் கோவிட் -19 க்கு சாதகமாக சோதனை செய்ததாக இலங்கை கிரிக்கெட் (எஸ்எல்சி) தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதன் மூலம் இலங்கை தேசிய அணி வீரர்களின் மொத்த எண்ணிக்கை வைரஸுக்கு சாதகமாக உள்ளது.",
        "முன்னதாக, நட்சத்திர ஆல்-ரவுண்டர், ஏஞ்சலோ மேத்யூஸ் முதல் டெஸ்டின் 2 ஆம் நாள் தாமதமாக நேர்மறை சோதனை செய்தார், பின்னர் போட்டியில் இருந்து வெளியேற்றப்பட்டார்; அவருக்குப் பதிலாக ஓஷத பெர்னாண்டோ அழைக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "மேத்யூஸ் உடல்நிலை சரியில்லாமல் இருந்ததால் பாசிட்டிவ் ரேபிட் ஆன்டிஜென் சோதனைக்கு திரும்பினார். அதன் பின்னர் அவர் மற்ற அணி உறுப்பினர்களிடமிருந்து தனிமைப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாக இலங்கை கிரிக்கெட் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜூலை 04 அன்று, பிரவீன் ஜெயவிக்ரமவும் கோவிட் -19 க்கு நேர்மறை சோதனை செய்தார் மற்றும் உடனடியாக ஐந்து நாட்களுக்கு தனிமைப்படுத்தப்பட்டார்.",
        "ஜூலை 04 ஆம் தேதி காலை அவர் 'உடல்நிலை சரியில்லை' என்று புகார் செய்ததால், அவர் பரிசோதிக்கப்பட்டபோது (ரேபிட் ஆன்டிஜென் டெஸ்ட்) கோவிட் பாசிட்டிவ் இருப்பது கண்டறியப்பட்டது என்று SLC கூறியது.",
        "ஜெயவிக்ரம உடனடியாக மற்ற குழு உறுப்பினர்களிடமிருந்து தனிமைப்படுத்தப்பட்டு 5 நாட்களுக்கு அறையில் தனிமைப்படுத்தப்படுவார் என்று அது கூறியது.",
        "ஜெயவிக்ரம, கோவிட் பாசிட்டிவ் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டவுடன், மீதமுள்ள குழு உறுப்பினர்கள் (வீரர்கள் மற்றும் துணை ஊழியர்கள்) ரேபிட் ஆன்டிஜென் சோதனைக்கு உட்படுத்தப்பட்டனர், இருப்பினும் அவர்கள் அனைவரும் எதிர்மறையான முடிவுகளை அளித்தனர் என்று SLC கூறியது.",
        "ஜூலை 8 ஆம் தேதி வெள்ளிக்கிழமை தொடங்கும் இரண்டாவது டெஸ்ட் போட்டிக்கான சரியான நேரத்தில் மேத்யூஸ் மீண்டு வருவார் என இலங்கை எதிர்பார்க்கிறது.",
        "முதல் டெஸ்டில் 10 விக்கெட் வித்தியாசத்தில் அபார வெற்றி பெற்ற ஆஸ்திரேலியா 2 போட்டிகள் கொண்ட தொடரில் 1-0 என முன்னிலை வகிக்கிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தனஞ்சய",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "வாண்டர்சே",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனஞ்சய டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெஃப்ரி வாண்டர்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2வது டெஸ்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கிரிக்கெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏஞ்சலோ மேத்யூஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓஷத பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கிரிக்கெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 04",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரவீன் ஜெயவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 04 காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெயவிக்ரம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயவிக்ரம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவிட் பாசிட்டிவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேத்யூஸ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோதனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}