{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/රට-පනින්-හැදූ-67ක්-අත්අඩංගුවට/1-616076",
  "time_ut": 1657278722,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රට පනින් හැදූ 67ක් අත්අඩංගුවට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "67 foreigners arrested",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to the Sri Lanka Navy, 67 people and a multi-day vessel suspected of attempting to illegally migrate from Sri Lanka to a foreign country by sea were arrested in the Kalmunai area of ​​the East Sea this morning (8).",
        "The Sri Lanka Navy ship Ranarisi inspected a suspected multi-day fishing vessel sailing in the sea area off the Kalmunai area early this morning and found 06 smugglers who were suspected of trying to illegally migrate to a foreign country by sea in that multi-day fishing vessel. The navy also said that 67 people, including 53 men, 6 women and 8 children, were taken into custody along with the multi-day fishing vessel.",
        "The Navy said that the people taken into custody were identified as residents of Mannar, Vavuniya, Mullaitivu, Trincomalee and Batticaloa, aged between one year and 56."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "67",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "67",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalmunai",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "​​the East Sea",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "8)",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranarisi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "multi-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalmunai",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "early this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "multi-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "67",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "53",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar, Vavuniya,",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mullaitivu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee and Batticaloa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "between one year and",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "56",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රට පනින් හැදූ 67ක් අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "නීති විරෝධී ලෙස මුහුදු මාර්ග ඔස්සේ මෙරටින් විදෙස් රටකට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සහ කළ බවට සැකකෙරෙන පුද්ගලයන් 67 දෙනෙකු සහ බහුදින යාත්‍රාවක් නැගෙනහිර මුහුදේ කල්මුණේ ප්‍රදේශයේදී අද (8) අළුයම අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව පවසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා රණරිසි නෞකාව කල්මුණේ ප්‍රදේශයට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයේ අද අළුයම  සිදුකළ මුර සංචාරයකදී යාත්‍රා කරමින් තිබූ සැකකටයුතු මෙරට බහුදින ධීවර යාත්‍රාවක් පරීක්ෂා කළ බවත් එහිදී එම බහුදින ධීවර යාත්‍රාව තුළ සිටි නීති විරෝධීව මුහුද මඟින් විදෙස් රටකට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ බවට සැකකෙරෙන ජාවාරම්කරුවන් 06 දෙනෙකු සමඟ පිරිමි පුද්ගලයන් 53 ක්, කාන්තාවන් 6 ක් සහ ළමුන් 8 ක් ඇතුළු පුද්ගලයින් 67 දෙනෙකු එම බහුදින ධීවර යාත්‍රාව සමඟ නාවික හමුදා භාරයට ගත් බවත් නාවික හමුදාව සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මෙලෙස නාවික හමුදාව භාරයට ගත් පිරිස වයස අවුරුද්දත් 56 ත් අතර පසුවන මන්නාරම, වව්නියාව, මුලතිව්, ත්‍රීකුණාමලය සහ මඩකලපුව යන ප්‍රදේශයන්හී පදිංචිකරුවන් බවට හඳුනාගත් බව කී නාවික හමුදාව එම පිරිස ඉදිරි නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා ත්‍රීකුණාමලය වරාය පොලිසියට භාරදීමට නියමිත බව ද සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "67",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "67",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කල්මුණේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර මුහුද",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "8)",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රණරිසි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බහු දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කල්මුණේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද උදේ පාන්දර",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බහු දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "67",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "53",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම, වවුනියාව,",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුලතිව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රිකුණාමලය සහ මඩකලපුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරක් අතර සහ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "56",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "67 வெளிநாட்டவர்கள் கைது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையில் இருந்து கடல் மார்க்கமாக வெளிநாட்டுக்கு செல்ல முயன்றதாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் 67 பேரும் பல நாள் படகு ஒன்றும் இன்று (8) காலை கிழக்கு கடல் பகுதியின் கல்முனை பகுதியில் வைத்து கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக இலங்கை கடற்படை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இன்று அதிகாலை கல்முனை கடற்பகுதியில் பயணித்த சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான பல நாள் மீன்பிடிக் கப்பலை இலங்கை கடற்படை கப்பலான ரணரிசி சோதனையிட்டதுடன், கடல் மார்க்கமாக வெளிநாடுகளுக்கு சட்டவிரோதமாக செல்ல முயன்றதாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் 06 ஆட்கடத்தல்காரர்கள் பல நாள் மீன்பிடியில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர். பல நாள் மீன்பிடி கப்பலுடன் 53 ஆண்கள், 6 பெண்கள் மற்றும் 8 குழந்தைகள் உட்பட 67 பேர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக கடற்படை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர்கள் மன்னார், வவுனியா, முல்லைத்தீவு, திருகோணமலை மற்றும் மட்டக்களப்பு ஆகிய பிரதேசங்களைச் சேர்ந்த ஒரு வயதுக்கும் 56 வயதுக்கும் இடைப்பட்டவர்கள் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளதாக கடற்படை தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "67",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "67",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்முனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு கடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "8)",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணரிசி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்முனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "67",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "53",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார், வவுனியா,",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முல்லைத்தீவு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை மற்றும் மட்டக்களப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வருடம் மற்றும் இடையே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "56",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}