{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Party-Leaders-ask-for-RW-to-step-down/108-241012",
  "time_ut": 1657722539,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Party Leaders ask for RW to step down",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Party Leaders ask for RW to step down",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Party leaders decided to request Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe to resign forthwith and allow the Speaker to take charge of the country, PTA Leader Mano Ganesan said.",
        "Commanders of the three armed forces, joint staff and IGP had also participated in the meeting. Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena expressed confidence that he can obtain the letter of resignation from President Gotabaya Rajapaksa before the end of the day, if not, he will resign from his post as the Speaker.",
        "Opposition Party leaders refused to approve the use of live ammunition against the Protesters. Instead as political solution, we the opposition party leaders decided to request PM Ranil Wickremesinghe to resign forthwith and the Speaker to take charge of the country until July 20 on the day where the voting for new president takes place in parliament.",
        "Almost all Party Leaders of the Opposition participated while only the Law and Order minister Tiran Alles from Government side participated, Mano Ganesan said. ✅"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IGP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Protesters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PM Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Law",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Order",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tiran Alles",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පක්ෂ නායකයෝ RW ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටිති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට වහාම ඉල්ලා අස්වී කථානායකවරයාට රට පාලනය කිරීමට ඉඩ දෙන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටීමට පක්ෂ නායකයින් තීරණය කළ බව ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනතේ නායක මනෝ ගනේෂන් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "මෙම හමුව සඳහා ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාපතිවරුන්, ඒකාබද්ධ කාර්ය මණ්ඩල සහ පොලිස්පතිවරුන් ද සහභාගී වී ඇත. අද දින අවසන් වීමට පෙර තමාට ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගෙන් ලබාගත හැකි බවත් එසේ නොමැති නම් කතානායක ධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වන බවත් කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන විශ්වාසය පළ කළේය.",
        "විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට එරෙහිව ජීව උණ්ඩ භාවිතා කිරීම අනුමත කිරීම විරුද්ධ පක්ෂ නායකයෝ ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළහ. දේශපාලන විසඳුම වෙනුවට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනීම සඳහා ඡන්ද විමසීම පැවැත්වෙන ජූලි 20 වැනිදා දක්වා අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට වහාම ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙසත්, කථානායකවරයාට රට භාර ගන්නා ලෙසත් ඉල්ලා සිටීමට විපක්ෂයේ පක්ෂ නායකයන් වූ අපි තීරණය කළා.",
        "විපක්‍ෂයේ සියලුම පක්‍ෂ නායකයන් පාහේ ඊට සහභාගි වූ අතර රජය පාර්ශවයෙන් නීතිය හා සාමය පිළිබඳ අමාත්‍ය ටිරාන් අලස් මහතා පමණක් සහභාගි වූ බව මනෝ ගනේෂන් මහතා පැවසීය. ✅"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවසේ අවසානය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විරුද්ධ පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විරෝධතාකරුවන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නීති",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නියෝග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටිරාන් අලස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் ஆர்.டபிள்யூ பதவி விலகுமாறு கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறார்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை உடனடியாக பதவி விலகுமாறும், சபாநாயகரை நாட்டைப் பொறுப்பேற்க அனுமதிக்குமாறும் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக பயங்கரவாதத் தடுப்புச் சட்டத்தின் தலைவர் மனோ கணேசன் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இந்த சந்திப்பில் முப்படைகளின் தளபதிகள், கூட்டுப் பணியாளர்கள் மற்றும் ஐஜிபி ஆகியோரும் கலந்துகொண்டனர். ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவிடம் ராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை பெற்றுக்கொள்ள முடியுமெனவும், இல்லாவிடின் சபாநாயகர் பதவியை ராஜினாமா செய்வதாகவும் சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன நம்பிக்கை தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "எதிர்க் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் எதிர்ப்பாளர்களுக்கு எதிராக உயிருள்ள வெடிமருந்துகளைப் பயன்படுத்துவதற்கு ஒப்புதல் அளிக்க மறுத்துவிட்டனர். அரசியல் தீர்வாக, பாராளுமன்றத்தில் புதிய ஜனாதிபதிக்கான வாக்கெடுப்பு நடைபெறும் ஜூலை 20 ஆம் திகதி வரை பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவை உடனடியாக பதவி விலகுமாறும் சபாநாயகரை நாட்டைப் பொறுப்பேற்குமாறும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர்களான நாங்கள் தீர்மானித்தோம்.",
        "ஏறக்குறைய அனைத்து எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர்களும் கலந்து கொண்டதாகவும், அரசாங்கம் தரப்பில் சட்டம் மற்றும் ஒழுங்கு அமைச்சர் திரான் அலஸ் மாத்திரமே பங்குபற்றியதாகவும் மனோ கணேசன் தெரிவித்தார். ✅"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.ஜி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாள் முடிவு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்க்கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சட்டம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்டர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிரன் அலஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}