{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/foreign-banks-refuse-to-confirm-sri-lanka-state-bank-letters-of-credit-minister-96474/",
  "time_ut": 1656296820,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Foreign banks refuse to confirm Sri Lanka state bank letters of credit: Minister",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Foreign banks refuse to confirm Sri Lanka state bank letters of credit: Minister",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Foreign banks are refusing to confirm letters of credit issued by Sri Lanka state banks, and oil suppliers are also rejecting them, Power and Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekera said as the country reels from the worst currency crisis in the history of the central bank.",
        "A supplier who was given an order for petrol had rejected a letter of credit issued by a state bank.",
        "At first efforts were made with Bank of Ceylon to issue a Letter of Credit and later People’s Bank agreed to issue a letter of credit.",
        "Minister Wijesekera said efforts were made to get Standard Chartered Bank and some Indian banks to confirm the Letter of Credit but they had declined.",
        "The supplier then tried to get the trade credit approved by a financial institution affiliated to them, but a few days later the agency had also refused.",
        "The ship had then been diverted to an Indian port, he said and CPC could not confirm when the next petrol ship would come.",
        "State run Ceylon Petroleum Corporation owes US$326mn to traditional suppliers through transactions made via Bank of Ceylon and would owe US$372mn to suppliers by June through letters of credit opened by People’s Bank by June, he said.",
        "Some suppliers like Petro China used to give Sri Lanka 180 days of credit through LCs, Minister Wijesekera said.",
        "Sri Lanka is operating probably the most deadly monetary regime cooked up mainly by US neo-Mercantilists and peddled to third world nations called flexible inflation targeting where a unstable reserve collecting peg (flexible exchange rate) is bombarded with liquidity injections via open market operation (flexible inflation targeting) until it collapses.",
        "Traditional suppliers to Ceylon Petroleum Corporation could no longer bear the risk of supplying Sri Lanka due to unsettled arrears, he said.",
        "However efforts were underway to develop a payment plan to settle them, he said.",
        "Sri Lanka was not getting responses for recent oil tenders he said. Except for a solitary tender for Jet-A1 which was too expensive, there were no responses for regular tenders, he said.",
        "With old suppliers in arrears the CPC had evaluated proposals from a number of new suppliers who had made proposals and given letters of awards.",
        "“Two suppliers told me that their banks when they went to their banks, their suppliers refused to supply after a further downgrade a few days ago they cannot agree to LCs with these banks or tripartite agreements,” Wijesekera said.",
        "The new supplier had asked for pre-payment but there was no provision in the agreement to do that.",
        "However the CPC was now looking at paying upfront and getting oil, he said. (Colombo/June27/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bank of Ceylon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "People’s Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Standard Chartered Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Letter of Credit",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "a few days later",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "326mn",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bank of Ceylon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$372mn",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "People’s Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Petro China",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "180 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "a few days ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රාජ්‍ය බැංකු ණයවර ලිපි තහවුරු කිරීම විදේශීය බැංකු ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරයි: ඇමති",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකා රාජ්‍ය බැංකු විසින් නිකුත් කරන ලද ණයවර ලිපි තහවුරු කිරීම විදේශීය බැංකු ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන අතර තෙල් සැපයුම්කරුවන් ද ඒවා ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර මහතා පැවසුවේ මහ බැංකු ඉතිහාසයේ දරුණුතම මුදල් අර්බුදයෙන් රට පෙරළී යද්දී ය.",
        "පෙට්‍රල් සඳහා ඇණවුමක් ලබාදුන් සැපයුම්කරුවෙකු රාජ්‍ය බැංකුවකින් නිකුත් කළ ණයවර ලිපියක් ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "මුලින්ම ලංකා බැංකුව සමඟ ණයවර ලිපියක් නිකුත් කිරීමට උත්සාහ කළ අතර පසුව මහජන බැංකුව ණයවර ලිපියක් නිකුත් කිරීමට එකඟ විය.",
        "අමාත්‍ය විජේසේකර පැවසුවේ, ස්ටෑන්ඩර්ඩ් චාර්ටඩ් බැංකුව සහ සමහර ඉන්දීය බැංකු ණයවර ලිපිය තහවුරු කර ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කළ නමුත් ඒවා ප්‍රතික්ෂේප වූ බවයි.",
        "එවිට සැපයුම්කරු ඔවුන්ට අනුබද්ධ මූල්‍ය ආයතනයකින් වෙළඳ ණය අනුමත කර ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කළ නමුත් දින කිහිපයකට පසු ඒජන්සිය ද එය ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කර ඇත.",
        "පසුව නෞකාව ඉන්දීය වරායකට හරවා යවා ඇති බවත්, මීළඟ පෙට්‍රල් නැව එන්නේ කවදාදැයි CPC වෙත තහවුරු කළ නොහැකි බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "රජය විසින් පවත්වාගෙන යනු ලබන ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව ලංකා බැංකුව හරහා සිදු කරන ලද ගනුදෙනු හරහා සම්ප්‍රදායික සැපයුම්කරුවන්ට ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 326ක් ණය වී ඇති අතර ජුනි මාසය වන විට මහජන බැංකුව විසින් විවෘත කරන ලද ණයවර ලිපි මඟින් සැපයුම්කරුවන්ට ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 372ක් ගෙවිය යුතු බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "පෙට්‍රෝ චයිනා වැනි ඇතැම් සැපයුම්කරුවන් LC හරහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට දින 180 ක ණය ලබාදුන් බව අමාත්‍ය විජේසේකර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ක්‍රියාත්මක වන්නේ ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් එක්සත් ජනපද නව වෙළඳවාදීන් විසින් සකස් කරන ලද සහ නම්‍යශීලී උද්ධමනය ලෙස හැඳින්වෙන තුන්වන ලෝකයේ ජාතීන්ට පොළඹවන ලද වඩාත්ම මාරාන්තික මූල්‍ය පාලන තන්ත්‍රය වන අතර එහිදී විවෘත වෙළඳපල ක්‍රියාකාරිත්වය (නම්‍යශීලී) හරහා ද්‍රවශීලතා එන්නත් වලින් අස්ථායී සංචිත එකතු කිරීමේ කූඩුවක් (නම්‍යශීලී විනිමය අනුපාතිකයක්) බෝම්බ හෙලන ලදී. උද්ධමනය ඉලක්ක කිරීම) එය කඩා වැටෙන තුරු.",
        "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව වෙත සම්ප්‍රදායික සැපයුම්කරුවන්ට නොවිසඳුණු හිඟ මුදල් හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සැපයීමේ අවදානම තවදුරටත් දරාගත නොහැකි බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ඒවා පියවීම සඳහා ගෙවීම් සැලැස්මක් සකස් කිරීමට උත්සාහ ගනිමින් සිටින බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මෑතකාලීන තෙල් ටෙන්ඩර් සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ප්‍රතිචාර නොලබන බව ඔහු පැවසීය. Jet-A1 සඳහා මිල අධික වූ හුදකලා ටෙන්ඩරයක් හැර සාමාන්‍ය ටෙන්ඩර් සඳහා ප්‍රතිචාර නොමැති බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "පැරණි සැපයුම්කරුවන් හිඟ වීමත් සමඟ තෙල් සංස්ථාව යෝජනා ඉදිරිපත් කර සම්මාන ලිපි ලබා දුන් නව සැපයුම්කරුවන් රැසකගේ යෝජනා ඇගයීමට ලක් කර තිබුණි.",
        "\"සැපයුම්කරුවන් දෙදෙනෙක් මට කිව්වා ඔවුන්ගේ බැංකු ඔවුන්ගේ බැංකුවලට ගිය විට, ඔවුන්ගේ සැපයුම්කරුවන් දින කිහිපයකට පෙර තවදුරටත් පහත හෙලීමෙන් පසු සැපයීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළ බව ඔවුන්ට මෙම බැංකු හෝ ත්‍රෛපාර්ශ්වික ගිවිසුම් සමඟ LC වලට එකඟ විය නොහැකි බව\" විජේසේකර පැවසීය.",
        "නව සැපයුම්කරු පෙරගෙවුම් ඉල්ලා සිටි නමුත් එය කිරීමට ගිවිසුමේ ප්‍රතිපාදන නොමැත.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව දැන් බලා සිටින්නේ පෙර මුදල් ගෙවා තෙල් ලබා ගැනීමට බව ඔහු පැවසීය. (කොළඹ/ජුනි27/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්ටෑන්ඩර්ඩ් චාර්ටඩ් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ණයවර ලිපිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින කිහිපයකට පසු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 326",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 372ක්",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෙට්රෝ චීනය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 180 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින කිහිපයකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை அரச வங்கி கடன் கடிதங்களை வெளிநாட்டு வங்கிகள் உறுதிப்படுத்த மறுக்கின்றன: அமைச்சர்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கை அரச வங்கிகளால் வழங்கப்பட்ட கடன் கடிதங்களை வெளிநாட்டு வங்கிகள் உறுதிப்படுத்த மறுத்து வருகின்றன, மேலும் எண்ணெய் வழங்குநர்களும் அவற்றை நிராகரித்து வருகின்றனர், மத்திய வங்கியின் வரலாற்றில் மிக மோசமான நாணய நெருக்கடியில் நாடு தள்ளாடிக்கொண்டிருப்பதாக மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பெட்ரோலுக்கான ஆர்டரை வழங்கிய சப்ளையர் ஒருவர் அரச வங்கியினால் வழங்கப்பட்ட கடன் கடிதத்தை நிராகரித்துள்ளார்.",
        "முதலில் கடன் கடிதம் வழங்குவதற்கு இலங்கை வங்கியுடன் முயற்சிகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டது, பின்னர் மக்கள் வங்கி கடன் கடிதம் வழங்க ஒப்புக்கொண்டது.",
        "ஸ்டாண்டர்ட் சார்ட்டர்ட் வங்கி மற்றும் சில இந்திய வங்கிகள் கடன் கடிதத்தை உறுதிப்படுத்த முயற்சிகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டதாகவும் ஆனால் அவை நிராகரிக்கப்பட்டதாகவும் அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகர கூறினார்.",
        "சப்ளையர் பின்னர் வர்த்தகக் கடனை அவர்களுடன் இணைந்த ஒரு நிதி நிறுவனத்தால் அங்கீகரிக்க முயன்றார், ஆனால் சில நாட்களுக்குப் பிறகு ஏஜென்சியும் மறுத்து விட்டது.",
        "கப்பல் இந்திய துறைமுகத்திற்கு திருப்பி விடப்பட்டது, அடுத்த பெட்ரோல் கப்பல் எப்போது வரும் என்று CPC யால் உறுதிப்படுத்த முடியவில்லை.",
        "அரசாங்கத்தால் நடத்தப்படும் இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம், இலங்கை வங்கி ஊடாக மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட பரிவர்த்தனைகள் மூலம் பாரம்பரிய சப்ளையர்களுக்கு 326 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களை செலுத்த வேண்டியுள்ளது. மேலும் ஜூன் மாதத்திற்குள் மக்கள் வங்கியினால் திறக்கப்பட்ட கடன் கடிதங்கள் மூலம் சப்ளையர்களுக்கு 372 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களை செலுத்த வேண்டியிருக்கும் என அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "பெட்ரோ சைனா போன்ற சில சப்ளையர்கள் இலங்கைக்கு 180 நாட்கள் கடனுதவியை LCக்கள் மூலம் வழங்கியதாக அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையானது அமெரிக்க நவ வணிகர்களால் பிரதானமாக சமைத்து மூன்றாம் உலக நாடுகளுக்கு வளைந்து கொடுக்கும் பணவீக்கம் என்று அழைக்கப்படும் மிகவும் கொடிய பண ஆட்சியாக இயங்கிக்கொண்டிருக்கிறது. பணவீக்க இலக்கு) அது சரியும் வரை.",
        "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்திற்கு பாரம்பரிய சப்ளையர்கள் நிலுவையில் உள்ள நிலுவைத் தொகையால் இலங்கைக்கு விநியோகம் செய்யும் அபாயத்தை இனி தாங்க முடியாது என அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், அவற்றைத் தீர்ப்பதற்கான கட்டணத் திட்டத்தை உருவாக்குவதற்கான முயற்சிகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டு வருகின்றன, என்றார்.",
        "சமீபத்திய எண்ணெய் டெண்டர்களுக்கு இலங்கை பதில்களைப் பெறவில்லை என்று அவர் கூறினார். ஜெட்-ஏ1க்கான தனி டெண்டர் மிகவும் விலை உயர்ந்தது தவிர, வழக்கமான டெண்டர்களுக்கு பதில் இல்லை, என்றார்.",
        "பழைய சப்ளையர்கள் நிலுவையில் இருப்பதால், CPC பல புதிய சப்ளையர்களின் முன்மொழிவுகளை மதிப்பீடு செய்து, அவர்கள் முன்மொழிவுகளைச் செய்து விருதுக் கடிதங்களை வழங்கியது.",
        "\"இரண்டு சப்ளையர்கள் என்னிடம் தங்கள் வங்கிகள் தங்கள் வங்கிகளுக்குச் சென்றபோது, ​​அவர்களின் சப்ளையர்கள் சில நாட்களுக்கு முன்பு மேலும் தரமிழக்கத்திற்குப் பிறகு வழங்க மறுத்துவிட்டனர், இந்த வங்கிகள் அல்லது முத்தரப்பு ஒப்பந்தங்களுடன் LC களுக்கு உடன்பட முடியாது\" என்று விஜேசேகர கூறினார்.",
        "புதிய சப்ளையர் முன்பணம் கேட்டுள்ளார் ஆனால் ஒப்பந்தத்தில் அதற்கான எந்த ஏற்பாடும் இல்லை.",
        "இருப்பினும், CPC இப்போது முன்பணம் செலுத்தி எண்ணெய் பெறுவதைப் பார்க்கிறது, என்றார். (கொழும்பு/ஜூன்27/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நியம பட்டய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடன் கடிதம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சில நாட்களுக்கு பின்னர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "326 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$372 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோ சீனா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "180 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு சில நாட்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}