{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Ken-Vijayakumar-elected-President-of-CIPM-SL/34-738954",
  "time_ut": 1661113854,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ken Vijayakumar elected President of CIPM SL",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ken Vijayakumar elected President of CIPM SL",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Ken Vijayakumar, a versatile business, and people’s professional, currently holding the position of Deputy General Manager – Human Resources, Admin-istration, Purchasing and Sustainability at A. Baur & Company Ltd., was elected as President of CIPM Sri Lanka, the nation’s leader in human resource management, at its Annual General Meeting held recently.",
        "Prior to his appointment as the President of CIPM Sri Lanka, he held office as the Vice President in the preceding year and served for seven years in the CIPM Executive Council, including as the Honorary Secretary and Honorary Treasurer in his tenure at CIPM, making him the ideal choice to navigate CIPM in these challenging times.",
        "Vijayakumar counts over 30 years of experience in the field of human resource management and general management with prestigious appointments at Lankem (Ceylon) Ltd., Watawala Plantations, MAS Holdings, Keells Plantations, Lanka Equities, Brandix, WNS/AVIA, Delmege Forsyth, and Waters Edge Ltd. where he held managerial and senior managerial positions. He also held the position of Regional Head of HR for Malaysia at Good Hope Asia (Holdings), a diversified conglomerate.",
        "“Developing HR professionals to be resilient to face any type of crises and challenges, spreading CIPM’s much acclaimed education courses to the neighbouring countries and thereby opening a new avenue to infuse dollars/foreign currency to the country, making representation to the Government of Sri Lanka to amend the labour laws to take advantage of the gig economy such as part time employment, multiple employment contracts, flexible work arrangements, and positioning HR professionals as partners for business while ensuring more C-suite/Boardroom representation are some of the key areas that I will be working on during my tenure,” said CIPM Sri Lanka President Ken Vijayakumar.",
        "His expertise spans multiple industries with exposure to plantations, apparel manufacturing, business process outsourcing/knowledge process outsourcing, palm oil refineries, hospitality and FMCG.",
        "Vijayakumar is also a Senior faculty member of CIPM Sri Lanka since 2008. He has a Bachelor of Arts qualification from the University of Peradeniya and a Post Graduate Diploma in Management from the Post Graduate Institute of Management (PIM) of the University of Sri Jayewardenepura and holds membership in CIPM Sri Lanka and the Malaysian Institute of Human Resource Management (MIHRM)."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ken Vijayakumar",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "CIPM SL",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ken Vijayakumar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIPM Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CIPM Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the preceding year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vijayakumar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 30 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lankem (Ceylon) Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Watawala Plantations",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "MAS Holdings",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Keells Plantations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka Equities",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Brandix",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WNS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Delmege Forsyth",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Waters Edge Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Regional Head",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malaysia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CIPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boardroom",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ken Vijayakumar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FMCG",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vijayakumar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIPM Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2008",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bachelor of Arts",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the University of Peradeniya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Post Graduate Institute of Management",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PIM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the University of Sri Jayewardenepura",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIPM Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Malaysian Institute of Human Resource Management",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කෙන් විජයකුමාර් CIPM SL හි සභාපති ලෙස තේරී පත් විය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "A. Baur & Company හි දැනට නියෝජ්‍ය සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරී - මානව සම්පත්, පරිපාලනය, මිලදී ගැනීම් සහ තිරසාරත්වය දරන, බහුකාර්ය ව්‍යාපාරයක් සහ ජනතා වෘත්තිකයෙකු වන Ken Vijayakumar, CIPM Sri Lanka හි සභාපති ලෙස තේරී පත් විය. මානව සම්පත් කළමනාකරණයේ ප්‍රමුඛයා, පසුගියදා පැවති එහි වාර්ෂික මහා සභා රැස්වීමේදී.",
        "CIPM Sri Lanka හි සභාපතිවරයා ලෙස පත්වීමට පෙර, ඔහු පෙර වසරේ උප සභාපතිවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කළ අතර CIPM හි ඔහුගේ සේවා කාලය තුළ ගරු ලේකම් සහ ගෞරව භාණ්ඩාගාරික ඇතුළුව CIPM විධායක සභාවේ වසර හතක් සේවය කළේය. මෙම අභියෝගාත්මක කාලවලදී CIPM සැරිසැරීමට සුදුසුම තේරීම.",
        "Lankem (Ceylon) Ltd., Watawala Plantations, MAS Holdings, Keells Plantations, Lanka Equities, Brandix, WNS/AVIA, Delmege Forsyth, සහ යන ආයතනවල කීර්තිමත් පත්වීම් සමඟින් විජයකුමාර් මානව සම්පත් කළමනාකරණ සහ සාමාන්‍ය කළමනාකරණ ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ වසර 30කට වැඩි පළපුරුද්දක් ඇත. ඔහු කළමනාකාර සහ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ කළමනාකාර තනතුරු දැරූ වෝටර්ස් එජ් ලිමිටඩ්. ඔහු විවිධාංගීකරණය වූ සමූහ ව්‍යාපාරයක් වන Good Hope Asia (Holdings) හි මැලේසියාව සඳහා මානව සම්පත් අංශයේ කලාපීය ප්‍රධානියා ලෙස ද කටයුතු කළේය.",
        "“ඕනෑම ආකාරයක අර්බුදවලට සහ අභියෝගවලට මුහුණ දීමට ඔරොත්තු දෙන ලෙස මානව සම්පත් වෘත්තිකයන් සංවර්ධනය කිරීම, CIPM හි බෙහෙවින් පිළිගත් අධ්‍යාපන පාඨමාලා අසල්වැසි රටවලට ව්‍යාප්ත කිරීම සහ එමඟින් ඩොලර්/විදේශ මුදල් රටට පුරවාලීමට නව මාවතක් විවෘත කරමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයට නියෝජනයක් ලබා දීම. අර්ධකාලීන රැකියා, බහු රැකියා කොන්ත්‍රාත්තු, නම්‍යශීලී වැඩ විධිවිධාන, සහ HR වෘත්තිකයන් ව්‍යාපාර සඳහා හවුල්කරුවන් ලෙස ස්ථානගත කිරීම වැනි ගිග් ආර්ථිකයේ වාසිය ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා කම්කරු නීති සංශෝධනය කිරීම සහ වැඩි C-suite/Boardroom නියෝජනයක් සහතික කරන ප්‍රධාන ක්ෂේත්‍ර කිහිපයකි. මම මගේ ධුර කාලය තුළ වැඩ කරනවා,” CIPM ශ්‍රී ලංකා සභාපති කෙන් විජයකුමාර් පැවසීය.",
        "ඔහුගේ ප්‍රවීණත්වය වැවිලි, ඇඟලුම් නිෂ්පාදනය, ව්‍යාපාර ක්‍රියාවලි බාහිරින් ලබා ගැනීම/දැනුම ක්‍රියාවලි බාහිරින් ලබා ගැනීම, ෆාම් ඔයිල් පිරිපහදු, ආගන්තුක සත්කාරය සහ FMCG යන ක්ෂේත්‍ර ගණනාවකට විහිදේ.",
        "විජයකුමාර් 2008 වසරේ සිට CIPM Sri Lanka හි ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පීඨ සාමාජිකයෙකි. ඔහු පේරාදෙණිය විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයෙන් ශාස්ත්‍රවේදී උපාධියක් සහ ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ කළමනාකරණ පශ්චාත් උපාධි ආයතනයෙන් (PIM) කළමනාකරණය පිළිබඳ පශ්චාත් උපාධි ඩිප්ලෝමාවක් ද ලබා ඇත. CIPM Sri Lanka සහ Malaysian Institute of Human Resource Management (MIHRM) හි සාමාජිකත්වය දරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කෙන් විජයකුමාර්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "CIPM SL",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කෙන් විජයකුමාර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIPM ශ්‍රී ලංකා",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CIPM ශ්‍රී ලංකා",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙර වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හතක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජයකුමාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 30 කට වැඩි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකෙම් (සිලෝන්) ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වටවල වැවිලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "MAS Holdings",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කීල්ස් වැවිලි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා කොටස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රැන්ඩික්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WNS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩෙල්මේජ් ෆෝසයිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෝටර්ස් එජ් ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රාදේශීය ප්රධානියා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැලේසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CIPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල කාමරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙන් විජයකුමාර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එෆ්.එම්.සී.ජී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජයකුමාර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIPM ශ්‍රී ලංකා",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2008",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශාස්ත්රවේදී උපාධිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පේරාදෙණිය විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළමනාකරණ පශ්චාත් උපාධි ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PIM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIPM ශ්‍රී ලංකා",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැලේසියානු මානව සම්පත් කළමනාකරණ ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "CIPM SL தலைவராக கென் விஜயகுமார் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கென் விஜயகுமார், பல்துறை வணிகம் மற்றும் மக்கள் தொழில்முறை, தற்போது A. Baur & Company Ltd. இல் துணை பொது மேலாளர் - மனித வளங்கள், நிர்வாகம், கொள்முதல் மற்றும் நிலைத்தன்மை பதவியை வகிக்கிறார், CIPM இலங்கையின் தலைவராக தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார். மனித வள மேலாண்மையில் தலைவர், அதன் ஆண்டு பொதுக் கூட்டத்தில் சமீபத்தில் நடைபெற்றது.",
        "CIPM இலங்கையின் தலைவராக அவர் நியமிக்கப்படுவதற்கு முன்னர், அவர் முந்தைய ஆண்டில் துணைத் தலைவராகப் பதவி வகித்தார் மற்றும் CIPM நிர்வாகக் குழுவில் ஏழு ஆண்டுகள் பணியாற்றினார். இந்த சவாலான காலங்களில் CIPM இல் செல்ல சிறந்த தேர்வு.",
        "லங்கெம் (சிலோன்) லிமிடெட், வட்டவளை பிளான்டேஷன்ஸ், எம்ஏஎஸ் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ், கீல்ஸ் பிளான்டேஷன்ஸ், லங்கா ஈக்விடீஸ், பிராண்டிக்ஸ், டபிள்யூஎன்எஸ்/ஏவிஐஏ, டெல்மேஜ் ஃபோர்சித், மற்றும் ஆகியவற்றில் மதிப்புமிக்க நியமனங்களுடன் மனித வள மேலாண்மை மற்றும் பொது மேலாண்மை துறையில் 30 ஆண்டுகளுக்கும் மேலான அனுபவத்தை விஜயகுமார் பெற்றுள்ளார். வாட்டர்ஸ் எட்ஜ் லிமிடெட். அங்கு அவர் நிர்வாக மற்றும் மூத்த மேலாளர் பதவிகளை வகித்தார். குட் ஹோப் ஏசியா (ஹோல்டிங்ஸ்) என்ற பல்வகைப்பட்ட கூட்டு நிறுவனத்தில் மலேசியாவுக்கான மனிதவளத்தின் பிராந்தியத் தலைவராகவும் இருந்தார்.",
        "“எந்தவிதமான நெருக்கடிகள் மற்றும் சவால்களையும் எதிர்கொள்ளும் வகையில் மனிதவள நிபுணர்களை உருவாக்குதல், CIPM இன் மிகவும் பாராட்டப்பட்ட கல்விப் பாடநெறிகளை அண்டை நாடுகளுக்குப் பரப்புதல் மற்றும் அதன் மூலம் நாட்டிற்கு டாலர்கள்/அந்நிய நாணயத்தைப் புகுத்துவதற்கான புதிய வழியைத் திறந்து, இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்திற்கு பிரதிநிதித்துவம் செய்தல். பகுதி நேர வேலை, பல வேலை ஒப்பந்தங்கள், நெகிழ்வான பணி ஏற்பாடுகள் மற்றும் வணிகத்திற்கான பங்குதாரர்களாக மனிதவள வல்லுனர்களை நிலைநிறுத்துதல் போன்ற கிக் பொருளாதாரத்தைப் பயன்படுத்திக் கொள்ள தொழிலாளர் சட்டங்களைத் திருத்துவது, மேலும் சி-சூட்/போர்டுரூம் பிரதிநிதித்துவத்தை உறுதி செய்யும் சில முக்கிய பகுதிகளாகும். எனது பதவிக்காலத்தில் நான் வேலை செய்வேன், ”என்று சிஐபிஎம் இலங்கை தலைவர் கென் விஜயகுமார் கூறினார்.",
        "அவரது நிபுணத்துவம் தோட்டங்கள், ஆடை உற்பத்தி, வணிக செயல்முறை அவுட்சோர்சிங்/அறிவு செயல்முறை அவுட்சோர்சிங், பாமாயில் சுத்திகரிப்பு நிலையங்கள், விருந்தோம்பல் மற்றும் எஃப்எம்சிஜி போன்ற பல தொழில்களில் பரவியுள்ளது.",
        "விஜயகுமார் 2008 ஆம் ஆண்டு முதல் சிஐபிஎம் ஸ்ரீலங்காவின் சிரேஷ்ட ஆசிரிய உறுப்பினராகவும் உள்ளார். அவர் பேராதனைப் பல்கலைக்கழகத்தில் இளங்கலை கலைத் தகைமையையும், ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் முகாமைத்துவ பட்டதாரி நிறுவனத்தில் (PIM) முகாமைத்துவத்தில் முதுகலைப் டிப்ளோமாவையும் பெற்றுள்ளார். சிஐபிஎம் இலங்கை மற்றும் மலேசிய மனித வள மேலாண்மை நிறுவனம் (எம்ஐஎச்ஆர்எம்) ஆகியவற்றில் உறுப்பினராக உள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கென் விஜயகுமார்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "சிஐபிஎம் எஸ்.எல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கென் விஜயகுமார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஐபிஎம் இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிஐபிஎம் இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஐபிஎம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஐபிஎம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜயகுமார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கெம் (சிலோன்) லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட்டவளை தோட்டங்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "MAS ஹோல்டிங்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கீல்ஸ் தோட்டங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கா ஈக்விட்டிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிராண்டிக்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WNS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெல்மேஜ் ஃபோர்சித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாட்டர்ஸ் எட்ஜ் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிராந்திய தலைவர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலேசியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிஐபிஎம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சபை அறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கென் விஜயகுமார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஃப்எம்சிஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜயகுமார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஐபிஎம் இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2008",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இளங்கலை கலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேராதனை பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேலாண்மை முதுகலை நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PIM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஐபிஎம் இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலேசிய மனித வள மேலாண்மை நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}