{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/AKD-calls-for-an-immediate-snap-poll/56-737905",
  "time_ut": 1658780826,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "AKD calls for an immediate snap poll",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "AKD calls for an immediate snap poll",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna (JVP) led National People’s Power (NPP) Party Leader Anura Kumara Dissanayaka is calling for the dissolution of Parliament and the holding of a snap poll immediately.",
        "Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna (JVP) led National People’s Power (NPP) Party Leader Anura Kumara Dissanayaka",
        "According to Dissanayaka, the current Parliament is a distorted reflection of the people’s will. “The current Parliament is alienated from the people; therefore, a Parliament representing the true will and wishes of the people must now be elected,” he said.",
        "Dissanayaka made these comments at a seminar titled ‘From a deviant governance to a people’s governance’ held on Sunday at the National Youth Services Council in Maharagama. The seminar is the first of a series of seminars organised by the party to present to the public its vision on how to successfully overcome the current challenges faced by the country.",
        "The NPP leader also said the party intends to ensure the complete political vanquishing of the Rajapaksa family. Noting the people’s uprising and struggle had sought to rid the country of the Rajapaksa family and nepotism, Dissanayaka said shadows of the family however remain in Parliament.",
        "“The head of the Rajapaksa rule may have been sliced off through the people’s struggle but the body remains in the form of the 134 Sri Lanka Podujana Party (SLPP) members in Parliament,” he said.",
        "Dissanayaka alleged the SLPP supported President Ranil Wickremesinghe and Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena to secure the positions as it was unwilling to let a person outside the Rajapaksa family rise to clinch the leadership of the party.  “Wickremesinghe is the protector of the SLPP for the future generations of the Rajapaksa family,” Dissanayaka claimed. “Had Dullas Alahapperuma won, the Rajapaksa’s would have lost their grip on the SLPP,” he added.",
        "According to Dissanayaka, therefore those representing the Rajapaksa’s in Parliament must be defeated at an election. “This is the only way to ensure their defeat,” he said.",
        "The NPP leader said the party will therefore lead the struggle to ensure a snap general election is held, which in turn will allow the people to elect the representatives of their choice."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "AKD",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National People’s Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Dissanayaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National People’s Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Dissanayaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dissanayaka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dissanayaka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Youth Services Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dissanayaka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dissanayaka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe is the protector of the SLPP for the future generations of the",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dissanayaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Had Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dissanayaka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "AKD වහාම හදිසි මත විමසුමක් ඉල්ලා සිටී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ (ජවිපෙ) ප්‍රමුඛ ජාතික ජන බලවේගයේ (එන්පීපී) නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක වහාම පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසුරුවා හැර හදිසි ඡන්දයක් පවත්වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටී.",
        "ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ (ජවිපෙ) ප්‍රමුඛ ජාතික ජන බලවේගයේ (එන්පීපී) පක්ෂයේ නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
        "දිසානායකට අනුව වත්මන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ජනතා කැමැත්තේ විකෘති පිළිබිඹුවකි. “වත්මන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ජනතාවගෙන් ඈත්වෙලා; එබැවින් ජනතාවගේ සැබෑ කැමැත්ත සහ අභිලාෂයන් නියෝජනය කරන පාර්ලිමේන්තුවක් දැන් තෝරා පත් කර ගත යුතු බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "දිසානායක මහතා මේ අදහස් පළ කළේ මහරගම ජාතික තරුණ සේවා සභාවේදී ඉරිදා පැවති ‘විපරීත පාලනයකින් ජනතාවාදී පාලනයකට’ යන මැයෙන් වූ සම්මන්ත්‍රණයකදීය. රට මුහුණ දී සිටින වත්මන් අභියෝග සාර්ථකව ජය ​​ගන්නේ කෙසේද යන්න පිළිබඳ තම දැක්ම ජනතාව වෙත ඉදිරිපත් කිරීම සඳහා පක්ෂය විසින් සංවිධානය කරනු ලබන සම්මන්ත්‍රණ මාලාවේ පළමු සම්මන්ත්‍රණය මෙම සම්මන්ත්‍රණය වේ.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ පවුල සම්පූර්ණයෙන් දේශපාලන වශයෙන් පරාජය කිරීම සහතික කිරීම තම පක්ෂය අපේක්ෂා කරන බව ද එන්පීපී නායකයා පැවසීය. ජනතා නැගිටීම සහ අරගලය රාජපක්ෂ පවුලෙන් සහ ඥාති සංග්‍රහයෙන් රට මුදා ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කළ බව සඳහන් කළ දිසානායක, කෙසේ වෙතත් පවුලේ සෙවණැලි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව තුළ පවතින බව පැවසීය.",
        "\"රාජපක්‍ෂ පාලනයේ හිස ජන අරගලය හරහා කපා දමන්නට ඇත, නමුත් දේහය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පක්‍ෂයේ (SLPP) මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 134 දෙනාගේ ස්වරූපයෙන් පවතී,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ පවුලෙන් පිට පුද්ගලයකුට පක්ෂයේ නායකත්වය ලබා දීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ අකමැති නිසා එම තනතුරු ලබා ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ සහය දුන් බව දිසානායක මහතා චෝදනා කළේය. \"රාජපක්ෂ පවුලේ අනාගත පරපුර වෙනුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ආරක්ෂකයා වික්‍රමසිංහ\" යැයි දිසානායක කියා සිටියේය. “ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම දිනුවා නම් රාජපක්ෂලාට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ග්‍රහණය නැති වෙන්න තිබුණා,” ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "දිසානායකට අනුව පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ රාජපක්ෂලා වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටින අය මැතිවරණයකින් පරාජය කළ යුතුය. \"ඔවුන්ගේ පරාජය සහතික කිරීමට ඇති එකම මාර්ගය මෙයයි,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "එබැවින් හදිසි මහ මැතිවරණයක් පැවැත්වීම සහතික කිරීමේ අරගලයට පක්ෂය නායකත්වය දෙන බවත්, එමඟින් ජනතාවට තමන් කැමති නියෝජිතයන් තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමට ඉඩ සැලසෙන බවත් එන්පීපී නායකයා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "AKD",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්පීපී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්පීපී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික තරුණ සේවා සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එන්පීපී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනාගත පරපුර වෙනුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ආරක්ෂකයා වික්‍රමසිංහය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම තිබුණා",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එන්පීපී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "உடனடி வாக்கெடுப்புக்கு ஏகேடி அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனதா விமுக்தி பெரமுன (ஜேவிபி) தலைமையிலான தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி (என்பிபி) கட்சியின் தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க, நாடாளுமன்றத்தை கலைத்து உடனடியாக வாக்கெடுப்பை நடத்த வேண்டும் என்று வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனதா விமுக்தி பெரமுனா (ஜேவிபி) தலைமையிலான தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி (என்பிபி) கட்சியின் தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
        "திஸாநாயக்கவின் கூற்றுப்படி, தற்போதைய பாராளுமன்றம் மக்களின் விருப்பத்தின் சிதைந்த பிரதிபலிப்பாகும். “தற்போதைய நாடாளுமன்றம் மக்களிடமிருந்து அந்நியப்பட்டுவிட்டது; எனவே, மக்களின் உண்மையான விருப்பத்தையும் விருப்பத்தையும் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் ஒரு பாராளுமன்றம் இப்போது தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட வேண்டும்” என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "மஹரகமவில் உள்ள தேசிய இளைஞர் சேவைகள் மன்றத்தில் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை நடைபெற்ற ‘விரோதமான ஆட்சியில் இருந்து மக்கள் ஆட்சிக்கு’ என்ற தலைப்பிலான கருத்தரங்கில் திஸாநாயக்க இந்தக் கருத்துக்களை வெளியிட்டார். நாடு எதிர்கொள்ளும் தற்போதைய சவால்களை எவ்வாறு வெற்றிகரமாக சமாளிப்பது என்பது குறித்த தனது பார்வையை பொதுமக்களுக்கு முன்வைக்கும் வகையில் கட்சி ஏற்பாடு செய்துள்ள கருத்தரங்குகளில் முதலாவது கருத்தரங்கு இதுவாகும்.",
        "ராஜபக்ச குடும்பத்தை அரசியல் ரீதியாக முழுமையாக தோற்கடிப்பதை உறுதி செய்வதே கட்சி உத்தேசித்துள்ளதாகவும் என்பிபி தலைவர் கூறினார். மக்களின் எழுச்சியும் போராட்டமும் நாட்டை ராஜபக்ச குடும்பம் மற்றும் தேசபக்தியிலிருந்து விடுவிப்பதாகக் குறிப்பிட்ட திஸாநாயக்க, குடும்பத்தின் நிழல்கள் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் எவ்வாறாயினும் என்றும் கூறினார்.",
        "\"மக்கள் போராட்டத்தின் மூலம் ராஜபக்ச ஆட்சியின் தலை வெட்டப்பட்டிருக்கலாம், ஆனால் உடல் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் உள்ள 134 ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன கட்சி (SLPP) உறுப்பினர்களின் வடிவத்தில் உள்ளது,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "ராஜபக்ச குடும்பத்திற்கு வெளியே ஒருவரை கட்சியின் தலைமைத்துவத்திற்கு வர அனுமதிக்க விரும்பாததால், பதவிகளைப் பெறுவதற்கு ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க மற்றும் பிரதமர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தன ஆகியோரை ஆதரிப்பதாக திஸாநாயக்க குற்றஞ்சாட்டினார். \"ராஜபக்ஷ குடும்பத்தின் எதிர்கால சந்ததியினருக்கான SLPP யின் பாதுகாவலர் விக்கிரமசிங்க\" என்று திஸாநாயக்க கூறினார். \"டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும வெற்றி பெற்றிருந்தால், ராஜபக்சவின் பிடியை ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன இழந்திருக்கும்\" என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "திஸாநாயக்கவின் கூற்றுப்படி, பாராளுமன்றத்தில் ராஜபக்சவை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்துபவர்கள் தேர்தலில் தோற்கடிக்கப்பட வேண்டும். \"அவர்களின் தோல்வியை உறுதி செய்வதற்கான ஒரே வழி இதுதான்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "எனவே பொதுத் தேர்தலை உடனடியாக நடத்துவதை உறுதி செய்வதற்கான போராட்டத்தை கட்சி வழிநடத்தும் என்றும், இதன் மூலம் மக்கள் தங்களுக்கு விருப்பமான பிரதிநிதிகளை தேர்ந்தெடுக்க முடியும் என்றும் என்பிபி தலைவர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஏ.கே.டி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனதா விமுக்தி பெரமுனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனதா விமுக்தி பெரமுனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய இளைஞர் சேவைகள் மன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.பி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க SLPP இன் எதிர்கால சந்ததியினருக்கான பாதுகாவலர்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும இருந்தார்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}