{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Bangladesh-will-never-face-situation-like-Sri-Lanka-Sheikh-Hasina/108-244004",
  "time_ut": 1661853168,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Bangladesh will never face situation like Sri Lanka: Sheikh Hasina",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Bangladesh will never face situation like Sri Lanka: Sheikh Hasina",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina today expressed her firm conviction that Bangladesh will never plunge into Sri Lanka-like situation for its development spree, rather the country will continue to move ahead overcoming all global challenges.",
        "\"Remember one thing (my party leaders and activists) that Bangladesh will never be Sri Lanka, can't be . . .,\" she said at a discussion as the chief guest.",
        "The premier, however, said that Bangladesh had to face Sri Lanka-like situation in the regime of BNP, but Awami League (AL) government has pulled the country out of that state.",
        "Dhaka South City AL and Dhaka North City AL jointly organized the discussion in the city's Bangabandhu International Conference Center (BICC), marking the National Mourning Day and 47th martyrdom anniversary of Father of the Nation Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujibur Rahman.",
        "Sheikh Hasina, also the ruling AL President, said during BNP's regime in 2001-2006, Bangladesh became champion in corruption for five consecutive times, while the country saw huge price hike of essential commodities, and scarcity of electricity, water and employment.",
        "She also said Bangladesh witnessed militancy, terrorism, grenade attack, August 21 grade attack, grenade attack in 500 places across the country, former finance minister Kibria murder and bomb attack in many places as well.",
        "She added that, \"Bangladesh's economy came to standstill due to terrorism, militancy and corruption.\"",
        "The prime minister continued that people at that time (BNP's regime) took to the street, actually they were compelled to come down on the street.",
        "She went on saying that, \"AL government has rescued the country from that state. So, why will Bangladesh become Sri Lanka today?\"",
        "With Dhaka South City AL President Freedom Fighter Abu Ahmed Mannafi in the chair, Dhaka North AL General Secretary SM Mannan Kochi moderated the discussion.",
        "Dhaka South City Corporation Mayor Sheikh Fazle Noor Taposh, Dhaka North City AL Adviser and Dhaka North City Corporation Mayor Atiqul Islam, Dhaka North City AL President Sheikh Bazlur Rahman, Dhaka South City AL General Secretary Humayun Kabir, North AL Vice President Sadek Khan, South AL Vice President Advocate Nurul Amin Ruhul, North AL Vice President Freedom Fighter MA Quader Khan and South City AL Vice President Shaheed Serniyabat, among others, also spoke.(BSS)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sheikh Hasina",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "BNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Awami League",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhaka South City AL",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhaka North City AL",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangabandhu International Conference Center",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Mourning Day",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "47th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mujibur Rahman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sheikh Hasina",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "BNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2001-2006",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kibria",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "BNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhaka South City",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Freedom Fighter",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abu Ahmed Mannafi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhaka North AL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SM Mannan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kochi",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhaka South City Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fazle Noor Taposh",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhaka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhaka North City Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Atiqul Islam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhaka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "North City",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bazlur Rahman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhaka South City",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Humayun Kabir",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sadek Khan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Advocate Nurul",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amin Ruhul",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Freedom Fighter MA",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Quader Khan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "South City",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shaheed Serniyabat",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වැනි තත්ත්වයකට බංග්ලාදේශයට කිසිදා මුහුණ දීමට සිදු නොවනු ඇත: ෂෙයික් හසීනා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "බංගලාදේශය සිය සංවර්ධන ව්‍යායාමය සඳහා කිසිදා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වැනි තත්ත්වයකට නොපැමිණෙන බවත්, ඒ වෙනුවට රට සියලු ගෝලීය අභියෝග ජයගනිමින් ඉදිරියටම යන බවත් බංග්ලාදේශ අගමැතිනි ෂීක් හසීනා අද සිය ස්ථිර විශ්වාසය ප්‍රකාශ කළාය.",
        "\"බංගලාදේශය කිසිදා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව නොවනු ඇත, එසේ විය නොහැක.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, BNP පාලනය තුළ බංග්ලාදේශයට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වැනි තත්වයකට මුහුණ දීමට සිදු වූ නමුත් Awami League (AL) රජය එම ප්‍රාන්තයෙන් රට ඇදගෙන ගොස් ඇති බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "Dhaka South City AL සහ Dhaka North City AL ඒකාබද්ධව ජාතික ශෝක දිනය සහ ජාතියේ පියා බංගබන්ධු ෂෙයික් මුජිබර් රහ්මාන්ගේ 47 වැනි දිවි පිදීමේ සංවත්සරය සනිටුහන් කරමින් නගරයේ බංගබන්ධු ජාත්‍යන්තර සම්මන්ත්‍රණ මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ (BICC) සාකච්ඡාව සංවිධානය කරන ලදී.",
        "2001-2006 BNP පාලන සමයේදී බංග්ලාදේශය අඛණ්ඩව පස් වතාවක් දූෂණයේ ශූරයා බවට පත් වූ අතර, අත්‍යවශ්‍ය භාණ්ඩවල විශාල මිල ඉහළ යාමක් සහ විදුලිය, ජලය සහ රැකියා හිඟය රට දුටුවේය.",
        "බංග්ලාදේශය සටන්කාමීත්වය, ත්‍රස්තවාදය, අත්බෝම්බ ප්‍රහාරය, අගෝස්තු 21 ශ්‍රේණියේ ප්‍රහාරය, රට පුරා ස්ථාන 500 ක ග්‍රෙනේඩ් ප්‍රහාරය, හිටපු මුදල් ඇමති කිබ්‍රියා ඝාතනය සහ බොහෝ ස්ථානවල බෝම්බ ප්‍රහාර ද දැක ඇති බව ඇය පැවසුවාය.",
        "\"ත්‍රස්තවාදය, සටන්කාමීත්වය සහ දූෂණය හේතුවෙන් බංගලාදේශයේ ආර්ථිකය ඇනහිට ඇති බව\" ඇය වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසුවාය.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා තවදුරටත් කියා සිටියේ ඒ කාලයේ (බීඑන්පී පාලනය) ජනතාව පාරට බැස්ස බවත්, ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම ඔවුන්ට පාරට බැසීමට සිදු වූ බවත්ය.",
        "ඇය තවදුරටත් කියා සිටියේ, \"AL රජය එම ප්‍රාන්තයෙන් රට මුදාගෙන ඇත. එසේනම්, අද බංග්ලාදේශය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව බවට පත්වන්නේ ඇයි?\"",
        "ඩකා සවුත් සිටි ඒඑල් සභාපති නිදහස් සටන්කාමී අබු අහමඩ් මන්නාෆි මුලසුන දැරූ අතර ඩකා නෝර්ත් ඒඑල් ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් එස්එම් මන්නන් කෝචි සාකච්ඡාව මෙහෙයවීය.",
        "ඩකා දකුණු නගර සංස්ථාවේ නගරාධිපති ෂෙයික් ෆස්ලේ නූර් තපෝෂ්, ඩකා නෝර්ත් සිටි ඒඑල් උපදේශක සහ ඩකා නෝර්ත් සිටි කෝපරේෂන් නගරාධිපති අටිකුල් ඉස්ලාම්, ඩකා නෝර්ත් සිටි ඒඑල් සභාපති ෂෙයික් බස්ලූර් රහ්මාන්, ඩකා දකුණු සිටි ඒඑල් ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් හුමායුන් කබීර්, උතුරු ඒඑල් උප සභාපති සදෙක් ඛාන්, දකුණ AL උපසභාපති අධිනීතිඥ Nurul Amin Ruhul, North AL උපසභාපති නිදහස් සටන්කාමී MA Quader Khan සහ South City AL උපසභාපති Shaheed Serniyabat ඇතුළු පිරිසක් ද කතා කළහ.(BSS)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ෂෙයික් හසීනා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීඑන්පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවාමි ලීගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩකා දකුණු නගරය AL",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩකා උතුරු නගරය AL",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංගබන්ධු ජාත්‍යන්තර සම්මන්ත්‍රණ මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ශෝක දිනය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "47 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුජිබර් රහ්මාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෂෙයික් හසීනා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීඑන්පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2001-2006",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිබ්රියා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "බීඑන්පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩකා දකුණු නගරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් සටන්කාමියා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබු අහමඩ් මන්නාෆි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩකා උතුරු ඒඑල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස් එම් මන්නන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොචි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩකා දකුණු නගර සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆසල් නූර් තපෝෂ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩකා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩකා උතුරු නගර සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අතිකුල් ඉස්ලාම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩකා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු නගරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bazlur Rahman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩකා දකුණු නගරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හුමායුන් කබීර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සදෙක් ඛාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධිනීතිඥ නුරුල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමීන් රුහුල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් සටන්කාමී එම්.ඒ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්වාඩර් ඛාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු නගරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂහීඩ් සර්නියාබත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையைப் போன்ற சூழலை வங்கதேசம் சந்திக்காது: ஷேக் ஹசீனா",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பங்களாதேஷ் பிரதமர் ஷேக் ஹசீனா இன்று தனது உறுதியான நம்பிக்கையை வெளிப்படுத்தினார், பங்களாதேஷ் அதன் வளர்ச்சிக்காக இலங்கை போன்ற சூழ்நிலையில் ஒருபோதும் மூழ்காது, மாறாக நாடு அனைத்து உலகளாவிய சவால்களையும் கடந்து தொடர்ந்து முன்னேறும்.",
        "“பங்களாதேஷ் ஒருபோதும் இலங்கையாக இருக்காது, இருக்க முடியாது.. என்ற ஒரு விஷயத்தை (எனது கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் மற்றும் செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள்) நினைவில் வையுங்கள்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், பிஎன்பியின் ஆட்சியில் பங்களாதேஷ் இலங்கை போன்ற சூழ்நிலையை எதிர்கொள்ள வேண்டியிருந்தது, ஆனால் அவாமி லீக் (ஏஎல்) அரசாங்கம் நாட்டை அந்த மாநிலத்தில் இருந்து வெளியேற்றியுள்ளது என்று பிரதமர் கூறினார்.",
        "டாக்கா சவுத் சிட்டி ஏஎல் மற்றும் டாக்கா நார்த் சிட்டி ஏஎல் ஆகியவை இணைந்து நகரின் பங்கபந்து சர்வதேச மாநாட்டு மையத்தில் (பிஐசிசி) கலந்துரையாடலை ஏற்பாடு செய்தன, இது தேசிய துக்க நாள் மற்றும் தேசத் தந்தை பங்கபந்து ஷேக் முஜிபுர் ரஹ்மானின் 47வது தியாக நினைவு தினத்தைக் குறிக்கும்.",
        "ஷேக் ஹசீனா, ஆளும் AL தலைவர், 2001-2006 இல் BNP ஆட்சியின் போது, ​​வங்காளதேசம் தொடர்ந்து ஐந்து முறை ஊழலில் சாம்பியன் ஆனது, அதே நேரத்தில் நாடு அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களின் பெரும் விலை உயர்வு மற்றும் மின்சாரம், தண்ணீர் மற்றும் வேலைவாய்ப்பு பற்றாக்குறை ஆகியவற்றைக் கண்டது.",
        "வங்காளதேசம் தீவிரவாதம், பயங்கரவாதம், கையெறி குண்டு தாக்குதல், ஆகஸ்ட் 21 கிரேடு தாக்குதல், நாடு முழுவதும் 500 இடங்களில் கையெறி குண்டு தாக்குதல், முன்னாள் நிதியமைச்சர் கிப்ரியா கொலை மற்றும் பல இடங்களில் வெடிகுண்டு தாக்குதல் போன்றவற்றையும் கண்டதாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "பயங்கரவாதம், தீவிரவாதம் மற்றும் ஊழலால் வங்கதேசத்தின் பொருளாதாரம் ஸ்தம்பிதமடைந்துள்ளது என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "அந்த நேரத்தில் (பிஎன்பி ஆட்சி) மக்கள் தெருவில் இறங்கினர், உண்மையில் அவர்கள் தெருவில் இறங்க வேண்டிய கட்டாயம் ஏற்பட்டது என்று பிரதமர் தொடர்ந்தார்.",
        "அவள் தொடர்ந்து சொன்னாள், \"அந்த மாநிலத்திலிருந்து AL அரசாங்கம் நாட்டை மீட்டெடுத்தது. எனவே, பங்களாதேஷ் ஏன் இன்று இலங்கையாக மாறும்?\"",
        "டாக்கா சவுத் சிட்டி ஏஎல் தலைவர் சுதந்திரப் போராட்ட வீரர் அபு அகமது மன்னாஃபி தலைமையில், டாக்கா வடக்கு ஏஎல் பொதுச் செயலாளர் எஸ்.எம்.மன்னன் கொச்சி விவாதத்தை நெறிப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "டாக்கா சவுத் சிட்டி கார்ப்பரேஷன் மேயர் ஷேக் ஃபஸ்லே நூர் தபோஷ், டாக்கா நார்த் சிட்டி ஏஎல் ஆலோசகர் மற்றும் டாக்கா நார்த் சிட்டி கார்ப்பரேஷன் மேயர் அதிகுல் இஸ்லாம், டாக்கா நார்த் சிட்டி ஏஎல் தலைவர் ஷேக் பஸ்லூர் ரஹ்மான், டாக்கா சவுத் சிட்டி ஏஎல் பொதுச் செயலாளர் ஹுமாயூன் கபீர், வடக்கு ஏஎல் துணைத் தலைவர் சதேக் கான், தெற்கு AL துணைத் தலைவர் வழக்கறிஞர் நூருல் அமின் ரூஹுல், வடக்கு AL துணைத் தலைவர் சுதந்திரப் போராளி எம்.ஏ. குவாடர் கான் மற்றும் தெற்கு நகர AL துணைத் தலைவர் ஷஹீத் செர்னியாபத் உள்ளிட்டோர் பேசினர்.(BSS)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஷேக் ஹசீனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிஎன்பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அவாமி லீக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டாக்கா தெற்கு நகரம் AL",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டாக்கா வடக்கு நகரம் AL",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்கபந்து சர்வதேச மாநாட்டு மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய துக்க நாள்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "47வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முஜிபுர் ரஹ்மான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஷேக் ஹசீனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிஎன்பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2001-2006",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிப்ரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிஎன்பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டாக்கா தெற்கு நகரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விடுதலை போராளி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபு அகமது மன்னாஃபி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டாக்கா வடக்கு AL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எம்.மன்னன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொச்சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டாக்கா சவுத் சிட்டி கார்ப்பரேஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபஸ்லே நூர் தபோஷ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டாக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டாக்கா வடக்கு நகர கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அத்திகுல் இஸ்லாம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டாக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு நகரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பஸ்லூர் ரஹ்மான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டாக்கா தெற்கு நகரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹுமாயூன் கபீர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சடேக் கான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வழக்கறிஞர் நூருல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமீன் ரூஹுல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரப் போராட்ட வீரர் எம்.ஏ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குவாடர் கான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு நகரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷஹீத் செர்னியாபத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}