{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Cardinal-calls-for-a-fresh-probe-on-Easter-attack/108-243001",
  "time_ut": 1660462077,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Cardinal calls for a fresh probe on Easter attack",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Cardinal calls for a fresh probe on Easter attack",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Calling for a fresh probe on the Easter Sunday attacks, Archbishop of Colombo Cardinal Malcolm Ranjith today said the incumbent President will be accepted only if he works towards uncovering the hidden truth on the Easter Sunday attacks.",
        "Speaking during a service held at St Anthony’s Shrine, Kochikade, during which Euros 100,000 was donated by Pope Francis to the Easter Sunday victims, Cardinal Ranjith said the present government also must work towards finding the hidden truth with regards to the Easter Sunday attacks.",
        "“We will accept the present President only if he works towards uncovering the truth on the Easter Sunday attacks. The executive summary of the Select Committee has said there could be a conspiracy behind the attack. The incumbent President should work towards uncovering the truth about it,” the Cardinal said.",
        "“Also it is essential to penalize those who prevented the police officer who was going to arrest Zahran who led the attack prior to April 21, 2019. This police officer was arrested for an alleged involvement in a plot to assassinate powerful people. Those who prevented this police officer from arresting Zahran should be penalized as he had also committed a crime similar to Zaharan. We are not seeking revenge for anyone but only want to know the truth”  he added.",
        "Apostolic Nuncio  (Vatican Ambassador in Colombo) Archbishop Brian Udaigwe said the Easter Sunday Attack had taught Sri Lankans a lesson. “The attacks on April 21, 2019 had taught Sri Lankas a lesson. It had taught the importance of inter religious peace and cooperation in Sri Lanka,” he said.(Yohan Perera)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Easter",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Easter",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malcolm Ranjith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Easter",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "St Anthony’s",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shrine",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kochikade",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Euros",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Francis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Easter",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Easter",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Easter",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Select Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cardinal",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Zahran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "April 21, 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zahran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zaharan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Apostolic Nuncio",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vatican",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Archbishop Brian Udaigwe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Easter Sunday Attack",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "April 21, 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankas",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාස්කු ප්‍රහාරය ගැන අලුත් පරීක්ෂණයක් කරන්නැයි කාදිනල් හිමිපාණන් ඉල්ලා සිටී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාස්කු ඉරිදා ත්‍රස්ත ප්‍රහාරයේ සැඟවුණු සත්‍ය හෙළි කිරීමට කටයුතු කරන්නේ නම් පමණක් වත්මන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා පිළිගන්නේ යැයි කොළඹ අගරදගුරු කාදිනල් මැල්කම් රංජිත් හිමිපාණන් අද ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ෆ්‍රැන්සිස් පාප් වහන්සේ විසින් පාස්කු ඉරිදා විපතට පත් වූවන් සඳහා යුරෝ 100,000 පරිත්‍යාග කිරීම වෙනුවෙන් කොච්චිකඩේ ශාන්ත අන්තෝනි සිද්ධස්ථානයේ පැවති දේව මෙහෙය අමතමින් කාදිනල් රංජිත් හිමිපාණන් පාස්කු ඉරිදා ප්‍රහාරයේ සැඟවුණු සත්‍ය සෙවීමට වත්මන් රජය ද කටයුතු කළ යුතු බව පැවසීය.",
        "“අපි වත්මන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා පිළිගන්නේ පාස්කු ඉරිදා ප්‍රහාරයේ සත්‍ය හෙළි කිරීමට ඔහු කටයුතු කළහොත් පමණයි. තේරීම් කාරක සභාවේ විධායක සාරාංශය ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත්තේ ප්‍රහාරය පිටුපස කුමන්ත්‍රණයක් තිබිය හැකි බවයි. ඒ පිළිබඳ සත්‍ය හෙළි කිරීමට වත්මන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා කටයුතු කළ යුතුයි” කාදිනල් හිමියෝ පැවසූහ.",
        "“ඒ වගේම 2019 අප්‍රේල් 21 ට පෙර ප්‍රහාරය මෙහෙයවූ සහරාන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට ගිය පොලිස් නිලධාරියා වැළැක්වූ අයට දඬුවම් කිරීම අත්‍යාවශ්‍යයි. මෙම පොලිස් නිලධාරියා අත්අඩංගුවට ගනු ලැබුවේ ප්‍රබල පුද්ගලයන් ඝාතනය කිරීමේ කුමන්ත්‍රණයකට සම්බන්ධ යැයි කියන චෝදනාව මතයි. මෙම පොලිස් නිලධාරියා සහරාන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම වැළැක්වූ අයට දඩුවම් දිය යුත්තේ ඔහුද සහරාන් හා සමාන අපරාධයක් කර ඇති බැවිනි. අපට අවශ්‍ය වන්නේ කාගෙන්වත් පළිගැනීමක් නොව සත්‍යය දැනගැනීමට පමණයි”  ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "Apostolic Nuncio  (කොළඹ වතිකානු තානාපති) අගරදගුරු Brian Udaigwe පැවසුවේ පාස්කු ඉරිදා ප්‍රහාරය ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ට පාඩමක් උගන්වා ඇති බවයි. “2019 අප්‍රේල් 21 ප්‍රහාරය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පාඩමක් උගන්වා තිබුණි. එය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අන්තර් ආගමික සාමයේ සහ සහයෝගීතාවයේ වැදගත්කම උගන්වා ඇත.(යොහාන් පෙරේරා)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාස්කු",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැල්කම් රංජිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශාන්ත අන්තෝනි",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිද්ධස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kochikade",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆ්රැන්සිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංජිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තේරීම් කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාදිනල්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සහරාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019 අප්‍රේල් 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සහරාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සහරාන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අපෝස්තලික නන්සියෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වතිකානුව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගරදගුරු Brian Udaigwe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු ඉරිදා ප්‍රහාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019 අප්‍රේල් 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஈஸ்டர் தாக்குதல் குறித்து புதிய விசாரணைக்கு கார்டினல் அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு தாக்குதல்கள் குறித்து புதிய விசாரணை நடத்தப்பட வேண்டும் என கோரிய கொழும்பு பேராயர் கர்தினால் மல்கம் ரஞ்சித், ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு தாக்குதல் தொடர்பான மறைக்கப்பட்ட உண்மைகளை வெளிக்கொணர முயற்சித்தால் மட்டுமே தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதியை ஏற்றுக்கொள்ள முடியும் என தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கொச்சிக்கடை புனித அந்தோணியார் ஆலயத்தில் நடைபெற்ற ஆராதனையின் போது, ​​ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர்களுக்கு பாப்பரசர் பிரான்சிஸ் அவர்களால் 100,000 யூரோக்கள் நன்கொடையாக வழங்கப்பட்டபோது பேசிய கர்தினால் ரஞ்சித், ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு தாக்குதல்கள் தொடர்பான மறைக்கப்பட்ட உண்மையைக் கண்டறிய தற்போதைய அரசாங்கம் உழைக்க வேண்டும் என்றார்.",
        "“ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு தாக்குதல்கள் தொடர்பான உண்மையை வெளிக்கொணரும் நோக்கில் தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி செயற்பட்டால் மட்டுமே அவரை ஏற்றுக்கொள்வோம். இந்தத் தாக்குதலுக்குப் பின்னால் சதி இருக்கலாம் என்று தெரிவுக்குழுவின் நிறைவேற்றுச் சுருக்கம் கூறியுள்ளது. இது குறித்த உண்மையை வெளிக்கொணர தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி உழைக்க வேண்டும்” என்று கர்தினால் கூறினார்.",
        "2019 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஏப்ரல் 21 ஆம் திகதிக்கு முன்னர் தாக்குதலை நடத்திய சஹ்ரானை கைது செய்யவிருந்த பொலிஸ் அதிகாரியை தடுத்தவர்களுக்கு தண்டனை வழங்குவது அவசியமாகும். இந்த பொலிஸ் அதிகாரி சக்திவாய்ந்த நபர்களை படுகொலை செய்வதற்கான சதித்திட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டதாக கூறப்பட்டதற்காக கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார். சஹ்ரானை கைது செய்ய விடாமல் தடுத்த காவல்துறை அதிகாரிகளுக்கு தண்டனை வழங்கப்பட வேண்டும், ஏனெனில் அவரும் ஜஹாரானைப் போன்ற குற்றத்தை செய்துள்ளார். நாங்கள் யாரையும் பழிவாங்க முயற்சிக்கவில்லை, ஆனால் உண்மையை மட்டுமே அறிய விரும்புகிறோம்”  அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "அப்போஸ்தலிக் நன்சியோ  (கொழும்பில் உள்ள வத்திக்கான் தூதுவர்) பேராயர் பிரையன் உதய்க்வே, ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு தாக்குதல் இலங்கையர்களுக்கு பாடம் கற்பித்ததாக கூறினார். ஏப்ரல் 21, 2019 அன்று நடந்த தாக்குதல்கள் இலங்கைக்கு பாடம் கற்பித்தன. இலங்கையில் மதங்களுக்கிடையிலான சமாதானம் மற்றும் ஒத்துழைப்பின் முக்கியத்துவத்தை இது போதித்துள்ளது” என்று அவர் கூறினார்.(யோஹான் பெரேரா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஈஸ்டர்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மால்கம் ரஞ்சித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செயின்ட் அந்தோனிஸ்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "திண்ணை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kochikade",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யூரோக்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரான்சிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேர்வுக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கார்டினல்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஹ்ரான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 21, 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஹ்ரான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜஹாரான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அப்போஸ்தலிக்க நன்சியோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாடிகன்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேராயர் பிரையன் உதய்க்வே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு தாக்குதல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 21, 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கைகள்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}