{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/සුපිරි-බොලිවුඩ්-නිළි-ජැකලීන්-කප්පම්-නඩුවේ-විත්තිකාරිය-කරයි/1-618269",
  "time_ut": 1660722997,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "සුපිරි බොලිවුඩ් නිළි ජැකලීන් කප්පම් නඩුවේ විත්තිකාරිය කරයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Super Bollywood actress Jacqueline is the defendant in the extortion case",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Indian media reports that Sri Lankan super Bollywood actress Jacqueline Fernandez has been named as a defendant in the money laundering case filed against Sukesh Chandrashekhar by the Indian Financial Intelligence Unit for extorting an amount of 215 crore Indian rupees.",
        "The Financial Intelligence Unit has started an investigation into Sukesh Chandrashekhar's ex-Ranbaxy promoter Mr. Shivendra Singh's bail by deceiving his wife, Mrs. Aditi Singh, and obtaining nearly INR 215 crores.",
        "Jacqueline Fernandez was given gifts of 5.71 crore Indian rupees from the money obtained and due to the close friendship between Mr. Sukesh Chandrashekar and Mrs. Jacqueline Fernandez, the officers of the Financial Intelligence Unit questioned Jacqueline Fernandez for more than 5 hours in August last year.",
        "Indian media said that Jacqueline Fernandez revealed during the questioning that she recognized Chandrashekar through Sukesh Chandrashekar's wife Lena Paul and that Sukesh Chandrashekar also cheated her.",
        "The Indian media reported that the officers of the Indian Financial Intelligence Unit have made Mrs. Fernandez a defendant in the case of Mr. Sukesh Chandrashekhar, alleging that Jacqueline Fernandez knew that Mr. Sukesh Chandrashekhar would give her gifts from the fraudulently obtained money."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Super Bollywood",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Jacqueline",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bollywood",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sukesh Chandrashekhar",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Financial Intelligence Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "215",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Financial Intelligence Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sukesh Chandrashekhar's",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shivendra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aditi Singh",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.71",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sukesh Chandrashekar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Financial Intelligence Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 5 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "August last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandrashekar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sukesh Chandrashekar's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lena Paul",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandrashekar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Financial Intelligence Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sukesh Chandrashekhar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sukesh Chandrashekhar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සුපිරි බොලිවුඩ් නිළි ජැකලීන් කප්පම් නඩුවේ විත්තිකාරිය කරයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දීය රුපියල් කෝටි 215 ක මුදලක් කප්පම් ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉන්දීය මූල්‍ය බුද්ධි ඒකකය සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රශේකර්ට විරුද්ධ ගොනු කර ඇති මූල්‍ය විශුද්ධිකරණ නඩුවේ විත්තිකාරියක් ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා සම්භවයක් ඇති සුපිරි බොලිවුඩ් නිළි ජැකලීන් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් මහත්මිය නම් කර ඇතැයි ඉන්දීය මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රශේකර්  රැන්බැක්සි ආයතනයේ හිටපු ප්‍රවර්ධකයකු වන ශිවේන්ද්‍ර සිංග් මහතාට ඇප ලබා දෙන බව පවසා ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ වන ආදිති සිංග් මහත්මිය රවටා ඉන්දීය රුපියල් කෝටි 215 කට ආසන්න මුදලක් ලබා ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් මූල්‍ය බුද්ධි ඒකකය විමර්ෂණයක් ආරම්භ කළේය.",
        "එසේ ලබාගත් මුදලින් ජැකලීන් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් මහත්මියට ඉන්දීය රුපියල් කෝටි 5.71 ක තෑගි ලබා දී තිබූ අතර සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රශේකර් මහතා සහ ජැකලීන් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් මහත්මිය අතර සමීප හිතවත්කමක් පැවැතිම හේතුවෙන් මූල්‍ය බුද්ධි ඒකකයේ නිලධාරීන් පසුගිය වසරේ අගෝස්තු මස ජැකලීන් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්ගෙන් පැය 5 කට අධික කාලයක්  ලෙස ප්‍රශ්න කළේය.",
        "එහිදී සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රශේකර්ගේ බිරිඳ ලීනා පෝල් හරහා තමන් චන්ද්‍රශේකර් හඳුනාගත් බවත්, සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රශේකර් තමන්ට ද මුදල් වංචාවක් කළ බවත් ප්‍රශ්න කිරීම්වල දී ජැක්ලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් හෙළි කළ බව ඉන්දීය මාධ්‍ය පැවසුවේය.",
        "සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රශේකර් මහතා වංචනිකව ලබා ගත් මුදලින් තමාට තෑගි ලබා දෙන බව ජැකලීන් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් දැන සිටි බව චෝදනා කරමින් ඉන්දීය මූල්‍ය බුද්ධි ඒකකයේ නිලධාරීන් ෆර්ඩිනැන්ඩස් මහත්මිය සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රශේකර්ගේ නඩුවේ විත්තිකාරියක් කර ඇතැයි ඉන්දීය මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සුපිරි බොලිවුඩ්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජැකලින්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොලිවුඩ්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය මූල්‍ය බුද්ධි අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "215",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය බුද්ධි අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර්ගේ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශිවේන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අදිති සිං",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.71",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය බුද්ධි ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 5 කට වඩා වැඩි කාලයක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය අවුරුද්දේ අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රසේකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර්ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලීනා පෝල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රසේකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය මූල්‍ය බුද්ධි අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மிரட்டி பணம் பறித்தல் வழக்கில் குற்றவாளியாக பாலிவுட் நடிகை ஜாக்குலின் உள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்திய நிதிப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினால் 215 கோடி இந்திய ரூபாயை மிரட்டி பணம் பறித்ததாக சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகருக்கு எதிராக தொடரப்பட்ட பணமோசடி வழக்கில் இலங்கையின் சூப்பர் பாலிவுட் நடிகை ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ் பிரதிவாதியாக குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளதாக இந்திய ஊடகங்கள் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளன.",
        "சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகரின் முன்னாள் ரான்பாக்ஸி புரமோட்டர் திரு. சிவேந்திர சிங்கின் ஜாமீன், அவரது மனைவி திருமதி அதிதி சிங்கை ஏமாற்றி, கிட்டத்தட்ட INR 215 கோடியை பெற்றுக்கொண்டது குறித்து நிதிப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவு விசாரணையைத் தொடங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸுக்கு கிடைத்த பணத்தில் 5.71 கோடி இந்திய ரூபாய் பரிசாக வழங்கப்பட்டது மற்றும் திரு.சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகர் மற்றும் திருமதி.ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ் இடையேயான நெருங்கிய நட்பு காரணமாக கடந்த ஆண்டு ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸிடம் நிதிப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவு அதிகாரிகள் 5 மணி நேரத்திற்கும் மேலாக விசாரணை நடத்தினர். .",
        "சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகரின் மனைவி லீனா பால் மூலம் தான் சந்திரசேகரை அடையாளம் கண்டுகொண்டதாகவும், சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகரும் தன்னை ஏமாற்றிவிட்டதாகவும் ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ் விசாரணையின் போது தெரிவித்ததாக இந்திய ஊடகங்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளன.",
        "திருமதி. சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகர் மோசடியாகப் பெற்ற பணத்தில் தனக்குப் பரிசு வழங்குவார் என்பதை ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸுக்குத் தெரியும் என்று குற்றம்சாட்டி, இந்திய நிதிப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவு அதிகாரிகள் திருமதி பெர்னாண்டஸை திரு."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சூப்பர் பாலிவுட்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜாக்குலின்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாலிவுட்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகர்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய நிதி புலனாய்வு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "215",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிதிப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகரின்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிவேந்திரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதிதி சிங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.71",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி புலனாய்வு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 மணி நேரத்திற்கும் மேலாக",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்திரசேகர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகரின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லீனா பால்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்திரசேகர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய நிதி புலனாய்வு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}