{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-pm-appointed-as-acting-president-speaker-97335/",
  "time_ut": 1657699020,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka PM appointed as acting President: Speaker",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka PM appointed as acting President: Speaker",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe has been appointed acting President because President Gotabaya Rajapaksa is abroad, Parliamentary speaker Mahinda Abeywardene said.",
        "“I was informed that Under the 37-1 article of the constitution, because President Gotabya Rajapaksa is abroad, to cover the functions of the office, Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe  has been appointed,” Speaker Abeywardene said in a video statement.",
        "President Rajapaksa fled the country early in the morning to Maldives.",
        "Police have teargassed protestors around the Prime Ministers office and also fired into the air.",
        "Curfew had been declared in the Western province of Sri Lanka and emergency around the island, the PMs office said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Abeywardene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "37",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abeywardene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Curfew",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වැඩ බලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා අගමැති පත් කෙරේ: කතානායක",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආර්ථිකය - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වැඩ බලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස පත් කර ඇත්තේ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා විදේශගතව සිටින නිසා බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු කථානායක මහින්ද අබේවර්ධන මහතා පවසයි.",
        "“ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 37-1 වගන්තිය යටතේ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා විදේශගතව සිටින නිසා එම කාර්යාලයේ කටයුතු ආවරණය කිරීම සඳහා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පත් කර ඇති බව මට දන්වා තිබුණා,” කථානායක අබේවර්ධන වීඩියෝ නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ අලුයම රටින් මාලදිවයිනට පලා ගියේය.",
        "අගමැති කාර්යාලය අවට විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට පොලිසිය කඳුළු ගෑස් ප්‍රහාර එල්ල කර ඇති අතර අහසට වෙඩි තබා ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බස්නාහිර පළාතේ ඇඳිරි නීතිය සහ දිවයින පුරා හදිසි තත්ත්වයක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර ඇති බව අගමැති කාර්යාලය පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "37",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇඳිරි නීතිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தற்காலிக ஜனாதிபதியாக இலங்கை பிரதமர் நியமனம்: சபாநாயகர்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச வெளிநாட்டில் இருப்பதால் இலங்கையின் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார் என பாராளுமன்ற சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த அபேவர்தன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"அரசியலமைப்பின் 37-1 சரத்தின் கீழ், ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ வெளிநாட்டில் இருப்பதால், அலுவலகத்தின் பணிகளை மறைப்பதற்காக, பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார் என்று எனக்குத் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டது,\" என்று சபாநாயகர் அபேவர்தன காணொளி மூலம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ அதிகாலையில் மாலத்தீவுக்கு தப்பிச் சென்றார்.",
        "பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்தை சுற்றி வளைத்த போராட்டக்காரர்கள் மீது போலீசார் கண்ணீர் புகை குண்டுகளை வீசி வானத்தை நோக்கி துப்பாக்கியால் சுட்டனர்.",
        "இலங்கையின் மேற்கு மாகாணத்தில் ஊரடங்குச் சட்டம் மற்றும் தீவு முழுவதும் அவசரநிலை பிரகடனப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பிரதமர் அலுவலகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "37",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊரடங்கு உத்தரவு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}