{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/aias-national-safety-endeavour-the-poson-safety-programme-successfully-concludes-with-zero-deaths/",
  "time_ut": 1657628880,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "AIA’s national safety endeavour, the Poson Safety Programme, successfully concludes with zero deaths",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "AIA’s national safety endeavour, the Poson Safety Programme, successfully concludes with zero deaths",
      "author": "Sahan Weerasooriya",
      "body_lines": [
        "The AIA Poson Safety Programme, AIA’s flagship CSR commitment to Sri Lanka, successfully ended for 2022, with zero deaths reported due to drowning in and around the sacred city of Anuradhapura in the month of June.",
        "As a result of this programme, the thousands of pilgrims that visited Anuradhapura this Poson were able to bathe safely in the surrounding lakes and reservoirs to cleanse themselves before engaging in their religious rituals.",
        "AIA Insurance’s commitment towards the AIA Poson Safety Programme goes back to 1993 where AIA together with Sri Lanka Lifesaving and Sri Lanka Police facilitated lifeguards across most reservoirs and lakes around Anuradhapura to ensure that pilgrims were safe when they bathe in the bodies of water.  In this 27th year, the programme was held across three days, covering Anuradhapura, Polonnaruwa, Dambulla and Mihintale and facilitated 500 lifeguards across 22 reservoirs.  AIA also marked warning signs around the areas on where it is dangerous and safe to bathe while creating awareness on the dangers of drowning through displays, signboards, hoardings, and pennants across the Anuradhapura District, to encourage pilgrims to be cautious.",
        "Despite the current economic challenges, AIA was determined to continue its societal endeavours. Having saved many lives and achieving zero deaths, indeed highlights the importance of this societal endeavour.",
        "“I am so deeply grateful and indebted to the volunteers who saved mine and my son’s life” said a rescued pilgrim, adding “we come on pilgrimage to Anuradhapura every year, but this was the first time my son visited Anuradhapura for Poson with so many dreams to achieve ahead in life. This initiative organised to ensure the pilgrims’ safety is meritorious because if not for them my family would have lost two lives unnecessarily.”",
        "AIA’s Chief Executive Officer Chathuri Munaweera noted, “As Sri Lankans this is a time that we need to find ways to help each other. Seeing thousands of Sri Lankans gathering to Anuradhapura to celebrate Poson irrespective of the challenges in transportation and being there for them to ensure their safety was such a heartening experience. As always AIA kept our promise of safety in this programme and over the years have helped to save over 200 lives. This year too AIA’s Senior Management was at site in Anuradhapura together with our project team and Wealth Planners showing our commitment to the cause. I am so grateful and thankful to our partners – Sri Lanka Lifesaving, Sri Lanka Police, Sri Lanka Navy and the Civil Security Division who so enthusiastically support AIA’s Poson Safety Programme with their lifeguards each year in this great cause of protecting lives.”",
        "Increasing interest in investing in TBs likely to negatively impact CSE",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "AIA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "the Poson Safety Programme",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "zero",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Poson Safety Programme",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "zero",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the month of June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poson",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AIA Insurance’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Lifesaving and Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this 27th year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dambulla",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mihintale",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "zero",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poson",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chathuri Munaweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poson",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "This year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Lifesaving",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Civil Security Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poson Safety Programme",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "AIA හි ජාතික ආරක්‍ෂක ප්‍රයත්නය වන පොසොන් ආරක්‍ෂාව වැඩසටහන මරණ ශුන්‍යයකින් සාර්ථකව අවසන්",
      "author": "සහන් වීරසූරිය",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා AIA හි ප්‍රමුඛතම CSR කැපවීම වන AIA පොසොන් ආරක්ෂණ වැඩසටහන 2022 සඳහා සාර්ථකව අවසන් වූ අතර, ජුනි මාසයේදී අනුරාධපුර පූජා නගරය සහ ඒ අවට ප්‍රදේශයේ දියේ ගිලීමෙන් සිදු වූ මරණ බිංදුවක් වාර්තා විය.",
        "මෙම වැඩසටහන හේතුවෙන් මෙවර පොසොන් දින අනුරාධපුරයට පැමිණි දහස් සංඛ්‍යාත බැතිමතුන්ට තම ආගමික වතාවත්වල නිරත වීමට පෙර අවට වැව් හා ජලාශවල ආරක්ෂිතව ස්නානය කර පිරිසුදු වීමට හැකි විය.",
        "AIA පොසොන් ආරක්ෂණ වැඩසටහන සඳහා AIA රක්ෂණයේ කැපවීම 1993 දක්වා ඈතට දිව යයි. එහිදී AIA ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජීවිතාරක්ෂක සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය සමඟ එක්ව අනුරාධපුර අවට බොහෝ ජලාශ සහ වැව් හරහා වන්දනාකරුවන් ජල කඳේ ස්නානය කරන විට ආරක්ෂිත බව සහතික කිරීම සඳහා ජීවිතාරක්ෂකයින්ට පහසුකම් සැලසීය. මෙම 27 වන වසරේ දී අනුරාධපුරය, පොළොන්නරුව, දඹුල්ල සහ මිහින්තලය ආවරණය වන පරිදි දින තුනක් පුරා මෙම වැඩසටහන පැවැත්වුණු අතර ජලාශ 22 ක් හරහා ජීවිතාරක්ෂකයින් 500 කට පහසුකම් සලසා ඇත. AIA විසින් අනුරාධපුර දිස්ත්‍රික්කය පුරා ප්‍රදර්ශන, සංඥා පුවරු, පුවරු සහ පෑන හරහා දියේ ගිලීමෙන් සිදුවන අනතුරු පිළිබඳව දැනුවත් කරමින් වන්දනාකරුවන් ප්‍රවේශම් වන ලෙස දිරිමත් කිරීම සඳහා දිය නෑම අනතුරුදායක සහ ආරක්ෂිත ප්‍රදේශ අවට අනතුරු ඇඟවීමේ පුවරු සලකුණු කළේය.",
        "වත්මන් ආර්ථික අභියෝග මධ්‍යයේ වුවද, AIA සිය සමාජීය ප්‍රයත්නයන් දිගටම කරගෙන යාමට අධිෂ්ඨාන කරගෙන සිටියේය. ජීවිත ගණනාවක් බේරාගෙන මරණ බිංදුවක් අත්කරගෙන සිටීම, ඇත්තෙන්ම මෙම සමාජීය උත්සාහයේ වැදගත්කම ඉස්මතු කරයි.",
        "“මගේත් මගේ පුතාගේත් ජීවිතය බේරා දුන් ස්වේච්ඡා සේවකයන්ට මම බෙහෙවින් ස්තූතිවන්ත වන අතර ණයගැතියි” යැයි බේරාගත් වන්දනාකරුවෙක් පැවසුවේ “අපි සෑම වසරකම අනුරාධපුර වන්දනාවේ එන නමුත් මගේ පුතා මෙතරම් පිරිසක් සමඟ පොසොන් එකට අනුරාධපුරයට ගිය පළමු අවස්ථාව මෙයයි. ජීවිතයේ ඉදිරියෙන් සිටීමට සිහින දකියි. වන්දනාකරුවන්ගේ ආරක්ෂාව සහතික කිරීම සඳහා සංවිධානය කරන ලද මෙම මුලපිරීම පිනක් වන්නේ ඔවුන් නොවන්නට මගේ පවුලට අනවශ්‍ය ලෙස ජීවිත දෙකක් අහිමි වීමට ඉඩ තිබූ බැවිනි.",
        "AIA හි ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී චතුරි මුණවීර සඳහන් කළේ, “ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් වශයෙන් මෙය අප එකිනෙකාට උපකාර කිරීමට ක්‍රම සොයා ගත යුතු කාලයකි. ප්‍රවාහනයේ ඇති අභියෝග නොතකා පොසොන් සැමරීමට දහස් ගණන් ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් අනුරාධපුරයට රැස්ව සිටිනු දැකීම සහ ඔවුන්ගේ ආරක්‍ෂාව තහවුරු කර ගැනීම සඳහා ඔවුන් සමඟ සිටීම එතරම් හද දනවන අත්දැකීමක් විය. සෑම විටම මෙන් AIA මෙම වැඩසටහනේදී අපගේ ආරක්ෂාව පිළිබඳ අපගේ පොරොන්දුව ඉටු කළ අතර වසර ගණනාවක් පුරා ජීවිත 200කට වැඩි පිරිසක් බේරා ගැනීමට උපකාර කර ඇත. මෙම වසරේ ද AIA හි ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ කළමනාකාරීත්වය අපගේ ව්‍යාපෘති කණ්ඩායම සහ වෙල්ත් ප්ලෑනර්ස් සමඟ අනුරාධපුරයේ වැඩබිමෙහි අපගේ කැපවීම පෙන්නුම් කළහ. ජීවිත ආරක්‍ෂා කිරීමේ මෙම මහඟු කාර්යයේදී සෑම වසරකම AIA හි පොසොන් ආරක්ෂණ වැඩසටහනට තම ජීවිතාරක්ෂකයින් සමඟ ඉතා උද්‍යෝගයෙන් සහයෝගය දක්වන අපගේ හවුල්කරුවන් වන ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජීවිතාරක්ෂක, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය, ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව සහ සිවිල් ආරක්‍ෂක අංශයට මම බෙහෙවින් ස්තූතිවන්ත වෙමි.",
        "TB වල ආයෝජනය කිරීමට ඇති උනන්දුව වැඩි වීම CSE වලට අහිතකර ලෙස බලපානු ඇත",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "AIA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "පොසොන් ආරක්ෂණ වැඩසටහන",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශුන්ය",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පොසොන් සුරක්ෂිතතා වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශුන්ය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොසොන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AIA Insurance’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජීවිතාරක්ෂක සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම 27 වන වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස් තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දඹුල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිහින්තලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශුන්ය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොසොන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරි මුණවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොසොන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජීවිතාරක්ෂක",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිවිල් ආරක්ෂක අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොසොන් සුරක්ෂිතතා වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "AIA இன் தேசியப் பாதுகாப்பு முயற்சியான போசன் பாதுகாப்புத் திட்டம், வெற்றிகரமாக பூஜ்ஜிய இறப்புடன் முடிவடைகிறது",
      "author": "சஹான் வீரசூரிய",
      "body_lines": [
        "AIA Poson Safety Programme, AIA இன் இலங்கைக்கான முதன்மை CSR அர்ப்பணிப்பு, 2022 இல் வெற்றிகரமாக முடிவடைந்தது, ஜூன் மாதத்தில் புனித நகரமான அனுராதபுரத்திலும் அதைச் சுற்றியுள்ள பகுதிகளிலும் நீரில் மூழ்கியதால் பூஜ்ஜிய இறப்புகள் பதிவாகியுள்ளன.",
        "இந்த நிகழ்ச்சித்திட்டத்தின் விளைவாக, இந்த பொசன் அனுராதபுரத்திற்கு வருகை தந்த ஆயிரக்கணக்கான யாத்ரீகர்கள் தங்கள் மத சடங்குகளில் ஈடுபடுவதற்கு முன்பு தங்களைச் சுற்றியுள்ள ஏரிகள் மற்றும் நீர்த்தேக்கங்களில் பாதுகாப்பாக நீராட முடிந்தது.",
        "AIA இன்சூரன்ஸ் AIA பொசன் பாதுகாப்புத் திட்டத்திற்கான அர்ப்பணிப்பு 1993 ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கு முந்தையது, அங்கு AIA இலங்கை உயிர்காக்கும் மற்றும் இலங்கை காவல்துறையுடன் இணைந்து அனுராதபுரத்தைச் சுற்றியுள்ள பெரும்பாலான நீர்த்தேக்கங்கள் மற்றும் ஏரிகளில் யாத்ரீகர்கள் நீர்நிலைகளில் நீராடும்போது பாதுகாப்பாக இருப்பதை உறுதிசெய்யும் வகையில் உயிர்காக்கும் காவலர்களுக்கு உதவியது. இந்த 27வது வருடத்தில் அனுராதபுரம், பொலன்னறுவை, தம்புள்ளை மற்றும் மிஹிந்தலை ஆகிய இடங்களை உள்ளடக்கிய மூன்று நாட்கள் நிகழ்ச்சித்திட்டம் இடம்பெற்றதுடன், 22 நீர்த்தேக்கங்களில் 500 உயிர்காப்பாளர்களுக்கு வசதியளிக்கப்பட்டது. அநுராதபுரம் மாவட்டம் முழுவதும் உள்ள காட்சிகள், பலகைகள், போர்டுகள் மற்றும் பென்னண்டுகள் மூலம், யாத்ரீகர்களை எச்சரிக்கையாக இருக்க ஊக்குவிப்பதற்காக, நீரில் மூழ்குவதால் ஏற்படும் அபாயங்கள் குறித்து விழிப்புணர்வை ஏற்படுத்தும் அதே வேளையில், குளிப்பது ஆபத்தானது மற்றும் பாதுகாப்பானது என்ற எச்சரிக்கைப் பலகைகளையும் AIA அடையாளப்படுத்தியது.",
        "தற்போதைய பொருளாதார சவால்கள் இருந்தபோதிலும், AIA அதன் சமூக முயற்சிகளைத் தொடர உறுதியுடன் இருந்தது. பல உயிர்களைக் காப்பாற்றி, உயிரிழப்பை அடையவில்லை, உண்மையில் இந்த சமூக முயற்சியின் முக்கியத்துவத்தை எடுத்துக்காட்டுகிறது.",
        "“என்னுடைய மற்றும் எனது மகனின் உயிரைக் காப்பாற்றிய தன்னார்வலர்களுக்கு நான் மிகவும் நன்றியுள்ளவனாக இருக்கிறேன், நன்றியுள்ளவனாக இருக்கிறேன்” என்று மீட்கப்பட்ட யாத்ரீகர் ஒருவர் கூறினார், “நாங்கள் ஒவ்வொரு ஆண்டும் அனுராதபுரத்திற்கு புனித யாத்திரையாக வருகிறோம், ஆனால் எனது மகன் பொசன் பண்டிகைக்காக அனுராதபுரத்திற்கு செல்வது இதுவே முதல் முறை. வாழ்க்கையில் முன்னேற வேண்டும் என்ற கனவுகள். யாத்ரீகர்களின் பாதுகாப்பை உறுதி செய்வதற்காக ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்ட இந்த முன்முயற்சி தகுதியானது, ஏனெனில் அவர்கள் இல்லாவிட்டால் எனது குடும்பம் தேவையில்லாமல் இரண்டு உயிர்களை இழந்திருக்கும்.\"",
        "AIA இன் பிரதம நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரி சத்துரி முனவீர குறிப்பிடுகையில், “இலங்கையர்களாகிய நாம் ஒருவருக்கொருவர் உதவுவதற்கான வழிகளைக் கண்டறிய வேண்டிய தருணம் இது. போக்குவரத்தில் உள்ள சவால்களைப் பொருட்படுத்தாமல் அனுராதபுரத்தில் பொசோனைக் கொண்டாட ஆயிரக்கணக்கான இலங்கையர்கள் திரண்டு வருவதைக் கண்டது மற்றும் அவர்களின் பாதுகாப்பை உறுதிசெய்வதற்காக அவர்களுடன் இருப்பது மிகவும் மகிழ்ச்சியான அனுபவமாக இருந்தது. எப்பொழுதும் போலவே AIA இந்த திட்டத்தில் எங்கள் பாதுகாப்பு வாக்குறுதியை காப்பாற்றியது மற்றும் பல ஆண்டுகளாக 200 உயிர்களை காப்பாற்ற உதவியது. இந்த வருடமும் AIA இன் மூத்த முகாமைத்துவம் அனுராதபுரத்தில் எங்கள் திட்டக்குழு மற்றும் வெல்த் பிளானர்களுடன் இணைந்து எங்கள் அர்ப்பணிப்பை வெளிப்படுத்தியது. உயிர்களைப் பாதுகாக்கும் இந்த மகத்தான நோக்கத்தில் ஒவ்வொரு ஆண்டும் AIA இன் பொசன் பாதுகாப்புத் திட்டத்திற்கு தங்கள் உயிர்காப்பாளர்களுடன் மிகவும் ஆர்வத்துடன் ஆதரவளிக்கும் எங்கள் பங்காளிகளான இலங்கை உயிர்காப்பு, இலங்கை காவல்துறை, இலங்கை கடற்படை மற்றும் சிவில் பாதுகாப்புப் பிரிவு ஆகியோருக்கு நான் மிகவும் நன்றியையும் நன்றியையும் தெரிவித்துக்கொள்கிறேன்.",
        "காசநோய்களில் முதலீடு செய்வதில் ஆர்வம் அதிகரிப்பது CSE-யை எதிர்மறையாக பாதிக்கும்",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "AIA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "போசன் பாதுகாப்பு திட்டம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "பூஜ்யம்",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "போசன் பாதுகாப்பு திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூஜ்யம்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "போசன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AIA Insurance’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை உயிர்காக்கும் மற்றும் இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த 27வது வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்புள்ளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிஹிந்தலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூஜ்யம்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "போசன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரி முனவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "போசன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA இன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை உயிர்காக்கும்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிவில் பாதுகாப்பு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "போசன் பாதுகாப்பு திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}