{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/නොපෙනෙන-බලවෙිගයක්-ගැන-වෙල්ගමගෙන්-හෙලිදරව්වක්/1-619121",
  "time_ut": 1662021569,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "නොපෙනෙන බලවෙිගයක් ගැන වෙල්ගමගෙන් හෙලිදරව්වක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A revelation from Welgama about an invisible force",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Kumara Welgama, Kalutara District Member of the Samagi Jana Balavega, said in the Parliament that an invisible force is pulling the President's leg.",
        "Mr. Welgama said that it is not the Members of Parliament who are dragging their feet like that and the Members like the President.",
        "Mr. Kumara Welgama said that if the President's proposals are implemented, the invisible force will be displeased and if there are corrupt people, he will tell the President not to give them positions.",
        "\"Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe's budget is really good. It is a budget suitable for today's times. I don't know if this can be implemented? I don't know if it is possible. The budget gap is 100 percent. We have to borrow for it.",
        "The only thing that happened in the last budget was hitting the table. They say that it will not happen this time. I think Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe will do the job as a generous politician,\" said Mr. Welgama.",
        "The MP said that he is not going to join the government and that he has not been a minister for seven years and now he has no need to be a minister, but to build the country, we should get rid of the differences and come together.",
        "Countries like China and America are helping with great hopes, but India has currently given 4 billion dollars in aid and we should bow our hands to \"our big brother\" and it seems that \"big brother and younger brothers\" are taking good care of them, joining the budget debate in the Parliament. Mr. Kumara Welgama mentioned."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Welgama",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kumara Welgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalutara District",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balavega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Welgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kumara Welgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "America",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 billion dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Welgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නොපෙනෙන බලවෙිගයක් ගැන වෙල්ගමගෙන් හෙලිදරව්වක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපතිට නොපෙනෙන බලවේගයක් එතුමාගේ කකුලෙන් අදින බව සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ කලුතර දිස්ත්‍රික් මන්ත්‍රී කුමාර වෙල්ගම මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ දී පැවසීය.",
        "එලෙස කකුලෙන් අදින්නේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු  මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් නොවෙි යැයිද මන්ත්‍රීවරු ජනාධිපතිතුමාට කැමති බවද වෙල්ගම මහතා කීය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිතුමාගේ යෝජනා ක්‍රියාත්මක කළොත් නොපෙනෙන බලවේගය අප්‍රසාදයට පත් වෙන බවත් දූෂිතයන් සිටිනවා නම් ඔවුන්ට තනතුරු දෙන්න එපා යැයි තමා ජනපතිට කියන බවත් කුමාර වෙල්ගම මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "\"රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ අයවැය ඇත්තටම හොඳයි.එය අද කාලෙට ගැලපෙන අය වැයක්.මේක ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන්න බැරිද? පුළුවන් ද කියා මා දන්නේ නැහැ. අයවැය  පරතරය සියයට සියයයි. ඒකට ණය ගන්න වෙනවා.",
        "පසුගිය අයවැයේ වුනේ  මේසෙට ගහපු එක පමණයි. මේ සැරේ එහෙම නොවේවා කියා කියනවා .කෘතහස්ත දේශපාලකයෙක් විදියට රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වැඩේ කරනු ඇතැයි මා සිතනවා\"යනුවෙන් ද වෙල්ගම මහතා කීය.",
        "තමා ආණ්ඩුවට යන්නේ නැතැයි ද අවුරුදු හතක් ඇමතිකම් නැතිව හිටපු තමාට දැන් ඇමතිකම් වැඩක් නැතැයිද  නමුත් රට ගොඩනැගීමට  වාද භේද දුරලා එකතු විය යුතු බවද මන්ත්‍රීවරයා කීය.",
        "චීනය ,ඇමරිකාව ආදී රටවල් උදව් කරන්නේ ලොකු බලාපොරොත්තු ඇතිව නමුත් ඉන්දියාව දැනට ඩොලර් බිලියන 4ක ආධාර ලබා දී තිබෙන බවත් මේ පිළිබඳව අපි\" අපේ ලොකු අයියාට\" අත් දෙක උත්සාහ වැඳිය යුතු අතර \"ලොකු අයියා,මල්ලිලා\" හොඳට බලාගන්නා බව පෙනෙන්නට ඇතැයි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ අයවැය විවාදයට එක්වෙමින් කුමාර වෙල්ගම මහතා සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "වෙල්ගම",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කුමාර වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුමාර වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට සියයක්",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 4 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கண்ணுக்கு தெரியாத சக்தி பற்றி வெல்கமவிடமிருந்து ஒரு வெளிப்பாடு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கண்ணுக்குத் தெரியாத சக்தியொன்று ஜனாதிபதியின் காலை இழுப்பதாக சமகி ஜன பலவேகவின் களுத்துறை மாவட்ட உறுப்பினர் திரு.குமார வெல்கம நாடாளுமன்றில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அவ்வாறு இழுத்தடிப்பது பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களல்ல, ஜனாதிபதி போன்ற உறுப்பினர்களே இவ்வாறு இழுத்தடிக்கிறார்கள் எனவும் திரு.வெல்கம தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் பிரேரணைகள் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட்டால் கண்ணுக்குத் தெரியாத சக்தி அதிருப்தி அடையும் எனவும் ஊழல்வாதிகள் இருந்தால் பதவிகளை வழங்க வேண்டாம் என ஜனாதிபதியிடம் கூறுவதாகவும் குமார வெல்கம தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"மிஸ்டர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் வரவு செலவு திட்டம் உண்மையிலேயே நன்றாக உள்ளது. இது இன்றைய காலத்திற்கு ஏற்ற வரவு செலவுத் திட்டம். இதை நடைமுறைப்படுத்த முடியுமா என்று எனக்குத் தெரியவில்லை. இது சாத்தியமா என்று எனக்குத் தெரியவில்லை. வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட இடைவெளி 100 சதவீதம். நாம் செய்ய வேண்டும். அதற்காக கடன் வாங்குங்கள்.",
        "கடந்த பட்ஜெட்டில் நடந்த ஒரே விஷயம் டேபிள் அடித்தது. இம்முறை அது நடக்காது என்று கூறுகிறார்கள், தாராளமான அரசியல்வாதியாக திரு.ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க அந்த வேலையைச் செய்வார் என நான் நினைக்கின்றேன்” என திரு.வெல்கம தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "தாம் அரசாங்கத்துடன் இணையப் போவதில்லை எனவும், தாம் ஏழு வருடங்களாக அமைச்சராக இருக்கவில்லை எனவும், தற்போது அமைச்சராக பதவியேற்க வேண்டிய அவசியமில்லை எனவும், நாட்டைக் கட்டியெழுப்ப, கருத்து வேறுபாடுகளை களைந்து ஒன்றிணைவோம் எனவும் எம்.பி. .",
        "சீனா, அமெரிக்கா போன்ற நாடுகள் மிகுந்த நம்பிக்கையுடன் உதவுகின்றன, ஆனால் இந்தியா தற்போது 4 பில்லியன் டாலர்களை உதவி செய்துள்ளது, \"நம்முடைய பெரிய அண்ணனுக்கு\" நாம் கை வணங்க வேண்டும், \"பெரிய அண்ணன் தம்பிகள்\" அவர்களை நன்றாக கவனித்துக்கொள்கிறார்கள் என்று தெரிகிறது. , பாராளுமன்றத்தில் வரவு செலவுத்திட்ட விவாதத்தில் கலந்து கொண்டு திரு.குமார வெல்கம குறிப்பிட்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வெல்கம",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "குமார வெல்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெல்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குமார வெல்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெல்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 பில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார வெல்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}