{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Kumara-Welgama-released-from-corruption-case/108-239733",
  "time_ut": 1656089393,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Kumara Welgama released from corruption case",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Kumara Welgama released from corruption case",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Bribery Commission informed court it has decided to withdraw this case reserving its rights to file a fresh indictment",
        "The Former Minister had paved the way to confer a payment of Rs.3.2  million to the Deputy Chairman as his salary and other benefits",
        "The Colombo Chief Magistrate’s court yesterday ordered to release Kalutara District Parliamentarian Kumara Welgama from a corruption case following the Bribery Commission’s decision to withdraw it.",
        "The Bribery Commission had filed a corruption case against MP Kumara Welgama for allegedly causing unlawful loss to the government in 2010 after appointing an individual as a Deputy Chairman of Sri Lanka Transport Board (SLTB) in contrary to the Transport Act.",
        "The Bribery Commission informed court it has decided to withdraw this case reserving its rights to file a fresh indictment with the written sanction of three commissioners of the Bribery Commission.  The Director General of the Commission to Investigate Allegations of Bribery or Corruption had filed this case against former Minister Welgama under section 70 of the Bribery Act on four charges.",
        "The Bribery Commission alleged that Welgama had unlawfully appointed L.A. Wimalaratne as the Deputy Chairman of the SLTB on June 23, 2010, while he was serving as the Transport Minister."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kumara Welgama",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Bribery Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rs.3.2  million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalutara District",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Welgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bribery Commission’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Bribery Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Welgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Transport Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Transport Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Bribery Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bribery Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Investigate Allegations of Bribery or Corruption",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "section 70",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bribery Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Bribery Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welgama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "L.A. Wimalaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 23, 2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කුමාර වෙල්ගම දූෂණ නඩුවෙන් නිදහස්",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "අලුතින් අධිචෝදනා ගොනු කිරීමේ අයිතිය රඳවා ගනිමින් මෙම නඩුව ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගැනීමට තීරණය කළ බව අල්ලස් කොමිසම අධිකරණයට දැනුම් දුන්නා",
        "උප සභාපතිවරයාගේ වැටුප සහ අනෙකුත් ප්‍රතිලාභ ලෙස රුපියල් මිලියන 3.2 ක ගෙවීමක් හිටපු අමාත්‍යවරයා විසින් ලබා දීමට කටයුතු කර ඇත.",
        "අල්ලස් කොමිසම විසින් දූෂණ නඩුවක් ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගැනීමට ගත් තීරණයත් සමඟ කළුතර දිස්ත්‍රික් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී කුමාර වෙල්ගම මහතා එම නඩුවෙන් නිදහස් කිරීමට කොළඹ ප්‍රධාන මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය ඊයේ නියෝග කළේය.",
        "2010 වසරේ ප්‍රවාහන පනතට පටහැනිව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයේ (ශ්‍රී ලංගම) නියෝජ්‍ය සභාපතිවරයෙකු ලෙස පුද්ගලයෙකු පත් කර රජයට අයුතු පාඩුවක් සිදු කළ බවට චෝදනා කරමින් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී කුමාර වෙල්ගමට එරෙහිව අල්ලස් කොමිසම විසින් දූෂණ නඩුවක් පවරා තිබුණා.",
        "අල්ලස් කොමිසමේ කොමසාරිස්වරුන් තිදෙනෙකුගේ ලිඛිත අවසරය මත අලුතින් අධි චෝදනා ගොනු කිරීමේ අයිතිය රඳවා ගනිමින් මෙම නඩුව ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගැනීමට තීරණය කළ බව අල්ලස් කොමිසම අධිකරණයට දන්වා සිටියේය. හිටපු අමාත්‍ය වෙල්ගම මහතාට එරෙහිව අල්ලස් පනතේ 70 වැනි වගන්තිය යටතේ චෝදනා හතරක් යටතේ මෙම නඩුව පවරා තිබුණේ අල්ලස් හෝ දූෂණ චෝදනා විමර්ශන කොමිෂන් සභාවේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල්වරයා විසිනි.",
        "2010 ජුනි 23 වැනි දින ප්‍රවාහන අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කරමින් සිටියදී වෙල්ගම මහතා එල්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කුමාර වෙල්ගම",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුපියල් මිලියන 3.2",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් කොමිසමේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රවාහන පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් හෝ දූෂණ චෝදනා විමර්ශනය කරන්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්.ඒ.විමලරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2010 ජූනි 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஊழல் வழக்கில் இருந்து குமார வெல்கம விடுதலை",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதிய குற்றப்பத்திரிகையை தாக்கல் செய்வதற்கான உரிமையை ஒதுக்கி இந்த வழக்கை வாபஸ் பெற தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக இலஞ்ச ஊழல் ஆணைக்குழு நீதிமன்றத்திற்கு அறிவித்தது",
        "முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் பிரதித் தலைவருக்கு சம்பளம் மற்றும் இதர சலுகைகள் என 3.2 மில்லியன் ரூபாவை வழங்க வழிவகை செய்திருந்தார்.",
        "களுத்துறை மாவட்ட பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் குமார வெல்கமவை ஊழல் மோசடி வழக்கில் இருந்து விடுவிக்க இலஞ்ச ஊழல் ஆணைக்குழு தீர்மானித்ததையடுத்து கொழும்பு பிரதான நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம் நேற்று உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "2010 ஆம் ஆண்டு இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் (SLTB) பிரதித் தலைவராக போக்குவரத்துச் சட்டத்திற்கு முரணாக நபரொருவரை நியமித்து அரசாங்கத்திற்கு சட்டவிரோதமான நஷ்டத்தை ஏற்படுத்தியதாகக் கூறி பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் குமார வெல்கமவுக்கு எதிராக இலஞ்ச ஊழல் ஆணைக்குழு வழக்குத் தாக்கல் செய்தது.",
        "இலஞ்ச ஊழல் ஆணைக்குழுவின் மூன்று ஆணையாளர்களின் எழுத்துமூல அனுமதியுடன் புதிய குற்றப்பத்திரிகையை தாக்கல் செய்வதற்கான உரிமையை தமக்கென ஒதுக்கி இந்த வழக்கை வாபஸ் பெற தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக இலஞ்ச ஊழல் ஆணைக்குழு நீதிமன்றில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. இலஞ்சம் அல்லது ஊழல் குற்றச்சாட்டுகளை விசாரணை செய்யும் ஆணைக்குழுவின் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் வெல்கமவுக்கு எதிராக இலஞ்ச சட்டத்தின் 70ஆவது பிரிவின் கீழ் நான்கு குற்றச்சாட்டுகளின் கீழ் இந்த வழக்கை தாக்கல் செய்திருந்தார்.",
        "வெல்கம 2010 ஜூன் 23ஆம் திகதி போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சராக கடமையாற்றிய போது, ​​எல்.ஏ.விமலரத்னவை இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் பிரதித் தலைவராக நியமித்ததாக இலஞ்ச ஊழல் ஆணைக்குழு குற்றம் சுமத்தியுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "குமார வெல்கம",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலஞ்ச ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரூ.3.2 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார வெல்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலஞ்ச ஆணைக்குழுவின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலஞ்ச ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார வெல்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "போக்குவரத்து சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலஞ்ச ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலஞ்ச ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லஞ்சம் அல்லது ஊழல் குற்றச்சாட்டுகளை விசாரிக்கவும்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெல்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிவு 70",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "லஞ்ச ஒழிப்பு சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலஞ்ச ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெல்கம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்.ஏ.விமலரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 23, 2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Kumara Welgama released from corruption case",
  "body_lines": [
    "The Bribery Commission informed court it has decided to withdraw this case reserving its rights to file a fresh indictment",
    "The Former Minister had paved the way to confer a payment of Rs.3.2  million to the Deputy Chairman as his salary and other benefits",
    "The Colombo Chief Magistrate’s court yesterday ordered to release Kalutara District Parliamentarian Kumara Welgama from a corruption case following the Bribery Commission’s decision to withdraw it.",
    "The Bribery Commission had filed a corruption case against MP Kumara Welgama for allegedly causing unlawful loss to the government in 2010 after appointing an individual as a Deputy Chairman of Sri Lanka Transport Board (SLTB) in contrary to the Transport Act.",
    "The Bribery Commission informed court it has decided to withdraw this case reserving its rights to file a fresh indictment with the written sanction of three commissioners of the Bribery Commission.  The Director General of the Commission to Investigate Allegations of Bribery or Corruption had filed this case against former Minister Welgama under section 70 of the Bribery Act on four charges.",
    "The Bribery Commission alleged that Welgama had unlawfully appointed L.A. Wimalaratne as the Deputy Chairman of the SLTB on June 23, 2010, while he was serving as the Transport Minister."
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Kumara Welgama released from corruption case",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Bribery Commission informed court it has decided to withdraw this case reserving its rights to file a fresh indictment",
        "The Former Minister had paved the way to confer a payment of Rs.3.2  million to the Deputy Chairman as his salary and other benefits",
        "The Colombo Chief Magistrate’s court yesterday ordered to release Kalutara District Parliamentarian Kumara Welgama from a corruption case following the Bribery Commission’s decision to withdraw it.",
        "The Bribery Commission had filed a corruption case against MP Kumara Welgama for allegedly causing unlawful loss to the government in 2010 after appointing an individual as a Deputy Chairman of Sri Lanka Transport Board (SLTB) in contrary to the Transport Act.",
        "The Bribery Commission informed court it has decided to withdraw this case reserving its rights to file a fresh indictment with the written sanction of three commissioners of the Bribery Commission.  The Director General of the Commission to Investigate Allegations of Bribery or Corruption had filed this case against former Minister Welgama under section 70 of the Bribery Act on four charges.",
        "The Bribery Commission alleged that Welgama had unlawfully appointed L.A. Wimalaratne as the Deputy Chairman of the SLTB on June 23, 2010, while he was serving as the Transport Minister."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kumara Welgama",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Bribery Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rs.3.2  million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalutara District",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Welgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bribery Commission’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Bribery Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Welgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Transport Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Transport Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Bribery Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bribery Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Investigate Allegations of Bribery or Corruption",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "section 70",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bribery Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Bribery Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welgama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "L.A. Wimalaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 23, 2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කුමාර වෙල්ගම දූෂණ නඩුවෙන් නිදහස්",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "අලුතින් අධිචෝදනා ගොනු කිරීමේ අයිතිය රඳවා ගනිමින් මෙම නඩුව ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගැනීමට තීරණය කළ බව අල්ලස් කොමිසම අධිකරණයට දැනුම් දුන්නා",
        "උප සභාපතිවරයාගේ වැටුප සහ අනෙකුත් ප්‍රතිලාභ ලෙස රුපියල් මිලියන 3.2 ක ගෙවීමක් හිටපු අමාත්‍යවරයා විසින් ලබා දීමට කටයුතු කර ඇත.",
        "අල්ලස් කොමිසම විසින් දූෂණ නඩුවක් ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගැනීමට ගත් තීරණයත් සමඟ කළුතර දිස්ත්‍රික් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී කුමාර වෙල්ගම මහතා එම නඩුවෙන් නිදහස් කිරීමට කොළඹ ප්‍රධාන මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය ඊයේ නියෝග කළේය.",
        "2010 වසරේ ප්‍රවාහන පනතට පටහැනිව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයේ (ශ්‍රී ලංගම) නියෝජ්‍ය සභාපතිවරයෙකු ලෙස පුද්ගලයෙකු පත් කර රජයට අයුතු පාඩුවක් සිදු කළ බවට චෝදනා කරමින් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී කුමාර වෙල්ගමට එරෙහිව අල්ලස් කොමිසම විසින් දූෂණ නඩුවක් පවරා තිබුණා.",
        "අල්ලස් කොමිසමේ කොමසාරිස්වරුන් තිදෙනෙකුගේ ලිඛිත අවසරය මත අලුතින් අධි චෝදනා ගොනු කිරීමේ අයිතිය රඳවා ගනිමින් මෙම නඩුව ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගැනීමට තීරණය කළ බව අල්ලස් කොමිසම අධිකරණයට දන්වා සිටියේය. හිටපු අමාත්‍ය වෙල්ගම මහතාට එරෙහිව අල්ලස් පනතේ 70 වැනි වගන්තිය යටතේ චෝදනා හතරක් යටතේ මෙම නඩුව පවරා තිබුණේ අල්ලස් හෝ දූෂණ චෝදනා විමර්ශන කොමිෂන් සභාවේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල්වරයා විසිනි.",
        "2010 ජුනි 23 වැනි දින ප්‍රවාහන අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කරමින් සිටියදී වෙල්ගම මහතා එල්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කුමාර වෙල්ගම",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුපියල් මිලියන 3.2",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් කොමිසමේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රවාහන පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් හෝ දූෂණ චෝදනා විමර්ශනය කරන්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්.ඒ.විමලරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2010 ජූනි 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஊழல் வழக்கில் இருந்து குமார வெல்கம விடுதலை",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதிய குற்றப்பத்திரிகையை தாக்கல் செய்வதற்கான உரிமையை ஒதுக்கி இந்த வழக்கை வாபஸ் பெற தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக இலஞ்ச ஊழல் ஆணைக்குழு நீதிமன்றத்திற்கு அறிவித்தது",
        "முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் பிரதித் தலைவருக்கு சம்பளம் மற்றும் இதர சலுகைகள் என 3.2 மில்லியன் ரூபாவை வழங்க வழிவகை செய்திருந்தார்.",
        "களுத்துறை மாவட்ட பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் குமார வெல்கமவை ஊழல் மோசடி வழக்கில் இருந்து விடுவிக்க இலஞ்ச ஊழல் ஆணைக்குழு தீர்மானித்ததையடுத்து கொழும்பு பிரதான நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம் நேற்று உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "2010 ஆம் ஆண்டு இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் (SLTB) பிரதித் தலைவராக போக்குவரத்துச் சட்டத்திற்கு முரணாக நபரொருவரை நியமித்து அரசாங்கத்திற்கு சட்டவிரோதமான நஷ்டத்தை ஏற்படுத்தியதாகக் கூறி பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் குமார வெல்கமவுக்கு எதிராக இலஞ்ச ஊழல் ஆணைக்குழு வழக்குத் தாக்கல் செய்தது.",
        "இலஞ்ச ஊழல் ஆணைக்குழுவின் மூன்று ஆணையாளர்களின் எழுத்துமூல அனுமதியுடன் புதிய குற்றப்பத்திரிகையை தாக்கல் செய்வதற்கான உரிமையை தமக்கென ஒதுக்கி இந்த வழக்கை வாபஸ் பெற தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக இலஞ்ச ஊழல் ஆணைக்குழு நீதிமன்றில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. இலஞ்சம் அல்லது ஊழல் குற்றச்சாட்டுகளை விசாரணை செய்யும் ஆணைக்குழுவின் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் வெல்கமவுக்கு எதிராக இலஞ்ச சட்டத்தின் 70ஆவது பிரிவின் கீழ் நான்கு குற்றச்சாட்டுகளின் கீழ் இந்த வழக்கை தாக்கல் செய்திருந்தார்.",
        "வெல்கம 2010 ஜூன் 23ஆம் திகதி போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சராக கடமையாற்றிய போது, ​​எல்.ஏ.விமலரத்னவை இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் பிரதித் தலைவராக நியமித்ததாக இலஞ்ச ஊழல் ஆணைக்குழு குற்றம் சுமத்தியுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "குமார வெல்கம",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலஞ்ச ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரூ.3.2 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார வெல்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலஞ்ச ஆணைக்குழுவின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலஞ்ச ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார வெல்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "போக்குவரத்து சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலஞ்ச ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலஞ்ச ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லஞ்சம் அல்லது ஊழல் குற்றச்சாட்டுகளை விசாரிக்கவும்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெல்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிவு 70",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "லஞ்ச ஒழிப்பு சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலஞ்ச ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெல்கம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்.ஏ.விமலரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 23, 2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}