{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/අම්බලන්ගොඩ-වෙඩි-තැබීමකින්-අයෙක්-රෝහලට/11-395752",
  "time_ut": 1658821979,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අම්බලන්ගොඩ වෙඩි තැබීමකින් අයෙක් රෝහලට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ambalangoda shooting, one person in hospital",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to Ambalangoda Police, a person was seriously injured in a shooting that took place this afternoon (26th) at Gangarama Mawatha, Uravatta, Ambalangoda.",
        "Police say that Murukkuwadura Wasantha de Soyza, a resident of Ambalangoda Landthota, was injured in this shooting.",
        "The police also say that two unknown gunmen who came on a motorcycle shot at this person who was riding a motorcycle and fled.",
        "The police say that the person who was shot is a person who was released on bail after being remanded in custody for an incident of shooting at a person in Uravatta Parathandia area of ​​Ambalangoda more than two years ago.",
        "The police suspect that this may be the result of collusion. Ambalangoda Police is conducting further investigations in this regard."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "one",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "this afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "26th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gangarama Mawatha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uravatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambalangoda",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Murukkuwadura Wasantha de Soyza",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambalangoda Landthota",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Uravatta Parathandia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than two years ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ambalangoda Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අම්බලන්ගොඩ වෙඩි තැබීමකින් අයෙක් රෝහලට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අම්බලන්ගොඩ ඌරවත්ත ගංගාරාම මාවතේදී අද(26දා) දහවල් සිදුවූ වෙඩි තැබීමකින් පුද්ගලයකු බරපතල තුවාල ලබා රෝහල් ගත කළ බව අම්බලන්ගොඩ පොලීසිය පවසයි.",
        "මේ වෙඩි තැබීමෙන් තුවාල ලබා ඇත්තේ අම්බලන්ගොඩ ඉඩම්තොට පදිංචි මුරුක්කුවාදුර  වසන්ත ද සොයිසා  නමැත්තෙක් බවද පොලීසිය කියයි.",
        "යතුරු පැදියෙන් යමින් සිටි මේ තැනැත්තාට යතුරු පැදියකින් පැමිණි නාදුනන තුවක්කුකරුවන් දෙදෙනෙක් වෙඩි තබා පලා ගොස් ඇති බවද පොලීසිය කියයි.",
        "වෙඩි වැදුණු තැනැත්තා මීට වසර දෙකකට උඩදී අම්බලන්ගොඩ ඌරවත්ත පැරට්හංදිය පදේශයේදී පුද්ගලයකුට වෙඩි තැබීමේ සිද්ධියකට රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාරගත කොට ඇප මත නිදහස්ව පැමිණ සිටි අයෙක් බවද පොලීසිය කියයි.",
        "මෙය එකට එක කිරීමේ පතිපලයක් විය හැකි බවට පොලීසිය සැකකරයි. අම්බලන්ගොඩ පොලීසිය මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් වැඩිදුර පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගංගාරාම මාවත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌරවත්ත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්බලන්ගොඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුරුක්කුවදුර වසන්ත ද සොයිසා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්බලන්ගොඩ ලන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඌරවත්ත පරතන්ඩියා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු දෙකකට වඩා කලින්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අම්බලන්ගොඩ පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அம்பலாங்கொடை துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டில் ஒருவர் வைத்தியசாலையில்!",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அம்பலாங்கொடை, உரவத்த, கங்காராம மாவத்தையில் இன்று (26) பிற்பகல் இடம்பெற்ற துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டில் ஒருவர் படுகாயமடைந்துள்ளதாக அம்பலாங்கொடை பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இந்த துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டில் அம்பலாங்கொட லந்தோட்டையைச் சேர்ந்த முருக்குவடுர வசந்த டி சொய்சா என்பவர் காயமடைந்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் வந்த இனந்தெரியாத இரு துப்பாக்கிதாரிகள் மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் சென்ற நபரை நோக்கி துப்பாக்கியால் சுட்டுவிட்டு தப்பிச் சென்றுள்ளதாகவும் பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "இரண்டு வருடங்களுக்கு முன்னர் அம்பலாங்கொட, உரவத்த பரதண்டி பிரதேசத்தில் நபர் ஒருவர் மீது துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்திய சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டு பிணையில் விடுவிக்கப்பட்டவர் சுடப்பட்டவர் என பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இது சதித்திட்டத்தின் விளைவாக இருக்கலாம் என போலீசார் சந்தேகிக்கின்றனர். இது தொடர்பான மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை அம்பலாங்கொடை பொலிஸார் மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஒன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கங்காராம மாவத்தை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உரவத்த",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பலாங்கொட",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முருக்குவடுர வசந்த டி சொய்சா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பலாங்கொட லந்தோட்ட",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உரவத்த பரதண்டியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அம்பலாங்கொடை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}