{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/26/coal-tender-awarded-to-lowest-bidder/",
  "time_ut": 1661529600,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Coal Tender awarded to lowest bidder",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Coal Tender awarded to lowest bidder",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Minister of Power and Energy says that a tender was awarded yesterday (25) to the lowest bid received for the procurement of Coal for the Norochcholai Plant based on the procurement process followed by evaluation & approval from STEC, SSCAPC.",
        "\"Supplier will provide 6 months credit facility from the date of supply of each shipment\". Minister Wijesekara said.",
        "Linking lives and villages: Gammadda launches bridge construction in remote Kegalle",
        "Children need to be at heart of resolving SL crisis: UNICEF regional director"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Coal Tender",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Coal",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "STEC",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SSCAPC",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6 months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijesekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kegalle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගල් අඟුරු ටෙන්ඩරය අඩුම ලංසුකරුට ලබා දී ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); නොරොච්චෝලේ බලාගාරය සඳහා ගල් අඟුරු මිලදී ගැනීම සඳහා STEC, SSCAPC හි ඇගයීම් සහ අනුමැතිය අනුව ප්‍රසම්පාදන ක්‍රියාවලිය මත ලැබුණු අඩුම ලංසුවට ටෙන්ඩරයක් ඊයේ (25) ප්‍රදානය කළ බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍යවරයා පවසයි.",
        "\"සැපයුම්කරු විසින් එක් එක් නැව්ගත කිරීම සපයන දිනයේ සිට මාස 6 ක ණය පහසුකම් ලබා දෙනු ඇත\". විජේසේකර ඇමැතිවරයා කීවේය.",
        "ජීවිත සහ ගම් සම්බන්ධ කිරීම: ගම්මැද්ද දුර බැහැර කෑගල්ලේ පාලම් ඉදිකිරීම ආරම්භ කරයි",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා අර්බුදය විසඳීමේ හදවතේ දරුවන් සිටිය යුතුයි: යුනිසෙෆ් කලාපීය අධ්‍යක්ෂ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගල් අඟුරු ටෙන්ඩරය",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල් අඟුරු",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "STEC",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SSCAPC",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාස 6 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நிலக்கரி டெண்டர் குறைந்த ஏலதாரருக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); STEC, SSCAPC ஆகியவற்றின் மதிப்பீடு மற்றும் ஒப்புதலின் அடிப்படையில், நேற்று (25) நொரோச்சோலை ஆலைக்கான நிலக்கரியை கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்கு பெறப்பட்ட குறைந்த விலைக்கு டெண்டர் வழங்கப்பட்டதாக மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் கூறுகிறார்.",
        "\"ஒவ்வொரு கப்பலுக்கும் சப்ளை செய்யப்பட்ட நாளிலிருந்து சப்ளையர் 6 மாத கடன் வசதியை வழங்குவார்\". அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "வாழ்க்கையையும் கிராமங்களையும் இணைக்கிறது: கேகாலை தொலைவில் பாலம் கட்டும் பணியை கம்மத்தா தொடங்கினார்",
        "இலங்கை நெருக்கடியைத் தீர்ப்பதில் குழந்தைகள் இதயத்தில் இருக்க வேண்டும்: யுனிசெஃப் பிராந்திய இயக்குநர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நிலக்கரி டெண்டர்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலக்கரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "STEC",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எஸ்.சி.ஏ.பி.சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6 மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}