{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lankas-crucial-presidential-vote-becomes-two-horse-race-97630/",
  "time_ut": 1658206680,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s crucial presidential vote becomes two-horse race",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s crucial presidential vote becomes two-horse race",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s upcoming election in parliament for an interim president has effectively become a two-horse race with two strong contenders emerging following the last minute dropout of  opposition leader Sajith Premadasa.",
        "The candidatures of Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe, ruling Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuan (SLPP) MP Dullas Alahapperuma and National People’s Power (NPP) MP Anura Kumara Dissanayake proposed and seconded in parliament Tuesday July 19 morning.",
        "Parliament called nominations for the vacancy left by the resignation of former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa who fled the country on July 13 following massive protests demanding his resignation.",
        "Wickremesinghe’s name was proposed by Minister Dinesh Gunawardena and was backed by Minister Manusha Nanayakkara amid some hooting from the opposition benches.",
        "Opposition leader Premadasa, who had previously announced that he was contesting, proposed Alahapperuma’s name which was seconded by SLPP Chairman and parliamentarian G L Peiris.",
        "NPP MP Vijitha Herath proposed the name of party leader Dissanayake for the position, seconded by his colleague Harini Amarasuriya.",
        "With Premadasa’s Samagi Jana Balavegaya (SJB), the main opposition, backing Alahapperuma and the NPP only holing three seats in parliament, Alahapperuma’s chances against Wickremesinghe are now looking better.",
        "At least 105 SLPP members have met Wickremesinghe and discussed their grievances, particularly regarding new housing in place of their homes that were burnt by angry mobs on May 09. SLPP general secretary Sagara Kariyawasam has said the SLPP will back Wickremesinghe, a statement later contradicted by party chair Peiris.",
        "Sri Lanka’s parliament has 225 members. Over half a dozen members are abroad and may return today for the vote tomorrow.",
        "The Sri Lanka Freedom Party (SLFP), which has around 15 members, has said they will stay out of the vote in a bid to push for a consensus candidate. But at least 10 may break ranks, reports said.",
        "SLFP chief ex-President Maithripala Sirisena has claimed that large sums of money was being offered to buy legislators.",
        "Sri Lanka is going through its worst economic crisis since Independence, with a crippling dollar shortage resulting in long queues for fuel, cooking gas and other essentials.",
        "The country has also seen much unrest in recent weeks, with protests intensifying and leading to confrontations between protestors and security forces.",
        "While activists and opposition lawmakers accuse the government of overreach and violent suppression of peaceful protest, the government claims that “fascist” elements within the protest movement are deliberately engaging in violence seeking to destabilise the country. (Colombo/Jul19/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last minute",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National People’s Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday July 19 morning",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manusha Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "parliamentarian G L Peiris",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harini Amarasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balavegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "At least 105",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sagara Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Over half a dozen",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "at least 10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Independence",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "recent weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තීරණාත්මක ජනාධිපතිවරණ ඡන්ද දෙක අශ්ව තරගයක් බවට පත්වේ",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - විපක්‍ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස  අවසාන මොහොතේ අතහැර දැමීමෙන් පසු මතුවන ප්‍රබල තරඟකරුවන් දෙදෙනෙකු සමඟින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අන්තර්වාර ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත මැතිවරණය ඵලදායී ලෙස අශ්වයන් දෙකක තරඟයක් බවට පත්ව ඇත.",
        "වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, පාලක ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම සහ ජාතික ජන බලවේගයේ (NPP) පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී අනුර කුමාර දිසානායකගේ අපේක්ෂකත්වය ජූලි 19 අඟහරුවාදා පෙරවරුවේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට යෝජනා කර ස්ථිර කරන ලදී.",
        "පසුගිය ජුලි 13 වැනිදා රටින් පලා ගිය හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බලකරමින් එල්ල වූ දැවැන්ත විරෝධතා හේතුවෙන් පුරප්පාඩු වූ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධුරය සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නාමයෝජනා කැදවනු ලැබුවා.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ නම අමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා විසින් යෝජනා කරන ලද අතර විපක්ෂ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ හූ හඬ මධ්‍යයේ අමාත්‍ය මනූෂ නානායක්කාර මහතා විසින් ඔහුට සහාය පළ කරන ලදී.",
        "තමන් තරඟ කරන බව කලින් ප්‍රකාශ කළ විපක්ෂ නායක ප්‍රේමදාස අලහප්පෙරුමගේ නම යෝජනා කළ අතර එය ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සභාපති පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ජී එල් පීරිස් විසින් ස්ථිර කරන ලදී.",
        "එන්පීපී පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී විජිත හේරත් මහතා එම තනතුර සඳහා පක්ෂ නායක දිසානායකගේ නම යෝජනා කළ අතර එය ඔහුගේ සගයකු වන හරිනි අමරසූරිය විසින් ස්ථිර කළේය.",
        "ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂය වන ප්‍රේමදාසගේ සමගි ජන බලවේගය (SJB) අලහප්පෙරුම සහ NPP ට පිටුබලය දෙමින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ආසන තුනක් පමණක් ලබා ගැනීමත් සමඟ, වික්‍රමසිංහට එරෙහිව අලහප්පෙරුමගේ අවස්ථා දැන් හොඳ අතට හැරෙමින් තිබේ.",
        "අවම වශයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සාමාජිකයින් 105 දෙනෙකු වික්‍රමසිංහ හමුවී ඔවුන්ගේ දුක්ගැනවිලි සාකච්ඡා කර ඇත, විශේෂයෙන් මැයි 09 දින කෝපාවිෂ්ට මැර කල්ලි විසින් ගිනි තැබූ ඔවුන්ගේ නිවාස වෙනුවට නව නිවාස සම්බන්ධයෙන්. ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් සාගර කාරියවසම් පවසා ඇත්තේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ වික්‍රමසිංහට සහාය දෙන බව පසුව ප්‍රකාශය පටහැනි බවයි. පක්ෂයේ සභාපති පීරිස්.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 225 ක් ඇත. සාමාජිකයින් දුසිම් භාගයකට වඩා විදේශගතව සිටින අතර හෙට ඡන්දය සඳහා අද ආපසු පැමිණිය හැකිය.",
        "මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 15 දෙනෙකුගෙන් පමණ සමන්විත ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය (ශ්‍රීලනිප) සම්මුතික අපේක්ෂකයෙකු සඳහා බලකිරීමේ අරමුණින් ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් ඉවත්ව සිටින බව පවසා තිබේ. නමුත් අවම වශයෙන් 10 දෙනෙක් ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම් බිඳ දැමිය හැකි බව වාර්තා පවසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රීලනිප ප්‍රධානී හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත්තේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් මිලදී ගැනීම සඳහා විශාල මුදලක් ලබා දෙන බවයි.",
        "ඉන්ධන, ඉවුම් පිහුම් ගෑස් සහ අනෙකුත් අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය සඳහා දිගු පෝලිම්වල ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස අබලන් වන ඩොලර් හිඟයක් සමඟ, නිදහසින් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව එහි දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හරහා ගමන් කරමින් සිටී.",
        "විරෝධතා තීව්‍ර වෙමින් විරෝධතාකරුවන් සහ ආරක්ෂක අංශ අතර ගැටුම් ඇති වීමත් සමඟ පසුගිය සති කිහිපය තුළ රට බොහෝ නොසන්සුන්තාවන් ද දැක තිබේ.",
        "ක්‍රියාකාරීන් සහ විපක්ෂ නීති සම්පාදකයින් ආන්ඩුවට සාමකාමී විරෝධතාව ඉක්මවා ප්‍රචණ්ඩ ලෙස මර්දනය කරන බවට චෝදනා කරන අතර, විරෝධතා ව්‍යාපාරය තුල සිටින \"ෆැසිස්ට්\" කොටස් හිතාමතාම රට අස්ථාවර කිරීමට උත්සාහ කරමින් ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වයේ යෙදෙන බව ආන්ඩුව කියා සිටී. (කොළඹ/ජූලි19/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසාන මිනිත්තුව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 19 අඟහරුවාදා උදෑසන",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනූෂ නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ජී එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරිනි අමරසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්පීපී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් 105",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුසිම් භාගයකට වඩා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් 10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෑත සති",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் முக்கியமான ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல் இரண்டு குதிரைப் பந்தயமாக மாறுகிறது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "எக்கனாமினெக்ஸ்ட் - இலங்கையின் இடைக்கால ஜனாதிபதிக்கான நாடாளுமன்றத் தேர்தல் இரண்டு குதிரைப் பந்தயமாக மாறியுள்ளது, மேலும் எதிர்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச கடைசி நிமிடத்தில் பதவி விலகியதைத் தொடர்ந்து இரண்டு வலுவான போட்டியாளர்கள் உருவாகியுள்ளனர்.",
        "பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, ஆளும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுவான் (SLPP) பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும மற்றும் தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி (NPP) பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க ஆகியோரின் வேட்புமனுக்கள் ஜூலை 19 செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை காலை பாராளுமன்றத்தில் முன்மொழியப்பட்டு உறுதிப்படுத்தப்பட்டன.",
        "ஜூலை 13ஆம் திகதி நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறிய முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் இராஜினாமாவால் ஏற்பட்ட வெற்றிடத்துக்கான வேட்புமனுக்களை பாராளுமன்றம் கோரியது.",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் பெயர் அமைச்சர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தனவினால் முன்மொழியப்பட்டது மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சிகளின் சில கூச்சல்களுக்கு மத்தியில் அமைச்சர் மனுஷ நாணயக்கார அவருக்கு ஆதரவளித்தார்.",
        "தான் போட்டியிடுவதாக முன்னர் அறிவித்த எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் பிரேமதாச, அழகப்பெருமவின் பெயரை முன்மொழிந்தார், அதை SLPP தலைவரும் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருமான ஜி எல் பீரிஸ் உறுதிப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "NPP பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் விஜித ஹேரத், அவரது சகாவான ஹரிணி அமரசூரியவினால் ஆதரவளிக்கப்பட்ட பதவிக்கு கட்சியின் தலைவர் திஸாநாயக்கவின் பெயரை முன்மொழிந்தார்.",
        "பிரேமதாசவின் சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB), பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சி, அழகப்பெருமவை ஆதரிப்பதோடு, NPP யும் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் மூன்று ஆசனங்களை மட்டுமே பெற்றுள்ள நிலையில், விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு எதிரான அழகப்பெருமவின் வாய்ப்புகள் இப்போது சிறப்பாகக் காணப்படுகின்றன.",
        "குறைந்தது 105 SLPP உறுப்பினர்கள் விக்கிரமசிங்கவைச் சந்தித்து அவர்களின் குறைகளை, குறிப்பாக மே 09 அன்று கோபமான கும்பல்களால் எரிக்கப்பட்ட அவர்களது வீடுகளுக்குப் பதிலாக புதிய வீடுகள் தொடர்பாக விவாதித்துள்ளனர். SLPP பொதுச் செயலாளர் சாகர காரியவசம், SLPP விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு ஆதரவளிக்கும் என்று கூறினார். கட்சியின் தலைவர் பீரிஸ்.",
        "இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் 225 உறுப்பினர்கள் உள்ளனர். அரை டஜன் உறுப்பினர்கள் வெளிநாட்டில் உள்ளனர் மற்றும் நாளை வாக்களிக்க இன்று திரும்பலாம்.",
        "சுமார் 15 உறுப்பினர்களைக் கொண்ட ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி (SLFP) ஒருமித்த வேட்பாளரை முன்னிறுத்தும் முயற்சியில் வாக்களிப்பில் இருந்து விலகி இருப்பதாகத் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. ஆனால் குறைந்தபட்சம் 10 பேர் தரவரிசையை உடைக்கக்கூடும் என்று தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களை கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்காக பெருந்தொகை பணம் வழங்கப்படுவதாக ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திர கட்சியின் தலைவர் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை சுதந்திரத்திற்குப் பின்னர் மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளது. டாலர் தட்டுப்பாடு காரணமாக எரிபொருள், சமையல் எரிவாயு மற்றும் பிற அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களுக்கான நீண்ட வரிசையில் நிற்கிறது.",
        "சமீபத்திய வாரங்களில் நாடு மிகவும் அமைதியின்மையைக் கண்டது, எதிர்ப்புகள் தீவிரமடைந்து எதிர்ப்பாளர்களுக்கும் பாதுகாப்புப் படையினருக்கும் இடையே மோதல்களுக்கு வழிவகுத்தது.",
        "ஆர்வலர்கள் மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சி சட்டமியற்றுபவர்கள் அரசாங்கம் அமைதியான எதிர்ப்பை மீறி வன்முறையில் ஒடுக்குவதாக குற்றம் சாட்டுகையில், எதிர்ப்பு இயக்கத்தில் உள்ள \"பாசிச\" கூறுகள் வேண்டுமென்றே நாட்டை சீர்குலைக்க வன்முறையில் ஈடுபடுவதாக அரசாங்கம் கூறுகிறது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை19/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடைசி நிமிடம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுவான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 19 செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை காலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்கவின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனுஷ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஜி எல் பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹரினி அமரசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 105",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகர காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரை டசனுக்கும் மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமீபத்திய வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}