{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/sports/Sri-Lanka-held-a-special-place-in-Shane-Warnes-heart-says-his-brother/323-239729",
  "time_ut": 1656084900,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka held a special place in Shane Warne’s heart, says his brother",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka held a special place in Shane Warne’s heart, says his brother",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The brother of the late Australian cricketing great Shane Warne said that Sri Lanka held a special place in his brother’s heart, being involved in relief efforts soon after the 2004 tsunami that hit the country.",
        "Jason Warne, and his wife Shay, are scheduled to be at the first Test Sri Lanka-Australia Test next week, which is being dedicated to the former Australia leg-spinner who died following a heart attack in March.",
        "Sri Lanka Tourism has planned a special event during the first Test match which starts on Wednesday (29).",
        "The Test series between the two nations is played for the Warne-Muralitharan trophy.",
        "\"I know Sri Lanka held a special place in Shane’s heart. Galle was one of his favourite grounds and he was extremely upset by the devastating Tsunami in 2004,\" Jason said.",
        "\"He just wanted to help, in whatever way he could. Shane would be humbled by the way he is being remembered in Sri Lanka and the respect they are showing him.”",
        "\"On behalf of our family, I would like to thank Sri Lankan Cricket and Sri Lanka Tourism for planning to honour my brother, Shane, during the first Test starting next week. I was touched to be invited to attend and be a part of the plans they have in place,” he also said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Shane Warne’s",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Australian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shane Warne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2004",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jason Warne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shay",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "next week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "March",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Tourism",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Test",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shane",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tsunami",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2004",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Cricket",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "next week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ෂේන් ​​වෝන්ගේ හදවතේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හිමිව තිබුණේ විශේෂ ස්ථානයක් බව ඔහුගේ සහෝදරයා පවසයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "2004 සුනාමි ව්‍යසනයෙන් පසු සහන සේවා කටයුතුවල නිරත වෙමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය සොහොයුරාගේ හදවතේ විශේෂ ස්ථානයක් හිමි කර ගත් බව අභාවප්‍රාප්ත ඔස්ට්‍රේලියානු ක්‍රිකට් ක්‍රීඩක ෂේන් වෝන්ගේ සහෝදරයා පැවසීය.",
        "ජේසන් වෝන් සහ ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ ෂේ ලබන සතියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා-ඕස්ට්‍රේලියා පළමු ටෙස්ට් තරගයට සහභාගී වීමට නියමිත අතර එය මාර්තු මාසයේදී හෘදයාබාධයකින් මිය ගිය ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු හිටපු පා දඟ පන්දු යවන්නා වෙනුවෙන් කැප කෙරේ.",
        "බදාදා (29) ආරම්භ වන පළමු ටෙස්ට් තරගයේදී විශේෂ සිදුවීමක් ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරය සැලසුම් කර තිබේ.",
        "දෙරට අතර ටෙස්ට් තරගාවලිය පැවැත්වෙන්නේ වෝන්-මුරලිදරන් කුසලානය වෙනුවෙනි.",
        "\"ශේන්ගේ හදවතේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට විශේෂ ස්ථානයක් හිමි වූ බව මම දනිමි. ගාල්ල ඔහුගේ ප්‍රියතම ක්‍රීඩාංගණවලින් එකක් වූ අතර 2004 දී ඇති වූ විනාශකාරී සුනාමියෙන් ඔහු අතිශයින් කලබලයට පත් විය,\" ජේසන් පැවසීය.",
        "\"ඔහුට අවශ්‍ය වූයේ ඔහුට හැකි ඕනෑම ආකාරයකින් උදව් කිරීමට පමණි. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ ඔහුව සිහිපත් කරන ආකාරය සහ ඔවුන් ඔහුට දක්වන ගෞරවය නිසා ෂේන් නිහතමානී වනු ඇත.\"",
        "“ලබන සතියේ ආරම්භ වන පළමු ටෙස්ට් තරගයේදී මගේ සහෝදරයා වන ෂේන්ට ගෞරව දැක්වීමට සැලසුම් කිරීම පිළිබඳව අපගේ පවුල වෙනුවෙන් මම ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ක්‍ෂේත්‍රයට ස්තූතිය පුද කිරීමට කැමැත්තෙමි. එයට සහභාගී වීමට සහ එහි කොටස්කරුවෙකු වීමට ආරාධනා කිරීම ගැන මා සතුටු විය. ඔවුන් ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන සැලසුම්,” ඔහු ද පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ෂේන් ​​වෝන්ගේ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂේන් ​​වෝන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2004",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජේසන් වෝන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පරීක්ෂණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂේන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුනාමිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2004",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂේන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஷேன் வார்னின் இதயத்தில் இலங்கை சிறப்பான இடத்தைப் பிடித்துள்ளது என அவரது சகோதரர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "2004 ஆம் ஆண்டு சுனாமியைத் தாக்கிய உடனேயே நிவாரணப் பணிகளில் ஈடுபட்டு, தனது சகோதரரின் இதயத்தில் இலங்கை தனி இடத்தைப் பிடித்துள்ளதாக மறைந்த ஆஸ்திரேலிய கிரிக்கெட் ஜாம்பவான் ஷேன் வார்னின் சகோதரர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜேசன் வார்னே மற்றும் அவரது மனைவி ஷே ஆகியோர் அடுத்த வாரம் முதல் டெஸ்ட் இலங்கை-ஆஸ்திரேலியா டெஸ்டில் பங்கேற்க உள்ளனர், இது மார்ச் மாதம் மாரடைப்பால் இறந்த முன்னாள் ஆஸ்திரேலியா லெக் ஸ்பின்னருக்கு அர்ப்பணிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "புதன்கிழமை (29) ஆரம்பமாகவுள்ள முதலாவது டெஸ்ட் போட்டியின் போது இலங்கை சுற்றுலாத்துறை விசேட நிகழ்வொன்றை திட்டமிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இரு நாடுகளுக்கு இடையேயான டெஸ்ட் தொடர் வார்ன்-முரளிதரன் கோப்பைக்காக விளையாடப்படுகிறது.",
        "\"ஷேனின் இதயத்தில் இலங்கை ஒரு சிறப்பு இடத்தைப் பிடித்துள்ளது என்பதை நான் அறிவேன். காலி அவருக்கு மிகவும் பிடித்த மைதானங்களில் ஒன்றாகும், மேலும் 2004 இல் ஏற்பட்ட பேரழிவு சுனாமியால் அவர் மிகவும் வருத்தமடைந்தார்\" என்று ஜேசன் கூறினார்.",
        "\"அவர் தன்னால் முடிந்த விதத்தில் உதவ விரும்பினார். இலங்கையில் அவர் நினைவுகூரப்படும் விதம் மற்றும் அவர்கள் அவருக்குக் காட்டும் மரியாதை ஆகியவற்றால் ஷேன் தாழ்மையுடன் இருப்பார்.\"",
        "\"அடுத்த வாரம் தொடங்கும் முதல் டெஸ்டில் எனது சகோதரர் ஷேனைக் கௌரவிக்கத் திட்டமிட்டதற்காக இலங்கை கிரிக்கெட் மற்றும் இலங்கை சுற்றுலாத் துறைக்கு எங்கள் குடும்பத்தின் சார்பாக நன்றியைத் தெரிவித்துக் கொள்கிறேன். கலந்துகொள்ளவும், அதில் பங்கேற்கவும் அழைக்கப்பட்டதற்கு நான் மிகவும் மகிழ்ச்சியடைந்தேன். அவர்கள் வைத்திருக்கும் திட்டங்கள்,” என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஷேன் வார்னின்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷேன் வார்ன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2004",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜேசன் வார்ன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுற்றுலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோதனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷேன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுனாமி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2004",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கிரிக்கெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷேன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}