{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/மிஸ்டர்-பீன்-போன்று-செயற்பட-வேண்டாம்-விஜித/175-299862",
  "time_ut": 1657126324,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "’’மிஸ்டர் பீன்’’ போன்று செயற்பட வேண்டாம்: விஜித",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Don't act like 'Mr Bean': Vijitha",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Claiming that he came to power to solve the problems of the country, Ranil should inform the people how to solve the problems of the people as a responsible Prime Minister. Instead, Vijitha Herat, a member of the People's Liberation Front, told the Prime Minister that he should not act like Mr. Bean.",
        "Yesterday (6) during the Prime Minister's Question Time in Parliament Vijitha Herath MP. He raised questions about the problems faced by the people of the country. Also, the Ministers informed this House that the fuel ship will arrive on the 23rd.",
        "But now there is no hope for the arrival of the ship. He therefore asked what action the government would take against the ministers who had misled Parliament.",
        "The Prime Minister replied to this, only answer whether you are taking responsibility for the government or not. Your leader Anurakumara Dissanayake said that he will not take responsibility. You said you will take responsibility. Tell me one of these two.",
        "Commenting on the occasion, Vijitha Herath MP, do not act like Mr. Bean and as a responsible Prime Minister tell me the steps taken to solve the problems of the people. If you are acting like Mr. Bean, come and sit in opposition. You are currently the responsible Prime Minister of the country. So answer the questions asked about the issues related to people's lives, he said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vijitha Herat",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the People's Liberation Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bean",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vijitha Herath MP",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 23rd",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anurakumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vijitha Herath MP",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bean",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bean",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මිස්ටර් බීන් වගේ හැසිරෙන්න එපා: විජිත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "තමන් බලයට ආවේ රටේ ප්‍රශ්න විසඳන්න යැයි කියමින් රනිල් වගකිව යුතු අගමැතිවරයකු ලෙස ජනතාවගේ ප්‍රශ්න විසඳන්නේ කෙසේදැයි ජනතාව දැනුවත් කළ යුතුය. ඒ වෙනුවට මහජන විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රී විජිත හේරත් මහතා අගමැතිවරයාට කියා සිටියේ බීන් මහතා මෙන් ක්‍රියා නොකළ යුතු බවයි.",
        "ඊයේ (6) පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ ප්‍රශ්න කිරීම්වලදී පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී විජිත හේරත්. රටේ ජනතාව මුහුණ දෙන ප්‍රශ්න ගැන එතුමා ප්‍රශ්න කළා. එමෙන්ම ඉන්ධන නෞකාව ලබන 23 වනදා පැමිණෙන බවයි අමාත්‍යවරුන් මෙම සභාවට දැනුම් දුන්නේ.",
        "නමුත් දැන් නැවේ පැමිණීම ගැන බලාපොරොත්තුවක් නැහැ. එබැවින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නොමග යැවූ ඇමැතිවරුන්ට එරෙහිව රජය ගන්නා ක්‍රියාමාර්ගය කුමක්දැයි ඔහු විමසා සිටියේය.",
        "ඊට පිළිතුරු දුන් අගමැතිවරයා, ඔබ ආණ්ඩුවේ වගකීම ගන්නවාද නැද්ද යන්න පමණක් පිළිතුරු දෙන්න. ඔබතුමාගේ නායක අනුරකුමාර දිසානායක කිව්වා වගකීමක් ගන්නේ නැහැ කියලා. ඔයා වගකීම ගන්නවා කිව්වා.මේ දෙකෙන් එකක් කියන්න.",
        "මෙහිදී අදහස් දැක්වූ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී විජිත හේරත් මහතා බීන් මහතා මෙන් කටයුතු නොකර වගකිවයුතු අගමැතිවරයකු ලෙස ජනතාවගේ ගැටලු විසඳීමට ගෙන ඇති පියවර මට කියන්න. මිස්ටර් බීන් වගේ වැඩ කරනවා නම් ඇවිත් විපක්ෂයේ වාඩි වෙන්න. ඔබ දැනට රටේ වගකිවයුතු අගමැති. ඒ නිසා ජන ජීවිතයට සම්බන්ධ ප්‍රශ්න ගැන අහන ප්‍රශ්නවලට උත්තර දෙන්න යැයි ද ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෝංචි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජිත හේරත් පා.ම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "23 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුරකුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජිත හේරත් පා.ම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෝංචි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෝංචි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "’’மிஸ்டர் பீன்’’ போன்று செயற்பட வேண்டாம்: விஜித",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டின் பிரச்சினைகளை தீர்க்க அதிகாரத்திற்கு வந்ததாக கூறும் ரணில், பொறுப்புள்ள பிரதமராக மக்களின் பிரச்சினைக்கு எவ்வாறு தீர்வு காண்பது என்பதை மக்களுக்கு தெரிவிக்கவேண்டும். மாறாக  மிஸ்ட பீன் போன்று செயற்பட வேண்டாம் என மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணி உறுப்பினர் விஜித ஹேரத் பிரதமரை நோக்கி சபையில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நேற்று (6) பிரதமரிடமான கேள்வி நேரத்தின் போது விஜித்த ஹேரத் எம்.பி. நாட்டு மக்கள் எதிர்நோக்கும் பிரச்சினைகள் குறித்து கேள்வி எழுப்பியிருந்தார். அத்துடன் எதிர்வரும் 23ஆம் திகதி எரிபொருள் கப்பல் வருவதாக அமைச்சர்கள் இந்த சபையில் தெரிவித்திருந்தனர்.",
        "ஆனால் தற்போது அந்த கப்பல் வருவது தொடர்பில் எந்த நம்பிக்கையும் இல்லை. அதனால் பாராளுமன்றத்தை பிழையாக வழிநடத்திய அமைச்சர்களுக்கு எதிராக அரசாங்கம் எடுக்கும் நடவடிக்கை என்ன என கேட்டார்.",
        "இதற்கு பதிலளித்த பிரதமர்,அரசாங்கத்தை பொறுப்பேற்கின்றீர்களா இல்லையா என்பதற்கு மாத்திரம் பதில்கூறுங்கள். உங்களின் தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க பொறுப்பேற்பதில்லை என தெரிவித்தார். நீங்கள் பொறுப்பேற்பதாக கூறினீர்கள்.இந்த இரண்டில் ஒன்றை கூறுங்கள் என்றார்.",
        "இதன்போது கருத்து தெரிவித்த விஜித்த ஹேரத் எம்.பி, மிஸ்டர்  பீன் போன்று செயற்படாது பொறுப்புள்ள பிரதமராக மக்களின் பிரச்சினை தீர்ப்பதற்கு எடுத்திருக்கும் நடவடிக்கையை கூறுங்கள். மிஸ்டர்  பீன் பாேன்று செயற்படுவதாக இருந்தால் எதிர்க்கட்சிக்கு வந்து அமர்ந்துகொள்ளுங்கள். நீங்கள் தற்போது நாட்டின் பொறுப்புமிக்க பிரதமர். அதனால் மக்களின் வாழ்க்கையுடன் சம்பந்தப்பட்ட பிரச்சினைகள் தொடர்பில் கேட்கும் கேள்விகளுக்கு பதிலளியுங்கள் என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜிதா ஹெராத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜித ஹேரத் எம்.பி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "23 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜித ஹேரத் எம்.பி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}