{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Deployment-of-Dornier-220-Aircraft-gifted-by-India-to-SLAF/108-243087",
  "time_ut": 1660566005,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Deployment of Dornier 220 Aircraft gifted by India to SLAF",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Deployment of Dornier 220 Aircraft gifted by India to SLAF",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mutual security, safety of India and Sri Lanka is not only beneficial to both nations but to the entire region, Indian High Commissioner Gopal Baglay said today.",
        "Speaking during the deployment of Dornier 220 Aircraft gifted by India to the Sri Lanka Air Force, Mr. Baglay said the gifting of the new aircraft will serve this purpose.",
        "\"The new Dornier Aircraft is an example of India' s value of ensuring that benefits of a strong India is shared in the region,\" he said.",
        "\"India is celebrating 75th anniversary of its independence. Story of India's independence came along with struggles. With these struggles, India had become a strong entity that had uplifted the literacy and uplifted its people from poverty. India is in the world map today as a nation with the largest manpower team. India has also maintained its values and tradition of helping all mankind,\" he added.",
        "He noted that India's foreign policy of neighbours first and Sagara is also directed towards helping the region. (Yohan Perera)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "SLAF",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gopal Baglay",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dornier 220 Aircraft",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Baglay",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dornier Aircraft",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sagara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yohan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියාව විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාවට තෑගි කරන ලද ඩෝනියර් 220 ගුවන් යානා යෙදවීම",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දියාවේ සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අන්‍යෝන්‍ය ආරක්ෂාව, ආරක්ෂාව දෙරටටම පමණක් නොව සමස්ත කලාපයටම ප්‍රයෝජනවත් බව ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ අද ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ඉන්දියාව විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාවට ත්‍යාග කරන ලද ඩෝනියර් 220 ගුවන් යානය යෙදවීමේදී අදහස් දක්වමින් බැග්ලේ මහතා පැවසුවේ නව ගුවන් යානය පිරිනැමීම ඒ සඳහා ඉවහල් වන බවයි.",
        "\"නව ඩෝනියර් ගුවන් යානය ශක්තිමත් ඉන්දියාවේ ප්‍රතිලාභ කලාපය තුළ බෙදාහදා ගැනීම සහතික කිරීමේ ඉන්දියාවේ වටිනාකමට උදාහරණයකි,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "\"ඉන්දියාව නිදහස ලබා 75 වැනි සංවත්සරය සමරනවා. අරගල සමඟින් ඉන්දියාවේ නිදහසේ කතාව ආවා. මේ අරගලත් සමඟ ඉන්දියාව සාක්ෂරතාවය නඟා සිටුවීමට සහ එහි ජනතාව දරිද්‍රතාවයෙන් නගා සිටුවීමට ප්‍රබල ආයතනයක් බවට පත්වුණා. ඉන්දියාව අද ලෝක සිතියමේ ඉන්නවා. විශාලතම මිනිස් බල කණ්ඩායමක් සිටින ජාතිය, ඉන්දියාව ද සිය වටිනාකම් සහ සියලු මනුෂ්‍ය වර්ගයාට උපකාර කිරීමේ සම්ප්‍රදාය පවත්වා ගෙන ගොස් ඇත.",
        "අසල්වැසියන් පළමුව සහ සාගර යන ඉන්දියාවේ විදේශ ප්‍රතිපත්තිය ද කලාපයට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා යොමු වී ඇති බව ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය. (යොහාන් පෙරේරා)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩෝනියර් 220 ගුවන් යානය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බග්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩෝනියර් ගුවන් යානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යොහාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "விமானப்படைக்கு இந்தியா பரிசளித்த டோர்னியர் 220 விமானத்தை அனுப்புதல்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்தியாவுக்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையிலான பரஸ்பர பாதுகாப்பு, பாதுகாப்பு இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் மட்டுமல்ல, முழு பிராந்தியத்திற்கும் பயனுள்ளதாக இருக்கும் என்று இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் கோபால் பாக்லே இன்று தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கை விமானப்படைக்கு இந்தியாவினால் பரிசாக வழங்கப்பட்ட டோர்னியர் 220 வானூர்திகளை அனுப்பும் நிகழ்வின் போது பேசிய திரு.பாக்லே, புதிய விமானத்தை பரிசாக வழங்குவது இந்த நோக்கத்திற்காக உதவும் என்றார்.",
        "\"புதிய டோர்னியர் விமானம், வலுவான இந்தியாவின் பலன்கள் பிராந்தியத்தில் பகிர்ந்து கொள்ளப்படுவதை உறுதி செய்வதற்கான இந்தியாவின் மதிப்புக்கு ஒரு எடுத்துக்காட்டு\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"இந்தியா தனது 75வது சுதந்திர தினத்தை கொண்டாடுகிறது. போராட்டங்களோடு இந்தியா சுதந்திரம் பெற்ற கதையும் வந்தது. இந்த போராட்டங்களால் எழுத்தறிவை உயர்த்தி மக்களை வறுமையில் இருந்து மீட்டெடுக்கும் வலிமையான அமைப்பாக இந்தியா மாறியது. இந்தியா இன்று உலக வரைபடத்தில் உள்ளது. மிகப்பெரிய மனிதவளக் குழுவைக் கொண்ட நாடு. இந்தியாவும் அதன் மதிப்புகள் மற்றும் அனைத்து மனிதகுலத்திற்கு உதவும் பாரம்பரியத்தையும் பராமரித்து வருகிறது,\" என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "அண்டை நாடுகளுக்கு முதலில் இந்தியாவின் வெளியுறவுக் கொள்கை மற்றும் சாகாரா பிராந்தியத்திற்கு உதவுவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டுள்ளது என்று அவர் குறிப்பிட்டார். (யோஹான் பெரேரா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "விமானப்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோபால் பாக்லே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டோர்னியர் 220 விமானம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாக்லே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டோர்னியர் விமானம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோஹான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}