{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131675",
  "time_ut": 1658123812,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவு தொடர்பில் தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணியின் முடிவு நாளை  – மனோ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The Tamil Progressive Alliance's decision regarding the presidential election is tomorrow - Mano",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "Tamil Progressive Alliance leader Mano Ganesan said that the Tamil Progressive Alliance leadership committee will take a decision on the presidential election tomorrow.",
        "The leadership committee of the Tamil Progressive Alliance will meet tomorrow, Tuesday 19th at 06.00 pm at the party secretariat in Colombo.",
        "In this case, Tamil Progressive Alliance President Mano Ganesan has also informed that all the candidates who have submitted their nomination papers to run in the Parliament on the 20th will be discussed and decided."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "The Tamil Progressive Alliance's",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil Progressive Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Progressive Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Tamil Progressive Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow, Tuesday 19th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06.00 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil Progressive Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 20th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපතිවරණය සම්බන්ධයෙන් දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානයේ තීරණය හෙට - මනෝ",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානයේ නායක මනෝ ගනේෂන් පැවසුවේ ජනාධිපතිවරණය සම්බන්ධයෙන් දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානයේ නායක කමිටුව හෙට තීරණයක් ගන්නා බවයි.",
        "දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානයේ නායකත්ව කමිටුව හෙට 19 අඟහරුවාදා පස්වරු 06.00ට කොළඹ පක්ෂ ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේදී රැස්වේ.",
        "මෙම නඩුවේදී දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානයේ සභාපති මනෝ ගනේෂන් ද දන්වා ඇත්තේ ලබන 20 වැනිදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත්වීම සඳහා නාමයෝජනා පත්‍ර භාරදී ඇති සියලුම අපේක්ෂකයින් පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කර තීරණයක් ගන්නා බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානයේ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට, 19 අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06.00 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவு தொடர்பில் தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணியின் முடிவு நாளை  – மனோ",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணி தலைமைக்குழு ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவு தொடர்பில் நாளை முடிவெடுக்கும் என தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணி தலைவர் மனோ கணேசன் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணியின் தலைமைக்குழு நாளை செவ்வாய்கிழமை 19 ஆம் திகதி மாலை 06.00 மணிக்கு கொழும்பிலுள்ள கட்சி செயலகத்தில் கூடி கலந்துரையாடவுள்ளது.",
        "இந்நிலையில், 20ம் திகதி பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நடைபெறவுள்ள ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் போட்டியிட வேட்பு மனுக்கள் சமர்பித்துள்ள அனைத்து வேட்பாளர்கள் தொடர்பிலும், கலந்துரையாடி முடிவெடுக்கும் என  தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணி தலைவர் மனோ கணேசன்  மேலும் தெரிவத்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணியின்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை, செவ்வாய் 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை 06.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}