{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/08/gl-meets-european-union-amb-in-colombo/",
  "time_ut": 1657265040,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "GL meets European Union Amb. in Colombo",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "GL meets European Union Amb. in Colombo",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ​Minister of Foreign Affairs, Prof. G.L. Peiris met with the ​Ambassador of the European Union Denis Chaibi in Colombo at the Ministry of Foreign Affairs on 06 July 2022.",
        "During the discussion, Minister Peiris briefed the EU Ambassador on developments related to the current economic situation, review of the list of proscribed organizations and individuals under the United Nations Regulation No. 1 of 2012, release of detainees being held under PTA, progress made by the independent institutions and key features of the proposed 21st Amendment to the Constitution among other matters.",
        "The Minister emphasized that the government has achieved a great deal of verifiable and measurable progress through established domestic mechanisms and that it remains focused to deliver on the required political reforms despite the ongoing economic crisis. Further, the Minister informed that the Government intends to present a new budget shortly which includes a range of welfare measures aimed at the vulnerable sections of society.",
        "The EU Ambassador appreciated the details conveyed on the recent developments. The Ambassador stated that the next EU GSP regulation for 2024-2033 is currently being discussed in the EU Commission and the European Parliament.",
        "Minister Peiris stated that Sri Lanka is continuing its constructive engagement with the members of the Human Rights Council including at the recently concluded 50th session of the UN Human Rights Council session.",
        "Lanka IOC to suspend fuel delivery for Friday (8) and Saturday (9)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "European Union Amb",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the European Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06 July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations Regulation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21st Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024-2033",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the EU Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the European Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Human Rights Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the UN Human Rights Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජීඑල් යුරෝපියානු සංගමය ඇම්බ් හමුවෙයි. කොළඹ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය, මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්. පීරිස් මහතා 2022 ජූලි 06 වැනි දින කොළඹ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේදී යුරෝපා සංගමයේ තානාපති ඩෙනිස් චයිබි මහතා හමුවිය.",
        "සාකච්ඡාවේදී අමාත්‍ය පීරිස් මහතා වත්මන් ආර්ථික තත්ත්වයට අදාළ වර්ධනයන්, 2012 අංක 1 දරණ එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ රෙගුලාසි යටතේ තහනම් සංවිධාන සහ පුද්ගලයන්ගේ ලැයිස්තුව සමාලෝචනය කිරීම, ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත යටතේ රඳවා සිටින රැඳවියන් නිදහස් කිරීම, ලබා ඇති ප්‍රගතිය පිළිබඳව යුරෝපා සංගම් තානාපතිවරයා දැනුවත් කළේය. යෝජිත 21 වන ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනයේ ස්වාධීන ආයතන සහ අනෙකුත් කරුණු අතර ප්‍රධාන ලක්ෂණ.",
        "ස්ථාපිත දේශීය යාන්ත්‍රණයන් තුළින් රජය සත්‍යාපනය කළ හැකි සහ මැනිය හැකි විශාල ප්‍රගතියක් අත්කර ගෙන ඇති බවත් පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හමුවේ වුවද අවශ්‍ය දේශපාලන ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සිදුකිරීමට රජය අවධානය යොමු කර ඇති බවත් අමාත්‍යවරයා අවධාරණය කළේය. තවද, සමාජයේ අවදානමට ලක්විය හැකි කොටස් ඉලක්ක කර ගනිමින් සුබසාධන ක්‍රියාමාර්ග රැසක් ඇතුළත් නව අයවැයක් නුදුරේදීම ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට රජය අදහස් කරන බව අමාත්‍යවරයා දැනුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "මෑත කාලීන වර්ධනයන් පිළිබඳව ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලද තොරතුරු යුරෝපා සංගම් තානාපතිවරයා අගය කළේය. 2024-2033 සඳහා වන මීළඟ EU GSP නියාමනය මේ වන විට යුරෝපා සංගම් කොමිසමේ සහ යුරෝපා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සාකච්ඡා වෙමින් පවතින බව තානාපතිවරයා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "පසුගියදා අවසන් වූ එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිල සැසිවාරයේ 50 වැනි සැසිවාරය ඇතුළු මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයේ සාමාජිකයන් සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය නිර්මාණාත්මක සබඳතාව අඛණ්ඩව පවත්වාගෙන යන බව අමාත්‍ය පීරිස් ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "ලංකා IOC සිකුරාදා (8) සහ සෙනසුරාදා (9) ඉන්ධන බෙදා හැරීම අත්හිටුවයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "යුරෝපීය සංගමය ඇම්බ්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපා සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ රෙගුලාසි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024-2033",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපීය පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜிஎல் ஐரோப்பிய யூனியன் ஆம்பை ​​சந்திக்கிறார். கொழும்பில்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர், பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல். பீரிஸ், ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியத்தின் தூதுவர் டெனிஸ் சாய்பியை 06 ஜூலை 2022 அன்று வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சில் கொழும்பில் சந்தித்தார்.",
        "கலந்துரையாடலின் போது, ​​அமைச்சர் பீரிஸ், தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நிலைமை தொடர்பான அபிவிருத்திகள், 2012 ஆம் ஆண்டின் ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் ஒழுங்குமுறை இலக்கம் 1 இன் கீழ் தடைசெய்யப்பட்ட நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் தனிநபர்களின் பட்டியலை மீளாய்வு செய்தல், பயங்கரவாத தடைச்சட்டத்தின் கீழ் தடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள கைதிகளை விடுவித்தல், முன்னேற்றம் குறித்து ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றிய தூதுவரிடம் விளக்கினார். சுயாதீன நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பின் முன்மொழியப்பட்ட 21 வது திருத்தத்தின் முக்கிய அம்சங்கள் மற்ற விஷயங்களில்.",
        "ஸ்தாபிக்கப்பட்ட உள்நாட்டு பொறிமுறைகள் மூலம் அரசாங்கம் பெருமளவு சரிபார்க்கக்கூடிய மற்றும் அளவிடக்கூடிய முன்னேற்றத்தை அடைந்துள்ளதாகவும், தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு மத்தியிலும் தேவையான அரசியல் சீர்திருத்தங்களை வழங்குவதில் கவனம் செலுத்துவதாகவும் அமைச்சர் வலியுறுத்தினார். மேலும், சமூகத்தின் நலிவடைந்த பிரிவினரை இலக்காகக் கொண்ட பல்வேறு நலன்புரி நடவடிக்கைகளை உள்ளடக்கிய புதிய வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தை விரைவில் சமர்ப்பிக்க அரசாங்கம் உத்தேசித்துள்ளதாக அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றிய தூதர் சமீபத்திய முன்னேற்றங்கள் குறித்து தெரிவிக்கப்பட்ட விவரங்களைப் பாராட்டினார். 2024-2033 ஆம் ஆண்டிற்கான அடுத்த EU GSP ஒழுங்குமுறை தற்போது ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றிய ஆணைக்குழுவிலும் ஐரோப்பிய பாராளுமன்றத்திலும் விவாதிக்கப்பட்டு வருவதாக தூதுவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அண்மையில் முடிவடைந்த ஐ.நா மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவையின் 50 ஆவது கூட்டத் தொடரில் உட்பட மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவை உறுப்பினர்களுடனான ஆக்கபூர்வமான ஈடுபாட்டை இலங்கை தொடர்வதாக அமைச்சர் பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "வெள்ளி (8) மற்றும் சனிக்கிழமை (9) எரிபொருள் விநியோகத்தை இடைநிறுத்த லங்கா IOC"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியம் Amb",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளிநாட்டு விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் ஒழுங்குமுறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024-2033",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றிய ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐநா மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}