{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/දෙකෝටියක-රන්-හා-රිදී-ආභරණ-අත්අඩංගුවට/11-396675",
  "time_ut": 1661696134,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "දෙකෝටියක රන් හා රිදී ආභරණ අත්අඩංගුවට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Two crore gold and silver jewelery seized",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A Sri Lankan business woman who illegally brought silver ornaments and jewelery worth two million and thirty three lakh rupees from India to Sri Lanka has been arrested by a group of customs officers at the arrival terminal of Katunayake Airport this morning.",
        "She is a 38-year-old businesswoman residing in the Grandpass area of ​​Colombo. She had arrived at the Katunayake airport at 02.45 this morning from Chennai, India, on the AI-273 flight of the Indian Airlines.",
        "While she was carrying a stock of jewelery weighing 01 kg and 638 grams and a stock of silver jewelery weighing 01 kg and 600 grams, the customs officers found them and arrested them.",
        "Ordered confiscation of all jewelery and ordered her to pay a fine of Rs 30,000."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "two million and thirty",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "38-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "02.45 this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chennai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "01 kg and 638",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "01 kg and 600 grams",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දෙකෝටියක රන් හා රිදී ආභරණ අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රුපියල් දෙකෝටි තිස් තුන් ලක්ෂයක් වටිනා රිදී ආභරණ සහ ස්වර්ණාභරණ තොගයක් නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස ඉන්දියාවේ සිට මෙරටට ගෙන ආ ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ව්‍යාපාරික කාන්තාවක් අද අලුයම කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ පැමිණීමේ පර්යන්තයේ දී රේගු නිලධාරීන් පිරිසක් විසින් අත් අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "ඇය කොළඹ ග්‍රෑන්ඩ්පාස් ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 38 හැවිරිදි ව්‍යාපාරික කාන්තාවකි.  ඇය අද අලුයම 02.45 ට ඉන්දියාවේ චෙන්නායි සිට, ඉන්දීය ගුවන් සේවයේ ඒ.අයි.- 273 දරන ගුවන් යානයෙන් කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ වෙත පැමිණ තිබුණි.",
        "ඇය විසින් රැගෙන ආ ගමන් මල්ලේ කිලෝ ග්රැම් 01 යි ග්රැම් 638 ක් බරැති ස්වර්ණාභරණ තොගයක් සහ කිලෝ ග්රැම් 01 යි ග්රැම් 600 ක් බරැති රිදී ආභරණ තොගයක් සගවා ගෙන සිටියදී , රේගු නිලධාරීන් විසින් ඒවා සොයාගෙන අත් අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබුණි.",
        "ආභරණ සියල්ල රාජසන්තක කිරීමට නියෝග කළ අතර ඇයට රුපියල් 30,000 ක දඩ මුදලක් ගෙවන ලෙසද නියෝග කළාය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන දෙකයි තිහයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "38 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද උදෑසන 02.45",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "චෙන්නායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "01 kg සහ 638",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 01 යි ග්‍රෑම් 600 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இரண்டு கோடி தங்கம் மற்றும் வெள்ளி நகைகள் பறிமுதல் செய்யப்பட்டன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்தியாவில் இருந்து இரண்டு இலட்சத்து முப்பத்து மூன்று இலட்சம் ரூபா பெறுமதியான வெள்ளி ஆபரணங்கள் மற்றும் நகைகளை சட்டவிரோதமான முறையில் இலங்கைக்கு கொண்டு வந்த இலங்கை வர்த்தகப் பெண் ஒருவர் கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையத்தின் வருகை முனையத்தில் இன்று காலை சுங்க அதிகாரிகள் குழுவினால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இவர் கொழும்பு கிராண்ட்பாஸ் பகுதியில் வசிக்கும் 38 வயதான வர்த்தகர் ஆவார். இந்தியன் எயார்லைன்ஸின் AI-273 விமானத்தில் இந்தியாவின் சென்னையில் இருந்து இன்று அதிகாலை 02.45 மணியளவில் கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையத்தை வந்தடைந்துள்ளார்.",
        "01 கிலோ 638 கிராம் எடையுள்ள நகைகளையும், 01 கிலோ 600 கிராம் எடையுள்ள வெள்ளி நகைகளையும் எடுத்துச் சென்ற போது, ​​சுங்க அதிகாரிகள் அவர்களைக் கண்டுபிடித்து கைது செய்துள்ளனர்.",
        "நகைகள் அனைத்தையும் பறிமுதல் செய்து, 30,000 ரூபாய் அபராதம் விதித்து உத்தரவிட்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு மில்லியன் முப்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "38 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை 02.45",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "சென்னை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "01 கிலோ மற்றும் 638",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "01 கிலோ 600 கிராம்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}