{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Not-possible-to-purchase-fuel-from-any-nation-Champika/108-239888",
  "time_ut": 1656336433,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Not possible to purchase fuel from any nation: Champika",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Not possible to purchase fuel from any nation: Champika",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "It is not possible to purchase fuel from any nation without restoring Sri Lanka's image in the world which is tarnished badly, an opposition MP said today.",
        "MP Patali Champika Ranawaka made this remark responding to reports which came in yesterday that Sri Lanka is to purchase fuel from Russia.",
        "“Sri Lanka will not be able to purchase fuel from anywhere in the world until its image in the international arena is restored. The image has been tarnished because of corruption. A foreign bank in USA had already filed legal action against Sri Lanka for holding its assets,” the MP said.",
        "“There should be a real multi party government where all political parties in the opposition should play a role to restore the battered nation. All political parties in the opposition and government should get together,” he added. (Yohan Perera)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Patali Champika Ranawaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "USA",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yohan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කිසිම ජාතියකින් තෙල් ගන්න බෑ: චම්පික",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලෝකයේ බරපතළ ලෙස කැළැල් වී ඇති ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රතිරූපය යළි ලබා නොදී කිසිදු ජාතියකින් ඉන්ධන මිලදී ගැනීමට නොහැකි බව විපක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙක් අද පැවසීය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී පාඨලී චම්පික රණවක මහතා මේ බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව රුසියාවෙන් ඉන්ධන මිලදී ගැනීමට නියමිත බවට ඊයේ දිනයේ පළ වූ වාර්තා සම්බන්ධයෙන් ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වමින්.",
        "“ජාත්‍යන්තරය තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඇති ප්‍රතිරූපය යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් වන තුරු ලෝකයේ කොතැනකින් හෝ ඉන්ධන මිලදී ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට නොහැකි වනු ඇත. දූෂණය නිසා ප්‍රතිරූපය කෙලෙසී තිබෙනවා. ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදයේ විදේශීය බැංකුවක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට එරෙහිව නීතිමය ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගෙන තිබුණේ එහි වත්කම් තබා ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන්” මන්ත්‍රීවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "“විපක්‍ෂයේ සිටින සියලුම දේශපාලන පක්‍ෂ බැට කෑ ජාතිය යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් කිරීමට කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කළ යුතු සැබෑ බහු පක්‍ෂ ආණ්ඩුවක් තිබිය යුතුයි. විපක්ෂයේ සහ ආණ්ඩුවේ සියලුම දේශපාලන පක්ෂ එකට එකතු විය යුතුයි,” ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය. (යොහාන් පෙරේරා)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාඨලී චම්පික රණවක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇඑජ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යොහාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எந்த நாட்டிலிருந்தும் எரிபொருளை கொள்வனவு செய்ய முடியாது: சம்பிக்க",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "உலகில் மோசமாகப் பழுதடைந்துள்ள இலங்கையின் நன்மதிப்பை மீட்டெடுக்காமல் எந்தவொரு நாட்டிலிருந்தும் எரிபொருளை கொள்வனவு செய்ய முடியாது என எதிர்க்கட்சி எம்.பி.",
        "ரஷ்யாவிடம் இருந்து இலங்கை எரிபொருளை கொள்வனவு செய்யவுள்ளதாக நேற்று வெளியான செய்திக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் போதே பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பாட்டலி சம்பிக்க ரணவக்க இதனை தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "“சர்வதேச அரங்கில் இலங்கை தனது பிம்பத்தை மீட்டெடுக்கும் வரை உலகில் எங்கிருந்தும் எரிபொருளை கொள்வனவு செய்ய முடியாது. ஊழலால் இமேஜ் கெட்டுவிட்டது. அமெரிக்காவில் உள்ள வெளிநாட்டு வங்கியொன்று ஏற்கனவே இலங்கைக்கு எதிராக தனது சொத்துக்களை வைத்திருப்பதற்காக சட்ட நடவடிக்கை எடுத்துள்ளது” என எம்.பி.",
        "\"உண்மையான பல கட்சி அரசாங்கம் இருக்க வேண்டும், அங்கு எதிர்க்கட்சியில் உள்ள அனைத்து அரசியல் கட்சிகளும் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட தேசத்தை மீட்டெடுக்க பங்களிக்க வேண்டும். எதிர்க்கட்சி மற்றும் அரசாங்கத்தில் உள்ள அனைத்து அரசியல் கட்சிகளும் ஒன்றிணைய வேண்டும்” என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார். (யோஹான் பெரேரா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாட்டலி சம்பிக்க ரணவக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யோஹான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}