{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/international/නව-ඉන්දීය-ජනපතිනිය-වෙත-චීන-ජනපතිගෙන්-සුබ-පැතුම්/3-395761",
  "time_ut": 1658832170,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "නව ඉන්දීය ජනපතිනිය වෙත චීන ජනපතිගෙන් සුබ පැතුම්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Greetings from the Chinese President to the new Indian President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Chinese President Xi Jinping has sent a congratulatory message to Indian President Draupadi Murmu.",
        "Noting that China and India are each other's important neighbors, Xi said that a better and more stable Sino-Indian relationship would serve the basic interests of both countries and peoples, as well as be conducive to regional and world peace, stability and development.",
        "Xi said that he attaches great importance to China-India relations and is ready to work with President Murmu to improve political mutual trust, deepen practical cooperation, manage differences properly and push bilateral relations on the right track.",
        "Murmu was sworn in as the 15th President of India on Monday. She is the second President of India and the first person from India's tribal community to hold the country's highest constitutional post."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi Jinping",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Draupadi Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sino-Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Xi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Murmu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නව ඉන්දීය ජනපතිනිය වෙත චීන ජනපතිගෙන් සුබ පැතුම්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "චීන ජනාධිපති ෂී ජින්පිං ඉන්දීය ජනාධිපති ධුරයට පත් වූ ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු වෙත සුබපැතුම් පණිවිඩයක් යවා තිබේ.",
        "චීනය සහ ඉන්දියාව එකිනෙකාගේ වැදගත් අසල්වැසියන් බව සඳහන් කළ ෂී, වඩාත් යහපත් සහ ස්ථාවර චීන-ඉන්දියා සබඳතාවයක් දෙරටේ සහ ජනතාවගේ මූලික අවශ්‍යතා සඳහා සේවය කරන අතරම, කලාපීය සහ ලෝක සාමය, ස්ථාවරත්වය සහ සංවර්ධනය සඳහා හිතකර බව පැවසීය.",
        "චීන-ඉන්දියා සබඳතාවලට තමන් විශාල වැදගත්කමක් ලබාදෙන අතර, දේශපාලන අන්‍යෝන්‍ය විශ්වාසය වැඩි දියුණු කිරීමට, ප්‍රායෝගික සහයෝගීතාව ගැඹුරු කිරීමට, වෙනස්කම් නිසි ලෙස හසුරුවා ගැනීමට සහ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතා නිවැරදි මාවතට තල්ලු කිරීමට ජනාධිපති මුර්මු සමග කටයුතු කිරීමට සූදානම් බව ෂී පැවසීය.",
        "ඉන්දියාවේ 15 වැනි ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස මුර්මු සඳුදා දිවුරුම් දුන්නාය. ඇය ඉන්දියාවේ දෙවැනි ජනාධිපතිවරිය වන අතර, ඉන්දියාවේ ගෝත්‍රික ප්‍රජාවෙන් රටේ ඉහළම ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත තනතුරට පත් වූ පළමු වැනි පුද්ගලයා ද වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi Jinping",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන-ඉන්දියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Xi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුර්මු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුර්මු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புதிய இந்திய ஜனாதிபதிக்கு சீன ஜனாதிபதியின் வாழ்த்துகள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்திய அதிபர் திரௌபதி முர்முவுக்கு சீன அதிபர் ஜி ஜின்பிங் வாழ்த்து செய்தி அனுப்பியுள்ளார்.",
        "சீனாவும் இந்தியாவும் ஒன்றுக்கொன்று முக்கியமான அண்டை நாடுகள் என்று குறிப்பிட்ட ஜி, சிறந்த மற்றும் நிலையான சீன-இந்திய உறவு இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் மக்களின் அடிப்படை நலன்களுக்கும் சேவை செய்யும் என்றும், பிராந்திய மற்றும் உலக அமைதி, ஸ்திரத்தன்மை மற்றும் வளர்ச்சிக்கு உகந்ததாகவும் இருக்கும் என்றார்.",
        "சீன-இந்திய உறவுகளுக்கு தான் அதிக முக்கியத்துவம் கொடுப்பதாகவும், அரசியல் பரஸ்பர நம்பிக்கையை மேம்படுத்தவும், நடைமுறை ஒத்துழைப்பை ஆழப்படுத்தவும், வேறுபாடுகளை சரியாக நிர்வகிக்கவும், இருதரப்பு உறவுகளை சரியான பாதையில் கொண்டு செல்லவும் அதிபர் முர்முவுடன் இணைந்து பணியாற்றத் தயாராக இருப்பதாகவும் ஷி கூறினார்.",
        "இந்தியாவின் 15வது ஜனாதிபதியாக முர்மு திங்கள்கிழமை பதவியேற்றார். அவர் இந்தியாவின் இரண்டாவது குடியரசுத் தலைவர் மற்றும் இந்தியாவின் பழங்குடி சமூகத்திலிருந்து நாட்டின் மிக உயர்ந்த அரசியலமைப்பு பதவியை வகித்த முதல் நபர் ஆவார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi Jinping",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "திரௌபதி முர்மு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன-இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Xi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முர்மு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முர்மு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}