{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83900/singapore-extends-gotabaya-rajapaksas-visit-pass-by-14-days-report-",
  "time_ut": 1658904900,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Singapore extends Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s visit pass by 14 days: report",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Singapore extends Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s visit pass by 14 days: report",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka’s former president Gotabaya Rajapaksa has extended his stay in Singapore for another 14 days, the Straits Times reported on Wednesday.",
        "Rajapaksa was issued a 14-day visit pass when he arrived at the Changi Airport in Singapore from the Maldives on July 14.",
        "His pass to the city-state will now expire on August 11, the newspaper reported.",
        "Sri Lanka’s cabinet spokesman Bandula Gunawardena said on Tuesday at a press conference in Colombo that Rajapaksa is expected to return to the country from Singapore.",
        "The former president who sledged the nation initially stayed at a hotel in the city centre but is believed to have moved to a private residence, strait times reported.",
        "Singapore’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs said on July 14 that Rajapaksa had not asked for asylum and neither had he been granted any asylum.",
        "Singapore generally does not grant requests for asylum, the Ministry added.",
        "Sri Lanka’s Parliament Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena announced the official resignation of Rajapaksa on July 15.",
        "73-year-old Gotabaya Rajapaksa had left the country after crowds of protesters stormed his residence on July 9.",
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe was sworn in as President of Sri Lanka on July 21 in Parliament before Chief Justice Jayantha Jayasuriya.",
        "He was elected as president in an election held in Parliament a day prior to the swearing-in ceremony.",
        "Wickremesinghe received 134 votes following the resignation of Gotabaya Rajapaksa from the presidency last week amid severe economic turmoil in the country.",
        "After winning the parliament vote by secret ballot, Wickremesinghe addressed the parliament, calling on all legislators including the opposition parliamentarians to unite and work together with him to lead Sri Lanka out of the current economic crisis. “We are at a critical juncture.",
        "There is an economic crisis and the youth want a system change. People want all parliamentarians to come together,” he said.",
        "Out of the 225 parliamentarians, 223 voted to elect a new president and there were four invalid votes.",
        "Wickremesinghe is not a new name in politics and has served as the Prime Minister of the island nation six times earlier.",
        "He was one of the top contenders for the Presidential election in which members of the House voted through a secret ballot.",
        "Earlier, Wickremesinghe was appointed as the interim president of Sri Lanka after Gotabaya Rajapaksa fled abroad after his palace was stormed by angry protesters amid the unprecedented economic crisis. The country is facing a severe shortage of fuel and other essential supplies and is in the throes of its worst-ever economic crisis with soaring inflation. The oil supply shortage has forced schools and government offices to close until further notice.",
        "Reduced domestic agricultural production, a lack of foreign exchange reserves, and local currency depreciation have fuelled the shortages.",
        "The economic crisis will push many families into hunger and poverty - some for the first time - adding to the half a million people who the World Bank estimates have fallen below the poverty line because of the pandemic."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Singapore",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "14 days",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "another 14 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Straits Times",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Changi Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "73-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayantha Jayasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the half a million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සිංගප්පූරුව ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ සංචාරය දින 14කින් දීර්ඝ කරයි: වාර්තාව",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සිංගප්පූරුවේ රැඳී සිටීම තවත් දින 14කින් දීර්ඝ කර ඇති බව ස්ට්‍රේට් ටයිම්ස් බදාදා වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "පසුගිය ජූලි 14 වැනිදා මාලදිවයිනේ සිට සිංගප්පූරුවේ චැංගි ගුවන් තොටුපළට පැමිණි රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට දින 14ක සංචාරයක අවසර පත්‍රයක් නිකුත් කර ඇත.",
        "ඔහුගේ නගර රාජ්‍යය සඳහා අවසර පත්‍රය අගෝස්තු 11 දිනෙන් අවසන් වන බව පුවත්පත වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන අඟහරුවාදා කොළඹ පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී කියා සිටියේ රාජපක්ෂ සිංගප්පූරුවේ සිට නැවත මෙරටට පැමිණීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන බවයි.",
        "ජාතියම මරා දැමූ හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා මුලින් නවාතැන් ගෙන සිටියේ නගර මධ්‍යයේ හෝටලයක නමුත් ඔහු පෞද්ගලික නිවසකට ගොස් ඇතැයි විශ්වාස කෙරෙන බව ස්ට්‍රේට් ටයිම්ස් වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "සිංගප්පූරුවේ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය ජූලි 14 දා කියා සිටියේ රාජපක්ෂ සරණාගතභාවය ඉල්ලා නැති බවත් ඔහුට සරණාගතභාවය ලබා දී නැති බවත් ය.",
        "සිංගප්පූරුව සාමාන්‍යයෙන් සරණාගත ඉල්ලීම් ලබා නොදෙන බව අමාත්‍යාංශය වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා ජූලි 15 වැනිදා රාජපක්ෂ මහතා නිල වශයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව නිවේදනය කළේය.",
        "73 හැවිරිදි ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ජූලි 9 වන දින ඔහුගේ නිවසට විරෝධතාකරුවන් පිරිසක් කඩා වැදීමෙන් පසු රට හැර ගොස් තිබුණි.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස ජූලි 21 වැනිදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී අගවිනිසුරු ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "දිවුරුම් දීමේ උත්සවයට දිනකට පෙර පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ පැවති මැතිවරණයකින් ඔහු ජනාධිපති ලෙස තේරී පත් විය.",
        "පසුගිය සතියේ රටේ පැවති දැඩි ආර්ථික අවුල් මධ්‍යයේ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ජනාධිපති ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමත් සමඟ වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට ඡන්ද 134ක් හිමි විය.",
        "රහස් ඡන්දයෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ඡන්දය ජයග්‍රහණය කිරීමෙන් පසු වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අමතමින්, වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ගෙනයාමට තමන් සමඟ එක්ව කටයුතු කරන ලෙස විපක්ෂයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ඇතුළු සියලුම ව්‍යවස්ථාදායකයන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. “අපි ඉන්නේ තීරණාත්මක සන්ධිස්ථානයක.",
        "ආර්ථික අර්බුදයක් පවතින අතර තරුණයින්ට ක්‍රම වෙනසක් අවශ්‍යයි. ජනතාවට අවශ්‍ය සියලුම පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් එකට එකතු වන ලෙසයි.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 225 න් 223 ක් නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමට ඡන්දය දුන් අතර වලංගු නොවන ඡන්ද හතරක් තිබුණි.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ යනු දේශපාලනයට අලුත් නමක් නොවන අතර මීට පෙර හය වතාවක් දිවයිනේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කර ඇත.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් රහස් ඡන්දයකින් ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළ ජනාධිපතිවරණය සඳහා ඔහු ප්‍රමුඛ අපේක්ෂකයෙකු විය.",
        "පෙර නොවූ විරූ ආර්ථික අර්බුදයක් මධ්‍යයේ කෝපයට පත් විරෝධතාකරුවන් විසින් ඔහුගේ මාලිගාවට කඩා වැදීමෙන් පසු ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ විදේශගත වූ පසු වික්‍රමසිංහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අන්තර්වාර ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස මීට පෙර පත් කරන ලදී. රට ඉන්ධන සහ අනෙකුත් අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සැපයුම්වල උග්‍ර හිඟයකට මුහුන දී සිටින අතර උද්ධමනය ඉහළ යාමත් සමඟ මෙතෙක් පැවති දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයේ ගිලෙමින් පවතී. තෙල් හිඟය හේතුවෙන් පාසල් සහ රජයේ කාර්යාල නැවත දැනුම් දෙන තුරු වසා දැමීමට සිදුව තිබේ.",
        "දේශීය කෘෂිකාර්මික නිෂ්පාදනය අඩුවීම, විදේශ විනිමය සංචිත නොමැතිකම සහ දේශීය මුදල් අවප්‍රමාණය වීම හිඟයට හේතු වී ඇත.",
        "ආර්ථික අර්බුදය බොහෝ පවුල් කුසගින්න සහ දරිද්‍රතාවයට තල්ලු කරනු ඇත - සමහරක් පළමු වතාවට - වසංගතය හේතුවෙන් ලෝක බැංකුව ඇස්තමේන්තු කර ඇති මිලියන භාගයක ජනතාව දරිද්‍රතා රේඛාවෙන් පහළට වැටී ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "දින 14 යි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තවත් දින 14 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Straits Times",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චැංගි ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "73 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන භාගයක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் பயணத்தை சிங்கப்பூர் 14 நாட்களுக்கு நீட்டித்துள்ளது: அறிக்கை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச சிங்கப்பூரில் தங்கியிருக்கும் நேரத்தை மேலும் 14 நாட்களுக்கு நீட்டித்துள்ளதாக ஸ்ட்ரெய்ட்ஸ் டைம்ஸ் புதன்கிழமை செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜூலை 14-ம் தேதி மாலைதீவில் இருந்து சிங்கப்பூரில் உள்ள சாங்கி விமான நிலையத்துக்கு ராஜபக்சே வந்தபோது அவருக்கு 14 நாள் பயண அனுமதிச் சீட்டு வழங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "நகர-மாநிலத்திற்கான அவரது பாஸ் ஆகஸ்ட் 11 அன்று காலாவதியாகும் என்று செய்தித்தாள் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையின் அமைச்சரவைப் பேச்சாளர் பந்துல குணவர்தன செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை கொழும்பில் நடைபெற்ற செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பில், ராஜபக்சே சிங்கப்பூரிலிருந்து நாடு திரும்புவார் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "தேசத்தை ஸ்லெட்ஜ் செய்த முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி ஆரம்பத்தில் நகர மையத்தில் உள்ள ஹோட்டலில் தங்கியிருந்தார், ஆனால் அவர் ஒரு தனியார் இல்லத்திற்கு மாறியதாக நம்பப்படுகிறது, ஸ்ட்ரைட் டைம்ஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "சிங்கப்பூர் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம் ஜூலை 14 அன்று, ராஜபக்சே அடைக்கலம் கேட்கவில்லை என்றும் அவருக்கு எந்த அடைக்கலமும் வழங்கப்படவில்லை என்றும் கூறியது.",
        "சிங்கப்பூர் பொதுவாக புகலிடக் கோரிக்கைகளை வழங்குவதில்லை என்று அமைச்சகம் மேலும் கூறியது.",
        "இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்ற சபாநாயகர் மகிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன, ராஜபக்சேவின் அதிகாரப்பூர்வ பதவி விலகலை ஜூலை 15ஆம் தேதி அறிவித்தார்.",
        "73 வயதான கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச, ஜூலை 9 ஆம் தேதி அவரது இல்லத்தை முற்றுகையிட்ட போராட்டக்காரர்கள் பின்னர் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறினார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் அதிபராக ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கே ஜூலை 21ஆம் தேதி நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் பிரதம நீதியரசர் ஜெயந்த ஜெயசூர்யா முன்னிலையில் பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்து கொண்டார்.",
        "பதவியேற்பு விழாவுக்கு ஒரு நாள் முன்னதாக நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் நடைபெற்ற தேர்தலில் அவர் அதிபராகத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "நாட்டில் ஏற்பட்ட கடுமையான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு மத்தியில் கடந்த வாரம் ஜனாதிபதி பதவியிலிருந்து கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச ராஜினாமா செய்ததைத் தொடர்ந்து விக்கிரமசிங்க 134 வாக்குகளைப் பெற்றார்.",
        "இரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பு மூலம் பாராளுமன்ற வாக்கெடுப்பில் வெற்றி பெற்ற பின்னர், பாராளுமன்றத்தில் உரையாற்றிய விக்கிரமசிங்க, தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் இருந்து இலங்கையை மீட்க தன்னுடன் ஒன்றிணைந்து செயல்பட எதிர்க்கட்சி நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் உட்பட அனைத்து சட்டமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுக்கும் அழைப்பு விடுத்தார். \"நாங்கள் ஒரு முக்கியமான கட்டத்தில் இருக்கிறோம்.",
        "பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி உள்ளது, இளைஞர்கள் அமைப்பு மாற்றத்தை விரும்புகிறார்கள். அனைத்து நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களும் ஒன்று சேர வேண்டும் என்று மக்கள் விரும்புகிறார்கள்,'' என்றார்.",
        "225 நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களில் 223 பேர் புதிய அதிபரை தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதற்கு வாக்களித்தனர் மற்றும் நான்கு செல்லாத வாக்குகள் இருந்தன.",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்க அரசியலில் புதிய பெயர் அல்ல, இதற்கு முன்னர் ஆறு முறை தீவு நாட்டின் பிரதமராக பதவி வகித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் இரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பு மூலம் வாக்களித்த ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலுக்கான முதன்மைப் போட்டியாளர்களில் இவரும் ஒருவர்.",
        "முன்னதாக, முன்னெப்போதும் இல்லாத பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு மத்தியில் கோபமான எதிர்ப்பாளர்களால் அவரது அரண்மனை முற்றுகையிடப்பட்டதை அடுத்து, கோத்தபய ராஜபக்ச வெளிநாடு தப்பிச் சென்றதை அடுத்து, இலங்கையின் இடைக்கால அதிபராக விக்ரமசிங்கே நியமிக்கப்பட்டார். நாடு எரிபொருள் மற்றும் பிற அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களுக்கு கடுமையான பற்றாக்குறையை எதிர்கொள்கிறது மற்றும் பணவீக்கத்துடன் அதன் மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் உள்ளது. எண்ணெய் தட்டுப்பாடு காரணமாக பள்ளிகள் மற்றும் அரசு அலுவலகங்கள் மறு அறிவிப்பு வரும் வரை மூட வேண்டிய கட்டாயம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "உள்நாட்டு விவசாய உற்பத்தி குறைக்கப்பட்டது, அந்நிய செலாவணி இருப்பு பற்றாக்குறை மற்றும் உள்ளூர் நாணய தேய்மானம் ஆகியவை பற்றாக்குறையை தூண்டியுள்ளன.",
        "பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி பல குடும்பங்களை பட்டினி மற்றும் வறுமையில் தள்ளும் - சில முதல் முறையாக - உலக வங்கியின் மதிப்பீட்டின்படி, தொற்றுநோய் காரணமாக வறுமைக் கோட்டிற்குக் கீழே விழுந்துள்ள அரை மில்லியன் மக்களைச் சேர்க்கும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "14 நாட்கள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்னும் 14 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ட்ரெய்ட்ஸ் டைம்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14-நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாங்கி விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளிநாட்டு அலுவல்கள் அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "73 வயதானவர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரை மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}