{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84738/youth-falls-to-his-death-while-trying-to-take-a-selfie",
  "time_ut": 1662279060,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Youth falls to his death while trying to take a selfie",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Youth falls to his death while trying to take a selfie",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A youth has reportedly died after falling into a waterfall at Udaweriyawatta in Haldummulla.",
        "Last Friday (02), two youths had visited this waterfall located in the Sanweli Estate area of  Udaweriyawatta, Haldummulla.",
        "Police said that while attempting to take a ‘selfie’ photograph near the waterfall, one young man had slipped and fell into the waterfall.",
        "The body of the young man was recovered yesterday (03) in a waterhole about 200 meters below the place of the accident, during the search conducted by Haldummulla police officers and local residents.",
        "The victim is identified as a 24-year-old resident of Welamitiyawa, Guruthalawa."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Haldummulla",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Last Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Udaweriyawatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Haldummulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 200 meters",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Haldummulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "24-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welamitiyawa, Guruthalawa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සෙල්ෆියක් ගැනීමට යාමේදී තරුණයා ඇද වැටී මිය යයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හල්දුම්මුල්ල, උඩවේරියවත්ත ප්‍රදේශයේ දිය ඇල්ලකට වැටී තරුණයෙකු මිය ගොස් ඇති බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "හල්දුම්මුල්ල, උඩවේරියවත්ත, සංවැලි වත්ත ප්‍රදේශයේ පිහිටි මෙම දිය ඇල්ල නැරඹීමට පසුගිය සිකුරාදා (02) තරුණයින් දෙදෙනෙකු පැමිණ තිබුණා.",
        "පොලීසිය පැවසුවේ, දිය ඇල්ල ආසන්නයේ සෙල්ෆි ඡායාරූපයක් ගැනීමට යාමේදී එක් තරුණයෙකු පය ලිස්සා දිය ඇල්ලට වැටී ඇති බවයි.",
        "හල්දුම්මුල්ල පොලිසියේ නිලධාරීන් සහ ප්‍රදේශවාසීන් එක්ව සිදුකළ සෝදිසි කිරීම්වලදී අනතුර සිදුවූ ස්ථානයට මීටර් 200ක් පමණ පහළින් පිහිටි දිය වළක තිබී තරුණයාගේ සිරුර ඊයේ (03දා) සොයා ගෙන ඇත.",
        "ඝාතනයට ලක්ව ඇත්තේ ගුරුතලාව, වැලමිටියාව ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 24 හැවිරිදි තරුණයෙකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හල්දුම්මුල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "උඩවේරියවත්ත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හල්දුම්මුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීටර් 200 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "හල්දුම්මුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "24 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලමිටියාව, ගුරුතලාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "செல்ஃபி எடுக்க முயன்ற இளைஞர் கீழே விழுந்து உயிரிழந்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஹல்துமுல்ல, உடவெரியவத்த நீர்வீழ்ச்சியில் விழுந்து இளைஞர் ஒருவர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஹல்துமுல்ல, உடவெரியவத்த, சன்வேலி தோட்டப் பகுதியில் அமைந்துள்ள இந்த நீர்வீழ்ச்சிக்கு கடந்த வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (02) இரண்டு இளைஞர்கள் சென்றுள்ளனர்.",
        "நீர்வீழ்ச்சிக்கு அருகில் ‘செல்பி’ புகைப்படம் எடுக்க முற்பட்ட போது இளைஞர் ஒருவர் தவறி நீர்வீழ்ச்சியில் விழுந்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "ஹல்துமுல்ல பொலிஸ் உத்தியோகத்தர்கள் மற்றும் பிரதேசவாசிகள் இணைந்து மேற்கொண்ட தேடுதலின் போது, ​​விபத்து இடம்பெற்ற இடத்திலிருந்து சுமார் 200 மீற்றர் கீழே உள்ள நீர்க்குழாய் ஒன்றில் நேற்று (03) குறித்த இளைஞனின் சடலம் மீட்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "உயிரிழந்தவர் குருத்தலாவ வெலமிட்டியாவைச் சேர்ந்த 24 வயதுடையவர் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹல்துமுல்ல",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வெள்ளிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உடவெரியவத்த",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹல்துமுல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 200 மீட்டர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹல்துமுல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "24 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலமிட்டியாவ, குருதலாவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}