{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83649/sri-lanka-president-on-private-visit-not-granted-asylum-singapore",
  "time_ut": 1657804740,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka President on private visit, not granted asylum: Singapore",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka President on private visit, not granted asylum: Singapore",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka President Gotabaya Rajapaksa is on a private visit and has not been granted asylum, the Singapore government said today shortly before his flight was expected to land in the city state.",
        "“It is confirmed that Mr. Rajapaksa has been allowed entry into Singapore on a private visit,” Singapore’s foreign ministry was quoted as saying by news agency AFP.",
        "“He has not asked for asylum and neither has he been granted any asylum. Singapore generally does not grant requests for asylum,” the statement read.",
        "Mr Rajapaksa landed in Singapore on board a Saudia airlines flight this afternoon.",
        "Quoting sources in Sri Lankan security, AFP reported that he is expected to stay in Singapore for some time, before potentially moving to the United Arab Emirates.",
        "The Sri Lankan President had taken left Colombo for Maldives late on Tuesday evening. Last night, he requested the Maldives government to arrange a private jet to fly him to Singapore, fearing public backlash, sources had said.",
        "Before leaving Colombo, he had assured leaders that would send in his resignation. Thirty-six hours on, that is yet to happen.",
        "Back in Sri Lanka, protesters demanded that he keep his promise to step down over the island nation’s worst-ever economic crisis.",
        "Today, the protesters vacated several of the emblematic state buildings they had overrun earlier this week, including the Presidential palace and the office of Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "On Wednesday morning, shortly after Mr Rajapansa left, Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe declared a state of emergency and asked security forces to restore order."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Singapore",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudia",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Arab Emirates",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thirty-six hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "earlier this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනපති පෞද්ගලික සංචාරයක, සරණාගතභාවය ලබා දී නැත: සිංගප්පූරුව",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පුද්ගලික සංචාරයක යෙදී සිටින අතර ඔහුට සරණාගතභාවය ලබා දී නොමැති බව සිංගප්පූරු රජය අද ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ඔහුගේ ගුවන් යානය නගර ප්‍රාන්තයට ගොඩබසිනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කිරීමට ටික වේලාවකට පෙරය.",
        "\"පෞද්ගලික සංචාරයක් සඳහා රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට සිංගප්පූරුවට ඇතුළු වීමට අවසර දී ඇති බව තහවුරු වේ\" යනුවෙන් සිංගප්පූරු විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය උපුටා දක්වමින් AFP පුවත් සේවය වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "“ඔහු සරණාගතභාවය ඉල්ලා නැත, ඔහුට සරණාගතභාවය ලබා දී නැත. සිංගප්පූරුව සාමාන්‍යයෙන් සරණාගත ඉල්ලීම් ලබා දෙන්නේ නැත, ”ප්‍රකාශයේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ මහතා අද පස්වරුවේ සෞදියා ගුවන් සේවයට අයත් ගුවන් යානයකින් සිංගප්පූරුවට ගොඩ බැස්සේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආරක්ෂක මූලාශ්‍ර උපුටා දක්වමින් AFP වාර්තා කළේ ඔහු එක්සත් අරාබි එමීර් රාජ්‍යයට යාමට පෙර සිංගප්පූරුවේ ටික කලක් රැඳී සිටීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයා අඟහරුවාදා සවස කොළඹින් මාලදිවයින බලා පිටත්ව ගොස් ඇත. මහජන විරෝධයට බියෙන් තමා සිංගප්පූරුවට පියාසර කිරීමට පෞද්ගලික ජෙට් යානයක් සූදානම් කරන ලෙස ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ ඔහු මාලදිවයින් රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටි බව ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කර ඇත.",
        "කොළඹින් පිටවීමට පෙර ඔහු සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීම යවන බවට නායකයින්ට සහතික විය. පැය තිස් හයක් ගතවී ඇතත් එය තවම සිදු නොවේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළදී, විරෝධතාකරුවන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ, දිවයින ජාතියේ මෙතෙක් පැවති දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඔහු ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට දුන් පොරොන්දුව ඉටු කරන ලෙසයි.",
        "අද විරෝධතාකරුවන් ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ කාර්යාලය ඇතුළුව මෙම සතිය මුලදී තමන් විසින් අත්පත් කරගෙන සිටි සංකේතාත්මක රාජ්‍ය ගොඩනැගිලි කිහිපයක් ඉවත් කර ඇත.",
        "බදාදා උදෑසන, රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පිටත්ව ගොස් ටික වේලාවකට පසු, අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ හදිසි තත්වයක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර, සාමය යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් කරන ලෙස ආරක්ෂක අංශවලට ඉල්ලා සිටියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවුදියාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් අරාබි එමීර් රාජ්‍යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය තිස් හයක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ සතියේ මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி தனிப்பட்ட விஜயத்தில், புகலிடம் வழங்கப்படவில்லை: சிங்கப்பூர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச தனிப்பட்ட விஜயமொன்றை மேற்கொண்டுள்ள நிலையில், அவருக்கு புகலிடம் வழங்கப்படவில்லை என சிங்கப்பூர் அரசாங்கம் இன்று தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "\"திரு. ராஜபக்ச தனிப்பட்ட பயணமாக சிங்கப்பூருக்குள் நுழைய அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டார் என்பது உறுதிப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது\" என சிங்கப்பூர் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம் மேற்கோள்காட்டி செய்தி நிறுவனமான AFP தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "\"அவர் புகலிடம் கேட்கவில்லை, அவருக்கு எந்த புகலிடமும் வழங்கப்படவில்லை. சிங்கப்பூர் பொதுவாக புகலிடக் கோரிக்கைகளை வழங்குவதில்லை” என்று அந்த அறிக்கையில் கூறப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இன்று பிற்பகல் சவுதியா ஏர்லைன்ஸ் விமானத்தில் திரு ராஜபக்ச சிங்கப்பூர் வந்திறங்கினார்.",
        "அவர் ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸுக்குச் செல்வதற்கு முன்னர், சிங்கப்பூரில் சிறிது காலம் தங்கியிருப்பார் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுவதாக இலங்கை பாதுகாப்புத் துறை வட்டாரங்களை மேற்கோள்காட்டி AFP செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை அதிபர் செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை மாலை கொழும்பில் இருந்து மாலைத்தீவுக்கு புறப்பட்டுச் சென்றார். நேற்றிரவு, பொதுமக்களின் எதிர்ப்புக்கு அஞ்சி, சிங்கப்பூர் செல்ல தனியார் ஜெட் விமானத்தை ஏற்பாடு செய்யுமாறு மாலத்தீவு அரசாங்கத்திடம் அவர் கோரிக்கை விடுத்ததாக வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன.",
        "கொழும்பிலிருந்து வெளியேறும் முன், அவர் தனது பதவி விலகலை அனுப்புவதாக தலைவர்களுக்கு உறுதியளித்திருந்தார். முப்பத்தாறு மணிநேரம், அது இன்னும் நடக்கவில்லை.",
        "மீண்டும் இலங்கையில், தீவு நாட்டின் மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் பதவி விலகுவதாக அவர் அளித்த வாக்குறுதியை அவர் காப்பாற்ற வேண்டும் என்று எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் கோரினர்.",
        "இன்று, எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை மற்றும் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் அலுவலகம் உட்பட, இந்த வார தொடக்கத்தில் தாங்கள் கைப்பற்றிய பல சின்னமான அரச கட்டிடங்களை காலி செய்தனர்.",
        "புதன்கிழமை காலை, திரு ராஜபன்சா வெளியேறிய சிறிது நேரத்திலேயே, பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க அவசரகால நிலையைப் பிரகடனம் செய்து, அமைதியை மீட்டெடுக்குமாறு பாதுகாப்புப் படையினரைக் கேட்டுக் கொண்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவுதியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாயங்காலம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முப்பத்தாறு மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வார தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}