{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/16/derailed-ruhunu-kumari-back-on-track/",
  "time_ut": 1660626480,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Derailed Ruhunu Kumari back on track",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Derailed Ruhunu Kumari back on track",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Sri Lanka Railways said that the Ruhunu Kumari Express train derailed in the Boossa area on Monday (15) morning while operating from Matara to Colombo, was placed back on the train tracks.",
        "The railways' control room said operations were reported on Monday (15) evening.",
        "The Ruhunu Kumari express train which was en route from Matara to Colombo derailed in Boossa.",
        "Although the derailment had been rectified by Monday (15) evening, restoration work on the railway track continues.",
        "Several incidents of train derailing were reported in the recent past with trade unions alleging they are faced with serious issues in terms of maintenance.",
        "Deputy General Manager of Railways Gamini Senevirathne said the dollar crisis had hampered the Railways Department's ability to import new tracks and equipment required to repair the railway system.",
        "Speaking further he said, the tenders called to import new train tracks had also been canceled, stating that the railway system is growing decrepit daily as a result.",
        "Vice Admiral of Indian Navy pays homage at memorial of Indian soldiers in Sri Lanka"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ruhunu Kumari",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Sri Lanka Railways",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumari Express",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boossa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15) evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ruhunu Kumari",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boossa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15) evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gamini Senevirathne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Railways Department's",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පීලි පැන්න රුහුණු කුමාරි නැවතත් ධාවන පථයට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); රුහුණු කුමාරි ශීඝ්‍රගාමී දුම්රිය මාතර සිට කොළඹ බලා ධාවනය වෙමින් තිබියදී සඳුදා (15) අලුයම බූස්ස ප්‍රදේශයේදී පීලි පැනීමකට ලක් වූ බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "සඳුදා (15) සවස මෙහෙයුම් වාර්තා වූ බව දුම්රිය පාලක මැදිරිය පවසයි.",
        "මාතර සිට කොළඹ බලා ධාවනය වූ රුහුණු කුමාරි ශීඝ්‍රගාමී දුම්රිය බූස්සේදී පීලි පැනීමකට ලක්ව තිබේ.",
        "සඳුදා (15) සවස් වන විට පීලි පැනීම යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් කර තිබුණද, දුම්රිය මාර්ගයේ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ කටයුතු තවදුරටත් සිදුවෙමින් පවතී.",
        "දුම්රිය පීලි පැනීමේ සිද්ධීන් කිහිපයක් පසුගිය කාලය තුළ වාර්තා වූ අතර, නඩත්තුව සම්බන්ධයෙන් තමන් බරපතල ගැටළුවලට මුහුණ පා සිටින බවට වෘත්තීය සමිති චෝදනා කරයි.",
        "නියෝජ්‍ය දුම්රිය සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරී ගාමිණී සෙනෙවිරත්න මහතා පැවසුවේ ඩොලර් අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් දුම්රිය පද්ධතිය අලුත්වැඩියා කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය නව පීලි සහ උපකරණ ආනයනය කිරීමට දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට ඇති හැකියාව අඩාල වී ඇති බවයි.",
        "එහිදී වැඩිදුරටත් අදහස් දැක්වූ ඒ මහතා කියා සිටියේ නව දුම්රිය මාර්ග ආනයනය කිරීම සඳහා කැඳවා තිබූ ටෙන්ඩර් ද අවලංගු කර ඇති අතර, මේ හේතුවෙන් දුම්රිය පද්ධතිය දෛනිකව අබලන් වන බව පවසමින්.",
        "ඉන්දීය නාවික හමුදාවේ වයිස් අද්මිරාල්වරයා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්දීය සෙබළුන්ගේ ස්මාරකය වෙත පුෂ්පෝපහාර දක්වයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රුහුණු කුමාරි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දුම්රිය සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාරි එක්ස්ප්‍රස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බූස්ස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුහුණු කුමාරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බූස්ස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාමිණී සෙනෙවිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தடம் புரண்ட ருஹுனு குமாரி மீண்டும் பாதைக்கு வந்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); திங்கட்கிழமை (15) காலை மாத்தறையில் இருந்து கொழும்பு நோக்கிச் சென்று கொண்டிருந்த ருஹுணு குமாரி விரைவு ரயில் பூஸ்ஸ பகுதியில் தடம் புரண்டதாக இலங்கை ரயில்வே தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "திங்கட்கிழமை (15) மாலை நடவடிக்கைகள் பதிவாகியுள்ளதாக ரயில்வே கட்டுப்பாட்டு அறை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மாத்தறையில் இருந்து கொழும்பு நோக்கி பயணித்த ருஹுனு குமாரி விரைவு ரயில் பூஸ்ஸ பகுதியில் தடம் புரண்டது.",
        "திங்கட்கிழமை (15) மாலைக்குள் தடம் புரண்டது சீர்செய்யப்பட்ட போதிலும், ரயில் பாதையின் சீரமைப்புப் பணிகள் தொடர்கின்றன.",
        "அண்மைக்காலமாக பல ரயில் தடம் புரண்ட சம்பவங்கள் பதிவாகியுள்ளன.",
        "ரயில்வேயின் பிரதி பொது முகாமையாளர் காமினி செனவிரத்ன கூறுகையில், டொலர் நெருக்கடி காரணமாக புகையிரத திணைக்களத்தின் புதிய பாதைகள் மற்றும் புகையிரத அமைப்பை சீர்செய்வதற்கு தேவையான உபகரணங்களை இறக்குமதி செய்வதில் தடை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மேலும் பேசிய அவர், புதிய ரயில் பாதைகளை இறக்குமதி செய்ய கோரப்பட்ட டெண்டர்களும் ரத்து செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும், இதனால் ரயில்வே அமைப்பு நாளுக்கு நாள் நலிவடைந்து வருவதாகவும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் உள்ள இந்திய ராணுவ வீரர்களின் நினைவிடத்தில் இந்திய கடற்படை வைஸ் அட்மிரல் மரியாதை செலுத்தினார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ருஹுனு குமாரி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ரயில்வே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமரி எக்ஸ்பிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூஸ்ஸா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15) மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ருஹுனு குமாரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூஸ்ஸா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15) மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "காமினி செனவிரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரயில்வே துறையின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}