{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/පොහොට්ටු-සභාපති---ලේකම්ගෙන්-කරුණු-විමසයි/101-616526",
  "time_ut": 1657960920,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පොහොට්ටු සභාපති - ලේකම්ගෙන් කරුණු විමසයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Pohottu inquires from the Chairman-Secretary",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. G. L. Peiris, the chairman of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna, has asked the Secretary General Sagara Kariyawasam in a letter on what basis the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna announced that it would support Ranil Wickramasinghe in the election of a suitable candidate for the currently vacant presidential post.",
        "The Secretary of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna Mr. Sagara Kariyawasam stated in a statement yesterday that Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna has decided to provide support to Acting President Ranil Wickramasinghe in the election of a new president.",
        "The Chairman of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna has forwarded this letter requesting an answer to that announcement. The article states:"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "G. L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sagara Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sagara Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පොහොට්ටු සභාපති - ලේකම්ගෙන් කරුණු විමසයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "දැනට පුරප්පාඩු වී ඇති ජනාධිපති තනතුරට සුදුස්සකු තෝරා ගැනීමේ ඡන්දයේ දී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සහාය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට ලබා දෙන බවට ප්‍රකාශ කළේ කුමන පදනමක් මත දැයි එහි සභාපති ජී.එල්.පීරිස් මහතා ලිපියක් යොමු කරමින් පක්ෂ මහලේකම් සාගර කාරියවසම්ගෙන් විමසා ඇත.",
        "නව ජනාධිපතිවරයකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමේ ඡන්දයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සහාය වැඩ බලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට ලබාදීමට තීරණය කළ බවට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ  ලේකම් සගාර කාරියවසම් මහතා ඊයේ  නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "එම නිවේදනයට පිළිතුරක් ඉල්ලමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සභාපතිවරයා මෙම ලිපිය යොමු කර ඇත. එම ලිපියේ මෙසේ සඳහන් වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල්. පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பொஹொட்டு தலைவர்-செயலாளரிடம் கேட்கிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தற்போது வெற்றிடத்திற்கு பொருத்தமான வேட்பாளரை தெரிவு செய்ய ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவிற்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதாக ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன எந்த அடிப்படையில் அறிவித்தது என ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் தலைவர் ஜீ.எல்.பீரிஸ், செயலாளர் நாயகம் சாகர காரியவசத்திடம் கடிதம் மூலம் வினவியுள்ளார். ஜனாதிபதி பதவி.",
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவுசெய்வதற்கு பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு ஆதரவளிக்க ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் செயலாளர் திரு.சாகர காரியவசம் நேற்று விடுத்துள்ள அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அந்த அறிவிப்புக்கு பதிலளிக்குமாறு கோரி ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் தலைவர் இந்தக் கடிதத்தை அனுப்பி வைத்துள்ளார். கட்டுரை கூறுகிறது:"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகர காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகர காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}