{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/රටවල්-හතරකට-තැපැල්-භාණ්ඩ-භාරගැනීම-නවතියි/11-395458",
  "time_ut": 1657882527,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රටවල් හතරකට තැපැල් භාණ්ඩ භාරගැනීම නවතියි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Four countries will stop receiving mail",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Postmaster General Ranjith Ariyaratne Masahatha informs that due to the restriction and suspension of flights to Sri Lanka due to the existing fuel crisis, the acceptance of postal items to 4 countries has been suspended until further notice.",
        "Accordingly, the acceptance of postal items to the United States of America, the Netherlands, Israel and Russia has been suspended.",
        "In addition to this, he further announced that postal transport within the country has been delayed due to difficulty in providing fuel."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Four",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Ariyaratne Masahatha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the United States of America",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Netherlands",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Israel",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රටවල් හතරකට තැපැල් භාණ්ඩ භාරගැනීම නවතියි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පවත්නා ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය හමුවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙන ගුවන් ගමන් සීමා කිරිම හා අත්හිටුවීම හේතුවෙන් රටවල් 4ක් වෙත තැපැල් භාණ්ඩ භාර ගැනීම නැවත දැනුම් දෙන තුරු අත්හිටුවා ඇති බව තැපැල්පති රංජිත් ආරියරත්න මසහතා දන්වා සිටියි.",
        "ඒ අනුව ඇමෙරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය, නෙදර්ලන්තය, ඊශ්‍රාලය හා රුසියාව වෙත තැපැල් භාණ්ඩ භාර ගැනීම අත්හිටුවා තිබේ.",
        "මීට අමතරව ඉන්ධන සපයා ගැනීමේ අපහසුතාව හේතුවෙන් රට අභ්‍යන්තරයේ තැපැල් ප්‍රවාහන කටයුතු ප්‍රමාදයට ලක්ව ඇති බවද ඒ මහතා වැඩිදුරටත් නිවේදනය කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හතර",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් ආරියරත්න මාසහත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෙදර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊශ්රායෙල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நான்கு நாடுகள் அஞ்சல் பெறுவதை நிறுத்திவிடும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தற்போது நிலவும் எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடி காரணமாக இலங்கைக்கான விமான சேவைகள் தடை மற்றும் இடைநிறுத்தம் காரணமாக 4 நாடுகளுக்கு தபால் பொருட்களை ஏற்றுக்கொள்வது மறு அறிவித்தல் வரை இடைநிறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தபால் மா அதிபர் ரஞ்சித் ஆரியரத்ன மசஹத தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதன்படி அமெரிக்கா, நெதர்லாந்து, இஸ்ரேல் மற்றும் ரஷ்யா ஆகிய நாடுகளுக்கு தபால் பொருட்களை ஏற்றுக்கொள்வது தற்காலிகமாக நிறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இதற்கு மேலதிகமாக, எரிபொருள் வழங்குவதில் உள்ள சிரமம் காரணமாக நாட்டிற்குள் தபால் போக்குவரத்து தாமதமாகியுள்ளதாக அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நான்கு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சித் ஆரியரத்ன மசஹத",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நெதர்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்ரேல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}