{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ණය-සහන-ගැන-ස්ථාවරය--වෙනස්-කරන්නැයි-ජනපති-චිනයෙන්-ඉල්ලයි/11-396611",
  "time_ut": 1661427458,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ණය සහන ගැන ස්ථාවරය  වෙනස් කරන්නැයි ජනපති චිනයෙන් ඉල්ලයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The President asks China to change its stance on debt relief",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe said in a special interview to Nikkei Asia News Service that Sri Lanka is asking China to change its position on debt relief. The President also stated that it will not be easy to reach an agreement in this regard.",
        "Mr. Wickramasinghe said, \"We have informed the Chinese government of the need for debt restructuring and the need to treat all creditors equally.\"",
        "He insists that it will be a complicated path for Beijing to make a difference in this regard, but it will somehow depend on other lenders.",
        "China, Japan and India have given large bilateral loans to Sri Lanka. Sri Lanka's total foreign debt is 51 billion dollars, of which these three countries have 14 billion dollars.",
        "Some independent economists have estimated that the amount of credit given by China to Sri Lanka from 2001 to 2021 is close to 9.95 billion dollars.",
        "Sri Lanka has declared that it is unable to pay the foreign debt of 6.9 billion dollars this year."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nikkei Asia News Service",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "51 billion dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 billion dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2001 to 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.95 billion dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.9 billion dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ණය සහන ගැන ස්ථාවරය  වෙනස් කරන්නැයි ජනපති චිනයෙන් ඉල්ලයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ණය සහන පිළිබඳ සිය ස්ථාවරය  වෙනස් කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාව චීනයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා නික්කෙයි ඒෂියා පුවත් සෙවය වෙත විශේෂ සම්මුඛ සාකච්ඡාවකට එක්වෙමින් පැවැසිය.එසේම ඒ් සම්බන්ධයෙන් එකඟතාවයකට එළැඹීිම පහසු නොවන බවද ජනපතිවරයා සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "\"ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ අවශ්‍යතාවය සහ සියලුම ණය හිමියන් එකම ලෙස කටයුුතු කිරිමේ අවශ්‍යතාවය අපි චීන රජයට දන්වා තිබෙනවා\" යැයි වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පැවැසීිය.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන බීජිං  වෙනසක් ඇති  කිරීම සංකීර්ණ මාවතක් වුවත් එය යම්කිසි ආකාරයකට අනෙකුත් ණය දෙන්නන් මත රඳා පවතින බවද ඔහු පැවැසිය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට විශාල ලෙසම ද්විපාර්ශවීය ණය ලබාදී ඇත්තේ චීනය, ජපානය සහ ඉන්දියාව වෙයිි. ලංකාවේ සමස්ත විිදේශීය ණය ඩොලර් බිලිියන 51ක් වන අතර එයින් ඩොලර්  බිලිියන 14ක්ම ඇත්තේ මෙම රටවල්  තුනටය.",
        "2001 සිට 2021 දක්වා චීනය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබාදුන් ණය ප්‍රමාණය ඩොලර් බිලියන 9.95කට ආසන්න බව ඇතැම් ස්වාධීන ආර්ථික විද්‍යාඥයන් ඇස්තමේන්තු කර  තිබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට මේ වසරේදීි ඩොලර් බිලියන 6.9 ක විදේශ ණය  ගෙවිමට තිබුණත් එම ණය  ගෙවීමට  හැකියාවක් නොමැති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nikkei Asia පුවත් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 51 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 14 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2001 සිට 2021 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 9.95 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 6.9 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கடன் நிவாரணம் குறித்த தனது நிலைப்பாட்டை மாற்றிக்கொள்ளுமாறு சீனாவை ஜனாதிபதி கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கடன் நிவாரணம் தொடர்பில் சீனா தனது நிலைப்பாட்டை மாற்றிக்கொள்ளுமாறு இலங்கை கோருவதாக நிக்கேய் ஏசியா செய்திச் சேவைக்கு வழங்கிய விசேட நேர்காணலில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்க, “கடனை மறுசீரமைக்க வேண்டியதன் அவசியத்தையும், கடனாளிகள் அனைவரையும் சமமாக நடத்த வேண்டியதன் அவசியத்தையும் சீன அரசாங்கத்திற்கு நாங்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளோம்” என்றார்.",
        "பெய்ஜிங்கிற்கு இந்த விஷயத்தில் ஒரு வித்தியாசத்தை ஏற்படுத்துவது ஒரு சிக்கலான பாதையாக இருக்கும், ஆனால் அது எப்படியோ மற்ற கடன் வழங்குபவர்களைச் சார்ந்திருக்கும் என்று அவர் வலியுறுத்துகிறார்.",
        "சீனா, ஜப்பான் மற்றும் இந்தியா ஆகிய நாடுகள் இலங்கைக்கு இருதரப்புக் கடன்களை வழங்கியுள்ளன. இலங்கையின் மொத்த வெளிநாட்டுக் கடன் 51 பில்லியன் டொலர்களாகும், அதில் இந்த மூன்று நாடுகளிடமும் 14 பில்லியன் டொலர்கள் உள்ளன.",
        "சில சுயாதீன பொருளாதார நிபுணர்கள் 2001 முதல் 2021 வரை இலங்கைக்கு சீனா வழங்கிய கடன் தொகை 9.95 பில்லியன் டாலர்களை அண்மித்துள்ளதாக மதிப்பிட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்த வருடத்தில் 6.9 பில்லியன் டொலர் வெளிநாட்டு கடனை செலுத்த முடியாது என இலங்கை அறிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிக்கி ஆசியா செய்தி சேவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமாதித்தன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "51 பில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 பில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2001 முதல் 2021 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.95 பில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.9 பில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}