{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ගංජා-කිලෝ-50ක්-සමග-02ක්-මාට්ටූ/11-396719",
  "time_ut": 1661839016,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ගංජා කිලෝ 50ක් සමග 02ක් මාට්ටූ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "02 killed with 50 kilos of ganja",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Navy says that two suspects were arrested yesterday (29th) along with 51 kilos of 500 grams of Kerala Ganja worth more than one million rupees in the Thondamanaru area of ​​Jaffna.",
        "While inspecting a suspicious van near Thondamanaru Bridge, a group of officers belonging to the Northern Naval Command found this well-hidden Kerala ganja stock in the van and took steps to arrest the driver of the van and another person along with the van.",
        "This stock of Kerala ganja was brought from India by sea and was taken to other parts of the island and thus arrested.",
        "The arrested suspects, aged 39 and 44, are residents of Thondamanaru and the Navy added that they have taken steps to hand over the suspects and the stock of Kerala ganja to the Chhalweli Police for further investigation."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "50",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "51",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500 grams",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala Ganja",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than one million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thondamanaru",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thondamanaru Bridge",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Northern Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "39 and 44",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thondamanaru",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගංජා කිලෝ 50ක් සමග 02ක් මාට්ටූ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "යාපනය තොණ්ඩමනාරු ප්‍රදේශයේදී රුපියල් මිලියන අධික වටිනාකමින් යුතු කේරල ගංජා කිලෝ 51 ග්‍රෑම් 500 ක ප්‍රමාණයක් සමග සැකකරුවන් දෙදෙනෙකු ඊයේ (29දා) අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බවට නාවික හමුදාව පවසයි.",
        "උතුරු නාවික විධානයට අයත් නිලධාරීන් පිරිසක් විසින් තොණ්ඩමනාරු පාලම අසලදී සැකකටයුතු වෑන් රථයක් පරික්ෂාවට ලක් කිරීමේදී වෑන් රථය තුල ඉතා සූක්ෂමව සඟවා තිබූ මෙම කේරල ගංජා තොගය සොයාගෙන ඇති අතර එහිදී වෑන් රථයේ රියදුරු සහ තවත් අයෙකු වෑන් රථයද සමගින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට නාවික නිලධාරීන් පියවර ගන්නා ලදි.",
        "මෙම කේරල ගංජා තොගය ඉන්දියාවේ සිට මුහුදු මාර්ගයෙන් රැගෙනවිත් දිවයිනේ වෙනත් ප්‍රදේශයන් රැගෙන යමින් සිටයදී මෙලෙස අත්අඩංගුවට පත්ව ඇත.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරුවන් අවුරුදු 39 ක් සහ 44 යන වයස්හි පසුවන තොණ්ඩමනාරු ප්‍රදේශයේම පදිංචිකරුවන් වන අතර සැකකරුවන් සහ කේරල ගංජා තොගයන් වැඩිදුර පරික්ෂණ කටයුතු සඳහා අච්චුවේලි පොලීසියට භාරදීමට පියවර ගත් බවට නාවික හමුදාව වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "50",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "51",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ග්රෑම් 500 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරළ ගංජා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියනයකට වඩා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තොණ්ඩමනාරු",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තොණ්ඩමනාරු පාලම",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "39 සහ 44",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තොණ්ඩමනාරු",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "50 கிலோ கஞ்சாவுடன் 02 பேர் பலி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "யாழ்ப்பாணம் தொண்டமானாறு பகுதியில் ஒரு மில்லியன் ரூபாவுக்கும் அதிகமான பெறுமதியான 51 கிலோ 500 கிராம் கேரள கஞ்சாவுடன் இரண்டு சந்தேகநபர்கள் நேற்று (29) கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக கடற்படையினர் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "தொண்டமானாறு பாலத்திற்கு அருகில் சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான வேன் ஒன்றை சோதனையிட்ட போது, ​​வடக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை அதிகாரிகள் குழுவினர், வேனில் மறைத்து வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த இந்த கேரள கஞ்சா கையிருப்பை கண்டறிந்து, வேனின் சாரதியையும் வேனுடன் மேலும் ஒருவரையும் கைது செய்ய நடவடிக்கை எடுத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்த கேரளா கஞ்சா இந்தியாவிலிருந்து கடல் மார்க்கமாக கொண்டு வரப்பட்டு தீவின் பிற பகுதிகளுக்கு கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்டு கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேகநபர்கள் 39 மற்றும் 44 வயதுடைய தொண்டமனாறு பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள் எனவும், சந்தேகநபர்கள் மற்றும் கேரள கஞ்சாவை மேலதிக விசாரணைகளுக்காக சால்வேலி பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்க நடவடிக்கை எடுத்துள்ளதாக கடற்படையினர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "50",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "51",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500 கிராம்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரள கஞ்சா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமானவை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொண்டமானாறு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தொண்டமானாறு பாலம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "39 மற்றும் 44",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொண்டமானாறு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}