{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78189",
  "time_ut": 1656010620,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Second  Ship Carrying Humanitarian Aid  Donated  as a Gift  by the Govt and People of Tamil Nadu  arrived in Sri Lanka on 24 June 2022; Consignment  consisting of 14,700 MT of rice, 250 MT of milk powder and 38 MT of medicines is valued at more than  3 billion Sri Lankan Rupees",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Second  Ship Carrying Humanitarian Aid  Donated  as a Gift  by the Govt and People of Tamil Nadu  arrived in Sri Lanka on 24 June 2022; Consignment  consisting of 14,700 MT of rice, 250 MT of milk powder and 38 MT of medicines is valued at more than  3 billion Sri Lankan Rupees",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "(Text of Press Release Issued by the High Commission of India in Colombo on June 24th 2022)",
        "High Commissioner Gopal Baglay, Hon’ble Keheliya Rambukwella, Minister of Health, Hon’ble Nalin Fernando, Minister of Trade, Hon’ble Members of Parliament namely M.A Sumanthiran,      V. Radhakrishnan, M. Udaya Kumar, Angajan Ramanthan, and several others including Senthil Thondaman welcomed a large humanitarian consignment consisting of 14,700 MT of rice, 250 MT of milk powder and 38 MT of medicines donated by the people of India in Colombo on 24 June 2022. The total value of this consignment is more than SLR 3 billion.",
        "2.     The large consignment of humanitarian supplies underscores abiding people to people bonds between India and Sri Lanka as also concerns of the people of India for the well-being of their brethren in Sri Lanka. These supplies shall be distributed among beneficiaries by Government of Sri Lanka in the coming days.",
        "3.      This is the second consignment under a larger commitment of 40,000 MT of rice, 500 MT of milk powder and medicines by Government of Tamil Nadu.",
        "4.      India’s unprecedented economic, financial and humanitarian assistance to the people of Sri Lanka stands at over USD 3.5 billion in 2022. In addition to the three credit lines to the tune of more than USD 1.5 billion and forex support of around USD 2 billion, assistance from the Government and people of India has taken the form of supply of medicines to several health-related establishments in various parts of Sri Lanka, distribution of kerosene among the fishermen of Sri Lanka, handing over of dry rations to needy sections etc."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Second",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Humanitarian Aid",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Gift",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Govt",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tamil Nadu",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "24 June 2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "14,700",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "250",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "38",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan Rupees",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Text of Press Release Issued",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 24th 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gopal Baglay",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Keheliya Rambukwella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "M.A Sumanthiran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "V. Radhakrishnan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "M. Udaya Kumar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Angajan Ramanthan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Senthil Thondaman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14,700",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 June 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coming days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Government of Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD 3.5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තමිල්නාඩු රජය සහ ජනතාව විසින් තෑග්ගක් ලෙස පරිත්‍යාග කරන ලද මානුෂීය ආධාර රැගත් දෙවන නෞකාව 2022 ජූනි 24 දින ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණියේය. සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 14,700 ක්, කිරිපිටි මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 250 ක් සහ ඖෂධ මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 38 කින් සමන්විත තොගයේ වටිනාකම ශ්‍රී ලංකා රුපියල් බිලියන 3 කට අධික වේ.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "(2022 ජුනි 24 වැනි දින කොළඹ පිහිටි ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය විසින් නිකුත් කරන ලද මාධ්‍ය නිවේදනයේ පාඨය)",
        "මහ කොමසාරිස් ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ, සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය ගරු කෙහෙළිය රඹුක්වැල්ල, ගරු නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු, වෙළඳ අමාත්‍ය, ගරු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන එම්. 2022 ජුනි 24 වැනි දින ඉන්දීය ජනතාව විසින් කොළඹදී පරිත්‍යාග කරන ලද සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 14,700 ක්, කිරිපිටි මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 250 ක් සහ ඖෂධ මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 38 කින් සමන්විත විශාල මානුෂීය තොගයක් සෙන්තිල් තොණ්ඩමන් මහතා ඇතුළු පිරිසක් විසින් පිළිගනු ලැබීය. මෙම තොගයේ මුළු වටිනාකම රුපියල් බිලියන 3 කට වඩා වැඩිය. .",
        "2. මානුෂීය සැපයුම් විශාල තොගයක් ඉන්දියාව සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර මිනිසුන්ට පවතින බැඳීම් මෙන්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිටින ඔවුන්ගේ සහෝදරයන්ගේ යහපැවැත්ම සඳහා ඉන්දියාවේ ජනතාවගේ සැලකිල්ල ද අවධාරණය කරයි. මෙම සැපයුම් ඉදිරි දිනවලදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය විසින් ප්‍රතිලාභීන් අතර බෙදා හරිනු ලැබේ.",
        "3. තමිල්නාඩු රජය විසින් සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 40,000 ක්, කිරිපිටි මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 500 ක් සහ ඖෂධ ලබා දීමේ විශාල කැපවීමක් යටතේ මෙය දෙවැනි තොගය වේ.",
        "4. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාව සඳහා ඉන්දියාවේ පෙර නොවූ විරූ ආර්ථික, මූල්‍ය සහ මානුෂීය ආධාර 2022 දී ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.5 ඉක්මවයි. ණය මාර්ග තුනට අමතරව ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.5 කට වඩා වැඩි අගයක් සහ ඩොලර් බිලියන 2 ක පමණ විදේශ විනිමය ආධාරයක්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විවිධ ප්‍රදේශවල සෞඛ්‍ය සම්බන්ධ ආයතන කිහිපයකට ඖෂධ සැපයීම, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ධීවරයින් අතර භූමිතෙල් බෙදා හැරීම, අවශ්‍යතා ඇති කොටස්වලට වියළි සලාක ලබා දීම යනාදී වශයෙන් ඉන්දීය රජයේ සහ ජනතාවගේ සහාය ලබාගෙන ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙවැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "මානුෂීය ආධාර",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "තෑගි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රජය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022 ජූනි 24",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "14,700 කි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "250",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "38",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රුපියල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නිකුත් කරන ලද මාධ්‍ය නිවේදනයේ පෙළ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ කොමසාරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූනි 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙහෙළිය රඹුක්වැල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම් ඒ සුමන්තිරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වී රාධක්‍රිෂ්ණන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම් උදය කුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අංගජන් රාමන්තන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙන්තිල් තොණ්ඩමන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14,700 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූනි 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩු රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.5 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தமிழ்நாட்டு அரசாங்கமும் மக்களும் அன்பளிப்பாக வழங்கிய மனிதாபிமான உதவிகளை ஏற்றிச் செல்லும் இரண்டாவது கப்பல் 24 ஜூன் 2022 அன்று இலங்கையை வந்தடைந்தது; 14,700 மெட்ரிக்தொன் அரிசி, 250 மெட்ரிக்தொன் பால் மா மற்றும் 38 மெட்ரிக்தொன் மருந்துகள் அடங்கிய சரக்கு 3 பில்லியன் இலங்கை ரூபாய்க்கு மேல் பெறுமதியானது.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "(ஜூன் 24, 2022 அன்று கொழும்பில் உள்ள இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயத்தால் வெளியிடப்பட்ட செய்திக்குறிப்பு உரை)",
        "உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் கோபால் பாக்லே, கௌரவ கெஹலிய ரம்புக்வெல்ல, சுகாதார அமைச்சர், கௌரவ நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ, வர்த்தக அமைச்சர், கௌரவ பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன், வி. ராதாகிருஷ்ணன், எம்.உதய குமார், அங்கஜன் இராமந்தன் மற்றும் பலர். செந்தில் தொண்டமான் உட்பட 14,700 மெட்ரிக் டன் அரிசி, 250 மெட்ரிக் டன் பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் 38 மெட்ரிக் டன் மருந்துகள் அடங்கிய பெரிய மனிதாபிமானப் பொருட்களை கொழும்பில் 24 ஜூன் 2022 அன்று கொழும்பில் நன்கொடையாக வழங்கினார். .",
        "2. பெருமளவிலான மனிதாபிமான பொருட்கள், இந்தியாவிற்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையில் மக்கள் பிணைப்பைக் கடைப்பிடிப்பதை அடிக்கோடிட்டுக் காட்டுகின்றன. இந்த பொருட்கள் எதிர்வரும் நாட்களில் இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தினால் பயனாளிகளுக்கு விநியோகிக்கப்படும்.",
        "3. தமிழக அரசின் 40,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் அரிசி, 500 மெட்ரிக் டன் பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் மருந்துகளின் பெரிய உறுதிப்பாட்டின் கீழ் இது இரண்டாவது சரக்கு.",
        "4. இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு இந்தியாவின் முன்னோடியில்லாத பொருளாதார, நிதி மற்றும் மனிதாபிமான உதவி 2022 இல் 3.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களாக உள்ளது. மூன்று கடன் வரிகளுக்கு கூடுதலாக 1.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் மற்றும் சுமார் 2 பில்லியன் டாலர் அந்நிய செலாவணி ஆதரவு, இலங்கையின் பல்வேறு பகுதிகளில் உள்ள சுகாதாரம் தொடர்பான பல நிறுவனங்களுக்கு மருந்து விநியோகம், இலங்கை மீனவர்களுக்கு மண்ணெண்ணெய் விநியோகம், தேவைப்படும் பிரிவினருக்கு உலர் உணவுப் பொருட்களை வழங்குதல் போன்ற பல்வேறு வகைகளில் இந்திய அரசு மற்றும் மக்களிடமிருந்து உதவி வருகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டாவது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "மனிதாபிமான உதவி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பரிசு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "அரசு",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "24 ஜூன் 2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "14,700",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "250",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "38",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை ரூபாய்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பத்திரிக்கை செய்தி வெளியிடப்பட்டது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உயர் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 24, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோபால் பாக்லே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெஹலிய ரம்புக்வெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.ஏ சுமந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வி.ராதாகிருஷ்ணன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.உதய குமார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அங்கஜன் இராமந்தன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செந்தில் தொண்டமான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14,700",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 ஜூன் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD 3.5 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Second  Ship Carrying Humanitarian Aid  Donated  as a Gift  by the Govt and People of Tamil Nadu  arrived in Sri Lanka on 24 June 2022; Consignment  consisting of 14,700 MT of rice, 250 MT of milk powder and 38 MT of medicines is valued at more than  3 billion Sri Lankan Rupees",
  "body_lines": [
    "(Text of Press Release Issued by the High Commission of India in Colombo on June 24th 2022)",
    "High Commissioner Gopal Baglay, Hon’ble Keheliya Rambukwella, Minister of Health, Hon’ble Nalin Fernando, Minister of Trade, Hon’ble Members of Parliament namely M.A Sumanthiran,      V. Radhakrishnan, M. Udaya Kumar, Angajan Ramanthan, and several others including Senthil Thondaman welcomed a large humanitarian consignment consisting of 14,700 MT of rice, 250 MT of milk powder and 38 MT of medicines donated by the people of India in Colombo on 24 June 2022. The total value of this consignment is more than SLR 3 billion.",
    "2.     The large consignment of humanitarian supplies underscores abiding people to people bonds between India and Sri Lanka as also concerns of the people of India for the well-being of their brethren in Sri Lanka. These supplies shall be distributed among beneficiaries by Government of Sri Lanka in the coming days.",
    "3.      This is the second consignment under a larger commitment of 40,000 MT of rice, 500 MT of milk powder and medicines by Government of Tamil Nadu.",
    "4.      India’s unprecedented economic, financial and humanitarian assistance to the people of Sri Lanka stands at over USD 3.5 billion in 2022. In addition to the three credit lines to the tune of more than USD 1.5 billion and forex support of around USD 2 billion, assistance from the Government and people of India has taken the form of supply of medicines to several health-related establishments in various parts of Sri Lanka, distribution of kerosene among the fishermen of Sri Lanka, handing over of dry rations to needy sections etc."
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Second  Ship Carrying Humanitarian Aid  Donated  as a Gift  by the Govt and People of Tamil Nadu  arrived in Sri Lanka on 24 June 2022; Consignment  consisting of 14,700 MT of rice, 250 MT of milk powder and 38 MT of medicines is valued at more than  3 billion Sri Lankan Rupees",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "(Text of Press Release Issued by the High Commission of India in Colombo on June 24th 2022)",
        "High Commissioner Gopal Baglay, Hon’ble Keheliya Rambukwella, Minister of Health, Hon’ble Nalin Fernando, Minister of Trade, Hon’ble Members of Parliament namely M.A Sumanthiran,      V. Radhakrishnan, M. Udaya Kumar, Angajan Ramanthan, and several others including Senthil Thondaman welcomed a large humanitarian consignment consisting of 14,700 MT of rice, 250 MT of milk powder and 38 MT of medicines donated by the people of India in Colombo on 24 June 2022. The total value of this consignment is more than SLR 3 billion.",
        "2.     The large consignment of humanitarian supplies underscores abiding people to people bonds between India and Sri Lanka as also concerns of the people of India for the well-being of their brethren in Sri Lanka. These supplies shall be distributed among beneficiaries by Government of Sri Lanka in the coming days.",
        "3.      This is the second consignment under a larger commitment of 40,000 MT of rice, 500 MT of milk powder and medicines by Government of Tamil Nadu.",
        "4.      India’s unprecedented economic, financial and humanitarian assistance to the people of Sri Lanka stands at over USD 3.5 billion in 2022. In addition to the three credit lines to the tune of more than USD 1.5 billion and forex support of around USD 2 billion, assistance from the Government and people of India has taken the form of supply of medicines to several health-related establishments in various parts of Sri Lanka, distribution of kerosene among the fishermen of Sri Lanka, handing over of dry rations to needy sections etc."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Second",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Humanitarian Aid",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Gift",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Govt",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tamil Nadu",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "24 June 2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "14,700",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "250",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "38",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan Rupees",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Text of Press Release Issued",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 24th 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gopal Baglay",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Keheliya Rambukwella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "M.A Sumanthiran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "V. Radhakrishnan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "M. Udaya Kumar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Angajan Ramanthan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Senthil Thondaman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14,700",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 June 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coming days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Government of Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD 3.5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තමිල්නාඩු රජය සහ ජනතාව විසින් තෑග්ගක් ලෙස පරිත්‍යාග කරන ලද මානුෂීය ආධාර රැගත් දෙවන නෞකාව 2022 ජූනි 24 දින ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණියේය. සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 14,700 ක්, කිරිපිටි මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 250 ක් සහ ඖෂධ මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 38 කින් සමන්විත තොගයේ වටිනාකම ශ්‍රී ලංකා රුපියල් බිලියන 3 කට අධික වේ.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "(2022 ජුනි 24 වැනි දින කොළඹ පිහිටි ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය විසින් නිකුත් කරන ලද මාධ්‍ය නිවේදනයේ පාඨය)",
        "මහ කොමසාරිස් ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ, සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය ගරු කෙහෙළිය රඹුක්වැල්ල, ගරු නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු, වෙළඳ අමාත්‍ය, ගරු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන එම්. 2022 ජුනි 24 වැනි දින ඉන්දීය ජනතාව විසින් කොළඹදී පරිත්‍යාග කරන ලද සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 14,700 ක්, කිරිපිටි මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 250 ක් සහ ඖෂධ මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 38 කින් සමන්විත විශාල මානුෂීය තොගයක් සෙන්තිල් තොණ්ඩමන් මහතා ඇතුළු පිරිසක් විසින් පිළිගනු ලැබීය. මෙම තොගයේ මුළු වටිනාකම රුපියල් බිලියන 3 කට වඩා වැඩිය. .",
        "2. මානුෂීය සැපයුම් විශාල තොගයක් ඉන්දියාව සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර මිනිසුන්ට පවතින බැඳීම් මෙන්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිටින ඔවුන්ගේ සහෝදරයන්ගේ යහපැවැත්ම සඳහා ඉන්දියාවේ ජනතාවගේ සැලකිල්ල ද අවධාරණය කරයි. මෙම සැපයුම් ඉදිරි දිනවලදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය විසින් ප්‍රතිලාභීන් අතර බෙදා හරිනු ලැබේ.",
        "3. තමිල්නාඩු රජය විසින් සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 40,000 ක්, කිරිපිටි මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 500 ක් සහ ඖෂධ ලබා දීමේ විශාල කැපවීමක් යටතේ මෙය දෙවැනි තොගය වේ.",
        "4. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාව සඳහා ඉන්දියාවේ පෙර නොවූ විරූ ආර්ථික, මූල්‍ය සහ මානුෂීය ආධාර 2022 දී ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.5 ඉක්මවයි. ණය මාර්ග තුනට අමතරව ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.5 කට වඩා වැඩි අගයක් සහ ඩොලර් බිලියන 2 ක පමණ විදේශ විනිමය ආධාරයක්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විවිධ ප්‍රදේශවල සෞඛ්‍ය සම්බන්ධ ආයතන කිහිපයකට ඖෂධ සැපයීම, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ධීවරයින් අතර භූමිතෙල් බෙදා හැරීම, අවශ්‍යතා ඇති කොටස්වලට වියළි සලාක ලබා දීම යනාදී වශයෙන් ඉන්දීය රජයේ සහ ජනතාවගේ සහාය ලබාගෙන ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙවැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "මානුෂීය ආධාර",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "තෑගි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රජය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022 ජූනි 24",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "14,700 කි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "250",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "38",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රුපියල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නිකුත් කරන ලද මාධ්‍ය නිවේදනයේ පෙළ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ කොමසාරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූනි 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙහෙළිය රඹුක්වැල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම් ඒ සුමන්තිරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වී රාධක්‍රිෂ්ණන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම් උදය කුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අංගජන් රාමන්තන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙන්තිල් තොණ්ඩමන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14,700 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූනි 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩු රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.5 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தமிழ்நாட்டு அரசாங்கமும் மக்களும் அன்பளிப்பாக வழங்கிய மனிதாபிமான உதவிகளை ஏற்றிச் செல்லும் இரண்டாவது கப்பல் 24 ஜூன் 2022 அன்று இலங்கையை வந்தடைந்தது; 14,700 மெட்ரிக்தொன் அரிசி, 250 மெட்ரிக்தொன் பால் மா மற்றும் 38 மெட்ரிக்தொன் மருந்துகள் அடங்கிய சரக்கு 3 பில்லியன் இலங்கை ரூபாய்க்கு மேல் பெறுமதியானது.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "(ஜூன் 24, 2022 அன்று கொழும்பில் உள்ள இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயத்தால் வெளியிடப்பட்ட செய்திக்குறிப்பு உரை)",
        "உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் கோபால் பாக்லே, கௌரவ கெஹலிய ரம்புக்வெல்ல, சுகாதார அமைச்சர், கௌரவ நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ, வர்த்தக அமைச்சர், கௌரவ பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன், வி. ராதாகிருஷ்ணன், எம்.உதய குமார், அங்கஜன் இராமந்தன் மற்றும் பலர். செந்தில் தொண்டமான் உட்பட 14,700 மெட்ரிக் டன் அரிசி, 250 மெட்ரிக் டன் பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் 38 மெட்ரிக் டன் மருந்துகள் அடங்கிய பெரிய மனிதாபிமானப் பொருட்களை கொழும்பில் 24 ஜூன் 2022 அன்று கொழும்பில் நன்கொடையாக வழங்கினார். .",
        "2. பெருமளவிலான மனிதாபிமான பொருட்கள், இந்தியாவிற்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையில் மக்கள் பிணைப்பைக் கடைப்பிடிப்பதை அடிக்கோடிட்டுக் காட்டுகின்றன. இந்த பொருட்கள் எதிர்வரும் நாட்களில் இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தினால் பயனாளிகளுக்கு விநியோகிக்கப்படும்.",
        "3. தமிழக அரசின் 40,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் அரிசி, 500 மெட்ரிக் டன் பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் மருந்துகளின் பெரிய உறுதிப்பாட்டின் கீழ் இது இரண்டாவது சரக்கு.",
        "4. இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு இந்தியாவின் முன்னோடியில்லாத பொருளாதார, நிதி மற்றும் மனிதாபிமான உதவி 2022 இல் 3.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களாக உள்ளது. மூன்று கடன் வரிகளுக்கு கூடுதலாக 1.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் மற்றும் சுமார் 2 பில்லியன் டாலர் அந்நிய செலாவணி ஆதரவு, இலங்கையின் பல்வேறு பகுதிகளில் உள்ள சுகாதாரம் தொடர்பான பல நிறுவனங்களுக்கு மருந்து விநியோகம், இலங்கை மீனவர்களுக்கு மண்ணெண்ணெய் விநியோகம், தேவைப்படும் பிரிவினருக்கு உலர் உணவுப் பொருட்களை வழங்குதல் போன்ற பல்வேறு வகைகளில் இந்திய அரசு மற்றும் மக்களிடமிருந்து உதவி வருகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டாவது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "மனிதாபிமான உதவி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பரிசு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "அரசு",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "24 ஜூன் 2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "14,700",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "250",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "38",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை ரூபாய்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பத்திரிக்கை செய்தி வெளியிடப்பட்டது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உயர் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 24, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோபால் பாக்லே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெஹலிய ரம்புக்வெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.ஏ சுமந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வி.ராதாகிருஷ்ணன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.உதய குமார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அங்கஜன் இராமந்தன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செந்தில் தொண்டமான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14,700",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 ஜூன் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD 3.5 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}