{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/இலங்கை-அணியின்-2-வீரர்களுக்கு-கொரோனா-தொற்று/175-299880",
  "time_ut": 1657163773,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இலங்கை அணியின் 2 வீரர்களுக்கு கொரோனா தொற்று",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "2 players of the Sri Lankan team are infected with Corona",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "All-rounder Dhananjaya de Silva and spinner Geoffrey Wendersay have been affected by the Covid-19 infection.",
        "According to Sri Lanka Cricket, both of them will not participate in the second Test match against Australia which starts tomorrow in Galle.",
        "It is reported that spinners Prabhat Jayasuriya and Lakshan Chandaken have been called into the squad for those players.",
        "During the rabbit antigen test conducted yesterday, the said players were found to be infected with Covid. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "2",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Corona",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhananjaya de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Geoffrey Wendersay",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Cricket",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lakshan Chandaken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා කණ්ඩායමේ ක්‍රීඩකයින් දෙදෙනෙකුට කොරෝනා ආසාදනය වී තිබෙනවා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "තුන් ඉරියව් ක්‍රීඩක ධනංජය ද සිල්වා සහ දඟ පන්දු යවන ක්‍රීඩක ජෙෆ්රි වෙන්ඩර්සේ කොවිඩ් 19 ආසාදනයට ලක්ව තිබෙනවා.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් ආයතනය පවසන්නේ ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාව සමග හෙට ගාල්ලේදී ආරම්භ වන දෙවන ටෙස්ට් ක්‍රිකට් තරගයට ඔවුන් දෙදෙනා සහභාගී නොවන බවයි.",
        "එම ක්‍රීඩකයින් සඳහා දඟ පන්දු යවන්නන් වන ප්‍රභාත් ජයසූරිය සහ ලක්ෂාන් චන්දකේන් සංචිතයට කැදවා ඇති බවයි වාර්තා වන්නේ.",
        "ඊයේ සිදු කළ හාවා ප්‍රතිදේහජනක පරීක්ෂණයේදී එම ක්‍රීඩකයින්ට කොවිඩ් ආසාදනය වී ඇති බව අනාවරණය විය. (ඒ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "2",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "කොරෝනා",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ධනංජය ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෙෆ්රි වෙන්ඩර්සේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂාන් චන්දකේන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை அணியின் 2 வீரர்களுக்கு கொரோனா தொற்று",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "சகலதுறை வீரர் தனஞ்சய டி சில்வா, சுழற்பந்து வீச்சாளர் ஜெஃப்ரி வெண்டர்சே ஆகியோர் கொவிட்-19 தொற்றால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "அதன்படி நாளை காலியில் ஆரம்பமாகும் அவுஸ்திரேலியாவுக்கு எதிரான இரண்டாவது டெஸ்ட் போட்டியில் இவர்கள் இருவரும் இடம்பெறமாட்டார்களென ஸ்ரீலங்கா கிரிக்கெட் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அந்த வீரர்களுக்காக சுழற்பந்து வீச்சாளர்களான பிரபாத் ஜயசூரிய மற்றும் லக்ஷான் சந்தகென் ஆகியோர் குழாமிற்கு அழைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது.",
        "நேற்று நடத்தப்பட்ட ரெபிட் அண்டிஜென் சோதனையின் போது குறித்த வீரர்கள் கொவிட் தொற்றுக்கு உள்ளாகி இருப்பது கண்டறியப்பட்டது. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "2",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "கொரோனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தனஞ்சய டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெஃப்ரி வெண்டர்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கிரிக்கெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லக்ஷன் சந்தகென்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}