{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84396/jaishankar-says-india-has-done-its-best-to-assist-sri-lanka",
  "time_ut": 1660893300,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Jaishankar says India has done its best to assist Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Jaishankar says India has done its best to assist Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "External Affairs Minister Dr. S. Jaishankar said on Thursday that the relationship between India and China is going through an “extremely difficult phase” after what Beijing has done at the border and emphasized that the Asian Century will not happen if the two neighbours could not join hands.",
        "Jaishankar made the remarks while responding to a series of questions after delivering a lecture on ‘India’s Vision of the Indo-Pacific’ at the prestigious Chulalongkorn University here.",
        "Responding to a question, Jaishankar said that the Asian Century will happen when China and India come together but the Asian Century will be difficult to happen if India and China could not come together.",
        "“At the moment (the India-China) relationship is going through an extremely difficult phase after what China did at the border,” he said.",
        "Chinese and Indian troops are engaged in a prolonged standoff in Eastern Ladakh. The two sides have so far held 16 rounds of Corps Commander Level talks to resolve the standoff which erupted on May 5, 2020, following a violent clash in the Pangong lake areas.",
        "“I think if India and China have to come together, there are many reasons to do so, not necessarily only Sri Lanka,” he said, adding that it is in India and China’s own interest to join hands.",
        "“We very much hope that wisdom dawns on the Chinese side,” he said while replying to another question from the audience.",
        "Jaishankar said India has done the best of its abilities to assist Sri Lanka. This year alone India has extended USD 3.8 billion of support to Sri Lanka, including line of credits and swap arrangements, he said.",
        "Sri Lanka, a nation of 22 million, is in the midst of an unprecedented economic crisis that has led to severe shortages of fuel and other essentials. The Sri Lankan government is negotiating with the IMF for a bailout package.",
        "“Any help we can give to Sri Lanka at the IMF that we will naturally do,” Jaishankar said.",
        "On the issue of Rohingya refugees, he said the issue has been discussed with Bangladesh. “What matters for them is repatriation. We have been supportive of Bangladesh,” he said.",
        "Currently, Bangladesh is hosting more than 1 million Rohingya refugees, who fled Myanmar following a military operation against them a few years ago.",
        "Responding to another question, Jaishankar dismissed criticism for importing discounted Russian oil, saying India is not the only oil importing country.",
        "The US and European nations have imposed heavy sanctions on Russia since Moscow sent troops into Ukraine on February 24.",
        "India has raised oil imports from Russia after the Ukraine war despite criticism from the west and continues to engage with Moscow for business.",
        "Jaishankar, who arrived here on Tuesday, co-chaired the 9th India-Thailand Joint Commission Meeting with his Thai counterpart and Deputy Prime Minister Don Pramudwinai on Wednesday during which they discussed advancing bilateral contacts in political, economic, security and defence, connectivity and health domains."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Jaishankar",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "S. Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Asian Century",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chulalongkorn University",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Asian Century",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Asian Century",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eastern Ladakh",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 5, 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pangong",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaishankar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "This year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rohingya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 1 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rohingya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Myanmar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a few years ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "European",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "February 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India-Thailand Joint Commission Meeting",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thai",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Don Pramudwinai",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජයිශංකර් පවසන්නේ ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට උපරිම සහය ලබා දී ඇති බවයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය ආචාර්ය එස්. ජයශංකර් බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ඉන්දියාව සහ චීනය අතර සම්බන්ධතාවය “අතිශයින්ම දුෂ්කර අවධියක්” හරහා ගමන් කරමින් සිටින බවත්, බීජිං දේශසීමාවේ සිදු කර ඇති දේවලින් පසුව බවත් අසල්වැසියන් දෙදෙනාට නොහැකි නම් ආසියානු සියවස සිදු නොවන බවත් අවධාරණය කළේය. අත්වැල් බැඳගන්න.",
        "ජයිශංකර් මේ බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේ කීර්තිමත් Chulalongkorn විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේදී ‘ඉන්දියානු පැසිෆික් කලාපයේ ඉන්දියාවේ දැක්ම’ පිළිබඳ දේශනයක් පැවැත්වීමෙන් අනතුරුව ප්‍රශ්න මාලාවකට පිළිතුරු දෙමිනි.",
        "ප්‍රශ්නයකට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් ජයිශංකර් කියා සිටියේ චීනය සහ ඉන්දියාව එකතු වූ විට ආසියානු සියවස සිදුවනු ඇති නමුත් ඉන්දියාව සහ චීනය එක්වීමට නොහැකි වුවහොත් ආසියානු සියවස සිදුවීම දුෂ්කර වනු ඇති බවයි.",
        "\"මේ මොහොතේ (ඉන්දියා-චීන) සම්බන්ධතාවය චීනය දේශසීමාවේ කළ දේවලින් පසු අතිශය දුෂ්කර අවධියක් හරහා ගමන් කරයි,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "චීන සහ ඉන්දීය හමුදා නැගෙනහිර ලඩාක් ප්‍රදේශයේ දීර්ඝ කාලීන ගැටුමක නිරතව සිටිති. 2020 මැයි 5 වන දින පැන්ගොං වැව් ප්‍රදේශයේ ඇති වූ ප්‍රචණ්ඩ ගැටුමකින් පසුව ඇති වූ ගැටුම විසඳීම සඳහා දෙපාර්ශ්වය මේ වන විට බලකා අණදෙන නිලධාරී මට්ටමේ සාකච්ඡා වට 16 ක් පවත්වා ඇත.",
        "\"මම හිතන්නේ ඉන්දියාව සහ චීනය එකට එකතු විය යුතු නම්, එසේ කිරීමට බොහෝ හේතු තිබේ, අවශ්‍යයෙන්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පමණක් නොවේ,\" ඔහු කියා සිටියේ අත්වැල් බැඳ ගැනීම ඉන්දියාවට සහ චීනයට අවශ්‍ය බවයි.",
        "ප්‍රේක්ෂකාගාරයේ තවත් ප්‍රශ්නයකට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් ඔහු පැවසුවේ “චීන පාර්ශ්වයෙන් ප්‍රඥාව උදාවේවායි අපි ඉතා බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා.",
        "ජයිශංකර් පැවසුවේ ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහය වීමට උපරිමයෙන් කටයුතු කර ඇති බවයි. මෙම වසරේ පමණක් ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ණය සහ හුවමාරු විධිවිධාන ඇතුළුව ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.8 ක ආධාර ලබා දී ඇති බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මිලියන 22 ක ජාතියක් වන ශ්‍රී ලංකාව, ඉන්ධන සහ අනෙකුත් අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍යවල උග්‍ර හිඟයකට තුඩු දී ඇති පෙර නොවූ විරූ ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකට මැදිව සිටී. ඇපදීමේ පැකේජයක් සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය IMF සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කරමින් සිටී.",
        "\"ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබා දිය හැකි ඕනෑම උදව්වක් අපි ස්වභාවිකවම කරන්නෙමු\" යැයි ජයශංකර් පැවසීය.",
        "රොහින්ග්‍යා සරණාගතයින්ගේ ප්‍රශ්නය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඔහු කියා සිටියේ මෙම ගැටලුව බංග්ලාදේශය සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කර ඇති බවයි. “ඔවුන්ට වැදගත් වන්නේ නැවත ගෙන්වා ගැනීමයි. අපි බංගලාදේශයට සහයෝගය ලබා දුන්නා,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "දැනට වසර කිහිපයකට පෙර ඔවුන්ට එරෙහි හමුදා මෙහෙයුමකින් මියන්මාරයෙන් පලා ගිය මිලියනයකට අධික රෝහින්ග්‍යා සරණාගතයින් සංඛ්‍යාවකට බංග්ලාදේශය සත්කාරකත්වය සපයනු ලබයි.",
        "තවත් ප්‍රශ්නයකට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් ජයිශංකර්, වට්ටම් සහිත රුසියානු තෙල් ආනයනය කිරීම පිළිබඳ විවේචන ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරමින්, තෙල් ආනයනය කරන එකම රට ඉන්දියාව නොවන බව පැවසීය.",
        "පෙබරවාරි 24 වන දින මොස්කව් විසින් යුක්රේනයට හමුදා යැවීමෙන් පසු එක්සත් ජනපදය සහ යුරෝපීය රටවල් රුසියාවට දැඩි සම්බාධක පනවා ඇත.",
        "යුක්රේන යුද්ධයෙන් පසු ඉන්දියාව බටහිරින් විවේචන නොතකා රුසියාවෙන් තෙල් ආනයනය ඉහළ නංවා ඇති අතර ව්‍යාපාර සඳහා මොස්කව් සමඟ දිගටම සම්බන්ධ වේ.",
        "අඟහරුවාදා මෙහි පැමිණි ජයිශංකර්, බදාදා ඔහුගේ තායි සහකරු සහ නියෝජ්‍ය අගමැති දොන් ප්‍රමුද්විනායි සමඟ 9 වැනි ඉන්දියා-තායිලන්ත ඒකාබද්ධ කොමිෂන් සභා රැස්වීමේ සම සභාපතිත්වය දැරූ අතර, එහිදී ඔවුන් දේශපාලන, ආර්ථික, ආරක්ෂාව සහ ආරක්ෂක, සම්බන්ධතා සහ සෞඛ්‍ය යන ක්ෂේත්‍රවල ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සම්බන්ධතා ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාම පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කළහ. වසම්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජයශංකර්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්. ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු සියවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chulalongkorn විශ්ව විද්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු සියවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු සියවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර ලඩාක්",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020 මැයි 5",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැන්ගොං",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 22 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොහින්ග්‍යා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1 කට වඩා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොහින්ග්‍යා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මියන්මාරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර කිහිපයකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙබරවාරි 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියා-තායිලන්ත ඒකාබද්ධ කොමිෂන් සභා රැස්වීම",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දොන් ප්‍රමුද්විනයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கைக்கு இந்தியா தன்னால் முடிந்த உதவிகளை செய்துள்ளதாக ஜெய்சங்கர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பெய்ஜிங் எல்லையில் செய்ததைத் தொடர்ந்து, இந்தியாவுக்கும் சீனாவுக்கும் இடையிலான உறவு மிகவும் கடினமான கட்டத்தை கடந்து வருவதாகவும், இரு அண்டை நாடுகளும் முடியாவிட்டால் ஆசிய நூற்றாண்டு நடக்காது என்றும் வெளியுறவுத்துறை அமைச்சர் டாக்டர் எஸ். ஜெய்சங்கர் வியாழக்கிழமை தெரிவித்தார். கைகளை இணைக்கவும்.",
        "இங்குள்ள புகழ்பெற்ற Chulalongkorn பல்கலைக்கழகத்தில் 'இந்தோ-பசிபிக் இந்தியாவின் பார்வை' என்ற தலைப்பில் விரிவுரை ஆற்றிய பின்னர் தொடர்ச்சியான கேள்விகளுக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் போது ஜெய்சங்கர் இந்த கருத்துக்களை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஒரு கேள்விக்கு பதிலளித்த ஜெய்சங்கர், சீனாவும் இந்தியாவும் இணைந்தால் ஆசிய நூற்றாண்டு நடக்கும், ஆனால் இந்தியாவும் சீனாவும் ஒன்றிணைய முடியாவிட்டால் ஆசிய நூற்றாண்டு நடப்பது கடினம் என்று கூறினார்.",
        "எல்லையில் சீனா செய்ததற்குப் பிறகு தற்போது (இந்தியா-சீனா) உறவு மிகவும் கடினமான கட்டத்தில் உள்ளது,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "கிழக்கு லடாக்கில் சீன மற்றும் இந்திய துருப்புக்கள் நீடித்த மோதலில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளன. மே 5, 2020 அன்று பாங்காங் ஏரி பகுதிகளில் ஏற்பட்ட வன்முறை மோதலைத் தொடர்ந்து வெடித்த மோதலைத் தீர்க்க இரு தரப்பினரும் இதுவரை 16 சுற்று கார்ப்ஸ் கமாண்டர் நிலை பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை நடத்தியுள்ளனர்.",
        "\"இந்தியாவும் சீனாவும் ஒன்று சேர வேண்டுமானால், அவ்வாறு செய்வதற்கு பல காரணங்கள் உள்ளன, இலங்கை மட்டும் அவசியமில்லை,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார், இந்தியா மற்றும் சீனாவின் சொந்த நலன் கைகோர்க்க வேண்டும் என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "பார்வையாளர்களின் மற்றொரு கேள்விக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் போது, ​​\"சீன தரப்பில் ஞானம் உதயமாகும் என்று நாங்கள் மிகவும் நம்புகிறோம்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "ஜெய்சங்கர், இலங்கைக்கு உதவ இந்தியா தனது திறமைகளை சிறப்பாகச் செய்துள்ளது என்றார். இந்த ஆண்டு மட்டும் இந்தியா இலங்கைக்கு 3.8 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் ஆதரவை வழங்கியுள்ளது, இதில் கடன்கள் மற்றும் இடமாற்று ஏற்பாடுகள் உள்ளன.",
        "22 மில்லியன் மக்களைக் கொண்ட இலங்கை, முன்னெப்போதும் இல்லாத பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு மத்தியில், எரிபொருள் மற்றும் ஏனைய அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களுக்கு கடும் தட்டுப்பாடு ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது. பிணை எடுப்புப் பொதிக்காக இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தி வருகிறது.",
        "\"IMF இல் இலங்கைக்கு நாம் எந்த உதவியையும் செய்ய முடியும், அதை நாங்கள் இயல்பாகவே செய்வோம்\" என்று ஜெய்சங்கர் கூறினார்.",
        "ரோஹிங்கியா அகதிகள் விவகாரம் குறித்து, வங்கதேசத்துடன் பேசப்பட்டதாக அவர் கூறினார். \"அவர்களுக்கு முக்கியமானது நாடு திரும்புவது. நாங்கள் பங்களாதேஷுக்கு ஆதரவாக இருந்தோம்,” என்றார்.",
        "தற்போது, ​​பங்களாதேஷ் 1 மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான ரோஹிங்கியா அகதிகளுக்கு விருந்தளித்து வருகிறது, அவர்கள் சில ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு அவர்களுக்கு எதிரான இராணுவ நடவடிக்கையைத் தொடர்ந்து மியான்மரை விட்டு வெளியேறினர்.",
        "மற்றொரு கேள்விக்கு பதிலளித்த ஜெய்சங்கர், தள்ளுபடி செய்யப்பட்ட ரஷ்ய எண்ணெயை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்கான விமர்சனங்களை நிராகரித்தார், இந்தியா மட்டும் எண்ணெய் இறக்குமதி செய்யும் நாடு அல்ல என்றார்.",
        "பிப்ரவரி 24 அன்று மாஸ்கோ உக்ரைனுக்குள் துருப்புக்களை அனுப்பியதிலிருந்து அமெரிக்கா மற்றும் ஐரோப்பிய நாடுகள் ரஷ்யா மீது கடுமையான பொருளாதாரத் தடைகளை விதித்தன.",
        "உக்ரைன் போருக்குப் பிறகு, மேற்கு நாடுகளின் விமர்சனங்களை மீறி இந்தியா ரஷ்யாவிலிருந்து எண்ணெய் இறக்குமதியை உயர்த்தியுள்ளது மற்றும் வணிகத்திற்காக மாஸ்கோவுடன் தொடர்ந்து ஈடுபடுகிறது.",
        "செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை இங்கு வந்த ஜெய்சங்கர், 9வது இந்தியா-தாய்லாந்து கூட்டுக் கமிஷன் கூட்டத்திற்குத் தலைமை தாங்கினார், புதன்கிழமை தனது தாய்லாந்து துணைப் பிரதமரும் துணைப் பிரதமருமான டான் பிரமுத்வினாய் அவர்கள் அரசியல், பொருளாதாரம், பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் பாதுகாப்பு, இணைப்பு மற்றும் சுகாதாரம் ஆகியவற்றில் இருதரப்பு தொடர்புகளை மேம்படுத்துவது குறித்து விவாதித்தனர். களங்கள்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜெய்சங்கர்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ். ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய நூற்றாண்டு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுலாலோங்கோர்ன் பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய நூற்றாண்டு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய நூற்றாண்டு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு லடாக்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 5, 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாங்காங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரோஹிங்கியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமாக",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோஹிங்கியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மியான்மர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு சில ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிப்ரவரி 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா - தாய்லாந்து கூட்டு கமிஷன் கூட்டம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "டான் பிரமுத்வினை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}