{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132140",
  "time_ut": 1658650193,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "யாழில் இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் ஊழியர்கள் பணிப்பகிஷ்கரிப்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lankan Transport Board employees sacked in Yali",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Sri Lankan Transport Board's Jaffna road workers went on strike on Sunday 24th.",
        "Last Friday around 9 pm, both the driver and the guard of the 57-route ECO bus from Jaffna to Colombo were attacked by the Kalkamuwa Road ECO road workers in Thaladagama area.",
        "They strongly condemned the attack and demanded that appropriate action be taken against the employees who carried out the attack."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan Transport Board",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yali",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Sri Lankan Transport Board's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday 24th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Last Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "57",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kalkamuwa Road",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thaladagama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයේ සේවකයින් යාලියේදී නෙරපා හරියි",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයේ යාපනය මාර්ග සේවකයින් 24 ඉරිදා වැඩ වර්ජනයක නිරත විය.",
        "පසුගිය සිකුරාදා රාත්‍රී 9 ට පමණ යාපනයේ සිට කොළඹ බලා ධාවනය වූ මාර්ග 57 ECO බස් රථයේ රියදුරුට සහ මුරකරුට තලදාගම ප්‍රදේශයේදී කල්කමූව පාර ECO මාර්ග සේවකයන්ගේ ප්‍රහාරයක් එල්ල විය.",
        "ඔවුන් මෙම ප්‍රහාරය දැඩි ලෙස හෙළා දකින අතර ප්‍රහාරය සිදුකළ සේවකයන්ට එරෙහිව නිසි ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගන්නා ලෙසද ඔවුන් ඉල්ලා සිටියා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "යාලි",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප.ව.9",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "57",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කල්කමුව පාර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලදාගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "யாழில் இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் ஊழியர்கள் பணிப்பகிஷ்கரிப்பு",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் யாழ் சாலை ஊழியர்கள் 24 ஆம் திகதி ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை பணிப்பகிஷ்கரிப்பில் ஈடுபட்டனர்.",
        "கடந்த வெள்ளிக்கிழமை இரவு 9 மணியளவில் யாழ்ப்பாணத்தில் இருந்து கொழும்பு நோக்கி பெறப்பட்ட 57 வழித்தட இ.போ.ச பேருந்தின் சாரதி மற்றும் காப்பாளர் இருவரும் கல்கமுவ சாலை இ.போ.ச சாலை ஊழியர்களினால் தலாதகம பகுதியில் தாக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "தாக்குதல் சம்பவத்தை மிகவும் வன்மையாக கண்டித்தும், தாக்குதலை நடாத்திய ஊழியர்களுக்கு எதிராக உரிய நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என கோரியே போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "யாளி",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வெள்ளிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு 9 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "57",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்கமுவ வீதி",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலடகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}