{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Finnish-PM-Sanna-Marin-facing-backlash-over-leaked-party-footage/108-243357",
  "time_ut": 1660895374,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Finnish PM Sanna Marin facing backlash over leaked party footage",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Finnish PM Sanna Marin facing backlash over leaked party footage",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Finnish Prime Minister Sanna Marin is facing a political backlash after video footage of her partying with fellow politicians and celebrities was leaked online.",
        "The footage, published on social media on Wednesday, shows Marin and five other people dancing and singing in what appears to be a gathering held at a private home. At one point, Marin, 36, is seen on her knees with her arms behind her head, dancing and mimicking a song.",
        "According to Finnish media reports, one of the other partygoers can seemingly be heard in the background shouting “jauhojengi”, which means “flour gang” in Finnish and is also slang for cocaine.",
        "It wasn’t immediately clear when the party – which was reportedly also attended by Ilmari Nurminen, a member of parliament for the prime minister’s Social Democratic Party, and Finnish singer Alma – was held.",
        "But the footage has prompted calls from Marin’s political opponents for her to take a voluntary drug test, with opposition party leader Riikka Purra saying there was a “shadow of doubt” hanging over the prime minister.",
        "Marin on Thursday denied taking any drugs during what she described as the “wild” party in a private home and contested the perceived use of the term “jauhojengi”.",
        "“I have not used drugs myself, or anything other than alcohol. I’ve danced, sung and partied and done perfectly legal things,” the Finnish leader told reporters, adding that she was “disappointed” that footage of the party had become public.",
        "Marin – who in December 2019 became Finland’s youngest prime minister ever – also said she would not change in the wake of the controversy, saying she intends to continue to be the same person as before.",
        "“I have a family life, I have a work life and I have free time to spend with my friends. Pretty much the same as many people my age,” she said. “I am going to be exactly the same person as I have been until now and I hope that it will be accepted.”",
        "This week’s developments came after Marin was forced to issue a public apology at the end of last year for going out clubbing after coming into close contact with a COVID-19-positive individual.",
        "The Finnish prime minister said at the time that she had missed a message telling her to isolate because she had left her work phone at home. She did not test positive for the virus.",
        "Marin, who is open about her penchant for partying and has often been photographed at music festivals, was dubbed the “coolest politican in the world” by German news outlet Bild last week.(AL JAZEERA)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Finnish",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sanna Marin",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Finnish",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanna Marin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marin",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marin",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "36",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Finnish",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finnish",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ilmari Nurminen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Social Democratic Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finnish",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Marin",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Riikka Purra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Marin",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Finnish",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Marin",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "December 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finland",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "This week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marin",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Finnish",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Marin",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "German",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bild",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "week.(AL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JAZEERA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ෆින්ලන්ත අගමැති සන්නා මැරින් සාදයේ දර්ශන කාන්දු වීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් පසුබෑමට ලක් වේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ෆින්ලන්ත අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය සන්නා මැරින් සිය සහෝදර දේශපාලනඥයන් සහ ප්‍රසිද්ධ පුද්ගලයින් සමඟ සාදයක ​​යෙදෙන වීඩියෝ දර්ශන අන්තර්ජාලයට කාන්දු වීමත් සමඟ දේශපාලන පසුබෑමකට ලක්ව තිබේ.",
        "බදාදා සමාජ මාධ්‍යවල ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද මෙම දර්ශන, පුද්ගලික නිවසක පැවති රැස්වීමක් ලෙස පෙනෙන දෙයක මාරින් සහ තවත් පස් දෙනෙකු නටමින් සහ ගායනා කරන ආකාරය පෙන්නුම් කරයි. එක් අවස්ථාවක, 36 හැවිරිදි Marin, ඇගේ දෑත් හිස පිටුපසට තබා, නටමින් සහ ගීතයක් අනුකරණය කරමින් සිටිනු දක්නට ලැබේ.",
        "ෆින්ලන්ත මාධ්‍ය වාර්තාවලට අනුව, අනෙකුත් සාදයට සහභාගිවන්නන්ගෙන් එක් අයෙකු පසුබිමේ කෑගසනු ඇසෙන්නේ “ජවුහෝජෙන්ගි”, එනම් ෆින්ලන්ත භාෂාවෙන් “පිටි කල්ලිය” වන අතර එය කොකේන් සඳහා ද භාවිතා වේ.",
        "අගමැතිගේ සමාජ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී පක්ෂයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඉල්මාරි නුර්මිනන් සහ ෆින්ලන්ත ගායිකා අල්මා ද සහභාගී වූ බව වාර්තා වන සාදය කවදා පැවැත්විණිද යන්න වහාම පැහැදිලි නොවීය.",
        "නමුත් මෙම දර්ශන මාරින්ගේ දේශපාලන විරුද්ධවාදීන්ගෙන් ඇයට ස්වේච්ඡා මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය පරීක්‍ෂණයක් කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා ඇති අතර, විරුද්ධ පක්ෂ නායිකා රීක්කා පුරා කියා සිටියේ අගමැති මත “සැකයේ සෙවනැල්ලක්” එල්ලී ඇති බවයි.",
        "මාරින් බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා පුද්ගලික නිවසක \"වල්\" සාදයක් ලෙස විස්තර කරන අතරතුර කිසිදු මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය ගැනීමක් ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළ අතර \"jauhojengi\" යන යෙදුම භාවිතා කිරීමට විරුද්ධ විය.",
        "“මම මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය හෝ මත්පැන් හැර වෙනත් කිසිවක් භාවිතා කර නැත. මම නැටුවා, ගායනා කළා, සාදයක් කරලා, සම්පූර්ණ නීත්‍යානුකූල දේවල් කරලා තියෙනවා,” ෆින්ලන්ත නායිකාව වාර්තාකරුවන්ට පැවසූ අතර, සාදයේ දර්ශන ප්‍රසිද්ධියට පත්වීම ගැන ඇය “කලකිරීමට” පත් වූ බව පැවසුවාය.",
        "2019 දෙසැම්බරයේ දී ෆින්ලන්තයේ ලාබාලතම අගමැති බවට පත් වූ Marin - මතභේදයෙන් පසුව ඇය වෙනස් නොවන බව ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇති අතර, ඇය පෙර පරිදිම එකම පුද්ගලයා ලෙස සිටීමට අදහස් කරන බව පවසමින්.",
        "“මට පවුල් ජීවිතයක් තියෙනවා, මට රැකියා ජීවිතයක් තියෙනවා, මට මගේ මිතුරන් සමඟ ගත කිරීමට නිදහස් කාලයක් තිබෙනවා. මගේ වයසේ බොහෝ මිනිසුන්ට බොහෝ දුරට සමානයි, ”ඇය පැවසුවාය. \"මම මේ දක්වා සිටි ආකාරයටම එකම පුද්ගලයා වීමට යන අතර එය පිළිගනු ඇතැයි මම බලාපොරොත්තු වෙමි.\"",
        "මෙම සතියේ වර්ධනයන් සිදු වූයේ COVID-19-ධනාත්මක පුද්ගලයෙකු සමඟ සමීප සම්බන්ධතා පැවැත්වීමෙන් පසු සමාජ ශාලාවලට යාම සම්බන්ධයෙන් පසුගිය වසර අවසානයේදී ප්‍රසිද්ධියේ සමාව ඉල්ලීමට Marin ට බල කිරීමෙන් පසුවය.",
        "ෆින්ලන්ත අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරිය එම අවස්ථාවේදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ඇය තම වැඩ කරන දුරකථනය නිවසේ තබා ඇති නිසා ඇයට හුදෙකලා වන ලෙස පණිවිඩයක් මග හැරී ඇති බවයි. ඇය වෛරසය සඳහා ධනාත්මක පරීක්ෂණයක් නොකළේය.",
        "සාද සඳහා ඇයගේ දැඩි ආශාව ගැන විවෘතව සිටින සහ බොහෝ විට සංගීත උත්සවවලදී ඡායාරූප ගත කර ඇති මාරින් පසුගිය සතියේ ජර්මානු ප්‍රවෘත්ති ආයතනයක් වන Bild විසින් \"ලෝකයේ සිසිල්ම දේශපාලනඥයා\" ලෙස නම් කරන ලදී.(AL JAZEERA)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ෆින්ලන්ත",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "සනා මැරින්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆින්ලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සනා මැරින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැරින්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැරින්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "36",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆින්ලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆින්ලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉල්මාරි නූර්මිනන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාජ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆින්ලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල්මා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැරින්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රීක්කා පුර්රා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැරින්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆින්ලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැරින්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙසැම්බර් 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆින්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැරින්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසරේ අවසානය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆින්ලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැරින්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිල්ඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිය.(AL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජසීරා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஃபின்லாந்து பிரதமர் சன்னா மரின் கட்சி காட்சிகள் கசிந்ததால் பின்னடைவை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஃபின்லாந்து பிரதமர் சன்னா மரின் சக அரசியல்வாதிகள் மற்றும் பிரபலங்களுடன் பார்ட்டியில் ஈடுபடும் வீடியோ காட்சிகள் இணையத்தில் கசிந்ததையடுத்து அவருக்கு அரசியல் பின்னடைவு ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "புதன்கிழமை சமூக ஊடகங்களில் வெளியிடப்பட்ட காட்சிகள், மரின் மற்றும் ஐந்து பேர் நடனமாடுவதையும் பாடுவதையும் ஒரு தனியார் வீட்டில் நடத்துவதைக் காட்டுகிறது. ஒரு கட்டத்தில், 36 வயதான மரின், முழங்காலில் தலைக்கு பின்னால் கைகளை வைத்து, நடனமாடுவது மற்றும் ஒரு பாடலைப் பின்பற்றுவது போன்றது.",
        "ஃபின்னிஷ் ஊடக அறிக்கைகளின்படி, மற்ற கட்சிக்காரர்களில் ஒருவர் பின்னணியில் \"ஜௌஹோஜெங்கி\" என்று கத்துவதைக் கேட்கலாம், இது ஃபின்னிஷ் மொழியில் \"மாவு கும்பல்\" என்று பொருள்படும் மற்றும் கோகோயின் ஸ்லாங்காகும்.",
        "பிரதம மந்திரியின் சமூக ஜனநாயகக் கட்சியின் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் இல்மரி நூர்மினென் மற்றும் ஃபின்னிஷ் பாடகி அல்மா ஆகியோரும் கலந்து கொண்டதாகக் கூறப்படும் இந்த விருந்து எப்போது நடைபெற்றது என்பது உடனடியாகத் தெரியவில்லை.",
        "ஆனால் இந்த காட்சிகள், மாரினின் அரசியல் எதிரிகளிடமிருந்து அவர் தன்னார்வ போதைப்பொருள் பரிசோதனைக்கு அழைப்பு விடுக்கத் தூண்டியது, எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் ரிக்கா புர்ரா, பிரதமர் மீது \"சந்தேகத்தின் நிழல்\" இருப்பதாகக் கூறினார்.",
        "மரின் வியாழன் அன்று ஒரு தனியார் வீட்டில் \"காட்டு\" விருந்து என்று விவரித்த போது எந்த மருந்துகளையும் உட்கொண்டதை மறுத்தார், மேலும் \"ஜௌஹோஜெங்கி\" என்ற சொல்லைப் பயன்படுத்துவதை எதிர்த்துப் போராடினார்.",
        "“நான் போதைப்பொருளையோ, மதுவைத் தவிர வேறு எதையும் பயன்படுத்தவில்லை. நான் நடனமாடினேன், பாடினேன், பார்ட்டி செய்தேன், சட்டப்படியான விஷயங்களைச் செய்திருக்கிறேன்,\" என்று ஃபின்னிஷ் தலைவர் செய்தியாளர்களிடம் கூறினார், விருந்தின் காட்சிகள் பகிரங்கமாகிவிட்டதால் தான் \"ஏமாற்றம்\" என்று கூறினார்.",
        "மரின் - டிசம்பர் 2019 இல் பின்லாந்தின் இளைய பிரதமராக ஆனார் - மேலும் சர்ச்சையின் பின்னணியில் தான் மாறப்போவதில்லை என்றும், முன்பு இருந்த அதே நபராகத் தொடர விரும்புவதாகக் கூறினார்.",
        "\"எனக்கு ஒரு குடும்ப வாழ்க்கை உள்ளது, எனக்கு ஒரு வேலை வாழ்க்கை உள்ளது மற்றும் எனது நண்பர்களுடன் செலவிட எனக்கு இலவச நேரம் உள்ளது. என் வயதுடைய பலரைப் போலவே, \"என்று அவர் கூறினார். \"நான் இப்போது வரை இருந்த அதே நபராக இருக்கப் போகிறேன், அது ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்படும் என்று நம்புகிறேன்.\"",
        "COVID-19-பாசிட்டிவ் தனிநபருடன் நெருங்கிய தொடர்புக்கு வந்த பிறகு, கிளப்பிங்கிற்குச் சென்றதற்காக கடந்த ஆண்டு இறுதியில் மரின் பகிரங்க மன்னிப்பு கேட்க வேண்டிய கட்டாயத்திற்குப் பிறகு இந்த வார முன்னேற்றங்கள் வந்தன.",
        "அந்த நேரத்தில் ஃபின்லாந்தின் பிரதம மந்திரி, அவர் தனது பணியிட தொலைபேசியை வீட்டில் விட்டுச் சென்றதால், தன்னை தனிமைப்படுத்தச் சொல்லும் செய்தியைத் தவறவிட்டதாகக் கூறினார். அவளுக்கு வைரஸுக்கு நேர்மறை சோதனை இல்லை.",
        "பார்ட்டிகளில் தனது ஆர்வத்தைப் பற்றி வெளிப்படையாகக் கூறும் மரின், இசை விழாக்களில் அடிக்கடி புகைப்படம் எடுத்தவர், கடந்த வாரம் ஜெர்மன் செய்தி நிறுவனமான பில்டால் \"உலகின் சிறந்த அரசியல்வாதி\" என்று அழைக்கப்பட்டார்.(அல் ஜசீரா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஃபின்னிஷ்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "சன்னா மரின்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃபின்னிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சன்னா மரின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மரின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மரின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "36",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃபின்னிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபின்னிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இல்மரி நூர்மினென்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமூக ஜனநாயகக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபின்னிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அல்மா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மரின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிக்கா புர்ரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மரின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃபின்னிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மரின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிசம்பர் 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பின்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மரின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃபின்னிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மரின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பில்ட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரம்.(AL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜசீரா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}