{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Cases-against-Gota-should-resume-after-his-return-JVP/342-242029",
  "time_ut": 1659086432,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Cases against Gota should resume after his return: JVP",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Cases against Gota should resume after his return: JVP",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The cases which were filed against former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa should resume soon after he returned to the country as his presidential immunity is no longer intact, Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna (JVP) MP Vijitha Herath said today.",
        "He told a news conference that Gotabaya Rajapaksa has the right to come to the country as a civilian because he is a Sri Lankan citizen. \"However, he is no longer the President of the country neither has the presidential immunity. Cases against him should be heard and law should be implemented against him,\" he said.",
        "MP Herath said the government should stop its cowardice actions to suppress and witch-hunt the peaceful protesters.",
        "\"The struggle can only be stopped by resolving fuel, gas, fertilizer and medicine shortages faced by the people. It can never be stopped through suppression or intimidation. More and more people will come forward against suppression and it will only worsen political crisis. When the political crisis aggravates, solutions to the economic crisis would also delay,\" he said.(Ajith Siriwardana)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gota",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "JVP",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vijitha Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "said.(Ajith Siriwardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගෝඨාට එරෙහි නඩු ආවට පස්සේ ආයෙත් පටන් ගත යුතුයි – ජ.වි.පෙ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා මෙරටට පැමිණි පසු ඔහුට එරෙහිව පවරා ඇති නඩු කඩිනමින් යළි ආරම්භ කළ යුතු බව ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී විජිත හේරත් මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ප්‍රවෘත්ති සාකච්ඡාවකදී ඔහු කියා සිටියේ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ශ්‍රී ලාංකික පුරවැසියෙකු නිසා සිවිල් වැසියෙකු ලෙස මෙරටට පැමිණීමට අයිතියක් ඇති බවයි. \"කෙසේ වෙතත්, ඔහු තවදුරටත් රටේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා නොවේ, ජනාධිපති මුක්තියද නැත, ඔහුට එරෙහි නඩු විභාග කර ඔහුට එරෙහිව නීතිය ක්‍රියාත්මක කළ යුතුය,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "හේරත් මන්ත්‍රීවරයා පැවසුවේ සාමකාමී විරෝධතාකරුවන් මර්දනය කිරීමට සහ මායාකාරියන් දඩයම් කිරීමට රජය ගන්නා නිවට ක්‍රියා නතර කළ යුතු බවයි.",
        "“ජනතාව මුහුණ දෙන ඉන්ධන, ගෑස්, පොහොර, ඖෂධ හිඟය විසඳීමෙන් පමණක් අරගලය නැවැත්විය හැකිය. මර්දනයෙන් හෝ බිය ගැන්වීමෙන් එය කිසි විටෙකත් නැවැත්විය නොහැක. මර්දනයට එරෙහිව තව තවත් ජනතාව ඉදිරිපත් වනු ඇත, එය දේශපාලන අර්බුදය තවත් නරක අතට හැරෙනු ඇත. දේශපාලන අර්බුදය උග්‍ර වෙනවා, ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට විසඳුම් ලබාදීමත් ප්‍රමාද වෙනවා,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.(අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨා",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පැවසීය.(අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோட்டாவுக்கு எதிரான வழக்குகள் அவர் நாடு திரும்பிய பின் தொடர வேண்டும்: ஜே.வி.பி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச நாடு திரும்பியவுடன் அவருக்கு எதிராக தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ள வழக்குகள் விரைவில் மீள ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணி (ஜேவிபி) பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் விஜித ஹேரத் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச இலங்கை பிரஜை என்பதாலேயே சிவிலியனாக நாட்டிற்கு வர உரிமை உண்டு என அவர் செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பில் தெரிவித்தார். \"எனினும், அவர் இனி நாட்டின் ஜனாதிபதியாக இல்லை, ஜனாதிபதியின் விலக்குரிமையும் இல்லை. அவர் மீதான வழக்குகள் விசாரிக்கப்பட வேண்டும், அவருக்கு எதிராக சட்டம் செயல்படுத்தப்பட வேண்டும்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "அமைதியான போராட்டக்காரர்களை அடக்கி வேட்டையாடும் கோழைத்தனமான நடவடிக்கைகளை அரசாங்கம் நிறுத்த வேண்டும் என பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஹேரத் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"மக்கள் எதிர்கொள்ளும் எரிபொருள், எரிவாயு, உரம் மற்றும் மருந்துப் பற்றாக்குறையைத் தீர்ப்பதன் மூலம் மட்டுமே போராட்டத்தை நிறுத்த முடியும். அடக்குமுறை அல்லது மிரட்டல் மூலம் இதை ஒருபோதும் நிறுத்த முடியாது. அடக்குமுறைக்கு எதிராக மேலும் மேலும் மக்கள் முன்வருவார்கள், அது அரசியல் நெருக்கடியை மோசமாக்கும். எப்போது அரசியல் நெருக்கடி மோசமடைகிறது, பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கான தீர்வுகளும் தாமதமாகும்\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.(அஜித் சிறிவர்தன)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கிடைத்தது ஒரு",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனதா விமுக்தி பெரமுனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜித ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "என்றார்.(அஜித் சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}