{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/මිලියන-09ක-රන්-සමග-03ක්-කොටුවෙයි/11-395749",
  "time_ut": 1658816936,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මිලියන 09ක රන් සමග 03ක් කොටුවෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "09 million gold with 03 boxes",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "03 suspects were taken into the custody of Navy in Pesala along with gold worth more than 09 million rupees which they tried to take out of the country illegally.",
        "The Sri Lanka Navy carried out a special search yesterday (25th) night in the sea coast off Kurusapadu area, Pesala, Mannar.",
        "In an operation, three persons suspected of trying to smuggle 470 grams of gold and a Valampuri out of the country were taken into custody by the Navy.",
        "Sri Lanka Naval Ships of North Central Naval Command deployed Coastal Patrol Vessels belonging to Tammanna to Mannar, Pesale Krusapadu area",
        "Suspicious dinghies left the Kurusapadu beach during a special search operation on the night of July 25, 2022 on the coast beyond.",
        "A vessel was observed and inspected. There, the dinghy was taken into custody along with three suspects along with a Valampuri and an amount of 470 grams of gold suspected to have been illegally taken to Meratin.",
        "The market value of the gold seized by the Navy is believed to be over nine million rupees.",
        "During this operation, the suspects who were taken into custody by the Navy were identified as residents of Puttalam and Paisal, between the ages of 24 and 39, and the suspects, Ratrang, Valampuria and the dinghy are to be handed over to the Jaffna Customs Office for further legal proceedings."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "09 million",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "03",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pesala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 09 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the sea coast",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurusapadu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pesala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Valampuri",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "North Central Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Coastal Patrol Vessels",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tammanna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pesale Krusapadu",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kurusapadu",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the night of July 25, 2022",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Valampuri",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "470 grams",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Meratin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paisal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "between the ages of 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "39",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratrang",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Valampuria",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Jaffna Customs Office",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මිලියන 09ක රන් සමග 03ක් කොටුවෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "නීති විරෝධි ලෙස මෙරටින් රැගෙන යාමට උත්සාහ කල රුපියල් මිලියන 09 කට අධික වටිනාකමකින් යුත් රත්‍රං සමඟ සැකකරුවන් 03 ක් පේසාලේදී නාවික හමුදා භාරයට ගනු ලැබිණි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව මන්නාරම පේසාලේ, කුරුසපාඩු ප්‍රදේශයට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ මුහුදු තීරයේ ඊයේ (25දා)  රාත්‍රී සිදු කල විශේෂ සෝදිසි",
        "මෙහෙයුමක් මඟින් රත්‍රං ග්‍රෑම් 470 ක පමණ ප්‍රමාණයක් සහ වාලම්පූරියක් නීති විරෝධී ලෙස මෙරටින් රැගෙන යාමට උත්සාහ කල බවට සැක කෙරෙන පුද්ගලයින් තිදෙනෙකු නාවික හමුදා භාරයට ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "උතුරු මැද නාවික විධානයේ ශ්‍රි ලංකා නාවික නෞකා තම්මැන්නා ආයතනයට අයත් වෙරළබඩ මුර යාත්‍රා යොදවා ‍මන්නාරම, පේසාලේ කුරුසපාඩු ප්‍රදේශයට",
        "ඔබ්බෙන් වූ මුහුදු තීරයේ 2022 ජූලි මස 25 වන දින රාත්‍රීයේ සිදුකල විශේෂ සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමකදී කුරුසපාඩු වෙරළ තීරයෙන් පිටත්වූ සැකකටයුතු ඩිංගි",
        "යාත්‍රාවක් නිරීක්ෂණය කර පරික්ෂාවට ලක් කරන ලදී. එහිදී නීති විරෝධී ලෙස මෙ‍රටින් රැගෙන යාමට උත්සාහ කල බවට සැක කෙරෙන රත්‍රං ග්‍රෑම් 470 ක පමණ ප්‍රමාණයක් සහ වාලම්පුරියක් සමඟ සැකකරුවන් තිදෙනෙකු  සහ එම ඩිංගි යාත්‍රාව නාවික හමුදා භාරයට ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "නාවික හමුදා භාරයට ගත් රත්‍රං ප්‍රමාණයේ වෙළඳපළ වටිනාකම රුපියල් මිලියන නවයකට  අධික වෙතැයි විශ්වාස කෙරේ.",
        "මෙම මෙහෙයුම මඟින් නාවික හමුදා භාරයට ගත් සැකකරුවන් වයස අවුරුදු 24 හා 39 අතර පසුවන පුත්තලම සහ පේසාලේ යන ප්‍රදේශයන්හි පදිංචිකරුවන් බවට හඳුනා ගන්නා  ලද අතර, එම සැකකරුවන්, රත්‍රං, වාලම්පුරිය සහ ඩිංගි යාත්‍රාව ඉදිරි නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා යාපනය, රේගු කාර්යාලය වෙත භාරදීමට නියමිතව ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මිලියන 09 කි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "03",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පේසාල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 09 කට වඩා වැඩිය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුහුදු වෙරළ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුසපාඩු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පේසාල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාලම්පුරි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු මැද නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙරළ මුර යාත්‍රා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තම්න්නා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පේසාලේ කෘසපාඩු",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුරුසපාඩු",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 25 රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාලම්පුරි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ග්රෑම් 470 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙරටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පයිසාල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 24 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "39",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්රන්ග්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාලම්පුරියා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය රේගු කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "03 பெட்டிகளுடன் 09 மில்லியன் தங்கம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சட்டவிரோதமான முறையில் நாட்டிற்கு கொண்டு செல்ல முயன்ற 09 மில்லியன் ரூபாவுக்கும் அதிகமான பெறுமதியான தங்கத்துடன் 03 சந்தேகநபர்கள் பேசாலையில் கடற்படையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "மன்னார், பேசாலை, குருசபாடு கடற்பகுதியில் நேற்று (25) இரவு இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் விசேட தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "470 கிராம் தங்கம் மற்றும் வலம்புரி ஒன்றை வெளிநாடுகளுக்கு கடத்த முயன்றதாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் மூவர் கடற்படையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "வடமத்திய கடற்படை கட்டளையின் இலங்கை கடற்படை கப்பல்கள் தம்மன்னாவிற்கு சொந்தமான கரையோர ரோந்து கப்பல்களை மன்னார், பேசாலை குருசபாடு பகுதிக்கு அனுப்பியுள்ளன.",
        "ஜூலை 25, 2022 அன்று இரவு குருசபாடு கடற்கரைக்கு அப்பால் கடற்கரையில் ஒரு சிறப்பு தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையின் போது சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான டிங்கிகள் வெளியேறின.",
        "ஒரு கப்பல் கண்காணிக்கப்பட்டு ஆய்வு செய்யப்பட்டது. அங்கு, டிங்கி படகு, மூன்று சந்தேக நபர்களுடன், ஒரு வலம்புரி மற்றும் 470 கிராம் தங்கம் சட்டவிரோதமாக மெரடினுக்கு கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்டதாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் ஒரு தொகையுடன் கைது செய்யப்பட்டன.",
        "கடற்படையினரால் கைப்பற்றப்பட்ட தங்கத்தின் சந்தைப் பெறுமதி ஒன்பது மில்லியன் ரூபாவுக்கும் அதிகம் என நம்பப்படுகிறது.",
        "இந்த நடவடிக்கையின் போது கடற்படையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேகநபர்கள் 24 முதல் 39 வயதுக்குட்பட்ட புத்தளம் மற்றும் பைசல் பிரதேசத்தை சேர்ந்தவர்கள் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டதுடன், சந்தேகநபர்களான ரத்ரங், வலம்புரி மற்றும் டிங்கி படகு யாழ்ப்பாணம் சுங்க அதிகாரிகளிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்படவுள்ளது. மேலதிக சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்கான அலுவலகம்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "09 மில்லியன்",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "03",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேசாலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "09 மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமானது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடல் கடற்கரை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருசபாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேசாலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வலம்புரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட மத்திய கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடலோர ரோந்து கப்பல்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மன்னா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேசலே க்ருசபாடு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குருசபாடு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 25, 2022 இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வலம்புரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "470 கிராம்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெரடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பைசல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 வயதுக்குள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "39",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரத்ராங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வலம்புரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாணம் சுங்க அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}