{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/richard-pieris-finance-announces-resilient-performance-for-fy-2021-22/",
  "time_ut": 1656680340,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Richard Pieris Finance announces resilient performance for FY 2021/22",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Richard Pieris Finance announces resilient performance for FY 2021/22",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "Richard Pieris Finance Limited, a fully owned subsidiary of the Richard Pieris Group, and the sole financing arm under the renowned Arpico brand, delivered solid financial performance for the Financial Year 2021/22, amidst a challenging economic backdrop. Supported by the Company’s committed workforce and prudent management strategies, Richard Pieris Finance’s profit before taxes (PBT) rose by a notable 283% to Rs. 444 Mn, compared to prior year. The company also saw revenues growing by 16% to Rs.2,441 Mn during the period. The Company’s deposit base and asset base too grew during the year to Rs.9,910 Mn and Rs.17,927 Mn respectively.",
        "Discussing the achievements and milestones of the year, Lohika Fonseka, CEO at Richard Pieris Finance Limited said, “We are pleased to inform all our stakeholders that the management of Richard Pieris Finance Limited has successfully guided the Company through some of the most challenging times our nation has ever faced. We intend continuing this trajectory, building on our achievements. Supported by our digital drive, the company obtained the membership in CEFTS and JustPay during the year to further customer convenience. Also, we have introduced several new products including pawning to expand our portfolio. Furthermore, taking our plans to fruition, we have upgraded three outlets as fully-fledged branches during 2021/22 to provide a better service to our valuable customers. During the year, Richard Pieris Group infused Rs. 280 Mn of equity capital for strengthening the company’s Tier-1 capital base and the company successfully concluded a debt capital infusion of Rs. 1 Bn to improve the Tier-2 capital base, which positioned the company well above its peers in terms of capital adequacy. While maintaining stability and resilience, we look forward to continuing our business expansion as we pivot and position to tackle the challenges ahead, while always focusing on customer convenience.”",
        "Underscoring the stability and strength of Richard Pieris Finance Limited, the Company has been assessed with the coveted AA-(RWN) from Fitch Ratings Lanka Limited, one of Sri Lanka’s premier credit rating agencies. The Company appointed Kithsiri Wanigasekara as the Chairman who is a veteran professional in the financial services industry together with Shantha Wijeweera, Kithsiri Wijeyaratne, Asoka Keppetipola and Kelum Senanayake to guide and support the Corporate Management team, to navigate the present turbulent economic environment skilfully and effectively. The corporate management team of Richard Pieris Finance Limited comprises of financial industry professionals in multiple disciplines including veteran bankers and legal professionals. Operating within a resilient corporate governance structure while maintaining robust internal controls relating to risk management, compliance and further supported by digital transformation, Richard Pieris Finance Limited is confident on maintaining its growth momentum in future.",
        "Richard Pieris Finance Limited provides Sri Lankans with a full-range of financial products and services including fixed deposits, savings, leasing, Islamic finance, business loans, personal loans, pawning, furniture financing and digital finance solutions. The Richard Pieris Group is a diversified business conglomerate with a rich history spanning over 90 years, having its arms spread across multiple sectors including manufacturing, plantations, financial services, exports, FMCG, logistics and retail. Its flagship brand, “Arpico Supercentres” is one of the most powerful local household brands in Sri Lanka for over 50 years, serving the community with a diverse range of products. A melting pot of talent, home to a workforce of over 27,000 people, Richard Pieris and Company PLC is one of the largest employers in Sri Lanka’s private sector.",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Richard Pieris Finance",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Richard Pieris Finance Limited",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Richard Pieris Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arpico",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Financial Year 2021/22",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Richard Pieris Finance",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PBT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "283%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "444",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "prior year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs.2,441 Mn",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lohika Fonseka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Richard Pieris Finance Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Richard Pieris Finance Limited",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEFTS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JustPay",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021/22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Richard Pieris Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "280",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tier-1",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tier-2",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Richard Pieris Finance Limited",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AA-(RWN",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fitch Ratings Lanka Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shantha Wijeweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kithsiri Wijeyaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asoka Keppetipola",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelum Senanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Corporate Management",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Richard Pieris Finance Limited",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Richard Pieris Finance Limited",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Richard Pieris Finance Limited",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Islamic",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "90 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FMCG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arpico Supercentres”",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 50 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 27,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Richard Pieris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Company PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Richard Pieris Finance 2021/22 FY සඳහා ඔරොත්තු දෙන කාර්ය සාධනය නිවේදනය කරයි",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "Richard Pieris Finance Limited, Richard Pieris Group හි පූර්ණ අනුබද්ධිත ආයතනයක් සහ සුප්‍රසිද්ධ Arpico සන්නාමය යටතේ ඇති එකම මූල්‍ය හස්තය, අභියෝගාත්මක ආර්ථික පසුබිමක් මධ්‍යයේ 2021/22 මූල්‍ය වර්ෂය සඳහා ශක්තිමත් මූල්‍ය කාර්ය සාධනයක් ලබා දුන්නේය. සමාගමේ කැපවූ ශ්‍රම බලකායේ සහ විචක්ෂණ කළමනාකරණ උපාය මාර්ගවල සහාය ඇතිව, රිචඩ් පීරිස් ෆිනෑන්ස් හි බදු වලට පෙර ලාභය (PBT) කැපී පෙනෙන 283% කින් රු. පෙර වසරට සාපේක්ෂව මිලියන 444 කි. මෙම කාලය තුළ සමාගමේ ආදායම රුපියල් මිලියන 2,441 දක්වා 16% කින් වර්ධනය වී ඇත. සමාගමේ තැන්පතු පදනම සහ වත්කම් පදනම ද වර්ෂය තුළ පිළිවෙලින් රුපියල් මිලියන 9,910 සහ රුපියල් මිලියන 17,927 දක්වා වර්ධනය විය.",
        "වසරේ ජයග්‍රහණ සහ සන්ධිස්ථාන පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කරමින් Richard Pieris Finance Limited හි ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී ලෝහිකා ෆොන්සේකා මහතා පැවසුවේ, “රිචඩ් පීරිස් ෆිනෑන්ස් ලිමිටඩ් කළමනාකාරීත්වය අපගේ අභියෝගාත්මක කාලවලදී සමාගමට සාර්ථකව මග පෙන්වූ බව අපගේ සියලුම පාර්ශ්වකරුවන්ට දැනුම් දීමට අපි සතුටු වෙමු. ජාතිය කවදා හෝ මුහුණ දී ඇත. අපගේ ජයග්‍රහණ මත ගොඩනැගෙන මෙම ගමන් පථය දිගටම කරගෙන යාමට අපි අදහස් කරමු. අපගේ ඩිජිටල් ඩ්‍රයිව් වෙතින් සහය ඇතිව, සමාගම තවදුරටත් පාරිභෝගික පහසුව සඳහා වසර තුළ CEFTS සහ JustPay හි සාමාජිකත්වය ලබා ගත්තේය. එසේම, අපගේ කළඹ පුළුල් කිරීම සඳහා උකස් කිරීම ඇතුළු නව නිෂ්පාදන කිහිපයක් අපි හඳුන්වා දී ඇත. තවද, අපගේ සැලසුම් ක්‍රියාවට නංවමින්, අපගේ වටිනා පාරිභෝගිකයින්ට වඩා හොඳ සේවාවක් සැපයීම සඳහා 2021/22 කාලය තුළ අපි අලෙවිසැල් තුනක් අංගසම්පූර්ණ ශාඛාවන් ලෙස උසස් කර ඇත. වසර තුළ රිචඩ් පීරිස් සමූහය විසින් රු. සමාගමේ පළමු ස්ථරයේ ප්‍රාග්ධන පදනම ශක්තිමත් කිරීම සඳහා මිලියන 280 ක කොටස් ප්‍රාග්ධනයක් සහ සමාගම විසින් රු. ප‍්‍රාග්ධන ප‍්‍රමාණාත්මතාවය අතින් සමාගම එහි සම වයසේ මිතුරන්ට වඩා ඉහළින් ස්ථානගත කළ Tier-2 ප්‍රාග්ධන පදනම වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම සඳහා බිලියන 1ක්. ස්ථාවරත්වය සහ ඔරොත්තු දීමේ හැකියාව පවත්වා ගනිමින්, පාරිභෝගික පහසුව සඳහා සෑම විටම අවධානය යොමු කරන අතරම, ඉදිරි අභියෝගවලට මුහුණ දීම සඳහා අපි හැරවීම සහ ස්ථානගත වීම නිසා අපගේ ව්‍යාපාර ව්‍යාප්තිය දිගටම කරගෙන යාමට අපි බලාපොරොත්තු වෙමු.",
        "Richard Pieris Finance Limited හි ස්ථාවරත්වය සහ ශක්තිය අවධාරණය කරමින්, සමාගම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රමුඛතම ණය ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීමේ නියෝජිතායතනයක් වන Fitch Ratings Lanka Limited වෙතින් ප්‍රශංසනීය AA-(RWN) සමඟ තක්සේරු කර ඇත. මූල්‍ය සේවා ක්‍ෂේත්‍රයේ ප්‍රවීණ වෘත්තිකයකු වන කිත්සිරි වනිගසේකර සභාපතිවරයා ලෙස ශාන්ත විජේවීර, කිත්සිරි විජයරත්න, අශෝක කැප්පෙටිපොළ සහ කැළුම් සේනානායක යන මහත්වරුන් සමඟ එක්ව, වත්මන් කැලඹිලි සහිත ආර්ථික පරිසරය දක්ෂ ලෙස හා ඵලදායී ලෙස ගමන් කිරීම සඳහා ආයතනික කළමනාකරණ කණ්ඩායමට මඟ පෙන්වීම සහ සහාය දැක්වීම සඳහා සමාගම විසින් පත් කරන ලදී. . Richard Pieris Finance Limited හි ආයතනික කළමනාකරණ කණ්ඩායම ප්‍රවීණ බැංකුකරුවන් සහ නීති වෘත්තිකයන් ඇතුළු විවිධ විෂය ක්ෂේත්‍රවල මුල්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ වෘත්තිකයන්ගෙන් සමන්විත වේ. අවදානම් කළමනාකරණයට අදාළව ශක්තිමත් අභ්‍යන්තර පාලනයක් පවත්වා ගනිමින් ප්‍රත්‍යස්ථ ආයතනික පාලන ව්‍යුහයක් තුළ ක්‍රියාත්මක වන රිචඩ් පීරිස් ෆිනෑන්ස් ලිමිටඩ් අනාගතයේදී සිය වර්ධන වේගය පවත්වා ගැනීමට විශ්වාස කරයි.",
        "Richard Pieris Finance Limited ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින්ට ස්ථාවර තැන්පතු, ඉතුරුම්, ලීසිං, ඉස්ලාමීය මූල්‍ය, ව්‍යාපාර ණය, පුද්ගලික ණය, උකස්, ගෘහ භාණ්ඩ මුල්‍යකරණය සහ ඩිජිටල් මුල්‍ය විසඳුම් ඇතුළු පූර්ණ පරාසයක මුල්‍ය නිෂ්පාදන සහ සේවා සපයයි. Richard Pieris Group යනු නිෂ්පාදන, වැවිලි, මූල්‍ය සේවා, අපනයන, FMCG, ලොජිස්ටික් සහ සිල්ලර වෙළඳාම ඇතුළු විවිධ ක්ෂේත්‍ර හරහා විහිදුණු වසර 90කට අධික පොහොසත් ඉතිහාසයක් ඇති විවිධාංගීකරණය වූ ව්‍යාපාරික සමූහ ව්‍යාපාරයකි. එහි ප්‍රමුඛතම සන්නාමය වන “Arpico Supercentres” වසර 50කට අධික කාලයක් පුරා විවිධ නිෂ්පාදන රැසක් සමඟින් ප්‍රජාවට සේවා සපයන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බලවත්ම දේශීය ගෘහස්ථ සන්නාමවලින් එකකි. 27,000කට අධික ශ්‍රම බළකායකට නිවහනක් වන රිචඩ් පීරිස් සහ සමාගම පීඑල්සී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පෞද්ගලික අංශයේ විශාලතම සේවා යෝජකයන්ගෙන් එකකි.",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රිචඩ් පීරිස් ෆිනෑන්ස්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Richard Pieris Finance Limited",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිචඩ් පීරිස් සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්පිකෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021/22 මුල්‍ය වර්ෂය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිචඩ් පීරිස් ෆිනෑන්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PBT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "283%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "444",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙර වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "රු.මි.2,441",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝහිකා ෆොන්සේකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Richard Pieris Finance Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Richard Pieris Finance Limited",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEFTS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JustPay",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021/22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිචඩ් පීරිස් සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "280",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්ථරය-1",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්ථරය-2",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Richard Pieris Finance Limited",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AA-(RWN",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fitch Ratings Lanka Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශාන්ත විජේවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිත්සිරි විජයරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අශෝක කැප්පෙටිපොළ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැළුම් සේනානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආයතනික කළමනාකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Richard Pieris Finance Limited",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Richard Pieris Finance Limited",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Richard Pieris Finance Limited",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉස්ලාමීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 90 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එෆ්.එම්.සී.ජී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්පිකෝ සුපර් සෙන්ටර්ස්”",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 50 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27,000 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිචඩ් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාගම PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் ஃபைனான்ஸ் 2021/22 நிதியாண்டுக்கான நெகிழ்ச்சியான செயல்திறனை அறிவிக்கிறது",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "Richard Pieris Group இன் முழுச் சொந்தமான துணை நிறுவனமான Richard Pieris Finance Limited, மற்றும் புகழ்பெற்ற Arpico பிராண்டின் கீழ் உள்ள ஒரே நிதியளிப்புப் பிரிவானது, 2021/22 நிதியாண்டில், சவாலான பொருளாதாரப் பின்னணியில் உறுதியான நிதிச் செயல்திறனை வழங்கியுள்ளது. நிறுவனத்தின் உறுதியான பணியாளர்கள் மற்றும் விவேகமான நிர்வாக உத்திகளால் ஆதரிக்கப்பட்டு, ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் ஃபினான்ஸின் வரிகளுக்கு முந்தைய லாபம் (PBT) குறிப்பிடத்தக்க வகையில் 283% அதிகரித்து ரூ. முந்தைய ஆண்டுடன் ஒப்பிடும்போது 444 மில்லியன். இந்த காலகட்டத்தில் நிறுவனத்தின் வருவாய் 16% அதிகரித்து ரூ.2,441 மில்லியனாக இருந்தது. நிறுவனத்தின் வைப்புத் தளம் மற்றும் சொத்துத் தளமும் இந்த ஆண்டில் முறையே ரூ.9,910 மில்லியன் மற்றும் ரூ.17,927 மில்லியனாக அதிகரித்தது.",
        "இந்த வருடத்தின் சாதனைகள் மற்றும் மைல்கற்கள் பற்றி விவாதித்த Richard Pieris Finance Limited இன் CEO லோஹிகா பொன்சேகா, “Richard Pieris Finance Limited நிறுவனத்தின் நிர்வாகம் மிகவும் சவாலான காலங்களில் நிறுவனத்தை வெற்றிகரமாக வழிநடத்தியுள்ளது என்பதை எங்கள் பங்குதாரர்கள் அனைவருக்கும் அறிவிப்பதில் நாங்கள் மகிழ்ச்சியடைகிறோம். நாடு எதிர்கொண்டது. எங்களின் சாதனைகளைக் கட்டியெழுப்பும் வகையில் இந்தப் பாதையைத் தொடர விரும்புகிறோம். எங்கள் டிஜிட்டல் டிரைவின் ஆதரவுடன், வாடிக்கையாளர்களின் வசதிக்காக, நிறுவனம் CEFTS மற்றும் JustPay இல் உறுப்பினரைப் பெற்றுள்ளது. மேலும், எங்கள் போர்ட்ஃபோலியோவை விரிவுபடுத்துவதற்காக அடகு வைத்தல் உட்பட பல புதிய தயாரிப்புகளை அறிமுகப்படுத்தியுள்ளோம். மேலும், எங்களது திட்டங்களை செயல்படுத்தி, எங்கள் மதிப்புமிக்க வாடிக்கையாளர்களுக்கு சிறந்த சேவையை வழங்குவதற்காக 2021/22 ஆம் ஆண்டில் மூன்று விற்பனை நிலையங்களை முழு அளவிலான கிளைகளாக மேம்படுத்தியுள்ளோம். இந்த ஆண்டில், ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் குழுமம் ரூ. நிறுவனத்தின் அடுக்கு-1 மூலதனத் தளத்தை வலுப்படுத்த 280 மில்லியன் பங்கு மூலதனம் மற்றும் நிறுவனம் ரூ. கடன் மூலதனத்தை வெற்றிகரமாக முடித்தது. டயர்-2 மூலதனத் தளத்தை மேம்படுத்த 1 பில்லியன், இது மூலதனப் போதுமான அளவு நிறுவனத்தை அதன் சக நிறுவனங்களுக்கு மேல் நிலைநிறுத்தியது. ஸ்திரத்தன்மை மற்றும் நெகிழ்ச்சித்தன்மையை பராமரிக்கும் அதே வேளையில், வாடிக்கையாளர்களின் வசதிக்காக எப்போதும் கவனம் செலுத்தும் அதே வேளையில், முன்னோக்கிச் செல்லும் சவால்களைச் சமாளிப்பதற்கான முன்னோக்கி மற்றும் நிலைப்பாட்டில், எங்கள் வணிக விரிவாக்கத்தைத் தொடர நாங்கள் எதிர்நோக்குகிறோம்.",
        "ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் ஃபைனான்ஸ் லிமிடெட்டின் ஸ்திரத்தன்மை மற்றும் பலத்தை அடிக்கோடிட்டுக் காட்டும் வகையில், இலங்கையின் முதன்மையான கடன் தரமதிப்பீட்டு நிறுவனங்களில் ஒன்றான ஃபிட்ச் ரேட்டிங்ஸ் லங்கா லிமிடெட் வழங்கும் AA-(RWN) உடன் நிறுவனம் மதிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது. தற்போதைய கொந்தளிப்பான பொருளாதார சூழலை திறமையாகவும் வினைத்திறனுடனும் வழிநடத்த, கூட்டாண்மை முகாமைத்துவ குழுவிற்கு வழிகாட்டுவதற்கும் ஆதரவளிப்பதற்கும் சாந்த விஜேவீர, கித்சிறி விஜேயரத்ன, அசோக கெப்பெட்டிபொல மற்றும் கெலும் சேனநாயக்க ஆகியோருடன் இணைந்து நிதிச் சேவைகள் துறையில் அனுபவம் வாய்ந்த நிபுணரான கித்சிறி வணிகசேகரவை தலைவராக நியமித்தது. . ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் ஃபைனான்ஸ் லிமிடெட்டின் பெருநிறுவன மேலாண்மைக் குழுவானது, மூத்த வங்கியாளர்கள் மற்றும் சட்ட வல்லுநர்கள் உட்பட பல துறைகளில் உள்ள நிதியியல் தொழில் வல்லுநர்களைக் கொண்டுள்ளது. ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் ஃபைனான்ஸ் லிமிடெட், ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் ஃபைனான்ஸ் லிமிடெட், ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் ஃபைனான்ஸ் லிமிடெட், ரிஸ்க் மேனேஜ்மென்ட் தொடர்பான வலுவான உள்ளகக் கட்டுப்பாடுகளைப் பராமரிக்கும் அதே வேளையில், ஒரு நெகிழ்ச்சியான நிறுவன ஆளுகைக் கட்டமைப்பிற்குள் இயங்குகிறது.",
        "ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் ஃபைனான்ஸ் லிமிடெட் இலங்கையர்களுக்கு நிலையான வைப்பு, சேமிப்பு, குத்தகை, இஸ்லாமிய நிதி, வணிகக் கடன்கள், தனிநபர் கடன்கள், அடகு வைத்தல், தளபாடங்கள் நிதி மற்றும் டிஜிட்டல் நிதி தீர்வுகள் உட்பட முழு அளவிலான நிதி தயாரிப்புகள் மற்றும் சேவைகளை வழங்குகிறது. ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் குழுமம் 90 ஆண்டுகளுக்கும் மேலான வளமான வரலாற்றைக் கொண்ட ஒரு பல்வகை வணிகக் குழுமமாகும், அதன் ஆயுதங்கள் உற்பத்தி, தோட்டங்கள், நிதிச் சேவைகள், ஏற்றுமதிகள், FMCG, தளவாடங்கள் மற்றும் சில்லறை விற்பனை உட்பட பல துறைகளில் பரவியுள்ளன. அதன் முதன்மையான வர்த்தக நாமமான “Arpico Supercentres” ஆனது 50 வருடங்களுக்கும் மேலாக இலங்கையின் மிகவும் சக்திவாய்ந்த உள்ளூர் வீட்டு வர்த்தக நாமங்களில் ஒன்றாகும். 27,000 க்கும் அதிகமான பணியாளர்களைக் கொண்ட திறமைகளின் உருகும் பகுதி, ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் மற்றும் கம்பனி பிஎல்சி இலங்கையின் தனியார் துறையில் மிகப்பெரிய முதலாளிகளில் ஒன்றாகும்.",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் நிதி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் ஃபைனான்ஸ் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அர்பிகோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதியாண்டு 2021/22",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் நிதி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PBT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "283%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "444",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ.2,441 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லோஹிகா பொன்சேகா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் ஃபைனான்ஸ் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் ஃபைனான்ஸ் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEFTS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JustPay",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021/22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "280",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுக்கு 1",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுக்கு-2",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் ஃபைனான்ஸ் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AA-(RWN",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபிட்ச் ரேட்டிங்ஸ் லங்கா லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாந்த விஜேவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கித்சிறி விஜயரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அசோக கெப்பெட்டிபொல",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெலும் சேனாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிறுவன மேலாண்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் ஃபைனான்ஸ் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் ஃபைனான்ஸ் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் ஃபைனான்ஸ் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்லாமிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "90 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஃப்எம்சிஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்பிகோ சூப்பர்சென்டர்ஸ்”",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27,000க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிறுவனம் பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}