{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/අඩු-ටෙන්ඩරය-අහෝසි-කර-වැඩි-මිලට-ගෑස්-අරන්/101-615959",
  "time_ut": 1657107842,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අඩු ටෙන්ඩරය අහෝසි කර වැඩි මිලට ගෑස් අරන්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Canceled the low tender and bought gas at a higher price",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Term Tender, which had been approved by the Cabinet to buy gas at a low price, was canceled c. Mr. Charita Herath, Chairman of the Parliamentary Committee on Public Enterprises (COPE Committee) recommended that an investigation be conducted through the Auditor General's Department regarding the purchase of 100,000 MT of gas at a higher price of USD 129 each.",
        "Also, the COPE committee has recommended to immediately look into the inability to purchase gas with the amount of 160 million USD allocated to purchase gas under the Indian credit facility.",
        "Yesterday, their heads were summoned before the CORP committee to inquire how the orders given by the committee, Litro Gas Lanka Company, Litro Gas Terminal Lanka (Pvt) Company and Sri Lanka Insurance Corporation were implemented and the performance of those institutions. These recommendations were given in that meeting.",
        "It was revealed that since the seasonal tender for the purchase of gas ended by last February, tenders were invited to purchase 2,80,000 mt of gas and accordingly, three gas suppliers submitted bids. Here, Siam Gas Company has submitted the lowest price as USD 96 and accordingly the Cabinet has approved to award the tender."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Charita Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliamentary Committee on Public Enterprises",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Auditor General's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "129",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "160 million USD",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the CORP committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas Lanka Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas Terminal Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Insurance Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last February",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,80,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Siam Gas Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අඩු ටෙන්ඩරය අහෝසි කර වැඩි මිලට ගෑස් අරන්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අඩුමිලට ගෑස් මිලදී ගැනීමට කැබිනට් අනුමැතිය ලැබී තිබූ වාර ටෙන්ඩරය (Term Tender) අහෝසි කර ඇ. ඩො 129 බැගින් වැඩි මිලට ගෑස් මෙ.ටො ලක්ෂයක් මිලදී ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් විගණකාධිපති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව මාර්ගයෙන් පරීක්ෂණයක් කරන ලෙස පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කාරක සභාවේ (කෝප් කමිටුව) සභාපති මහාචාර්ය චරිත හේරත් මහතා නිර්දේශ කළේය.",
        "එසේම ඉන්දියානු ණය පහසුකම යටතේ ගෑස් මිලදී ගැනීමට වෙන් කරන ලද ඇ.ඩො මිලියන 160 ක මුදලින් ගෑස් මිලදී ගැනීමට නොහැකිවීම සම්බන්ධයෙනන්ද වහාම සොයා බලන ලෙස කෝප් කමිටුව නිර්දේශ කර ඇත.",
        "කමිටුව දුන් නියෝග ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා සමාගම, ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ටර්මිනල් ලංකා (පුද්) සමාගම සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා රක්ෂණ සංස්ථාව යන ආයතන ක්‍රියාත්මක කළ ආකාරය සහ එම ආයතන වල කාර්ය සාධනය විමසීම සඳහා ඒවායේ ප්‍රධානීහු කෝප් කමිටුව හමුවට පෙරේදා කැඳවනු ලැබ සිටියහ. මේ නිර්දේශ ලබා දී ඇත්තේ ඒ රැස්වීමේදීය.",
        "ගෑස් මිලදී ගැනීම සදහා තිබූ වාර ටෙන්ඩරය පසුගිය පෙබරවාරි මාසය වන විට අවසන් වූ බැවින් ගෑස් මෙ.ටො 2,80,000 ක් මිලදී ගැනීමට ටෙන්ඩර් කැදවන ලද බවත් ඒ අනුව ගෑස්සැපයුම්කරුවන් තිදෙනකු ලංසු ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති බවත් මෙහිදී තොරතුරු අනාවරණයවිය. මෙහිදී සියාම් ගෑස් සමාගම ඇ.ඩො 96 බැවින් අවම මිල ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති අතර ඒ අනුව ටෙන්ඩරය ලබාදීමට කැබිනට් අනුමැතිය හිමිව ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චරිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විගණකාධිපතිගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "129",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 160 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CORP කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ ගෑස් පර්යන්තය ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රක්ෂණ සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය පෙබරවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,80,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියම් ගෑස් සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "குறைந்த டெண்டரை ரத்து செய்து அதிக விலைக்கு காஸ் வாங்கினார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "குறைந்த விலையில் எரிவாயுவை கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்கு அமைச்சரவையினால் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்ட டெண்டர் டெண்டர் ரத்து செய்யப்பட்டது. 100,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் எரிவாயுவை தலா 129 அமெரிக்க டொலர்கள் அதிக விலைக்கு கொள்வனவு செய்தமை தொடர்பில் கணக்காய்வாளர் நாயகம் திணைக்களத்தின் ஊடாக விசாரணை நடத்தப்பட வேண்டுமென பொது நிறுவனங்களுக்கான பாராளுமன்றக் குழுவின் (கோப் குழு) தலைவர் திரு.சரித ஹேரத் பரிந்துரைத்துள்ளார்.",
        "மேலும், இந்தியக் கடன் வசதியின் கீழ் எரிவாயுவைக் கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்காக ஒதுக்கப்பட்ட 160 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர் தொகையில் எரிவாயுவை கொள்வனவு செய்ய முடியாத நிலை குறித்து உடனடியாக ஆராயுமாறு கோப் குழு பரிந்துரைத்துள்ளது.",
        "குழு, லிட்ரோ கேஸ் லங்கா நிறுவனம், லிட்ரோ கேஸ் டெர்மினல் லங்கா (பிரைவேட்) நிறுவனம் மற்றும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா இன்சூரன்ஸ் கார்ப்பரேஷன் ஆகியவற்றின் உத்தரவுகள் எவ்வாறு நடைமுறைப்படுத்தப்பட்டன மற்றும் அந்த நிறுவனங்களின் செயல்பாடுகள் குறித்து விசாரிக்க, அவர்களின் தலைவர்கள் நேற்று CORP குழுவின் முன் அழைக்கப்பட்டனர். அந்த கூட்டத்தில் இந்த பரிந்துரைகள் அளிக்கப்பட்டன.",
        "காஸ் கொள்முதல் செய்வதற்கான பருவகால டெண்டர் கடந்த பிப்ரவரி மாதத்துடன் முடிவடைந்ததால், 2,80,000 மெ.டன் எரிவாயு கொள்முதல் செய்ய டெண்டர் கோரப்பட்டு, அதன்படி, மூன்று காஸ் சப்ளையர்கள் ஏலம் சமர்ப்பித்தது தெரியவந்தது. இங்கு சியாம் கேஸ் நிறுவனம் 96 அமெரிக்க டொலர்களாக குறைந்த விலையை சமர்ப்பித்துள்ளதுடன், அதற்கமைவாக டெண்டரை வழங்க அமைச்சரவை அங்கீகாரம் வழங்கியுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரிதா ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது நிறுவனங்களுக்கான நாடாளுமன்றக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆடிட்டர் ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "129",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "160 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CORP குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் லங்கா நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் டெர்மினல் லங்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காப்புறுதி கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த பிப்ரவரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,80,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியாம் எரிவாயு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}