{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/24/uk-parliament-discusses-attaching-hr-conditions-to-imf-bailout/",
  "time_ut": 1656081540,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "UK Parliament discusses attaching HR conditions to IMF bailout",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "UK Parliament discusses attaching HR conditions to IMF bailout",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Conservative Member of the Parliament of United Kingdom, Eliot Colburn urged for the UK Government ensure that any IMF bail-out is attached to human rights conditions, similar to that of GSP+.",
        "UK MP Eliot Colburn also pointed out that while the economic crisis on the island has indeed led to increased militarization in Sri Lanka, the Rajapaksa Government continues to fall apart.",
        "Member of the United Kingdom Parliament and the The Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State for Foreign, Commonwealth and Development Affairs, Vicky Ford has insisted that the current economic situation in Sri Lanka does not distract the country from human rights, and in response to MP Colburn, stated that the UK will work with fellow members on international debt forums on a solution to the country’s debt problem, and to improve the situation with regard to human rights.",
        "The UK Parliament Member, speaking further, mentioned that although the articles of the IMF do allow for conditionality linked to economic policy or to tackling the balance of payments, there is no provision to impose political-linked or human rights-linked conditionality in the IMF process.",
        "Therefore, Ford said that they will work with fellow members on international debt forums on a solution to the country’s debt problem, as well as continuing to lobby the Sri Lankan Government and working in other international forums on human rights.",
        "MP Ford continued to state that the Prime Minister had underlined UK’s continuing support for the people of Sri Lanka during their economic difficulties, and offered UK support through multilateral organizations such as the World Bank and IMF, and international forums such as the Paris Club.",
        "“We have a very significant voice on international debt forums and we are working closely with Paris Club members and multilateral organizations to find solutions to the debt crisis.” she added.",
        "EU Ambassadors urge President to send firm message on future economic plans"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "UK Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Parliament of United Kingdom",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eliot Colburn",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the UK Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "GSP+",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Eliot Colburn",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Rajapaksa Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the United Kingdom Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commonwealth and Development Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vicky Ford",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colburn",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ford",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ford",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Paris Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Paris Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "EU Ambassadors",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "එක්සත් රාජධානියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව IMF ඇපදීම සඳහා මානව සම්පත් කොන්දේසි අනුයුක්ත කිරීම ගැන සාකච්ඡා කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); එක්සත් රාජධානියේ කොන්සර්වේටිව් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී, එලියට් කොල්බර්න් එක්සත් රාජධානියේ රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ ඕනෑම IMF ඇපදීමක් GSP+ හා සමාන මානව හිමිකම් කොන්දේසිවලට අනුයුක්ත කර ඇති බවට සහතික වීමයි.",
        "එක්සත් රාජධානියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී එලියට් කොල්බර්න් ද පෙන්වා දුන්නේ දිවයිනේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සැබවින්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මිලිටරිකරණය වැඩි කිරීමට හේතු වී ඇති අතර, රාජපක්ෂ රජය දිගින් දිගටම බිඳ වැටෙන බවයි.",
        "එක්සත් රාජධානියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සහ විදේශ, පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය සහ සංවර්ධන කටයුතු පිළිබඳ පාර්ලිමේන්තු නියෝජ්‍ය රාජ්‍ය ලේකම්, Vicky Ford අවධාරනය කර ඇත්තේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය මානව හිමිකම්වලින් රට නොසලකන බවත්, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී කොල්බර්න්ට ප්‍රතිචාර වශයෙන් , එක්සත් රාජධානිය රටේ ණය ගැටලුවට විසඳුමක් සහ මානව හිමිකම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් තත්ත්වය වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම සඳහා ජාත්‍යන්තර ණය සංසදවල සෙසු සාමාජිකයන් සමඟ කටයුතු කරන බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "එක්සත් රාජධානියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයා වැඩිදුරටත් අදහස් දක්වමින් කියා සිටියේ IMF හි වගන්ති මගින් ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිපත්තියට සම්බන්ධ කොන්දේසිවලට හෝ ගෙවුම් ශේෂය පාලනය කිරීමට ඉඩ සලසන නමුත් IMF තුළ දේශපාලන සම්බන්ධ හෝ මානව හිමිකම් සම්බන්ධ කොන්දේසි පැනවීමට ප්‍රතිපාදන නොමැති බවයි. ක්රියාවලිය.",
        "එබැවින්, ඔවුන් රටේ ණය ප්‍රශ්නයට විසඳුමක් සඳහා ජාත්‍යන්තර ණය සංසදවල සෙසු සාමාජිකයින් සමඟ කටයුතු කරන බව මෙන්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයට දිගින් දිගටම බලපෑම් කරමින් මානව හිමිකම් පිළිබඳ අනෙකුත් ජාත්‍යන්තර සංසදවල කටයුතු කරන බව ෆෝඩ් පැවසීය.",
        "ෆෝඩ් මන්ත්‍රීවරයා දිගින් දිගටම ප්‍රකාශ කළේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවගේ ආර්ථික දුෂ්කරතාවලදී එක්සත් රාජධානියේ අඛණ්ඩ සහයෝගය අවධාරණය කළ අතර, ලෝක බැංකුව සහ IMF වැනි බහුපාර්ශ්වික සංවිධාන සහ පැරිස් ක්ලබ් වැනි ජාත්‍යන්තර සංසද හරහා එක්සත් රාජධානියේ සහාය ලබා දුන් බවයි.",
        "\"ජාත්‍යන්තර ණය සංසද පිළිබඳව අපට ඉතා වැදගත් හඬක් ඇති අතර ණය අර්බුදයට විසඳුම් සෙවීම සඳහා අපි පැරිස් සමාජ ශාලාවේ සාමාජිකයින් සහ බහුපාර්ශ්වික සංවිධාන සමඟ සමීපව කටයුතු කරමින් සිටිමු.\" ඇය වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසුවාය.",
        "අනාගත ආර්ථික සැලසුම් පිළිබඳ ස්ථිර පණිවිඩයක් යවන ලෙස යුරෝපා සංගම් තානාපතිවරු ජනාධිපතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටිති"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එලියට් කොල්බර්න්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානියේ රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "GSP+",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එලියට් කොල්බර්න්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ ආණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය හා සංවර්ධන කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විකී ෆෝඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝල්බර්න්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆෝඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆෝඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැරිස් සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පැරිස් සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "EU තානාපතිවරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "IMF பிணை எடுப்பிற்கு HR நிபந்தனைகளை இணைப்பது குறித்து UK பாராளுமன்றம் விவாதிக்கிறது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); யுனைடெட் கிங்டமின் கன்சர்வேடிவ் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் எலியட் கோல்பர்ன் எந்தவொரு IMF பிணையெடுப்பும் GSP+ போன்ற மனித உரிமைகள் நிபந்தனைகளுடன் இணைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதை உறுதிசெய்யுமாறு UK அரசாங்கத்தை வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "ஐக்கிய இராச்சிய நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் எலியட் கோல்பர்ன், தீவின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி உண்மையில் இலங்கையில் அதிகரித்த இராணுவமயமாக்கலுக்கு இட்டுச் சென்றாலும், ராஜபக்சே அரசாங்கம் தொடர்ந்து வீழ்ச்சியடைந்து வருவதாகவும் சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "ஐக்கிய இராச்சிய நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினரும் வெளிநாட்டு, பொதுநலவாய மற்றும் அபிவிருத்தி விவகாரங்களுக்கான நாடாளுமன்ற துணைச் செயலாளருமான விக்கி ஃபோர்ட், இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நிலைமை மனித உரிமைகளில் இருந்து நாட்டைத் திசைதிருப்பாது என்று வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளார். , நாட்டின் கடன் பிரச்சனைக்கு தீர்வு காண்பதற்கும், மனித உரிமைகள் தொடர்பாக நிலைமையை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கும், சர்வதேச கடன் மன்றங்களில் சக உறுப்பினர்களுடன் UK செயல்படும் என்று கூறியது.",
        "ஐக்கிய இராச்சிய நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மேலும் பேசுகையில், சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் கட்டுரைகள் பொருளாதாரக் கொள்கையுடன் இணைக்கப்பட்ட நிபந்தனைகளையோ அல்லது கொடுப்பனவு சமநிலையை சமாளிப்பதையோ அனுமதித்தாலும், IMF இல் அரசியல் சார்ந்த அல்லது மனித உரிமைகள் தொடர்பான நிபந்தனைகளை விதிக்க எந்த ஏற்பாடும் இல்லை என்று குறிப்பிட்டார். செயல்முறை.",
        "எனவே, நாட்டின் கடன் பிரச்சினைக்கு தீர்வு காண சர்வதேச கடன் மன்றங்களில் சக உறுப்பினர்களுடன் இணைந்து பணியாற்றுவதோடு, இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தை தொடர்ந்தும், மனித உரிமைகள் தொடர்பான மற்ற சர்வதேச மன்றங்களில் பணியாற்றுவோம் என்று Ford கூறியது.",
        "இலங்கை மக்களின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிகளின் போது பிரிட்டனின் ஆதரவை பிரதமர் அடிக்கோடிட்டுக் காட்டினார் என்றும், உலக வங்கி மற்றும் IMF போன்ற பலதரப்பு நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் Paris Club போன்ற சர்வதேச மன்றங்கள் மூலம் பிரிட்டன் ஆதரவை வழங்கியதாகவும் எம்.பி. ஃபோர்ட் தொடர்ந்து கூறினார்.",
        "\"சர்வதேச கடன் மன்றங்களில் எங்களுக்கு மிகவும் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க குரல் உள்ளது மற்றும் கடன் நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வு காண பாரிஸ் கிளப் உறுப்பினர்கள் மற்றும் பலதரப்பு நிறுவனங்களுடன் நாங்கள் நெருக்கமாக பணியாற்றி வருகிறோம்.\" அவள் சேர்த்தாள்.",
        "எதிர்கால பொருளாதார திட்டங்கள் குறித்து உறுதியான செய்தியை அனுப்புமாறு ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றிய தூதர்கள் ஜனாதிபதியை வலியுறுத்துகின்றனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இங்கிலாந்து பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய இராச்சியத்தின் பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எலியட் கோல்பர்ன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இங்கிலாந்து அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "GSP+",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எலியட் கோல்பர்ன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்ச அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய இராச்சிய பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமன்வெல்த் மற்றும் வளர்ச்சி விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கி ஃபோர்டு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோல்பர்ன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃபோர்டு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃபோர்டு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ் கிளப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ் கிளப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றிய தூதர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "UK Parliament discusses attaching HR conditions to IMF bailout",
  "body_lines": [
    "COLOMBO (News 1st); Conservative Member of the Parliament of United Kingdom, Eliot Colburn urged for the UK Government ensure that any IMF bail-out is attached to human rights conditions, similar to that of GSP+.",
    "UK MP Eliot Colburn also pointed out that while the economic crisis on the island has indeed led to increased militarization in Sri Lanka, the Rajapaksa Government continues to fall apart.",
    "Member of the United Kingdom Parliament and the The Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State for Foreign, Commonwealth and Development Affairs, Vicky Ford has insisted that the current economic situation in Sri Lanka does not distract the country from human rights, and in response to MP Colburn, stated that the UK will work with fellow members on international debt forums on a solution to the country’s debt problem, and to improve the situation with regard to human rights.",
    "The UK Parliament Member, speaking further, mentioned that although the articles of the IMF do allow for conditionality linked to economic policy or to tackling the balance of payments, there is no provision to impose political-linked or human rights-linked conditionality in the IMF process.",
    "Therefore, Ford said that they will work with fellow members on international debt forums on a solution to the country’s debt problem, as well as continuing to lobby the Sri Lankan Government and working in other international forums on human rights.",
    "MP Ford continued to state that the Prime Minister had underlined UK’s continuing support for the people of Sri Lanka during their economic difficulties, and offered UK support through multilateral organizations such as the World Bank and IMF, and international forums such as the Paris Club.",
    "“We have a very significant voice on international debt forums and we are working closely with Paris Club members and multilateral organizations to find solutions to the debt crisis.” she added.",
    "EU Ambassadors urge President to send firm message on future economic plans"
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "UK Parliament discusses attaching HR conditions to IMF bailout",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Conservative Member of the Parliament of United Kingdom, Eliot Colburn urged for the UK Government ensure that any IMF bail-out is attached to human rights conditions, similar to that of GSP+.",
        "UK MP Eliot Colburn also pointed out that while the economic crisis on the island has indeed led to increased militarization in Sri Lanka, the Rajapaksa Government continues to fall apart.",
        "Member of the United Kingdom Parliament and the The Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State for Foreign, Commonwealth and Development Affairs, Vicky Ford has insisted that the current economic situation in Sri Lanka does not distract the country from human rights, and in response to MP Colburn, stated that the UK will work with fellow members on international debt forums on a solution to the country’s debt problem, and to improve the situation with regard to human rights.",
        "The UK Parliament Member, speaking further, mentioned that although the articles of the IMF do allow for conditionality linked to economic policy or to tackling the balance of payments, there is no provision to impose political-linked or human rights-linked conditionality in the IMF process.",
        "Therefore, Ford said that they will work with fellow members on international debt forums on a solution to the country’s debt problem, as well as continuing to lobby the Sri Lankan Government and working in other international forums on human rights.",
        "MP Ford continued to state that the Prime Minister had underlined UK’s continuing support for the people of Sri Lanka during their economic difficulties, and offered UK support through multilateral organizations such as the World Bank and IMF, and international forums such as the Paris Club.",
        "“We have a very significant voice on international debt forums and we are working closely with Paris Club members and multilateral organizations to find solutions to the debt crisis.” she added.",
        "EU Ambassadors urge President to send firm message on future economic plans"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "UK Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Parliament of United Kingdom",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eliot Colburn",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the UK Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "GSP+",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Eliot Colburn",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Rajapaksa Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the United Kingdom Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commonwealth and Development Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vicky Ford",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colburn",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ford",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ford",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Paris Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Paris Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "EU Ambassadors",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "එක්සත් රාජධානියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව IMF ඇපදීම සඳහා මානව සම්පත් කොන්දේසි අනුයුක්ත කිරීම ගැන සාකච්ඡා කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); එක්සත් රාජධානියේ කොන්සර්වේටිව් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී, එලියට් කොල්බර්න් එක්සත් රාජධානියේ රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ ඕනෑම IMF ඇපදීමක් GSP+ හා සමාන මානව හිමිකම් කොන්දේසිවලට අනුයුක්ත කර ඇති බවට සහතික වීමයි.",
        "එක්සත් රාජධානියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී එලියට් කොල්බර්න් ද පෙන්වා දුන්නේ දිවයිනේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සැබවින්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මිලිටරිකරණය වැඩි කිරීමට හේතු වී ඇති අතර, රාජපක්ෂ රජය දිගින් දිගටම බිඳ වැටෙන බවයි.",
        "එක්සත් රාජධානියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සහ විදේශ, පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය සහ සංවර්ධන කටයුතු පිළිබඳ පාර්ලිමේන්තු නියෝජ්‍ය රාජ්‍ය ලේකම්, Vicky Ford අවධාරනය කර ඇත්තේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය මානව හිමිකම්වලින් රට නොසලකන බවත්, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී කොල්බර්න්ට ප්‍රතිචාර වශයෙන් , එක්සත් රාජධානිය රටේ ණය ගැටලුවට විසඳුමක් සහ මානව හිමිකම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් තත්ත්වය වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම සඳහා ජාත්‍යන්තර ණය සංසදවල සෙසු සාමාජිකයන් සමඟ කටයුතු කරන බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "එක්සත් රාජධානියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයා වැඩිදුරටත් අදහස් දක්වමින් කියා සිටියේ IMF හි වගන්ති මගින් ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිපත්තියට සම්බන්ධ කොන්දේසිවලට හෝ ගෙවුම් ශේෂය පාලනය කිරීමට ඉඩ සලසන නමුත් IMF තුළ දේශපාලන සම්බන්ධ හෝ මානව හිමිකම් සම්බන්ධ කොන්දේසි පැනවීමට ප්‍රතිපාදන නොමැති බවයි. ක්රියාවලිය.",
        "එබැවින්, ඔවුන් රටේ ණය ප්‍රශ්නයට විසඳුමක් සඳහා ජාත්‍යන්තර ණය සංසදවල සෙසු සාමාජිකයින් සමඟ කටයුතු කරන බව මෙන්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයට දිගින් දිගටම බලපෑම් කරමින් මානව හිමිකම් පිළිබඳ අනෙකුත් ජාත්‍යන්තර සංසදවල කටයුතු කරන බව ෆෝඩ් පැවසීය.",
        "ෆෝඩ් මන්ත්‍රීවරයා දිගින් දිගටම ප්‍රකාශ කළේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවගේ ආර්ථික දුෂ්කරතාවලදී එක්සත් රාජධානියේ අඛණ්ඩ සහයෝගය අවධාරණය කළ අතර, ලෝක බැංකුව සහ IMF වැනි බහුපාර්ශ්වික සංවිධාන සහ පැරිස් ක්ලබ් වැනි ජාත්‍යන්තර සංසද හරහා එක්සත් රාජධානියේ සහාය ලබා දුන් බවයි.",
        "\"ජාත්‍යන්තර ණය සංසද පිළිබඳව අපට ඉතා වැදගත් හඬක් ඇති අතර ණය අර්බුදයට විසඳුම් සෙවීම සඳහා අපි පැරිස් සමාජ ශාලාවේ සාමාජිකයින් සහ බහුපාර්ශ්වික සංවිධාන සමඟ සමීපව කටයුතු කරමින් සිටිමු.\" ඇය වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසුවාය.",
        "අනාගත ආර්ථික සැලසුම් පිළිබඳ ස්ථිර පණිවිඩයක් යවන ලෙස යුරෝපා සංගම් තානාපතිවරු ජනාධිපතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටිති"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එලියට් කොල්බර්න්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානියේ රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "GSP+",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එලියට් කොල්බර්න්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ ආණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය හා සංවර්ධන කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විකී ෆෝඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝල්බර්න්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆෝඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆෝඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැරිස් සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පැරිස් සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "EU තානාපතිවරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "IMF பிணை எடுப்பிற்கு HR நிபந்தனைகளை இணைப்பது குறித்து UK பாராளுமன்றம் விவாதிக்கிறது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); யுனைடெட் கிங்டமின் கன்சர்வேடிவ் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் எலியட் கோல்பர்ன் எந்தவொரு IMF பிணையெடுப்பும் GSP+ போன்ற மனித உரிமைகள் நிபந்தனைகளுடன் இணைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதை உறுதிசெய்யுமாறு UK அரசாங்கத்தை வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "ஐக்கிய இராச்சிய நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் எலியட் கோல்பர்ன், தீவின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி உண்மையில் இலங்கையில் அதிகரித்த இராணுவமயமாக்கலுக்கு இட்டுச் சென்றாலும், ராஜபக்சே அரசாங்கம் தொடர்ந்து வீழ்ச்சியடைந்து வருவதாகவும் சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "ஐக்கிய இராச்சிய நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினரும் வெளிநாட்டு, பொதுநலவாய மற்றும் அபிவிருத்தி விவகாரங்களுக்கான நாடாளுமன்ற துணைச் செயலாளருமான விக்கி ஃபோர்ட், இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நிலைமை மனித உரிமைகளில் இருந்து நாட்டைத் திசைதிருப்பாது என்று வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளார். , நாட்டின் கடன் பிரச்சனைக்கு தீர்வு காண்பதற்கும், மனித உரிமைகள் தொடர்பாக நிலைமையை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கும், சர்வதேச கடன் மன்றங்களில் சக உறுப்பினர்களுடன் UK செயல்படும் என்று கூறியது.",
        "ஐக்கிய இராச்சிய நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மேலும் பேசுகையில், சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் கட்டுரைகள் பொருளாதாரக் கொள்கையுடன் இணைக்கப்பட்ட நிபந்தனைகளையோ அல்லது கொடுப்பனவு சமநிலையை சமாளிப்பதையோ அனுமதித்தாலும், IMF இல் அரசியல் சார்ந்த அல்லது மனித உரிமைகள் தொடர்பான நிபந்தனைகளை விதிக்க எந்த ஏற்பாடும் இல்லை என்று குறிப்பிட்டார். செயல்முறை.",
        "எனவே, நாட்டின் கடன் பிரச்சினைக்கு தீர்வு காண சர்வதேச கடன் மன்றங்களில் சக உறுப்பினர்களுடன் இணைந்து பணியாற்றுவதோடு, இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தை தொடர்ந்தும், மனித உரிமைகள் தொடர்பான மற்ற சர்வதேச மன்றங்களில் பணியாற்றுவோம் என்று Ford கூறியது.",
        "இலங்கை மக்களின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிகளின் போது பிரிட்டனின் ஆதரவை பிரதமர் அடிக்கோடிட்டுக் காட்டினார் என்றும், உலக வங்கி மற்றும் IMF போன்ற பலதரப்பு நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் Paris Club போன்ற சர்வதேச மன்றங்கள் மூலம் பிரிட்டன் ஆதரவை வழங்கியதாகவும் எம்.பி. ஃபோர்ட் தொடர்ந்து கூறினார்.",
        "\"சர்வதேச கடன் மன்றங்களில் எங்களுக்கு மிகவும் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க குரல் உள்ளது மற்றும் கடன் நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வு காண பாரிஸ் கிளப் உறுப்பினர்கள் மற்றும் பலதரப்பு நிறுவனங்களுடன் நாங்கள் நெருக்கமாக பணியாற்றி வருகிறோம்.\" அவள் சேர்த்தாள்.",
        "எதிர்கால பொருளாதார திட்டங்கள் குறித்து உறுதியான செய்தியை அனுப்புமாறு ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றிய தூதர்கள் ஜனாதிபதியை வலியுறுத்துகின்றனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இங்கிலாந்து பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய இராச்சியத்தின் பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எலியட் கோல்பர்ன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இங்கிலாந்து அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "GSP+",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எலியட் கோல்பர்ன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்ச அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய இராச்சிய பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமன்வெல்த் மற்றும் வளர்ச்சி விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கி ஃபோர்டு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோல்பர்ன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃபோர்டு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃபோர்டு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ் கிளப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ் கிளப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றிய தூதர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}