{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Petition-challenging-appointment-of-Ranil-as-MP-SC-to-deliver-order-tomorrow/342-241300",
  "time_ut": 1658138536,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Petition challenging appointment of Ranil as MP: SC to deliver order tomorrow",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Petition challenging appointment of Ranil as MP: SC to deliver order tomorrow",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Supreme Court has fixed for tomorrow to announce whether it grants leave to proceed with a Fundamental Rights petition filed challenging the legality of the appointment of UNP leader Ranil Wickremasinghe as a Member of Parliament.",
        "General Secretary of Vinivida Peramuna Nagananda Kodituwakku filed this petition seeking a declaration that UNP leader Ranil Wickremasinghe is disqualified and not entitled to be elected as Member of Parliament of the UNP.",
        "Supreme Court three-judge-bench comprising Justices Gamini Marapana, Shiran Goonaratne and Janak de Silva announced that order regarding court's decision to grant leave to proceed will be announced today.",
        "Meanwhile, Deputy Solicitor General Kanishka de Silva appearing for the Attorney General raised preliminary objections against the petition citing it has been filed out of time.",
        "She further alleged that the petitioner has filed this petition concealing the material facts to effect that similar application filed by the petitioner has been dismissed by Supreme Court.",
        "While agreeing with preliminary objections raised by Attorney General, President's Counsel Ronald Perera appearing for Acting President moved Court to dismiss the petition in limine.",
        "The Petitioner states the sovereignty in the people which includes the election of MPs is an inalienable right protected by the Constitution itself and the people’s right to elect Members of Parliament at their choice, is an essential ingredient of sovereignty in the people, which cannot be defeated by way of an ordinary piece of legislation like Parliamentary Election Act.",
        "Kodituwakku states the supreme law of the land, the Constitution, clearly specified that National List nominations shall be presented to the Election Commission within one week from the Notice received by the Party Secretaries from the Election Commission.",
        "The Petitioner states that the General Secretary of UNP had failed to comply with the Notices served on them by the former Election Commission Chairman within the mandatory period specified by the Article 99A of the Constitution to tender the name to the fill the National List MP slot allocated for UNP by the Election Commission.",
        "The Petitioner states that he is entitled to a declaration that his right to equality and equal treatment before law under Article 12(1) has been violated by the Election Commission who had elected Ranil Wickremasinghe without jurisdiction.",
        "President's Counsel Ronald Perera with counsel Eraj de Silva appeared for Acting President Ranil Wickremasinghe. (Lakmal Sooriyagoda)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "tomorrow",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fundamental Rights",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vinivida Peramuna Nagananda Kodituwakku",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gamini Marapana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shiran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Goonaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janak de Silva",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kanishka de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ronald Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliamentary Election Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "National List",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Election Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Notice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Party Secretaries",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Election Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Notices",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Election Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Article 99A of the Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Election Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Article 12(1",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Election Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ronald Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eraj de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakmal Sooriyagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රනිල් මන්ත්‍රී ධුරයට පත්කිරීම අභියෝගයට ලක්කරමින් ගොනුකර ඇති පෙත්සම හෙට නියෝගයක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ නායක රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ලෙස පත්කිරීමේ නීත්‍යානුකූලභාවය අභියෝගයට ලක්කරමින් ගොනු කර ඇති මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් පෙත්සමක් විභාග කිරීමට අවසර ලබා දෙන්නේද යන්න ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය හෙට දින නියම කර තිබේ.",
        "විනිවිද පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් නාගානන්ද කොඩිතුවක්කු මහතා විසින් මෙම පෙත්සම ගොනු කළේ එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ නායක රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා නුසුදුස්සෙකු බවත් එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධූරයට තේරී පත්වීමට ඔහුට අයිතියක් නොමැති බවත් ප්‍රකාශ කරන ලෙසයි.",
        "ගාමිණී මාරපන, ශිරාන් ගුණරත්න සහ ජනක් ද සිල්වා යන ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ ත්‍රිපුද්ගල ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ විනිසුරු මඩුල්ල ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ඉදිරියට යාමට අවසර ලබාදීමට අධිකරණය ලබාදුන් තීන්දුව පිළිබඳ නියෝගය අද ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන බවයි.",
        "මේ අතර නීතිපතිවරයා වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි නියෝජ්‍ය සොලිසිටර් ජනරාල් කණිෂ්ක ද සිල්වා මහතා පෙත්සමට එරෙහිව මූලික විරෝධතා මතු කළේ එය කල් ඉකුත් වී ඇති බව පවසමිනි.",
        "පෙත්සම්කරු විසින් ගොනු කර තිබූ සමාන අයදුම්පතක් ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය විසින් නිෂ්ප්‍රභ කර ඇති බවට කරුණු සඟවා මෙම පෙත්සම ගොනු කර ඇති බවද ඇය වැඩිදුරටත් චෝදනා කළාය.",
        "නීතිපතිවරයා විසින් ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලද මූලික විරෝධතාවලට එකඟ වන අතර, වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ රොනල්ඩ් පෙරේරා මහතා මෙම පෙත්සම සීමා සහිතව නිෂ්ප්‍රභ කරන ලෙස අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කළේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම ඇතුළු ජනතා පරමාධිපත්‍යය ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවෙන්ම ආරක්‍ෂා කර ඇති අහිමි කළ නොහැකි අයිතිවාසිකමක් බවත්, තම අභිමතය පරිදි මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමට ජනතාවට ඇති අයිතිය පරාජය කළ නොහැකි ජනතා පරමාධිපත්‍යයේ අත්‍යවශ්‍ය අංගයක් බවත් පෙත්සම්කරු පවසයි. පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණ පනත වැනි සාමාන්‍ය පනතක් මගින්.",
        "කොඩිතුවක්කු පවසන්නේ රටේ උත්තරීතර නීතිය වන ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ පැහැදිලිව දක්වා ඇති ජාතික ලැයිස්තු නාමයෝජනා මැතිවරණ කොමිෂන් සභාවෙන් පක්ෂ ලේකම්වරුන්ට ලැබුණු දැනුම්දීමෙන් සතියක් ඇතුළත මැතිවරණ කොමිසමට ඉදිරිපත් කළ යුතු බවයි.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 99A ව්‍යවස්ථාවෙන් නියම කර ඇති ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රීධුරය පිරවීමට නියමිත කාලසීමාව තුළ එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ මහලේකම්වරයා හිටපු මැතිවරණ කොමිෂන් සභාවේ සභාපතිවරයා විසින් තමන් වෙත ලබාදුන් දැනුම්දීම්වලට අනුකූලව කටයුතු කිරීමට අපොහොසත් වූ බව පෙත්සම්කරු පවසයි. එජාපයට මැතිවරණ කොමිසමෙන්.",
        "12(1) වගන්තිය යටතේ සමානාත්මතාවයට සහ නීතිය ඉදිරියේ සමාන සැලකීමට ඇති අයිතිය අධිකරණ බලයකින් තොරව රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ පත්කළ මැතිවරණ කොමිසම විසින් උල්ලංඝනය කර ඇති බවට ප්‍රකාශයක් කිරීමට තමාට හිමිකම් ඇති බව පෙත්සම්කරු පවසයි.",
        "වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වෙනුවෙන් ජනාධිපති නීතීඥ රොනල්ඩ් පෙරේරා මහතා සහ නීතිඥ එරාජ් ද සිල්වා මහතා පෙනී සිටියේය. (ලක්මාල් සූරියගොඩ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "හෙට",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විනිවිද පෙරමුණ නාගානන්ද කොඩිතුවක්කු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාමිණී මාරපන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශිරාන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුණරත්න ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනක් ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කනිෂ්ක ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොනල්ඩ් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණ පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැතිවරණ කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතියක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දැනුම්දීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පක්ෂ ලේකම්වරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැතිවරණ කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දැන්වීම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැතිවරණ කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 99A වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැතිවරණ කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වගන්තිය 12(1",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැතිවරණ කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොනල්ඩ් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එරාජ් ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්මාල් සූරියගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரணிலை எம்.பி.யாக நியமித்ததை எதிர்த்து தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட மனு: உச்சநீதிமன்றம் நாளை உத்தரவு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தலைவர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக நியமித்தமைக்கு எதிராக தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ள அடிப்படை உரிமை மீறல் மனுவைத் தொடர்வதற்கு அனுமதி வழங்கப்படுமா என்பதை அறிவிப்பதற்கு உச்ச நீதிமன்றம் நாளை மறுதினம் தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தலைவர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தகுதி நீக்கம் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார் எனவும், ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக தெரிவு செய்யப்படுவதற்கு அவருக்கு தகுதியில்லை எனவும் அறிவிக்குமாறு கோரி வினிவிட பெரமுனவின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் நாகானந்த கொடிதுவாக்கு இந்த மனுவை தாக்கல் செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "உச்ச நீதிமன்ற நீதியரசர்களான காமினி மாரப்பன, ஷிரான் குணரத்ன மற்றும் ஜனக் டி சில்வா ஆகிய மூவரடங்கிய நீதியரசர்கள் குழாம் இன்று அனுமதி வழங்குவதற்கான நீதிமன்றத்தின் தீர்மானம் தொடர்பான உத்தரவு அறிவிக்கப்படும் என அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், சட்டமா அதிபர் சார்பில் ஆஜரான பிரதி சொலிசிட்டர் ஜெனரல் கனிஷ்க டி சில்வா, மனு தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ள காலக்கெடுவைக் காரணம் காட்டி பூர்வாங்க ஆட்சேபனைகளைத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மேலும், மனுதாரர் தாக்கல் செய்த இதேபோன்ற விண்ணப்பம் உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தால் தள்ளுபடி செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதற்கான உண்மைகளை மறைத்து மனுதாரர் இந்த மனுவை தாக்கல் செய்துள்ளதாகவும் அவர் குற்றம் சாட்டியுள்ளார்.",
        "சட்டமா அதிபரினால் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட பூர்வாங்க ஆட்சேபனைகளுக்கு உடன்பட்ட அதேவேளை, பதில் ஜனாதிபதியின் சார்பில் ஆஜரான ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி ரொனால்ட் பெரேரா, மனுவை வரம்புக்குள் தள்ளுமாறு நீதிமன்றத்தை நாடினார்.",
        "மக்களிடம் உள்ள இறையாண்மை என்பது அரசியலமைப்புச் சட்டத்தால் பாதுகாக்கப்பட்ட பிரிக்க முடியாத உரிமை என்றும், மக்கள் தங்கள் விருப்பப்படி நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களைத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கும் உரிமை என்றும் மனுதாரர் கூறுகிறார். பாராளுமன்ற தேர்தல் சட்டம் போன்ற ஒரு சாதாரண சட்டத்தின் மூலம்.",
        "தேசியப் பட்டியல் வேட்புமனுக்கள் தேர்தல்கள் ஆணைக்குழுவிடமிருந்து கட்சிச் செயலாளர்களால் பெறப்பட்ட அறிவிப்பிலிருந்து ஒரு வாரத்திற்குள் தேர்தல்கள் ஆணைக்குழுவிடம் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்று நாட்டின் உச்சபட்ச சட்டமான அரசியலமைப்பில் தெளிவாகக் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "முன்னாள் தேர்தல்கள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் தலைவரால் வழங்கப்பட்ட தேசியப்பட்டியல் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பதவிக்கான பெயரை வழங்குவதற்கு அரசியலமைப்பின் 99A விதியினால் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ள கட்டாய காலப்பகுதிக்குள் ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் இணங்கத் தவறியதாக மனுதாரர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சிக்கு தேர்தல் ஆணையம்.",
        "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை அதிகார வரம்பில்லாமல் தெரிவு செய்த தேர்தல்கள் ஆணைக்குழுவால் 12(1) பிரிவின் கீழ் சமத்துவம் மற்றும் சட்டத்தின் முன் சமமாக நடத்தப்படுவதற்கான தனது உரிமையை மீறுவதாக பிரகடனம் செய்ய உரிமை உள்ளதாக மனுதாரர் கூறுகிறார்.",
        "பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க சார்பில் ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி ரொனால்ட் பெரேரா மற்றும் சட்டத்தரணி எராஜ் டி சில்வா ஆகியோர் ஆஜராகியிருந்தனர். (லக்மால் சூரியகொட)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "நாளை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடிப்படை உரிமைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வினிவிட பெரமுன நாகானந்த கொடிதுவாக்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமினி மாரப்பன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷிரன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குணரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனக் டி சில்வா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கனிஷ்க டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரொனால்ட் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற தேர்தல் சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பட்டியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேர்தல் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கவனிக்கவும்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்சி செயலாளர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேர்தல் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அறிவிப்புகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேர்தல் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பின் பிரிவு 99A",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேர்தல் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கட்டுரை 12(1",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேர்தல் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரொனால்ட் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எராஜ் டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்மால் சூரியகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}