{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/world-bank-to-grant-110-mln-loan-to-crisis-hit-sri-lanka-for-fertilizer-import-minister-96972/",
  "time_ut": 1657024260,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "World Bank to grant $110 mln loan to crisis-hit Sri Lanka for fertilizer import – Minister",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "World Bank to grant $110 mln loan to crisis-hit Sri Lanka for fertilizer import – Minister",
      "author": "Neshella Perera",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – The World Bank has agreed to provide 110 million US dollars to purchase fertilizer to Sri Lanka, Agriculture Minister Mahinda Amaraweera said on Tuesday as the island nation is facing a looming food shortage amid an economic crisis.",
        "Sri Lanka’s fertilizer shortage has hit the production of its staple food rice and the price of rice has already more than doubled due to supply shortage. The rice production has reduced by up to 40 percent in the last Maha cultivation season ended in February this year, the government has said.",
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s gamble to make the country ‘only organic cultivation’ by banning chemical fertilizer hit farmers as well as consumers due to lower production.",
        "The ban was lifted in November last year, but the country could not import any fertilizer as it does not have dollars.",
        "“The amount given by the World Bank goes as a concessionary loan. It is not a commercial loan,” Amaraweera told the weekly cabinet media briefing on Tuesday (05) adding that the loan will bear lower interest rate.",
        "He also said the World Food Program (WFP) has pledged to provide 365,000 urea bags free of charge for low income Sri Lankan farmers.",
        "Amaraweera said the ultimate goal is to have a successful Maha cultivation season which starts in November this year to ensure self-sufficiency in rice production.",
        "“To have a successful Maha season we are underway with the relevant discussions. We will be able to produce the required rice with no requirement of importing in the next Maha season.” (Colombo/July 05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "World Bank",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "110",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "110 million US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "up to 40 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "February this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "November last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the World Food Program",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "365,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "November this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the next Maha season",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අර්බුදකාරී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පොහොර ආනයනය සඳහා ලෝක බැංකුව ඩොලර් මිලියන 110 ක ණයක් ලබා දෙන බව අමාත්‍යවරයා පවසයි",
      "author": "නෙෂෙල්ලා පෙරේරා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ආර්ථික අර්බුදයක් මධ්‍යයේ දිවයිනේ ජාතිය ආහාර හිඟයකට මුහුණ දී සිටින හෙයින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පොහොර මිලදී ගැනීම සඳහා ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 110 ක් ලබා දීමට ලෝක බැංකුව එකඟ වී ඇති බව කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර අඟහරුවාදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පොහොර හිඟය එහි ප්‍රධාන ආහාර සහල් නිෂ්පාදනයට බලපා ඇති අතර සැපයුම් හිඟය හේතුවෙන් සහල් මිල දැනටමත් දෙගුණයකට වඩා වැඩි වී ඇත. මේ වසරේ පෙබරවාරි මාසයේ අවසන් වූ පසුගිය මහ වගා කන්නයේ සහල් නිෂ්පාදනය සියයට 40 කින් පමණ අඩු වී ඇති බව රජය පවසයි.",
        "රසායනික පොහොර තහනම් කරමින් රට ‘කාබනික වගාවක් පමණක්’ කිරීමේ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ සූදුව නිෂ්පාදනය අඩුවීම නිසා ගොවීන්ට මෙන්ම පාරිභෝගිකයාට ද පහර වැදුණි.",
        "පසුගිය වසරේ නොවැම්බර් මාසයේදී මෙම තහනම ඉවත් කළ නමුත් ඩොලර් නොමැති නිසා රටට පොහොර ආනයනය කිරීමට නොහැකි විය.",
        "“ලෝක බැංකුවෙන් දෙන මුදල සහන ණයක් විදියට යනවා. එය වාණිජ ණයක් නොවේ, ”අඟහරුවාදා (05) සතිපතා කැබිනට් මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී අමරවීර කියා සිටියේ ණය සඳහා අඩු පොලී අනුපාතයක් දරනු ඇති බවයි.",
        "අඩු ආදායම්ලාභී ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ගොවීන් සඳහා යූරියා මළු 365,000ක් නොමිලේ ලබාදීමට ලෝක ආහාර වැඩසටහන (WFP) ප්‍රතිඥා දී ඇති බව ද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "අමරවීර මහතා පැවසුවේ සහල් නිෂ්පාදනයේ ස්වයංපෝෂිතභාවය සහතික කිරීම සඳහා මේ වසරේ නොවැම්බර් මාසයේ ආරම්භ වන සාර්ථක මහ වගා කන්නයක් ඇති කිරීම අවසාන ඉලක්කය බවයි.",
        "“සාර්ථක මහ කන්නයක් ගත කරන්න අපි අදාළ සාකච්ඡා කරගෙන යනවා. ඉදිරි මහ කන්නයේදී ආනයනය කිරීමේ අවශ්‍යතාවයකින් තොරව අවශ්‍ය සහල් නිෂ්පාදනය කිරීමට අපට හැකි වෙනවා.” (කොළඹ/ජූලි 05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "110",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 110 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 40 දක්වා",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ පෙබරවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසරේ නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක ආහාර වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "365,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ මහ කන්නය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நெருக்கடியில் சிக்கியுள்ள இலங்கைக்கு உர இறக்குமதிக்காக 110 மில்லியன் டொலர் கடனை உலக வங்கி வழங்கவுள்ளது – அமைச்சர்",
      "author": "நெஷெல்லா பெரேரா",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கைக்கு உரம் கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்கு உலக வங்கி 110 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களை வழங்குவதற்கு இணக்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளதாக விவசாய அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீர செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் உரத் தட்டுப்பாடு அதன் பிரதான உணவு அரிசியின் உற்பத்தியை பாதித்துள்ளது மற்றும் வழங்கல் பற்றாக்குறை காரணமாக அரிசியின் விலை ஏற்கனவே இரண்டு மடங்காக அதிகரித்துள்ளது. இந்த ஆண்டு பெப்ரவரி மாதத்துடன் முடிவடைந்த மகா பயிர்ச்செய்கைப் பருவத்தில் அரிசி உற்பத்தி 40 வீதம் வரை குறைந்துள்ளதாக அரசாங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இரசாயன உரத்தை தடைசெய்து நாட்டை ‘இயற்கை பயிர்ச்செய்கை மாத்திரம்’ ஆக்குவதற்கான ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் சூதாட்டம் குறைந்த உற்பத்தி காரணமாக விவசாயிகளையும் நுகர்வோரையும் பாதித்தது.",
        "கடந்த ஆண்டு நவம்பரில் தடை நீக்கப்பட்டது, ஆனால் நாட்டில் டாலர்கள் இல்லாததால் எந்த உரத்தையும் இறக்குமதி செய்ய முடியவில்லை.",
        "“உலக வங்கி வழங்கும் தொகை சலுகைக் கடனாகப் போகிறது. இது வணிகக் கடன் அல்ல” என்று செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (05) வாராந்த அமைச்சரவை ஊடகவியலாளர் மாநாட்டில் அமரவீர கூறினார்.",
        "குறைந்த வருமானம் பெறும் இலங்கை விவசாயிகளுக்கு 365,000 யூரியா பைகளை இலவசமாக வழங்க உலக உணவுத் திட்டம் (WFP) உறுதியளித்துள்ளதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "நெல் உற்பத்தியில் தன்னிறைவை உறுதி செய்வதற்காக இவ்வருடம் நவம்பரில் தொடங்கும் வெற்றிகரமான மஹா பயிர்ச்செய்கைப் பருவத்தை நடத்துவதே இறுதி இலக்கு என அமரவீர கூறினார்.",
        "“ஒரு வெற்றிகரமான மஹா பருவத்தை நாங்கள் நடத்துவது தொடர்பான கலந்துரையாடல்களை மேற்கொண்டு வருகிறோம். அடுத்த மகா பருவத்தில் இறக்குமதி செய்ய வேண்டிய அவசியமின்றி தேவையான அரிசியை உற்பத்தி செய்ய முடியும்” என்றார். (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை 05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "உலக வங்கி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "110",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "110 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 சதவீதம் வரை",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு பிப்ரவரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு நவம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உலக உணவு திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "365,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு நவம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த மகா பருவம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}