{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ලංකාවේ-පළමු-තැපැත්පත-නිකුත්-කර-වසර-150ක්-පිරීමට-සමරු-තැපැල්පතක්/101-619129",
  "time_ut": 1662027977,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ලංකාවේ පළමු තැපැත්පත නිකුත් කර වසර 150ක් පිරීමට සමරු තැපැල්පතක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A commemorative postcard to mark 150 years since the first post in Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A special commemorative postcard was issued today (1) at the Parliament Complex to mark 150 years since the first postcard was issued in Sri Lanka.",
        "There, this commemorative postcard was presented to Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena by the Minister of Transport, Highways and Mass Media Mr. Acharya Bandula Gunawardena.",
        "Acharya Bandula Gunawardena, Minister of Transport, Highways and Mass Media said that 1000 of these special commemorative postcards will be issued and can be purchased at a price of 300 rupees.",
        "Sri Lanka's first postcard was issued on September 1, 1872, a two-cent stamp with a portrait of Queen Victoria.",
        "This special commemorative postcard has been issued with a photo of the first postcard in this country.",
        "Former Speaker Chamal Rajapakse, Members of Parliament Mudita Prashanthi Soysa, Dr. Gayashan Navanda, Yadamini Gunawardena, Secretary of the Ministry of Mass Media Anusha Palpita, Postmaster General Ranjith Ariratne and senior officials of the Postal Department were also present on this occasion."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "150 years",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "first",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliament Complex",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "150 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mass Media",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 1, 1872",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two-cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Queen Victoria",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chamal Rajapakse",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament Mudita Prashanthi Soysa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gayashan Navanda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yadamini Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Mass Media Anusha Palpita",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Postmaster General",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Ariratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Postal Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලංකාවේ පළමු තැපැත්පත නිකුත් කර වසර 150ක් පිරීමට සමරු තැපැල්පතක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පළමු තැපැල්පත නිකුත් කර 150 වසරක් සපිරීම නිමිත්තෙන් විශේෂ සමරු තැපැල්පතක් නිකුත් කිරීම පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණයේදී අද (1) සිදුකෙරිණි.",
        "එහිදී මෙම සමරු තැපැල්පත ප්‍රවාහන, මහාමාර්ග හා ජනමාධ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය අචාර්ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා විසින් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා වෙත පිළිගන්වනු ලැබිණි.",
        "මෙම විශේෂ සමරු තැපැල්පත් 1000ක ප්‍රමාණයක් නිකුත් කරන අතර එය රුපියල් 300ක මිලකට මිලදී ගත හැකි බව ප්‍රවාහන, මහාමාර්ග හා ජනමාධ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය අචාර්ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පළමු තැපැල්පත 1872 වර්ෂයේ සැප්තැම්බර් 01 වන දින නිකුත්කර ඇති අතර, එය ශත දෙකක වටිනාකමින් යුතු මුද්දරය වික්ටෝරියා රැජිනගේ උඩුකය රූපයක් සහිත වූවකි.",
        "මෙම විශේෂ සමරු තැපැල්පත මෙරට පළමු තැපැල්පතේ ඡායාරූපයක් සහිතව නිකුත් කර තිබේ.",
        "හිටපු කතානායක චමල් රාජපක්ෂ, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන මුදිතා ප්‍රශාන්ති සොයිසා, වෛද්‍ය ගයාශාන් නවනන්ද, යදාමිනී ගුණවර්ධන, ජනමාධ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම් අනූෂ පැල්පිට, තැපැල්පති රංජිත් ආරිරත්න යන මහත්ම මහත්මීහු සහ තැපැල් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිළධාරීහු ද මෙම අවස්ථාවට එක්ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අවුරුදු 150 යි",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "පළමුවන",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 150 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන මාධ්‍ය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 1, 1872",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශත දෙකයි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්ටෝරියා රැජින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චමල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මුදිතා ප්‍රශාන්ති සොයිසා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගයාෂාන් නවන්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යදාමිණි ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනමාධ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය අනුෂ පැල්පිට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තැපැල්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් ආරිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තැපැල් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையில் முதல் பதவிக்கு 150 ஆண்டுகள் நிறைவடைந்ததைக் குறிக்கும் வகையில் ஒரு நினைவு அஞ்சல் அட்டை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையில் முதல் தபால் அட்டை வெளியிடப்பட்டு 150 ஆண்டுகள் நிறைவடைந்ததை முன்னிட்டு விசேட நினைவு அஞ்சல் அட்டை இன்று (1) பாராளுமன்ற வளாகத்தில் வெளியிடப்பட்டது.",
        "அங்கு போக்குவரத்து, நெடுஞ்சாலைகள் மற்றும் வெகுஜன ஊடக அமைச்சர் திரு.ஆச்சார்ய பந்துல குணவர்தனவினால் இந்த நினைவு அஞ்சல் அட்டை பிரதமர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தனவிடம் வழங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இவற்றில் 1000 விசேட நினைவு அஞ்சல் அட்டைகள் வழங்கப்படவுள்ளதாகவும், அவற்றை 300 ரூபா விலையில் கொள்வனவு செய்ய முடியும் எனவும் போக்குவரத்து, நெடுஞ்சாலைகள் மற்றும் வெகுஜன ஊடக அமைச்சர் ஆச்சார்ய பந்துல குணவர்தன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் முதல் அஞ்சல் அட்டை செப்டம்பர் 1, 1872 அன்று விக்டோரியா மகாராணியின் உருவப்படத்துடன் கூடிய இரண்டு சென்ட் முத்திரை வெளியிடப்பட்டது.",
        "இந்த நாட்டின் முதல் அஞ்சல் அட்டையின் புகைப்படத்துடன் இந்த சிறப்பு நினைவு அஞ்சல் அட்டை வெளியிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்நிகழ்வில் முன்னாள் சபாநாயகர் சமல் ராஜபக்ஷ, பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான முதித பிரசாந்தி சொய்சா, கலாநிதி கயாஷான் நவந்தா, யதாமினி குணவர்தன, வெகுஜன ஊடக அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் அனுஷ பல்பிட்ட, தபால் மா அதிபர் ரஞ்சித் அரிரத்ன மற்றும் தபால் திணைக்கள உயர் அதிகாரிகள் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "150 ஆண்டுகள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "முதலில்",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற வளாகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "150 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெகுஜன ஊடகம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 1, 1872",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு சென்ட்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்டோரியா மகாராணி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமல் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற முதித பிரசாந்தி சொய்சா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கயாஷன் நவண்டா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாதாமினி குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெகுஜன ஊடக அமைச்சு அனுஷ பல்பிட்ட",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "போஸ்ட் மாஸ்டர் ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சித் அரிரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தபால் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}