{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/business__main/Total-SOE-losses-in-first-4-months-of-2022-surpass-annual-losses-in-2021/245-243147",
  "time_ut": 1660598638,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Total SOE losses in first 4 months of 2022 surpass annual losses in 2021",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Total SOE losses in first 4 months of 2022 surpass annual losses in 2021",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Total loss of 52 key SOEs for first four months of 2022 at Rs.860bn compared to annual loss of Rs.86bn in 2021",
        "Three key contributors to massive losses are CPC, SriLankan Airlines and CEB",
        "Botched rupee depreciation identified as key reason for bloating up of losses",
        "The cumulative losses of 52 key state-owned enterprises (SOEs) during the first four months of 2022 topped the total annual loss recorded in 2021, with Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC) contributing 73 percent of the total SOE losses, driven by foreign exchange losses.",
        "During the first four months of 2022, the Rs.860 billion cumulative loss of the 52 key SOEs outweighed the annual loss of Rs.86 billion in 2021 and Rs.34 billion profit reported in 2020, according to the data parsed by PublicFinance.lk, a platform for public finance-related information in Sri Lanka.",
        "Severely impacted by the depreciation of the rupee, CPC’s loss widened to Rs.628 billion in the four months, far exceeding its annual loss of Rs.82 billion reported in 2021. The foreign exchange losses of CPC stood at Rs.550 billion in the period, which is 21 times higher than the Rs.26 billion reported in the same period in 2021.",
        "Although the government has reintroduced a cost-reflective pricing formula to assure operational sustainability of CPC, the Treasury noted that a multitude of issues remain to be addressed. “The primary concern is the legacy debt of CPC that is predominantly in foreign currency, resulting in frequent foreign exchange losses for the entity, which in turn results in additional fiscal stress for the government and financial stress for the state-owned banks. As a result, CPC has negative equity of Rs.986 billion as at end-April 2022,” it noted.",
        "Meanwhile, SriLankan Airlines (SLA) and the Ceylon Electricity Board (CEB) were the other two key contributors to the",
        "SLA incurred a loss of Rs.248 billion for the four-month period when compared to the Rs.171 billion annual loss recorded in 2021. Similarly, the CEB incurred a loss of Rs.47 billion for the four months, compared to an annual loss of Rs.21 billion 2021.",
        "In addition to the fiscal losses, SLA also has external liabilities that need to be honoured under the challenging operating circumstances where revenue is adversely affected by the decline in tourism and fuel costs have escalated along with the finance costs.",
        "SLA has Rs.618.67 billion in liabilities, including interest-bearing facilities such as a sovereign- guaranteed US $ 175 million international bond, Treasury-guaranteed bank loans from state banks, aircraft leases and debt with trade creditors, primarily with CPC."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "first 4 months of 2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "annual",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2021",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "first four months of 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "annual",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first four months of 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "annual",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "73 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the first four months of 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "annual",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs.34",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PublicFinance.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the four months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "annual",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs.550 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "end-April 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rs.248 billion",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "four-month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "annual",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the four months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "annual",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 175 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "2022 පළමු මාස ​​4 තුළ මුළු SOE පාඩු 2021 දී වාර්ෂික පාඩු ඉක්මවයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "2021 වසරේ රුපියල් බිලියන 86 ක වාර්ෂික පාඩුවට සාපේක්ෂව 2022 පළමු මාස ​​හතර සඳහා ප්‍රධාන SOEs 52 ක මුළු පාඩුව රුපියල් බිලියන 860 කි.",
        "දැවැන්ත පාඩු ලැබීමට ප්‍රධාන දායකයන් තිදෙනෙකු වන්නේ CPC, SriLankan Airlines සහ CEB ය",
        "රුපියල අවප්‍රමාණය වීම පාඩු වැඩි වීමට ප්‍රධාන හේතුව ලෙස හඳුනාගෙන ඇත",
        "2022 පළමු මාස ​​හතර තුළ ප්‍රධාන රාජ්‍ය ව්‍යවසාය (SOEs) 52 ක සමුච්චිත පාඩු 2021 දී වාර්තා වූ මුළු වාර්ෂික අලාභයට වඩා ඉහළින් ඇති අතර, ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව (CPC) මුළු SOE අලාභයෙන් සියයට 73 ක් විදේශ විනිමය අලාභයෙන් මෙහෙයවයි. .",
        "PublicFinance.lk විසින් විග්‍රහ කරන ලද දත්ත වලට අනුව, 2022 පළමු මාස ​​හතර තුළ, ප්‍රධාන SOEs 52 හි රුපියල් බිලියන 860 සමුච්චිත පාඩුව, 2021 දී වාර්තා වූ රුපියල් බිලියන 86 ක වාර්ෂික පාඩුව සහ 2020 දී වාර්තා කළ රුපියල් බිලියන 34 ලාභය ඉක්මවා ගියේය. , ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රාජ්‍ය මූල්‍ය සම්බන්ධ තොරතුරු සඳහා වේදිකාවකි.",
        "රුපියල අවප්‍රමාණය වීම හේතුවෙන් දැඩි ලෙස බලපෑ CPC හි පාඩුව මාස හතර තුළ රුපියල් බිලියන 628 දක්වා පුළුල් වූ අතර එය 2021 වසරේ වාර්තා වූ වාර්ෂික පාඩුව වූ රුපියල් බිලියන 82 ඉක්මවයි. CPC හි විදේශ විනිමය පාඩුව රුපියල් බිලියන 550 ක් විය. කාලසීමාව, එය 2021 එම කාලය තුළ වාර්තා වූ රුපියල් බිලියන 26ට වඩා 21 ගුණයකින් වැඩිය.",
        "CPC හි මෙහෙයුම් තිරසාර බව සහතික කිරීම සඳහා රජය විසින් පිරිවැය පරාවර්තක මිල සූත්‍රයක් නැවත හඳුන්වා දී ඇතත්, ගැටලු රාශියකට විසඳුම් ලබා දීමට ඉතිරිව ඇති බව භාණ්ඩාගාරය සඳහන් කළේය. “ප්‍රධාන අවධානය යොමු වන්නේ CPC හි උරුම ණය ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් විදේශ මුදලින් වන අතර, එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස ආයතනයට නිතර විදේශ විනිමය පාඩු සිදු වන අතර එමඟින් රජයට අතිරේක මූල්‍ය ආතතිය සහ රාජ්‍ය බැංකු සඳහා මූල්‍ය ආතතිය ඇති වේ. එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් වශයෙන්, 2022 අප්‍රේල් අග වන විට CPC සතුව රුපියල් බිලියන 986 ක සෘණ කොටස් ඇත.",
        "මේ අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකන් එයාර්ලයින්ස් (SLA) සහ ලංකා විදුලි බල මණ්ඩලය (CEB) අනෙකුත් ප්‍රධාන දායකයින් දෙක විය.",
        "2021 වසරේ වාර්තා වූ රුපියල් බිලියන 171 ක වාර්ෂික පාඩුව හා සසඳන විට SLA විසින් මාස හතරක කාලය සඳහා රුපියල් බිලියන 248 ක අලාභයක් ලබා ඇත. එසේම, ලංවිම වාර්ෂිකව හා සසඳන විට මාස හතර සඳහා රුපියල් බිලියන 47 ක අලාභයක් ලබා ඇත. 2021 බිලියන 21 ක පාඩුවක්.",
        "මූල්‍ය අලාභයන්ට අමතරව, සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරයේ පහත වැටීම සහ ඉන්ධන පිරිවැය මූල්‍ය පිරිවැය සමඟ ඉහළ ගොස් ඇති නිසා ආදායමට අහිතකර ලෙස බලපාන අභියෝගාත්මක මෙහෙයුම් තත්වයන් යටතේ ගරු කළ යුතු බාහිර වගකීම් ද SLA සතුව ඇත.",
        "SLA සතුව රුපියල් බිලියන 618.67 ක වගකීම් ඇති අතර, ස්වෛරී සහතික කළ ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 175 ක ජාත්‍යන්තර බැඳුම්කර, රාජ්‍ය බැංකුවලින් භාණ්ඩාගාර සහතික කළ බැංකු ණය, ගුවන් යානා කල්බදු සහ වෙළෙඳ ණය හිමියන් සමඟ මූලික වශයෙන් CPC සමඟ ණය වැනි පොලී සහිත පහසුකම් ඇතුළුව."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "2022 පළමු මාස ​​4",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "වාර්ෂික",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2021",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 පළමු මාස ​​හතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 පළමු මාස ​​හතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 73 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 පළමු මාස ​​හතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රු.34",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PublicFinance.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස හතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල් බිලියන 550ක්",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අප්‍රේල් අවසානය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුපියල් බිලියන 248 කි",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස හතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.එල්.ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.එල්.ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 175 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "2022 இன் முதல் 4 மாதங்களில் மொத்த SOE இழப்புகள் 2021 இல் ஆண்டு இழப்புகளை விட அதிகமாகும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "2021ல் ஏற்பட்ட ஆண்டு இழப்பான ரூ.86 பில்லியன்களுடன் ஒப்பிடுகையில், 2022 முதல் நான்கு மாதங்களில் 52 முக்கிய SOEகளின் மொத்த இழப்பு ரூ.860 பில்லியன்",
        "பாரிய இழப்புகளுக்கு மூன்று முக்கிய பங்களிப்பாளர்கள் CPC, SriLankan Airlines மற்றும் CEB ஆகும்",
        "ரூபாய் மதிப்பு சரிவு, நஷ்டம் பெருகுவதற்கு முக்கிய காரணமாகக் கண்டறியப்பட்டுள்ளது",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் முதல் நான்கு மாதங்களில் 52 முக்கிய அரச நிறுவனங்களின் (SOEs) ஒட்டுமொத்த இழப்புகள் 2021 இல் பதிவு செய்யப்பட்ட மொத்த வருடாந்த இழப்பில் முதலிடம் வகிக்கின்றன, இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் (CPC) மொத்த SOE இழப்புகளில் 73 சதவீதத்தை அந்நிய செலாவணி இழப்புகளால் உந்தப்பட்டது. .",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் முதல் நான்கு மாதங்களில், 52 முக்கிய SOE களின் ரூ.860 பில்லியன் ஒட்டுமொத்த இழப்பு, 2021 இல் ரூ.86 பில்லியன் மற்றும் 2020 இல் அறிவிக்கப்பட்ட ரூ.34 பில்லியன் லாபத்தை விட அதிகமாகும். , இலங்கையில் பொது நிதி தொடர்பான தகவல்களுக்கான தளம்.",
        "ரூபாயின் மதிப்பு வீழ்ச்சியால் கடுமையாகப் பாதிக்கப்பட்டது, CPC இன் இழப்பு நான்கு மாதங்களில் ரூ.628 பில்லியனாக விரிவடைந்தது, 2021 இல் அறிவிக்கப்பட்ட அதன் ஆண்டு இழப்பான ரூ.82 பில்லியனைத் தாண்டியது. CPC இன் அந்நியச் செலாவணி இழப்புகள் ரூ.550 பில்லியனாக இருந்தது. காலம், இது 2021 இல் இதே காலகட்டத்தில் பதிவான ரூ.26 பில்லியனை விட 21 மடங்கு அதிகம்.",
        "CPC இன் செயல்பாட்டு நிலைத்தன்மையை உறுதி செய்வதற்காக அரசாங்கம் செலவு-பிரதிபலிப்பு விலை சூத்திரத்தை மீண்டும் அறிமுகப்படுத்தியிருந்தாலும், பல சிக்கல்கள் தீர்க்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்று கருவூலம் குறிப்பிட்டது. \"முதன்மையான கவலை CPC இன் பாரம்பரியக் கடன் ஆகும், இது முக்கியமாக வெளிநாட்டு நாணயத்தில் உள்ளது, இதன் விளைவாக நிறுவனத்திற்கு அடிக்கடி அந்நிய செலாவணி இழப்பு ஏற்படுகிறது, இது அரசாங்கத்திற்கு கூடுதல் நிதி அழுத்தத்தையும், அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான வங்கிகளுக்கு நிதி அழுத்தத்தையும் ஏற்படுத்துகிறது. இதன் விளைவாக, CPC 2022 ஏப்ரல் இறுதியில் ரூ.986 பில்லியனுக்கு எதிர்மறையான ஈக்விட்டியைக் கொண்டுள்ளது,” என்று அது குறிப்பிட்டது.",
        "இதேவேளை, ஸ்ரீலங்கன் எயார்லைன்ஸ் (SLA) மற்றும் இலங்கை மின்சார சபை (CEB) ஆகிய இரண்டு முக்கிய பங்களிப்பாளர்களாகும்.",
        "2021 இல் பதிவான ரூ.171 பில்லியன் வருடாந்த இழப்புடன் ஒப்பிடும் போது, ​​நான்கு மாத காலப்பகுதியில் SLA ரூ.248 பில்லியன் இழப்பை சந்தித்துள்ளது. அதேபோன்று, CEB வருடாந்தத்துடன் ஒப்பிடுகையில், நான்கு மாதங்களில் ரூ.47 பில்லியன் இழப்பை சந்தித்துள்ளது. இழப்பு ரூ.21 பில்லியன் 2021.",
        "நிதி இழப்புகளுக்கு மேலதிகமாக, SLA ஆனது சவாலான இயக்க சூழ்நிலைகளின் கீழ் கௌரவிக்கப்பட வேண்டிய வெளிப்புற பொறுப்புகளையும் கொண்டுள்ளது, அங்கு சுற்றுலாத்துறையின் சரிவு மற்றும் எரிபொருள் செலவுகள் நிதி செலவினங்களுடன் அதிகரித்துள்ளன.",
        "SLA க்கு ரூ.618.67 பில்லியன் பொறுப்புகள் உள்ளன, இதில் ஒரு இறையாண்மை-உத்தரவாதமான US $ 175 மில்லியன் சர்வதேசப் பத்திரம், கருவூலத்தால் உத்தரவாதமளிக்கப்பட்ட வங்கிக் கடன்கள், விமானக் குத்தகைகள் மற்றும் வர்த்தகக் கடனாளர்களுடனான கடன்கள், முதன்மையாக CPC உடனான கடன்கள் உட்பட வட்டி தாங்கும் வசதிகள் உள்ளன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "2022 இன் முதல் 4 மாதங்கள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆண்டு",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2021",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 இன் முதல் நான்கு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 இன் முதல் நான்கு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "73 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 இன் முதல் நான்கு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ.34",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PublicFinance.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ.550 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 2022 இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரூ.248 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 175 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}