{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Monkeypox-not-proven-as-a-sexually-transmittable-disease/342-241804",
  "time_ut": 1658799284,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Monkeypox not proven as a sexually transmittable disease",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Monkeypox not proven as a sexually transmittable disease",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Monkeypox is not proven to be a sexually transmittable disease and it is not clinically proven that it is a disease which mostly affects homosexuals, a Sri Lankan expert said yesterday.",
        "Senior Lecturer Department of Immunology and Molecular Biology Prof. Chandima Jeewandara told Daily Mirror that Monkeypox is not a sexually transmittable disease.",
        "“Monkeypox is yet to be proven to be a sexually transmittable disease while it is not clinically proven that mostly homosexuals fall victim to the disease. Larger number of patients out of the 15,000 globally reported cases are gay people but nothing is proved yet.",
        "However according to data released by the World Health Organization (WHO), the disease could spread through casual contact including skin to skin, mouth to mouth and also through sexual contact. According to WHO, it is not proven that the virus could spread through bodily fluids such as semen, virginal fluid, or breast milk.",
        "Meanwhile Dr. Jeewandara warned on Sunday that the disease could enter Sri Lanka and precautions should be taken to prevent the disease.",
        "WHO during the weekend declared Monkeypox as a global pandemic. (Yohan Perera)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Monkeypox",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Monkeypox",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lecturer Department of Immunology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandima Jeewandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monkeypox",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monkeypox",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the World Health Organization",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WHO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jeewandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the weekend",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monkeypox",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yohan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වඳුරු රෝගය ලිංගිකව සම්ප්‍රේෂණය වන රෝගයක් ලෙස ඔප්පු වී නොමැත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "වඳුරු රෝගය ලිංගිකව සම්ප්‍රේෂණය වන රෝගයක් බව තහවුරු වී නොමැති අතර එය සමලිංගිකයන්ට වැඩි වශයෙන් බලපාන රෝගයක් බවට සායනිකව ඔප්පු වී නොමැති බව ශ්‍රී ලාංකික විශේෂඥයෙක් ඊයේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ප්‍රතිශක්තිකරණ හා අණුක ජීව විද්‍යා අංශයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ කථිකාචාර්ය මහාචාර්ය චන්දිම ජීවන්දර ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත පැවසුවේ වඳුරු යනු ලිංගිකව සම්ප්‍රේෂණය වන රෝගයක් නොවන බවයි.",
        "“වඳුරු උවදුර ලිංගාශ්‍රිතව සම්ප්‍රේෂණය වන රෝගයක් බව තවම ඔප්පු වී නොමැති අතර සමලිංගිකයින් වැඩි වශයෙන් මෙම රෝගයට ගොදුරු වන බව සායනිකව ඔප්පු වී නොමැත. ගෝලීය වශයෙන් වාර්තා වන රෝගීන් 15,000 න් විශාල සංඛ්‍යාවක් සමලිංගික පුද්ගලයින් වන නමුත් තවමත් කිසිවක් ඔප්පු වී නොමැත.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානය (WHO) විසින් නිකුත් කරන ලද දත්ත වලට අනුව, මෙම රෝගය සමෙන් සම, මුඛයෙන් මුඛය සහ ලිංගික සම්බන්ධතා ඇතුළු අනියම් සම්බන්ධතා හරහා පැතිර යා හැකිය. ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානයට අනුව, වෛරසය ශුක්‍රාණු, වර්ජිනල් තරල හෝ මව්කිරි වැනි ශරීර තරල හරහා පැතිර යා හැකි බව ඔප්පු වී නොමැත.",
        "මේ අතර වෛද්‍ය ජීවන්දර ඉරිදා අනතුරු ඇඟවූයේ මෙම රෝගය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඇතුළු විය හැකි බවත් රෝගය වැළැක්වීම සඳහා පූර්වාරක්ෂාවන් ගත යුතු බවත්ය.",
        "WHO සති අන්තයේ වඳුරු පොක්ස් ගෝලීය වසංගතයක් ලෙස ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කළේය. (යොහාන් පෙරේරා)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "වඳුරු උවදුර",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වඳුරු උවදුර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කථිකාචාර්ය ප්රතිශක්තිකරණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්දිම ජීවන්දර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වඳුරු උවදුර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වඳුරු උවදුර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක සෞඛ්ය සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කවුද",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජීවන්දර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සති අන්තය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වඳුරු උවදුර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යොහාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "குரங்கு நோய் பாலியல் ரீதியாக பரவும் நோயாக நிரூபிக்கப்படவில்லை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "குரங்குப்பழம் ஒரு பாலுறவு நோய் என்று நிரூபிக்கப்படவில்லை மற்றும் இது ஓரினச்சேர்க்கையாளர்களை அதிகம் பாதிக்கும் நோய் என்று மருத்துவ ரீதியாக நிரூபிக்கப்படவில்லை என்று இலங்கை நிபுணர் ஒருவர் நேற்று தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நோய்த்தடுப்பு மற்றும் மூலக்கூறு உயிரியல் துறையின் சிரேஷ்ட விரிவுரையாளர் பேராசிரியர் சந்திமா ஜீவந்தர டெய்லி மிரரிடம் கூறுகையில், குரங்குப்பழம் ஒரு பாலுறவு நோய் அல்ல.",
        "“குரங்கு பாக்ஸ் என்பது பாலியல் ரீதியாகப் பரவும் நோயாக இன்னும் நிரூபிக்கப்படவில்லை, அதே சமயம் பெரும்பாலும் ஓரினச்சேர்க்கையாளர்கள் இந்த நோய்க்கு பலியாகின்றனர் என்பது மருத்துவ ரீதியாக நிரூபிக்கப்படவில்லை. உலகளவில் பதிவாகியுள்ள 15,000 நோயாளிகளில் அதிக எண்ணிக்கையிலான நோயாளிகள் ஓரினச்சேர்க்கையாளர்கள் ஆனால் இதுவரை எதுவும் நிரூபிக்கப்படவில்லை.",
        "\"மக்களின் அபிலாஷைகளை நிறைவேற்ற உங்களால் முடிந்த அனைத்தையும் செய்வீர்கள் என்று நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம், அதை நோக்கி நாங்கள் எங்கள் முழு நிறுவனத்தையும் விரிவுபடுத்துகிறோம்\" என்று சங்கம் ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதேவேளை, இந்நோய் இலங்கைக்குள் நுழையக் கூடும் எனவும், இந்நோய் வராமல் தடுக்க முன்னெச்சரிக்கை நடவடிக்கை எடுக்க வேண்டும் எனவும் டாக்டர் ஜீவந்தரா ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை எச்சரித்துள்ளார்.",
        "WHO வார இறுதியில் குரங்கு காய்ச்சலை உலகளாவிய தொற்றுநோயாக அறிவித்தது. (யோஹான் பெரேரா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "குரங்கு நோய்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "குரங்கு நோய்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நோயெதிர்ப்புத் துறை விரிவுரையாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்திம ஜீவந்தர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குரங்கு நோய்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குரங்கு நோய்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உலக சுகாதார நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WHO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜீவந்தரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வார இறுதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குரங்கு நோய்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோஹான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}