{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/රඹුටන්-ඇටයක්-සිරවී-දස-හැවිරිදි-දරුවා-මරුට/1-615836",
  "time_ut": 1656915638,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රඹුටන් ඇටයක් සිරවී දස හැවිරිදි දරුවා මරුට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A ten-year-old child died after getting stuck in a rambutan bone",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to the Kankasanturaya police, a ten-year-old child who was admitted to Thelippalai Hospital, Jaffna, died after a rambutan seed got stuck in his throat.",
        "While eating the rambutan that was brought home, the rambutan seed got stuck in the child's throat and due to difficulty in breathing, the parents took the child to Thelippalai Hospital and died.",
        "The police said that the deceased was a ten-year-old boy named Dharmarasa Darshikan, a resident of Kollankalandi, Kankasanturaya, Jaffna.",
        "The child was eating rambutan when a rambutan seed got stuck and the child's parents, who did not know that a rambutan seed was stuck in his throat, took him to the hospital thinking it was an illness, police said.",
        "A Telippalai hospital spokesman said that if the parents had been aware of the rambutan seed stuck in the child's throat, the child's life could have been saved."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ten-year-old",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kankasanturaya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ten-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thelippalai Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thelippalai Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ten-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dharmarasa Darshikan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kollankalandi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kankasanturaya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රඹුටන් ඇටයක් සිරවී දස හැවිරිදි දරුවා මරුට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රඹුටන් ඇටයක් උගුරේ සිරවීමෙන් යාපනය, තෙලිප්පලෙයි රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කළ වයස අවුරුදු දහයක දරුවකු  ජිවිතක්ෂයට පත්ව ඇති බව කන්කසන්තුරය පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "නිවසට ගෙනවිත් තිබූ රඹුටන් ආහාරයට ගනිමින් සිටියදී රඹුටන් ඇටය දරුවාගේ උගුරේ සිරවී ඇති අතර හුස්ම ගැනීමේ අපහසුතාවයක් හේතුවෙන් මාපියන් දරුවා තෙලිප්පලෙයි රෝහල වෙත රැගෙනවිත් සිටියදී ජීවිතක්ෂයටපත්ව තිබේ.",
        "එලෙස මියගොස් ඇත්තේ යාපනය,කන්කසන්තුරය,කොල්ලන්කලන්ඩි ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි ධර්මරාසා දර්ෂිකන් නමැති දස හැවිරිදි පිරිමි දරුවකු බව පොලිසිය සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "දරුවා රඹුටන් කමින් සිටි අවස්ථාවේ රඹුටන් ඇටය සිරවී ඇති අතර රඹුටන් ඇටයක් උගුරේ සිරවී ඇති බවට නොදැන සිටි දරුවාගේ මාපියන් ඇතිවූ අසනීප තත්වයක් බවට සිතා රෝහල ගතකොට ඇති බව පොලිසිය පැවසීය.",
        "දරුවාගේ උගුරේ සිරවී තිබූ රඹුටන් ඇටය පිළිබඳ මාපියන් දැණුවත්ව සිටියේනම් දරුවාගේ ජීවිතය බේරාගැනීමට හැකිව තිබූ බවද තෙලිප්පලෙයි රෝහල් ප්‍රකාශකයකු සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දස හැවිරිදි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කන්කසන්තුරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දස හැවිරිදි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙලිප්පලෙයි රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තෙලිප්පලෙයි රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දස හැවිරිදි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධර්මරස දර්ශිකන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොල්ලන්කලන්ඩි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කන්කසන්තුරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரம்புட்டான் எலும்பில் சிக்கி பத்து வயது குழந்தை உயிரிழந்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "யாழ்ப்பாணம் தெல்லிப்பளை வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்ட பத்து வயதுக் குழந்தையொன்று தொண்டையில் ரம்புட்டான் விதை சிக்கி உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக காங்கேசன்துறை பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "வீட்டிற்கு கொண்டு வந்த ரம்புட்டானை சாப்பிட்டு கொண்டிருந்த போது குழந்தையின் தொண்டையில் ரம்புட்டான் விதை சிக்கியதால் மூச்சு விடுவதில் சிரமம் ஏற்பட்டதால் பெற்றோர்கள் குழந்தையை தெல்லிப்பளை வைத்தியசாலைக்கு கொண்டு சென்று உயிரிழந்துள்ளனர்.",
        "யாழ்ப்பாணம், காங்கசந்துறை கொல்லங்கலண்டியைச் சேர்ந்த பத்து வயதுடைய தர்மராசா தர்ஷிகன் என்ற சிறுவனே உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "குழந்தை ரம்புட்டான் சாப்பிட்டுக் கொண்டிருந்த போது, ​​ரம்புட்டான் விதை ஒன்று சிக்கியது, தொண்டையில் ரம்புட்டான் விதை சிக்கியதை அறியாத குழந்தையின் பெற்றோர், சுகவீனம் என நினைத்து மருத்துவமனைக்கு அழைத்துச் சென்றதாக போலீசார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "குழந்தையின் தொண்டையில் ரம்புட்டான் விதை சிக்கியிருப்பதை பெற்றோர்கள் அறிந்திருந்தால் குழந்தையின் உயிரை காப்பாற்றியிருக்க முடியும் என தெலிப்பளை வைத்தியசாலை பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பத்து வயது",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கங்கசந்துராய",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்து வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெல்லிப்பளை வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தெல்லிப்பளை வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பத்து வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தர்மராசா தர்ஷிகன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொல்லங்கலாண்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கங்கசந்துராய",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}