{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/20/court-bars-anyone-from-moving-close-to-bandaranaike-statue/",
  "time_ut": 1658315400,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Court bars anyone from moving close to Bandaranaike Statue",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Court bars anyone from moving close to Bandaranaike Statue",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Colombo Fort Magistrate Thilina Gamage issued an order barring any faction from entering or gathering within a 50 meter radius of the Bandaranaike Statue located in Galle Face, Colombo.",
        "Sri Lanka Police told the court that there is a possible attempt being made to cause harm to the statue.",
        "IMF hopes to complete Sri Lanka aid talks ‘as quickly as possible’"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Bandaranaike Statue",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Fort Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 meter",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandaranaike Statue",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බණ්ඩාරනායක ප්‍රතිමාව අසලින් කිසිවකුට ගමන් කිරීම අධිකරණය තහනම් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); කොළඹ ගාලු මුවදොර පිහිටි බණ්ඩාරනායක පිළිරුවට මීටර් 50ක අරය තුළ කිසිදු පාර්ශවයකට ඇතුළුවීම හෝ ඒකරාශී වීම වළක්වමින් කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් තිළිණ ගමගේ නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කළා.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය අධිකරණයට ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ප්‍රතිමාවට හානි කිරීමේ උත්සාහයක් පවතින බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආධාර සාකච්ඡා ‘හැකි ඉක්මනින්’ අවසන් කිරීමට IMF බලාපොරොත්තු වේ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක පිළිරුව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීටර් 50",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක පිළිරුව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பண்டாரநாயக்கா சிலைக்கு அருகில் யாரும் செல்லக்கூடாது என நீதிமன்றம் தடை விதித்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); கொழும்பு, காலி முகத்திடலில் அமைந்துள்ள பண்டாரநாயக்க சிலைக்கு 50 மீற்றர் சுற்றளவிற்குள் எந்தவொரு பிரிவினரும் பிரவேசிக்கவோ அல்லது ஒன்று கூடவோ தடை விதித்து கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் திலின கமகே உத்தரவு பிறப்பித்துள்ளார்.",
        "சிலைக்கு சேதம் விளைவிக்க முயற்சிகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்படலாம் என இலங்கை பொலிஸார் நீதிமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான உதவிப் பேச்சுக்களை ‘முடிந்தவரை விரைவாக’ முடிக்க சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் நம்புகிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்க சிலை",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 மீட்டர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்க சிலை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி முகம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}