{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Hirunika-says-Ranjans-release-to-attract-certain-political-groups/108-241302",
  "time_ut": 1658139139,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Hirunika says Ranjan’s release to attract certain political groups",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Hirunika says Ranjan’s release to attract certain political groups",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The objective behind the expected release of former actor-turned parliamentarian Ranjan Ramanayake may be to attract certain political groups, former Samagi Jana Balawegaya MP (SJB) Hirunika Premachnadra said today.",
        "While speaking to journalists, Ms. Premachandra said that the release of Mr. Ramanayake was a tactic by the Acting President to attract a target political group. “We saw the acting President visiting the soldiers who were injured in clashes with the protesters. We never saw him visiting the injured soldiers in the past. The objective of this would have been to build up his image. Promising to release Mr, Ramanayake could also be an exercise to build his image,” she said.",
        "Asked whether the release of Ranjan Ramanayake could be a political deal, the former MP said it is not clear as the latter is a person who dislikes deals. “However I feel that Mr. Ramanayake will come out as an Aragalist’ she said at the same time.",
        "“We keep mum if people accept Mr. Wickremesinghe as the President in the event he is elected, but will fight on if people do not endorse it. At the same time election of Mr. Wickremesinghe as the President could create a bloodbath if criticism against him escalates,” she said.",
        "“It is better if Mr. Wickremesinghe takes up a post in the UN ,” she suggested.",
        "Further Ms. Premachandra said she does not condone torching Mr. Wickremesinghe’s private residence. “The attack gathered momentum after some journalists were attacked by the security forces near his residence,” she said.  (Yohan Perera)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranjan",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hirunika Premachnadra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premachandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UN",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premachandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yohan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඇතැම් දේශපාලන කණ්ඩායම් ආකර්ෂණය කර ගැනීමට රන්ජන් නිදහස් කළ බව හිරුණිකා පවසයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක නිදහස් කර ගැනීමේ අපේක්ෂාව පිටුපස ඇතැම් දේශපාලන කණ්ඩායම් ආකර්ෂණය කර ගැනීම විය හැකි බව සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී (SJB) හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමච්නද්‍රා අද ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "මාධ්‍යවේදීන් අමතමින් ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර මහත්මිය කියා සිටියේ රාමනායක මහතා නිදහස් කිරීම වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉලක්ක කරගත් දේශපාලන කණ්ඩායමක් ආකර්ෂණය කර ගැනීමේ උපක්‍රමයක් බවයි. “අපි දැක්කා වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිතුමා විරෝධතාකරුවන් සමඟ ඇති වූ ගැටුම්වලින් තුවාල ලැබූ සෙබළුන් බලන්න යනවා. ඔහු පසුගිය කාලයේ තුවාල ලැබූ සොල්දාදුවන් බලන්නට යනවා අපි දැකලා නැහැ. ඔහුගේ ප්‍රතිරූපය ගොඩ නැගීම මෙහි අරමුණ වන්නට ඇත. රාමනායක මහතා නිදහස් කරන බවට පොරොන්දු වීමත් ඔහුගේ ප්‍රතිරූපය ගොඩනැගීමේ ව්‍යායාමයක් විය හැකියි.",
        "රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා නිදහස් කිරීම දේශපාලන ඩීල් එකක් විය හැකිද යන්න විමසූ විට හිටපු මන්ත්‍රීවරයා කියා සිටියේ රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා ඩීල්වලට අකමැති පුද්ගලයකු නිසා එය පැහැදිලි නැති බවයි. “කොහොම වුණත් රාමනායක මහත්තයා අරගලකාරයෙක් විදියට එළියට එයි කියලා මට දැනෙනවා’ ඇය ඒ සමඟම පැවසුවාය.",
        "“වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා තේරී පත් වූ විට ජනතාව ඔහුව ජනාධිපති ලෙස පිළිගන්නේ නම් අපි කට පියාගෙන සිටිමු, නමුත් ජනතාව එය අනුමත නොකරන්නේ නම් සටන් කරන්නෙමු. ඒත් එක්කම වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස තේරී පත්වීමෙන් ඔහුට එරෙහි විවේචන වැඩි වුණොත් ලේ විලක් ඇති කරන්න පුළුවන්.” ඇය පැවසුවාය.",
        "\"වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවිධානයේ තනතුරක් ගන්නවා නම් හොඳයි\" ඇය යෝජනා කළාය.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ගිනි තැබීම අනුමත නොකරන බවද ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර මහත්මිය පැවසුවාය. “ඔහුගේ නිවස අසලදී සමහර මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට ආරක්ෂක අංශ විසින් පහර දීමෙන් පසුව ප්‍රහාරය වේගවත් විය,” ඇය පැවසුවාය. (යොහාන් පෙරේරා)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රන්ජන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමච්නද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එ.ජා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යොහාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சில அரசியல் குழுக்களை கவரவே ரஞ்சனின் விடுதலை என்று ஹிருணிகா கூறுகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் நடிகரும் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருமான ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவின் விடுதலையின் நோக்கம் சில அரசியல் குழுக்களை ஈர்க்கும் நோக்கமாக இருக்கலாம் என முன்னாள் சமகி ஜன பலவேகய எம்.பி (SJB) ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சனத்ரா தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஊடகவியலாளர்களிடம் பேசும் போது திரு.ராமநாயக்கவின் விடுதலையானது, குறிவைத்துள்ள அரசியல் குழுவைக் கவர்ந்து இழுக்கும் ஜனாதிபதியின் தந்திரோபாயமே என திருமதி பிரேமச்சந்திர தெரிவித்தார். “போராட்டக்காரர்களுடனான மோதலில் காயமடைந்த இராணுவ வீரர்களை தற்காலிக ஜனாதிபதி பார்வையிட்டதை நாங்கள் பார்த்தோம். கடந்த காலங்களில் அவர் காயம்பட்ட ராணுவ வீரர்களை சென்று பார்த்ததில்லை. அவரது இமேஜை உருவாக்குவதே இதன் நோக்கமாக இருந்திருக்கும். திருவை விடுவிப்பதாக உறுதியளித்த ராமநாயக்கா தனது இமேஜை கட்டமைக்க ஒரு பயிற்சியாகவும் இருக்கலாம்,” என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவின் விடுதலையானது அரசியல் ஒப்பந்தமாக இருக்குமா என வினவியதற்கு பதிலளித்த முன்னாள் எம்.பி. “இருப்பினும், மிஸ்டர். ராமநாயகம் ஒரு அரகலிஸ்டாக வருவார் என்று நான் உணர்கிறேன்” என்று அவள் அதே நேரத்தில் சொன்னாள்.",
        "“திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்கவை ஜனாதிபதியாக மக்கள் ஏற்றுக்கொண்டால் நாங்கள் அமைதியாக இருக்கிறோம், ஆனால் மக்கள் அதை ஆதரிக்கவில்லை என்றால் போராடுவோம். அதே சமயம் திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்கவை ஜனாதிபதியாக தெரிவு செய்வது அவருக்கு எதிரான விமர்சனங்கள் அதிகரித்தால் இரத்தக்களரியை உருவாக்கலாம்,” என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்க ஐ.நா.வில் ஒரு பதவியை ஏற்றால் நல்லது,\" என்று அவர் பரிந்துரைத்தார்.",
        "மேலும் திரு.விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்திற்கு தீ வைப்பதை தான் மன்னிக்கவில்லை என திருமதி பிரேமச்சந்திர கூறினார். \"அவரது இல்லத்திற்கு அருகே சில பத்திரிகையாளர்கள் பாதுகாப்புப் படையினரால் தாக்கப்பட்டதை அடுத்து தாக்குதல் வேகத்தை அதிகரித்தது,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார். (யோஹான் பெரேரா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரஞ்சன்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சனத்ரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமச்சந்திர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமச்சந்திர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோஹான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}