{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/main_picture/පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට-ආරක්ෂාව-දුන්-හමුදාව-පොලිසිය-අතරට-ජනපති-යයි/11-616760",
  "time_ut": 1658318209,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ආරක්ෂාව දුන් හමුදාව-පොලිසිය අතරට ජනපති යයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The President goes between the army and the police who gave security to the parliament",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickramasinghe met with the security forces and the police deployed to protect the Parliament premises today (20) afternoon and thanked them.",
        "The President got out of his car and walked among the security forces while leaving the Parliament after assuming the office of President and thanked the three armed forces and the police for their mission to protect the parliamentary democracy.",
        "A tight security system was implemented in the Parliament premises for the election of the President.",
        "At three places, the President got down from the car and thanked the troops.",
        "Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe was elected to the 9th Parliament on June 23, 2021 as a National List Member of Parliament for the only National List Member of Parliament that the party was entitled to in the 2020 General Election.",
        "Born on March 24, 1949, Mr. Ranil Shrian Wickramasinghe held the position of Prime Minister in the previous good governance government.",
        "He started his political career as the chief organizer of the United National Party in Kelaniya Constituency in the middle of 1970 and was later appointed as the chief organizer of Byagama Constituency.",
        "In 1977, he was elected as a Member of Parliament for the first time. Jayawardena was the youngest minister in the government cabinet where he held the position of Minister of Youth Affairs and Defense. He was the Minister of Foreign Affairs at the age of 28, and later served as the Cabinet Minister for Youth Affairs, Education and Industry, Science and Technology.",
        "Mr. Wickramasinghe, who also served as the Leader of the Parliament between March 06, 1989 and May 07, 1993, served as the Leader of the Opposition in the Parliament of Sri Lanka from 1994 to 2001 and from 2004 to 2015.",
        "He was first elected as the Prime Minister of Sri Lanka on May 7, 1993 and held that position until August 19, 1994. Mr. Wickramasinghe was the Prime Minister of Sri Lanka for the second time from December 9, 2001 to April 2, 2004, for the third time from January 9, 2015 to August 21, 2015, for the fourth time from August 24, 2015 to October 26, 2018, and for the fifth time from December 16, 2018 to November 21, 2019. Has been done.",
        "After that, after the resignation of the former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa on the 9th of May, Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe returned to the post of Prime Minister on the 12th of the same month and was working in that position and after the resignation of Mr. Gotabhaya Rajapaksa from the post of President, according to the Constitution last (14) Since then, he became the acting president.",
        "Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe, an alumnus of the Royal College of Colombo, was later elected to the Faculty of Law of the University of Colombo and sworn in as a lawyer."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20) afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 23, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "National List",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National List",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "March 24, 1949",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Shrian",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the middle of 1970",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Byagama Constituency",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Youth Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defense",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the age of 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Youth Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Education",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "between March 06, 1989",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 07, 1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliament of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1994 to 2001",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2004 to 2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 7, 1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 19, 1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "December 9, 2001",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "April 2, 2004",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "January 9, 2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21, 2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "fourth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 24, 2015 to October 26, 2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "fifth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "December 16, 2018 to",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "November 21, 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Royal College of Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Faculty of Law of the University of Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ආරක්ෂාව දුන් හමුදාව-පොලිසිය අතරට ජනපති යයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු පරිශ්‍රයේ ආරක්ෂාවට යොදවා සිටි ආරක්ෂක හමුදාව සහ පොලිසිය හමුවී ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අද (20) පස්වරුවේ ඔවුන්ට ස්තුතිය පළ ක⁣ළේය.",
        "ජනාධිපති ධුරයට පත්වී පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් පිටත්ව යන අතරතුර සිය රථයෙන් බැස ආරක්ෂක හමුදාව අතරට ගිය ජනාධිපතිවරයා පාර්ලිමේන්තු ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය ආරක්ෂා කිරීම සඳහා ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදා සහ පොලිසිය කළ මෙහෙවර පිළිබඳව ස්තුතිය ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබෙි.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත්කර ගැනීමෙි ඡන්ද විමසීම වෙනුවෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු පරිශ්‍රයේ දැඩි ආරක්ෂක ක්‍රම වෙිදයක් ක්‍රියාත්මක විය.",
        "ස්ථාන තුනක දී ජනාධිපතිවරයා රථයෙන් බැස හමුදාවන්ට ස්තුතිය පළ කර තිබෙි.",
        "2020 මහ මැතිවරණයේ දී එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය අන්ත පරාජයට පත් වූ පසුබිම යටතේ පක්ෂයට හිමි වූ එකම ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රී මන්ත්‍රීධූරය සදහා රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා  ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ලෙස පසුගිය 2021 වර්ෂයේ ජුනි මස 23 දින 09 වැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට තේරී පත් විය.",
        "1949 මාර්තු 24 දා උපත ලද රනිල් ශ්‍රියාන් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පසුගිය යහපාලන රජයේ ද අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරය ද හෙබවීය.",
        "1970 වසරේ මැද භාගයේදී කැළණිය ආසනයේ එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායකවරයා ලෙස සිය දේශපාලන දිවිය ආරම්භ කළ එතුමා පසුව බියගම ආසනයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක ධූරයට පත් කෙරුණි.",
        "1977 දී ප්‍රථම වතාවට පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ලෙස තේරී පත්වූ ඒ මහතා ජේ.ආර්. ජයවර්ධන රජයේ කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයේ සිටි ලාබාලතම අමාත්‍යවරයා වූ අතර එහිදී ඔහු දැරුවේ තරුණ කටයුතු හා රැකීරක්ෂා අමාත්‍ය ධූරයයි. අවුරුදු 28 දී විදේශ කරයුතු නියෝජිත ඇමතිවරයා වූ හෙතෙම, පසුව තරුණ කටයුතු, අධ්‍යාපන සහ කර්මාන්ත, විද්‍යා සහ තාක්ෂණ ලෙස කැබිනට් අමාත්‍යධුර හෙබවීය.",
        "1989 මාර්තු 06 - 1993 මැයි 07 දක්වා කාලය තුළ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සභානායක ධුරයේද කටයුතු කළ වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා 1994 සිට 2001 දක්වාත් 2004 සිට 2015 දක්වාත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ විපක්ෂ නායක ධුරයේ කටයුතු කළේය.",
        "එතුමා ප්‍රථම වතාවට 1993 මැයි 7 වැනිදා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අග්‍රමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස තේරී පත්වූ අතර 1994 අගෝස්තු 19 දක්වා එම තනතුර හෙබවීය.  වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා, දෙවන වරට 2001 දෙසැම්බර් 9 සිට 2004 අප්‍රේල් 02 දක්වාත්, තෙවන වරට 2015 ජනවාරි 9 සිට 2015 අගෝස්තු 21 දක්වාත්, සිව්වන වරට 2015 අගෝස්තු 24 සිට 2018 ඔක්තෝම්බර් 26 දක්වාත්, පස්වන වරට 2018 දෙසැම්බර් මස 16 වන දින සිට 2019 නොවැම්බර් 21දක්වාත් මෙරට අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කර තිබේ.",
        "ඉන් අනතුරුව පසුගිය මැයි මස 09 දින හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස් වීමෙන් පසු  රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා එම මස 12 වැනිදා නැවත අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරයට පත් වී එම ධුරයේ කටයුතු කරමින් සිටි අතර ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ජනාධිපති ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස් වීමෙන් පසුව ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව ප්‍රකාරව පසුගිය (14) දා සිට වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති ධුරයට ද පත්විය.",
        "කොළඹ රාජකීය විදුහලේ ආදි සිසුවෙකු වන රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පසුව කොළඹ විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයේ නීති පීඨයට තේරී පත්වී නීතිඥයෙකු ලෙස දිවුරුම් දී තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 ජූනි 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1949 මාර්තු 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් ශ්‍රියන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1970 මැද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බියගම මැතිවරණ කොට්ඨාසය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යෞවන කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යෞවන කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්යාපන",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1989 මාර්තු 06 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993 මැයි 07",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1994 සිට 2001 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2004 සිට 2015 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993 මැයි 7",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1994 අගෝස්තු 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙසැම්බර් 9, 2001",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 2, 2004",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015 ජනවාරි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21, 2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතරවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015 අගෝස්තු 24 සිට 2018 ඔක්තෝබර් 26 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පස්වන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙසැම්බර් 16, 2018 සිට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොවැම්බර් 21, 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ රාජකීය විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ නීති පීඨය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு பாதுகாப்பு வழங்கிய இராணுவத்திற்கும் பொலிஸாருக்கும் இடையில் ஜனாதிபதி செல்கிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இன்று (20) பிற்பகல் பாராளுமன்ற வளாகத்தின் பாதுகாப்பில் ஈடுபடுத்தப்பட்டுள்ள பாதுகாப்பு படையினர் மற்றும் பொலிஸாரை சந்தித்து நன்றி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியாகப் பதவியேற்றுக் கொண்டதன் பின்னர் பாராளுமன்றத்திலிருந்து வெளியேறும் போது காரில் இருந்து இறங்கி பாதுகாப்புப் படையினர் மத்தியில் நடந்து சென்ற ஜனாதிபதி, பாராளுமன்ற ஜனநாயகத்தைப் பாதுகாப்பதற்காக முப்படையினருக்கும் பொலிஸாருக்கும் நன்றி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "குடியரசுத் தலைவர் தேர்தலையொட்டி, நாடாளுமன்ற வளாகத்தில் பலத்த பாதுகாப்பு ஏற்பாடுகள் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "மூன்று இடங்களில் ஜனாதிபதி காரில் இருந்து இறங்கி படையினருக்கு நன்றி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "திரு. ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க 2020 பொதுத் தேர்தலில் கட்சிக்கு உரிமையுள்ள ஒரே தேசியப் பட்டியல் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருக்கான தேசியப் பட்டியல் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக 2021 ஜூன் 23 அன்று 9ஆவது நாடாளுமன்றத்துக்குத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "1949 ஆம் ஆண்டு மார்ச் மாதம் 24 ஆம் திகதி பிறந்த திரு.ரணில் ஶ்ரியன் விக்கிரமசிங்க கடந்த நல்லாட்சி அரசாங்கத்தில் பிரதமராக பதவி வகித்தார்.",
        "1970 ஆம் ஆண்டின் நடுப்பகுதியில் களனி தொகுதியில் ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் பிரதம அமைப்பாளராக தனது அரசியல் வாழ்க்கையை ஆரம்பித்த அவர் பின்னர் பைகம தொகுதியின் பிரதான அமைப்பாளராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "1977ல் முதன்முறையாக நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராகத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார். ஜயவர்தன இளைஞர் விவகாரம் மற்றும் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சராக பதவி வகித்த அரசாங்க அமைச்சரவையில் இளைய அமைச்சராக இருந்தார். அவர் 28 வயதில் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சராக இருந்தார், பின்னர் இளைஞர் விவகாரங்கள், கல்வி மற்றும் தொழில்துறை, அறிவியல் மற்றும் தொழில்நுட்பத்திற்கான கேபினட் அமைச்சராக பணியாற்றினார்.",
        "மார்ச் 06, 1989 மற்றும் மே 07, 1993 க்கு இடையில் பாராளுமன்றத்தின் தலைவராகவும் பணியாற்றிய திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்க, 1994 முதல் 2001 வரை மற்றும் 2004 முதல் 2015 வரை இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவராக பணியாற்றினார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் பிரதமராக 1993 ஆம் ஆண்டு மே மாதம் 7 ஆம் திகதி முதன்முதலில் தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்ட அவர், 1994 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் 19 ஆம் திகதி வரை அப்பதவியில் இருந்தார். திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்கே இலங்கையின் பிரதமராக 2001 டிசம்பர் 9 முதல் ஏப்ரல் 2, 2004 வரை இரண்டாவது முறையாகவும், மூன்றாவது முறையாக ஜனவரி 9, 2015 முதல் ஆகஸ்ட் 21, 2015 வரை நான்காவது முறையாகவும் ஆகஸ்ட் 24, 2015 முதல் அக்டோபர் 26, 2018 மற்றும் ஐந்தாவது முறையாக டிசம்பர் 16, 2018 முதல் நவம்பர் 21, 2019 வரை செய்யப்பட்டது.",
        "அதன் பின்னர் கடந்த மே மாதம் 9ஆம் திகதி முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ பதவி விலகியதன் பின்னர், அதே மாதம் 12ஆம் திகதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க மீண்டும் பிரதமர் பதவிக்கு வந்து அந்த பதவியில் பணியாற்றிக் கொண்டிருந்தார். ஜனாதிபதி பதவியில் இருந்து கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச, அரசியலமைப்பின் பிரகாரம் கடந்த (14) அன்று முதல் பதில் ஜனாதிபதியானார்.",
        "கொழும்பு ரோயல் கல்லூரியின் பழைய மாணவரான திரு.ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பின்னர் கொழும்பு பல்கலைக்கழக சட்ட பீடத்திற்கு தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டு சட்டத்தரணியாக சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்து கொண்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20) பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 23, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பட்டியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பட்டியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 24, 1949",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் ஷ்ரியன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1970 இன் நடுப்பகுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பயகம தொகுதி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இளைஞர் விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வயது 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இளைஞர் விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்வி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமாதித்தன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 06, 1989 க்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 07, 1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1994 முதல் 2001 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2004 முதல் 2015 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 7, 1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 19, 1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமாதித்தன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிசம்பர் 9, 2001",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 2, 2004",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 9, 2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21, 2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்காவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 24, 2015 முதல் அக்டோபர் 26, 2018 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்தாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிசம்பர் 16, 2018 முதல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 21, 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு ராயல் கல்லூரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் சட்ட பீடம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}