{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131983",
  "time_ut": 1658422173,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "புதிய அமைச்சரவை நாளை புதிய ஜனாதிபதி முன்னிலையில் பதவி ஏற்கும்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The new cabinet will take office tomorrow in the presence of the new president",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "The new cabinet will be sworn in on Friday as an interim measure until an all-party government is formed. Ministers who have already been appointed will take oath tomorrow in the presence of the new President.",
        "Accordingly, the President's Media Division informed that the swearing-in ceremony of the ministers will be held at the Prime Minister's Office located at Flower Street, Colombo - 7.",
        "It is expected that Dinesh Gunawardena may be appointed as the Prime Minister this time. President Ranil Wickremesinghe has announced that he will seek the cooperation of all parties representing Parliament to form an all-party government.",
        "However, no party has announced a firm resolution on this. However, National People's Shakti leader Anurakumara Dissanayake announced at a media conference tomorrow that if an interim government is formed within a certain period of time, cooperation can be explored.",
        "Although Leader of the Opposition Sajith Premadasa did not comment on his participation in an all-party government, he posted on Twitter about the meeting with the President yesterday, \"Instead of giving a large number of ministerial posts to allow political opportunists to squander the country's national resources, the idea is to strengthen the parliamentary committee system to meet national expectations.\" I presented it to the President', he said.",
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe, responding to the media's questions regarding the vacancy in the post of Prime Minister, said, \"The one who has the majority support in the Parliament will be Pramara. \"I cannot appoint the Prime Minister because I am the only member of my party,\" he replied. However, political analysts have stated that the power to appoint the Prime Minister is vested in the Executive President as per the Constitution."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "tomorrow",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Flower Street",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "National People's Shakti",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anurakumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Opposition Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Twitter",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pramara",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Executive",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉදිරියේ නව කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය හෙට වැඩ භාර ගැනීමට නියමිතයි",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවන තුරු අතුරු පියවරක් ලෙස නව කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය සිකුරාදා දිවුරුම් දීමට නියමිතය. දැනටමත් පත් කර ඇති අමාත්‍යවරුන් හෙට නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව, අමාත්‍යවරුන් දිවුරුම් දීමේ උත්සවය කොළඹ - 7, මල් වීදියේ පිහිටි අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයේදී පැවැත්වෙන බවයි ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය දැනුම් දුන්නේ.",
        "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා මෙවර අගමැති ධූරයට පත්වීමට ඉඩ ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ. සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන සියලු පක්ෂවල සහයෝගය ලබා ගන්නා බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් කිසිදු පාර්ශ්වයක් ස්ථිර යෝජනාවක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර නොමැත. කෙසේ වෙතත්, යම් කාලසීමාවක් තුළ අන්තර්වාර ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවුවහොත් සහයෝගීතාව පිළිබඳව සොයා බැලිය හැකි බව ජාතික ජනතා ශක්ති නායක අනුරකුමාර දිසානායක මහතා හෙට පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවකට සහභාගි වීම ගැන අදහස් පළ නොකළත් ඊයේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා හමුවීම ගැන ට්විටර් ගිණුමේ සටහනක් තබමින්, “දේශපාලන අවස්ථාවාදීන්ට රට කාබාසිනියා කිරීමට ඉඩ සලසමින් විශාල ඇමතිකම් ලබා දෙනවා වෙනුවට. ජාතික සම්පත්, ජාතික බලාපොරොත්තු ඉටු වන පරිදි පාර්ලිමේන්තු කාරක සභා ක්‍රමය ශක්තිමත් කිරීම තමයි අදහස.” මම එය ජනාධිපතිතුමාට ඉදිරිපත් කළා.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරය පුරප්පාඩු වීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් මාධ්‍යවේදීන් නැගූ ප්‍රශ්නවලට පිළිතුරු දුන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා, “පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ බහුතර කැමැත්ත තියෙන කෙනා ප්‍රමරේ තමයි. “මගේ පක්‍ෂයේ එකම සාමාජිකයා මම නිසා මට අගමැති පත් කරන්න බැහැ,” ඔහු පිළිතුරු දුන්නේය. කෙසේ වෙතත්, ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවට අනුව අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා පත්කිරීමේ බලය විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයාට පැවරී ඇති බව දේශපාලන විශ්ලේෂකයින් ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබෙනවා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හෙට",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මල් වීදිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා ශක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරකුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂය සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්විටර්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රමර",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "විධායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புதிய அமைச்சரவை நாளை புதிய ஜனாதிபதி முன்னிலையில் பதவி ஏற்கும்",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் ஸ்தாபிக்கப்படும் வரை தற்காலிகமாக புதிய அமைச்சரவை நாளை வெள்ளிக்கிழமை பதவியேற்கவுள்ளது. ஏற்கனவே காணப்பட்ட அமைச்சுப்பதவிகளை அமைச்சர்களே நாளை புதிய ஜனாதிபதி முன்னிலையில் பதவியேற்கவுள்ளனர்.",
        "அதற்கமைய கொழும்பு - 7 , பிளவர் வீதியில் அமைந்துள்ள பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்தில் அமைச்சர்கள் பதவியேற்கும் நிகழ்வு இடம்பெறவுள்ளதாக ஜனாதிபதி ஊடகப்பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இம்முறை பிரதமராக தினேஷ் குணவர்தன நியமிக்கப்படலாம் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது. சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் அமைப்பதற்கு பாராளுமன்றத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் அனைத்து கட்சிகளினதும் ஒத்துழைப்பினை கோருவதாக ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க அறிவித்திருக்கின்றார்.",
        "எனினும் எந்தவொரு கட்சியும் இது குறித்து ஸ்திரமான தீர்மானமொன்றை அறிவிக்கவில்லை. எனினும் குறிப்பிட்ட கால வரையறைக்கு உட்பட்ட இடைக்கால அரசாங்கம் அமைக்கப்படுமாயின் அதற்கு ஒத்துழைப்பு வழங்குது குறித்து ஆராய முடியும் என்று தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தியின் தலைவர் அநுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க நாளை ஊடகவியலாளர் மாநாட்டில் அறிவித்தார்.",
        "சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தில் பங்கேற்பது குறித்து எதிர்க்கட்சி தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச எந்த கருத்தினையும் தெரிவிக்காத போதிலும் , நேற்றைய தினம் ஜனாதிபதியுடன் இடம்பெற்ற சந்திப்பு தொடர்பில் டுவிட்டரில் பதிவிட்டுள்ள அவர் , ''அரசியல் சந்தர்ப்பவாதிகள் நாட்டின் தேசிய வளங்களை வீணடிப்பதற்கு இடமளிக்கும் வகையில் பெருமளவான அமைச்சுப்பதவிகளை வழங்குவதற்குப் பதிலாக,  தேசிய ரீதியில் காணப்படும் எதிர்பார்ப்பை அடைந்துகொள்வதற்கு பாராளுமன்ற குழு முறைமையை மேலும் வலுப்படுத்தலாம் என்ற யோசனையையும் ஜனாதிபதியிடம் முன்வைத்தேன்' என்று  தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பிரதமர் பதவிக்கு நிலவும் வெற்றிடம் தொடர்பில் ஊடகவியலாளர்களின் கேள்விகளுக்கு பதிலளித்த ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, ''பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பெரும்பான்மை ஆதரவைக் கொண்டவர் பிரமராவார். எனது கட்சியின் நான் மாத்திரமே இருப்பதால் என்னால் பிரதமரை நியமிக்க முடியாது.'' என்று பதிலளித்தார். எவ்வாறிருப்பினும் அரசியலமைப்பின் பிரகாரம் பிரதமரை நியமிக்கும் அதிகாரம் நிறைவேற்றதிகார ஜனாதிபதிக்கு காணப்படுவதாக அரசியல் ஆய்வாளர்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நாளை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலர் தெரு",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்க்கட்சியான சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ட்விட்டர்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரமர",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிர்வாகி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}