{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132100",
  "time_ut": 1658568540,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "தம்மிகவின் இடத்திற்கு 3 பெயர்கள் பரிந்துரை",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Suggest 3 names for Dammika's place",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "The names of three members of the Podujana Peramuna have been nominated to fill the vacancy following the resignation of Member of Parliament Dammika Perora.",
        "However, Dhammika Perera has not yet officially announced that she will renounce her parliamentary membership.",
        "While there are unconfirmed reports that Member of Parliament Tammika Perera is resigning, the names of Sri Lanka Podujana Peremana Executive Secretary Renuka Perera, Southern Province Governor Wili Kamake and Central Environment Authority Chairman Siripala Amarasinghe have been nominated at the party level for the vacant position of Member of Parliament.",
        "Following former Finance Minister Bashil Rajapaksa's resignation as Member of Parliament on 09th of last month, Dammika Perera took oath as Member of Parliament on 22nd of last month through the national list.",
        "However, following the political changes that have taken place in the last few days, there have been reports that Member of Parliament Tammika Perera has decided to resign, although she has not yet officially announced her resignation to the Podujana Peramuna."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dammika",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament Dammika Perora",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peremana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Renuka Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southern Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Environment Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Siripala Amarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bashil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "09th of last month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd of last month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the last few days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දම්මිකගේ තැනට නම් 3ක් යෝජනා කරන්න",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී දම්මික පෙරේරා මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමත් සමඟ පුරප්පාඩු වූ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධුරය සඳහා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් තිදෙනෙකුගේ නම් යෝජනා වී තිබේ.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් ධම්මික පෙරේරා සිය පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධූරය අත්හරින බව මෙතෙක් නිල වශයෙන් ප්‍රකාශ කර නොමැත.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ටම්මික පෙරේරා ඉල්ලා අස්වන බවට තහවුරු නොකළ වාර්තා පවතින අතර පුරප්පාඩු වූ එම තනතුර සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ විධායක ලේකම් රේණුකා පෙරේරා, දකුණු පළාත් හිටපු ආණ්ඩුකාර විලී කමකේ සහ මධ්‍යම පරිසර අධිකාරියේ සභාපති සිරිපාල අමරසිංහ යන මහත්වරුන්ගේ නම් පක්ෂ මට්ටමින් යෝජනා වී තිබේ. මන්ත්‍රීවරයාගේ.",
        "හිටපු මුදල් අමාත්‍ය බෂීල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පසුගිය මස 09 වනදා පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් අනතුරුව දම්මික පෙරේරා මහතා ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයා ලෙස පසුගිය 22 වනදා දිවුරුම් දුන්නා.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් පසුගිය දින කිහිපයේ සිදු වූ දේශපාලන වෙනස්කම් හේතුවෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී තම්මික පෙරේරා පොදුජන පෙරමුණෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව මෙතෙක් නිල වශයෙන් ප්‍රකාශ කර නොමැති නමුත් ඇය ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට තීරණය කර ඇති බවට වාර්තා පළ වුණා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දම්මික",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු දම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරේමාන ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රේණුකා පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්‍යම පරිසර අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරිපාල අමරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මස 09 වැනිදාය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මස 22 වැනිදාය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය දින කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தம்மிகவின் இடத்திற்கு 3 பெயர்கள் பரிந்துரை",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் தம்மிக பெரோராவின் பதவி விலகலை தொடர்ந்து ஏற்படும் வெற்றிடத்திற்கு பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் மூன்று உறுப்பினர்களின் பெயர் பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "இருப்பினும் தம்மிக பெரேரா தனது பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்புரிமையை துறப்பதாக இதுவரை உத்தியோகப்பூர்வமாக அறிவிக்கவில்லை.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் தம்மிக பெரேரா பதவி விலகுவதாக உறுதிப்படுத்தப்படாத செய்திகள் வெளியாகியுள்ள நிலையில் அவர் பதவி விலகினால் வெற்றிடாகும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பதவிக்கு ஸ்ரீ லங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமனவின் நிர்வாக செயலாளர் ரேணுக பெரேரா, தென் மாகாண முன்னாள் ஆளுநர் விலி கமகே மற்றும் மத்திய சுற்றாடல் அதிகார சபையின் தலைவர் சிறிபால  அமரசிங்க ஆகியோரின் பெயர்கள் கட்சி மட்டத்தில் பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "முன்னாள் நிதியமைச்சர் பஷில் ராஜபக்ஷ கடந்த மாதம் 09ஆம் திகதி பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பதவியை துறந்ததை தொடர்ந்து தேசிய பட்டியல் ஊடாக தம்மிக பெரேரா கடந்த மாதம் 22ஆம் திகதி பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக பதவி பிரமாணம் செய்துக்கொண்டார்.",
        "இருப்பினும் கடந்த நாட்களில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள அரசியல் மாற்றத்தை தொடர்ந்து பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் தம்மிக்க பெரேரா பதவி விலக தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக செய்திகள் வெளியாகின இருப்பினும் அவர் பதவி விலகல் தொடர்பில் இதுவரை பொதுஜன பெரமுனவிற்கு உத்தியோகப்பூர்வமாக அறிவிக்கவில்லை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தம்மிகா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுனா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் தம்மிக்க பெரோரா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரேமனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரேணுகா பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய சுற்றுச்சூழல் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறிபால அமரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பஷில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம் 09 ஆம் திகதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம் 22ம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த சில நாட்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுனா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}