{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/’බයික්-රේස්’-ගිහින්-තරුණයෙකු-මරුට/11-396309",
  "time_ut": 1660546570,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "’බයික් රේස්’ ගිහින් තරුණයෙකු මරුට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A young man died after going to a 'bike race'",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Piliyandala Police said that a motorcycle ridden by a young man and a motorcycle ridden by a single-wheeler collided head-on yesterday (14th) evening on the Bokundara ICC road.",
        "Pawan Heshan, a 19-year-old resident of Piliandala Pelawatta Gorakapitiya area, who was riding the motorcycle to the race, died in the accident.",
        "The other seriously injured youth has been admitted to the Colombo National Hospital for further treatment.",
        "The deceased youth was using a motorcycle that he requested from a friend while driving at high speed from Bokundara ICC road towards Horana Colombo road with another youth. The police said that the accident occurred when the two motorcycles collided head-on while the motorcycle was moving towards the south.",
        "The police say that after the two motorcycles collided head-on, the motorcycle of the young man who was participating in the race was pulled along the road along with him for about thirty meters and stopped.",
        "A police officer said that steps have been taken to admit the other youths who were seriously injured to the Werahera KDU Hospital.",
        "Police say that the motorcycle ridden by the deceased youth has been missing till now after the accident and the other motorcycle (one wheeler) was found after it was handed over to a motorcycle repair shop in Bokundara area.",
        "The post-mortem examination of the deceased youth is to be conducted at the Kalubowila Teaching Hospital.",
        "Puriyandala Police Station Officer Chief Inspector Vishwanath on the instructions of Traffic Division Station Officer Sub Inspector Lakmina Police Sergeant 31505 Sarathchandra Constables 84752 Dharmawardena 82498 Shashika Constable Ishara conducts investigations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Piliyandala Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bokundara ICC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pawan Heshan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Piliandala Pelawatta Gorakapitiya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Colombo National Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bokundara ICC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Horana Colombo",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Werahera KDU Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bokundara area",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Kalubowila Teaching Hospital",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Puriyandala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Traffic Division Station Officer Sub Inspector",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "’බයික් රේස්’ ගිහින් තරුණයෙකු මරුට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "බෝකුන්දර අයි සි සි මාර්ගයේදී තරුණයෙක් තරඟයට පැදවූ යතුරුපැදියක් සහ  තනි රෝදයෙන්  තරුණයකු  පැද වූ යතුරු පැදියක් ඊයේ (14දා) සවස මුහුණට මුහුණ ගැටීමෙන් එක් තරුණයෙකු මිය ගොස් අනෙක් තරුණයා බරපතළ තුවාල ලබා රෝහල් ගත කළ බව පිලියන්දල පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "අනතුරින් මියගොස් ඇත්තේ  තරඟයට යතුරුපැදිය පැදවූ පිලියන්දල පැලවත්ත ගොරකපිටිය ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිව සිටි පවන් හේශාන් 19  හැවිරිදි තරුණයෙකි.",
        "බරපතළ තුවාල ලද අනෙක් තරුණයා වැඩිදුර ප්‍රතිකාර සඳහා කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කර ඇත.",
        "මියගිය තරුණයා මිතුරකුගෙන් ඉල්ලාගත් යතුරුපැදියක් භාවිතා කරමින්  තවත් තරුණයෙක් සමග බෝකුන්දර  අයි සි සි මාර්ගයේ සිට හොරණ කොළඹ මාර්ගයේ දෙසට අධික වේගයෙන් ධාවනය කිරීමේදී මියගිය තරුණයා ඉදිරියෙන් යතුරුපැදිය ධාවනය කර ඇති අතර ඔහු ඉදිරියෙන් ගමන් ගත් මෝටර් රථයකට ඉස්සර කර  මදක් ඉදිරියට  යාමේදී  ඔහුගේ සමීපතම මිතුරෙකු තනි රෝදයෙන් විරුද්ධ දිශාවේ සිට ඉදිරියට යතුරුපැදිය ධාවනය කර ඇති අතර එම යතුරුපැදිය මාර්ගයේ දකුණු දෙසට ඇදී යාමේ දී  යතුරු පැදි දෙක මුහුණට මුහුණ ගැටීමෙන් මෙම අනතුර වී ඇතැයි පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "යතුරුපැදි දෙක  මුහුණට මුහුණ ගැටීමෙන් අනතුරුව තරඟයට සහභාගි වූ යතුරු පැදියේ සිටි තරුණයාගේ යතුරු පැදිය ඔහුත් සමග මීටර් තිහක් පමණ මාර්ගය දිගේ ඇදී ගොස් නැවතී ඇතැයි පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "අනතුරක් සමඟම වහා ක්‍රියාත්මක වූ සෙසු තරුණයන් බරපතල තුවාල ලබා සිටි තරුණයන් දෙදෙනා  වේරහැර කේ ඩි යු රෝහල වෙත ඇතුළත් කිරීමට පියවර ගනු ලැබ ඇතැයි පොලිස් නිළධාරියෙකු පැවසීය.",
        "අනතුරින් පසු මේ දක්වා මියගිය තරුණයා පැදවූ යතුරුපැදිය අතුරුදහන්ව ඇති අතර  අනෙක් යතුරුපැදිය ( තනි රෝදයෙන් පැද වූ)  බෝකුන්දර ප්‍රදේශයේ යතුරුපැදි අලුත්වැඩියා කරන ස්ථානයකට බාර දී තිබියදී  සොයාගත් බව පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "මිය ගිය තරුණයාගේ පශ්චාත් මරණ පරීක්ෂණය කළුබෝවිල ශික්ෂණ රෝහලේදී සිදු රෝහලේ දී සිදුකිරීමට නියමිතය.",
        "පිළියන්දල පොලිසියේ ස්ථානාධිපති ප්‍රධාන පොලිස් පරීක්ෂක විශ්වනාත් මහතාගේ උපදෙස් මත රථවාහන අංශයේ ස්ථානාධිපති උප පොලිස් පරීක්ෂක  ලක්මිණ පොලිස් සැරයන්31505 සරත්චන්ද්‍ර කොස්තාපල්වරුන් වන 84752 ධර්මවර්ධන 82498  ශෂික  කොස්තාපල් ඉෂාර මහත්තුරු පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පිළියන්දල පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෝකුන්දර අයි.සී.සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pawan Heshan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිළියන්දල පැලවත්ත ගොරකාපිටිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බෝකුන්දර අයි.සී.සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හොරණ කොළඹ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වේරහැර KDU රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bokundara area",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කළුබෝවිල ශික්ෂණ රෝහල",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුරියන්දල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රථවාහන අංශයේ ස්ථානාධිපති උප පොලිස් පරීක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "'பைக் ரேஸ்' சென்ற இளைஞர் ஒருவர் உயிரிழந்தார்.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "போகுந்தர ஐ.சி.சி வீதியில் நேற்று (14) மாலை இளைஞன் ஒருவர் பயணித்த மோட்டார் சைக்கிளும் ஒற்றைச் சக்கர வாகனத்தில் சென்ற மோட்டார் சைக்கிளும் நேருக்கு நேர் மோதி விபத்துக்குள்ளானதாக பிலியந்தலை பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "மோட்டார் சைக்கிளை ஓட்டிச் சென்ற பிலியந்தல பெலவத்த கோரக்கபிட்டிய பிரதேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்த 19 வயதுடைய பவன் ஹேஷான் என்ற இளைஞனே விபத்தில் உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "படுகாயமடைந்த மற்றைய இளைஞர் மேலதிக சிகிச்சைக்காக கொழும்பு தேசிய வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "உயிரிழந்த இளைஞன் மற்றுமொரு இளைஞனுடன் பொகுந்தர ஐ.சி.சி வீதியிலிருந்து ஹொரண கொழும்பு வீதி நோக்கி அதிவேகமாக ஓட்டிச் சென்ற போது நண்பன் கேட்ட மோட்டார் சைக்கிளை பயன்படுத்திய போது மோட்டார் சைக்கிள் சென்று கொண்டிருந்த போது இரண்டு மோட்டார் சைக்கிள்கள் நேருக்கு நேர் மோதியதில் இந்த விபத்து இடம்பெற்றுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர். தெற்கு நோக்கி.",
        "இரண்டு மோட்டார் சைக்கிள்களும் நேருக்கு நேர் மோதியதையடுத்து, பந்தயத்தில் ஈடுபட்டிருந்த இளைஞனின் மோட்டார் சைக்கிள் சுமார் முப்பது மீற்றர் தூரம் வீதியில் இழுத்துச் செல்லப்பட்டு நிறுத்தப்பட்டதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "படுகாயமடைந்த ஏனைய இளைஞர்களை வெரஹெர KDU வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்க நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸ் அதிகாரி ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "உயிரிழந்த இளைஞன் பயணித்த மோட்டார் சைக்கிள் விபத்தின் பின்னர் இதுவரை காணாமல் போயுள்ளதாகவும் மற்றைய மோட்டார் சைக்கிள் (ஒரு சக்கர வாகனம்) பொகுந்தர பிரதேசத்தில் உள்ள மோட்டார் சைக்கிள் திருத்தும் நிலையமொன்றில் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டதன் பின்னர் கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டதாகவும் பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "உயிரிழந்த இளைஞனின் பிரேத பரிசோதனை களுபோவில போதனா வைத்தியசாலையில் நடைபெறவுள்ளது.",
        "போக்குவரத்து பிரிவு நிலைய பொறுப்பதிகாரி சப் இன்ஸ்பெக்டர் லக்மினா பொலிஸ் சார்ஜன்ட் 31505 சரத்சந்திர கான்ஸ்டபிள்கள் 84752 தர்மவர்தன 82498 சஷிகா கான்ஸ்டபிள் இஷாரா ஆகியோரின் அறிவுறுத்தலின் பேரில் புரியந்தலை பொலிஸ் நிலைய பொறுப்பதிகாரி பிரதம பரிசோதகர் விஸ்வநாத் விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பிலியந்தலை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாயங்காலம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "போகுந்தரா ஐ.சி.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pawan Heshan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிலியந்தல பெலவத்த கோரகபிட்டிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு தேசிய வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "போகுந்தரா ஐ.சி.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹொரண கொழும்பு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெரஹெர KDU மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bokundara area",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "களுபோவில போதனா வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புரியந்தலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "போக்குவரத்து பிரிவு நிலைய அலுவலர் சப் இன்ஸ்பெக்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}