{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83755/sjb-will-vote-for-dullas-as-decided-general-secretary",
  "time_ut": 1658282640,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SJB will vote for Dullas as decided - General Secretary",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SJB will vote for Dullas as decided - General Secretary",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) will vote for MP Dullas Alahapperuma in the parliamentary vote for presidency as decided yesterday, says SJB General Secretary Ranjith Madduma Bandara.",
        "His comments come after Minister and SJB MP Harin Fernando had claimed that a section of SJB, TNA and SLFP parliamentarians will vote in favour of Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe in today’s vote, despite their parties deciding to support Mr. Alahapperuma.",
        "Opposition Leader and SJB leader, Sajith Premadasa yesterday withdrew his candidacy for the position of President and declared that their alliance and opposition partners will work towards ensuring victory to SLPP MP Dullas Alahapperuma."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SJB",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dullas",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB General",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Madduma Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Harin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SJB තීරණය අනුව ඩලස්ට ඡන්දය දෙනවා - මහලේකම්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සමගි ජන බලවේගය ඊයේ තීරණය කළ පරිදි ජනාධිපතිවරණ පාර්ලිමේන්තු ඡන්ද විමසීමේදී පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාට ඡන්දය දෙන බව SJB ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් රංජිත් මද්දුම බණ්ඩාර මහතා පවසයි.",
        "අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාට සහය දැක්වීමට පක්ෂ තීරණය කළද SJB, TNA සහ SLFP පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් කොටසක් වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට පක්ෂව ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කරන බවට අමාත්‍ය සහ SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුව ඔහු මෙම අදහස් පළ කළේය.",
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සහ SJB නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ඊයේ ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂකත්වය ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගත් අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා ජයග්‍රහණය කිරීම සඳහා තම සන්ධානය සහ විපක්ෂ හවුල්කරුවන් කටයුතු කරන බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඩලස්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB ජෙනරාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් මද්දුම බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටීඑන්ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීලනිප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SJB முடிவு செய்தபடி டல்லாசுக்கு வாக்களிக்கும் - பொதுச் செயலாளர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலுக்கான நாடாளுமன்ற வாக்கெடுப்பில், சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவுக்கு வாக்களிக்கும் என, SJB பொதுச் செயலாளர் ரஞ்சித் மத்தும பண்டார தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இன்றைய வாக்கெடுப்பில் SJB, TNA மற்றும் SLFP பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களில் ஒரு பகுதியினர், திரு.அழப்பெருமவிற்கு ஆதரவளிக்கத் தீர்மானித்த போதிலும், இன்றைய வாக்கெடுப்பில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு ஆதரவாக வாக்களிப்பார்கள் என அமைச்சரும் SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருமான ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ கூறியதை அடுத்து அவரது கருத்துக்கள் வந்துள்ளன.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவரும் SJB தலைவருமான சஜித் பிரேமதாச நேற்று ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான தனது வேட்புமனுவை வாபஸ் பெற்றுக்கொண்டதுடன், SLPP பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவின் வெற்றியை உறுதிப்படுத்துவதற்கு தமது கூட்டணி மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சி பங்காளிகள் செயற்படுவார்கள் என அறிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சித் மத்தும பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}