{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-stocks-gain-for-3rd-straight-session-ahead-of-presidential-vote-97678/",
  "time_ut": 1658241480,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka stocks gain for 3rd straight session ahead of presidential vote",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka stocks gain for 3rd straight session ahead of presidential vote",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka stocks gained over 1 percent on Tuesday (19), rising for a third consecutive session to end at near four week closing high on hopes of an all-party government after the parliament vote to elect a new president on July 20, brokers said.",
        "Analysts said the chances of former Media Minister Dullas Alahapperuma winning has increased after opposition leader Sajith Premadasa withdrew his candidacy on Tuesday against acting president Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "The main All Share Price Index (ASPI) closed 1.43% or 107.51 points up at 7,644.12 , its highest close since June 24.",
        "“The market gained today following the news that main opposition leader Sajith Premadasa announced his withdrawal from the presidentship election,” a top market analyst said.",
        "“This gave hope that there is a possibility for a unity government thereby easing the political instability in the country.”",
        "Sri Lanka’s parliament finalised the nomination list for Wednesday’s parliament vote for the presidency after former leader Gotabaya Rajapaksa fled the country and announced his resignation from Singapore. Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe, Dullas Alahapperuma and the Marxists Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna leader Anura Kumara Dissanayake have been nominated as the candidates.",
        "Opposition leader Sajith Premadasa withdrew his nomination after an agreement was made between him and Alahapperuma that if Alahapperuma wins, Premadasa will be the Prime Minister.",
        "Previously analysts said the market is hopeful for an all-party unity government which could  boost the sentiment. They have said if the former ruling Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) gets control through any of its proxies, there could be another round of unrest in the country.",
        "Former President Rajapaksa resigned last week in a bid to ease the political crisis after an unprecedented economic crisis.",
        "The more liquid S&P SL20 index gained 1.50% or 36.38 points to close at 2,459.45.",
        "Sri Lanka is facing its worst fuel crisis in its post-independent era and the economy is expected to contract between 8-10% this year.",
        "Foreigners bought a net of 5.6 million rupees. The total foreign outflow so far this year is 802 million rupees.",
        "The turnover was 1.11 billion rupees, less than a half of this year’s daily average turnover of 3.1 billion rupees.",
        "The main ASPI has gained 4.1% in July so far after falling 9.3% in June, reversing a 6% gain in May. It lost 23% in April followed by a 14.5% fall in March.",
        "The market has lost 37.5% so far this year after being one of the world’s best stock markets with an 80% return last year when large volumes of money were printed.",
        "Sri Lanka’s sovereign debt default on April 12 has already led the country to be rated with restricted/selective default rating by rating agencies, which has weighed on investor sentiment.",
        "Investors are also concerned over the steep fall of the rupee from 203 to 370 levels so far in 2022.",
        "Commercial Bank, leading the ASPI’s gain, rose 2.5% to close at 53.2 rupees a share.",
        "Richard Pieris gained 6.0% to 15.9 rupees a share, while Sampath Bank closed 2.2% stronger at 32.6 rupees a share. (Colombo/July 19/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3rd",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 1 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "four week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Media",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1.43%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "107.51",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7,644.12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vimukthi Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "S&P",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.50%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "36.38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,459.45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8-10%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5.6 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "802 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1.11 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "less than a half",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.1 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4.1%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.3%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14.5%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "March",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "37.5%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "80%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "April 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "203 to 370",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Commercial Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ASPI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.5%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "53.2 rupees",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Richard Pieris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.0%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "15.9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sampath Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.2%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "32.6 rupees",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 19/2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපතිවරණ ඡන්ද විමසීමට පෙර අඛණ්ඩව 3 වැනි සැසිවාරය සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා කොටස් ලාභ ලබයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකා කොටස් අඟහරුවාදා (19) සියයට 1 ට වඩා වැඩි වූ අතර, ජූලි 20 වන දින නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ඡන්දයෙන් පසු සර්ව පාක්ෂික රජයක් පිළිබඳ බලාපොරොත්තුව මත සති හතරකට ආසන්න කාලයක් අවසන් වීමට අඛණ්ඩව තුන්වන සැසිවාරය සඳහා ඉහළ ගියේය. තැරැව්කරුවන් පැවසීය.",
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට එරෙහිව ඉදිරිපත් වූ අපේක්ෂකත්වය අඟහරුවාදා ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගැනීමත් සමඟ හිටපු ජනමාධ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා ජයග්‍රහණය කිරීමේ අවස්ථාව වැඩි වී ඇති බව විශ්ලේෂකයෝ පවසති.",
        "ප්‍රධාන සියලු කොටස් මිල දර්ශකය (ASPI) 1.43% හෝ ඒකක 107.51 කින් 7,644.12 හි අවසන් වූ අතර එය ජුනි 24 න් පසු එහි ඉහළම අවසානයයි.",
        "“ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස ජනාධිපතිවරණයෙන් ඉවත් වන බව ප්‍රකාශ කළ පුවතත් සමඟ අද වෙළෙඳපොළ ඉහළ ගියා” යැයි ඉහළ පෙළේ වෙළෙඳපොළ විශ්ලේෂකයෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "\"මෙය රටේ දේශපාලන අස්ථාවරත්වය සමනය කරමින් සමගි ආණ්ඩුවක් සඳහා හැකියාවක් පවතින බවට බලාපොරොත්තුවක් ඇති කළේය.\"",
        "හිටපු නායක ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා රටින් පලා ගොස් සිංගප්පූරුවෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් පසු බදාදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ජනාධිපති ධුරය සඳහා ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නාමයෝජනා ලැයිස්තුව අවසන් කළේය. වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම සහ මාක්ස්වාදී ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක අපේක්ෂකයන් ලෙස නම් කර ඇත.",
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා සිය නාමයෝජනා ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගත්තේ අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා ජයග්‍රහණය කළහොත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා අගමැති කරන බවට ඔහු සහ අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා අතර ඇති වූ එකඟතාවයෙන් පසුවය.",
        "මීට පෙර විශ්ලේෂකයින් කියා සිටියේ මනෝභාවය ඉහළ නැංවිය හැකි සර්ව පාක්ෂික එක්සත් රජයක් සඳහා වෙළඳපල බලාපොරොත්තු වන බවයි. හිටපු පාලක ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ (SLPP) එහි කිසියම් ප්‍රොක්සියක් හරහා පාලනය කළහොත් රට තුළ තවත් නොසන්සුන්තාවක් ඇති විය හැකි බව ඔවුන් පවසා තිබේ.",
        "පෙර නොවූ විරූ ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකින් පසු දේශපාලන අර්බුදය සමනය කිරීමේ උත්සාහයක් ලෙස හිටපු ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ පසුගිය සතියේ ඉල්ලා අස්විය.",
        "වැඩි ද්‍රවශීලතාවයකින් යුතු S&P SL20 දර්ශකය ඒකක 1.50% හෙවත් ඒකක 36.38කින් ඉහළ ගොස් 2,459.45 හි අවසන් විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය පශ්චාත් නිදහස් යුගයේ දරුණුතම ඉන්ධන අර්බුදයට මුහුණ දී සිටින අතර මේ වසරේ ආර්ථිකය 8-10% අතර සංකෝචනය වනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "විදේශිකයන් රුපියල් මිලියන 5.6ක දැලක් මිල දී ගත්තා. මේ වසරේ මේ දක්වා මුළු විදේශ ගලායාම රුපියල් මිලියන 802 කි.",
        "පිරිවැටුම රුපියල් බිලියන 1.11 ක් වූ අතර එය මේ වසරේ දෛනික සාමාන්‍ය පිරිවැටුම රුපියල් බිලියන 3.1 න් අඩකටත් වඩා අඩුය.",
        "ප්‍රධාන ASPI ජුනි මාසයේදී 9.3% පහත වැටීමෙන් පසු මේ දක්වා ජූලි මාසයේදී 4.1% ලබාගෙන ඇත, මැයි මාසයේදී 6% ලාභයක් ආපසු හැරවිය. එය අප්රේල් මාසයේදී 23% අහිමි වූ අතර මාර්තු මාසයේදී 14.5% පහත වැටුණි.",
        "පසුගිය වසරේ විශාල මුදල් ප්‍රමාණයක් මුද්‍රණය කළ විට 80% ක ප්‍රතිලාභයක් ලබා ගනිමින් ලෝකයේ හොඳම කොටස් වෙළෙඳපොළක් වූ පසු මේ වසරේ මේ දක්වා 37.5% කින් වෙළෙඳපොළ අහිමි වී ඇත.",
        "අපේ‍්‍රල් 12 වන දින ශ‍්‍රී ලංකාවේ ස්වෛරී නය පැහැර හැරීම, ආයෝජකයින්ගේ මනෝභාවය මත බර පටවා ඇති ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීමේ ආයතන විසින් සීමා කරන ලද/තෝරාගත් පැහැර හැරීම් ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීමකින් රට ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීමට දැනටමත් හේතු වී ඇත.",
        "2022 වසරේ මේ දක්වා රුපියල 203 සිට 370 දක්වා තියුනු ලෙස පහත වැටීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ආයෝජකයින් ද කනස්සල්ලට පත්ව සිටිති.",
        "ASPI හි ලාභයට ප්‍රමුඛයා වන කොමර්ෂල් බැංකුව, කොටසක මිල රුපියල් 53.2 ක් දක්වා 2.5% කින් ඉහළ ගියේය.",
        "රිචඩ් පීරිස් කොටසක් රුපියල් 15.9 දක්වා 6.0% කින් ඉහළ ගිය අතර සම්පත් බැංකුව 2.2% කින් කොටසක් රුපියල් 32.6 කින් ශක්තිමත් විය. (කොළඹ/ජූලි 19/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3 වැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 1 කට වඩා",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1.43%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "107.51 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7,644.12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "S&P",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.50%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "36.38 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,459.45 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8-10%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 5.6 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 802 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 1.11 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඩකට වඩා අඩුය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 3.1 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4.1%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.3%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14.5%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "37.5%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "80%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය අවුරුද්දේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "203 සිට 370 දක්වා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොමර්ෂල් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ASPI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.5%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල් 53.2 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රිචඩ් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.0%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "15.9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සම්පත් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.2%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල් 32.6 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 19/2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி வாக்கெடுப்புக்கு முன்னதாக இலங்கை பங்குச்சந்தைகள் தொடர்ந்து 3வது அமர்வுக்கு ஏற்றம் பெற்றுள்ளன",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – ஜூலை 20 அன்று புதிய ஜனாதிபதியைத் தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதற்கான பாராளுமன்ற வாக்கெடுப்புக்குப் பிறகு, அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கத்தின் நம்பிக்கையின் பேரில், இலங்கைப் பங்குச் சந்தைகள் செவ்வாய் (19) 1 சதவீதத்திற்கும் மேலாக உயர்ந்து, தொடர்ந்து மூன்றாவது அமர்வுக்கு உயர்ந்து நான்கு வாரங்களில் முடிவடைந்தது. தரகர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச, பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு எதிராக செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை தனது வேட்புமனுவை வாபஸ் பெற்றதையடுத்து, முன்னாள் ஊடகத்துறை அமைச்சர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவின் வெற்றிக்கான வாய்ப்புகள் அதிகரித்துள்ளதாக ஆய்வாளர்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "முக்கிய அனைத்து பங்கு விலைக் குறியீடு (ASPI) 1.43% அல்லது 107.51 புள்ளிகள் உயர்ந்து 7,644.12 இல் நிறைவடைந்தது, இது ஜூன் 24 க்குப் பிறகு அதன் அதிகபட்ச முடிவாகும்.",
        "\"ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் இருந்து விலகுவதாக பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச அறிவித்தார் என்ற செய்தியைத் தொடர்ந்து இன்று சந்தை ஏற்றம் கண்டுள்ளது\" என உயர்மட்ட சந்தை ஆய்வாளர் ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"நாட்டின் அரசியல் ஸ்திரமின்மையைத் தளர்த்துவதன் மூலம் ஒரு ஐக்கிய அரசாங்கத்திற்கான சாத்தியம் இருப்பதாக இது நம்பிக்கையை அளித்தது.\"",
        "இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் தலைவர் கோத்தபய ராஜபக்ச நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறி சிங்கப்பூரில் இருந்து ராஜினாமா செய்வதாக அறிவித்ததையடுத்து, ஜனாதிபதிக்கான பாராளுமன்ற வாக்கெடுப்புக்கான வேட்புமனுப் பட்டியலை இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்றம் இறுதி செய்துள்ளது. பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும மற்றும் மார்க்சிஸ்ட் மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணியின் தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க ஆகியோர் வேட்பாளர்களாக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாசவுக்கும், அழகப்பெருமவுக்கும் இடையில் ஏற்பட்ட உடன்படிக்கைக்கு அமைய, அழகப்பெரும வெற்றி பெற்றால் பிரேமதாசவே பிரதமராக பதவியேற்பார் என சஜித் பிரேமதாச தனது வேட்புமனுவை வாபஸ் பெற்றார்.",
        "முன்னதாக ஆய்வாளர்கள், அனைத்துக் கட்சி ஒற்றுமை அரசாங்கத்திற்கு சந்தை நம்பிக்கையுடன் இருப்பதாகக் கூறியுள்ளனர், இது உணர்வை அதிகரிக்கக் கூடியது. முன்னாள் ஆளும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன (SLPP) அதன் பினாமிகள் மூலம் கட்டுப்பாட்டைப் பெற்றால், நாட்டில் மற்றொரு சுற்று அமைதியின்மை ஏற்படலாம் என்று அவர்கள் கூறியுள்ளனர்.",
        "வரலாறு காணாத பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்குப் பிறகு ஏற்பட்ட அரசியல் நெருக்கடியைத் தணிக்கும் முயற்சியில் முன்னாள் அதிபர் ராஜபக்சே கடந்த வாரம் பதவி விலகினார்.",
        "அதிக திரவ S&P SL20 குறியீடு 1.50% அல்லது 36.38 புள்ளிகள் அதிகரித்து 2,459.45 இல் நிறைவடைந்தது.",
        "இலங்கை சுதந்திரத்திற்குப் பிந்தைய காலத்தில் மிக மோசமான எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளதுடன், இந்த ஆண்டு பொருளாதாரம் 8-10% க்கு இடையில் சுருங்கும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "வெளிநாட்டினர் 5.6 மில்லியன் ரூபாய்க்கு நிகர வாங்கியுள்ளனர். இவ்வருடத்தில் இதுவரையான மொத்த வெளிநாட்டு வெளியேற்றம் 802 மில்லியன் ரூபாவாகும்.",
        "விற்றுமுதல் 1.11 பில்லியன் ரூபாவாக இருந்தது, இந்த வருடத்தின் தினசரி சராசரி விற்றுமுதல் 3.1 பில்லியன் ரூபாயில் பாதிக்கும் குறைவாக இருந்தது.",
        "ஜூன் மாதத்தில் 9.3% சரிந்த பிறகு, மே மாதத்தில் 6% ஆதாயத்தை மாற்றியமைத்த பிறகு, முக்கிய ASPI ஜூலையில் 4.1% அதிகரித்துள்ளது. இது ஏப்ரல் மாதத்தில் 23% இழந்தது, அதைத் தொடர்ந்து மார்ச் மாதத்தில் 14.5% வீழ்ச்சியடைந்தது.",
        "கடந்த ஆண்டு அதிக அளவு பணம் அச்சிடப்பட்டபோது 80% வருமானத்துடன் உலகின் சிறந்த பங்குச் சந்தைகளில் ஒன்றாக இருந்த சந்தை இந்த ஆண்டு இதுவரை 37.5% இழந்துள்ளது.",
        "ஏப்ரல் 12 அன்று இலங்கையின் இறையாண்மைக் கடனைத் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தாததால், முதலீட்டாளர்களின் உணர்வுகளை எடைபோட்ட, மதிப்பீட்டு நிறுவனங்களால் கட்டுப்படுத்தப்பட்ட/தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட இயல்புநிலை மதிப்பீட்டில் நாட்டை ஏற்கனவே மதிப்பிட வழிவகுத்தது.",
        "2022ல் இதுவரை ரூபாய் மதிப்பு 203ல் இருந்து 370க்கு சரிந்தது குறித்து முதலீட்டாளர்கள் கவலையடைந்துள்ளனர்.",
        "ASPI இன் ஆதாயத்திற்கு முன்னணியில் இருக்கும் கொமர்ஷல் வங்கி, ஒரு பங்கு 2.5% அதிகரித்து 53.2 ரூபாயில் நிறைவடைந்தது.",
        "ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் பங்கு ஒன்றின் விலை 6.0% அதிகரித்து 15.9 ரூபாவாகவும், சம்பத் வங்கி 2.2% வலுவடைந்து ஒரு பங்கு 32.6 ரூபாவாகவும் முடிந்தது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை 19/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3வது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 சதவீதத்திற்கு மேல்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊடகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1.43%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "107.51",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7,644.12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமுக்தி பெரமுனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்&பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.50%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "36.38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,459.45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8-10%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5.6 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "802 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1.11 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு பாதிக்கு குறைவாக",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.1 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4.1%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.3%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14.5%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "37.5%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "80%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "203 முதல் 370 வரை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வணிக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ASPI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.5%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "53.2 ரூபாய்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.0%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "15.9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சம்பத் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.2%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "32.6 ரூபாய்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 19/2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}