{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/30/kerala-cannabis-worth-rs-15-mn-seized/",
  "time_ut": 1661840220,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Kerala cannabis worth Rs 15 Mn seized",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Kerala cannabis worth Rs 15 Mn seized",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); A special search operation conducted by the Navy in Thondamanaru, Jaffna yesterday (29) led to the apprehension of 02 suspects with Kerala cannabis.",
        "The suspects were transferring about 51kg and 500g of this narcotic drug by a van when the apprehension was made.",
        "Making a special emphasis on anti-drug operations, the Navy conducts operations across the island. As an extension of these efforts, SLNS Uththara in the Northern Naval Command searched a suspicious van at the Thondamanaru Bridge and recovered about 51kg and 500g of Kerala cannabis in 02 sacks, concealed in the vehicle.",
        "Accordingly, the Navy apprehended 02 suspects who were on the van with Kerala cannabis and the vehicle used for the illegal act.",
        "The approximate street value of the apprehended stock of Kerala cannabis is believed to be Rs. 15 million.",
        "The accused together with the narcotic substance and the van were handed over to the Achchuweli Police for onward investigation.",
        "Tokyo will coordinate with other Sri Lanka creditors on debt"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kerala",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mn",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thondamanaru",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 51kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS Uththara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Northern Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Thondamanaru Bridge",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tokyo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රුපියල් මිලියන 15ක් වටිනා කේරළ ගංජා අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); නාවික හමුදාව ඊයේ (29) යාපනය තොණ්ඩමනාරු ප්‍රදේශයේ සිදුකළ විශේෂ සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමකදී කේරළ ගංජා සමඟ සැකකරුවන් 02 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "සැකකරුවන් වෑන් රථයකින් මෙම මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 51 යි ග්‍රෑම් 500 ක් පමණ ප්‍රවාහනය කරමින් සිටියදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය විරෝධී මෙහෙයුම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් විශේෂ අවධානයක් යොමු කරමින් නාවික හමුදාව දිවයින පුරා මෙහෙයුම් සිදු කරයි. මෙම උත්සාහයේ දිගුවක් ලෙස උතුරු නාවික විධානයට අයත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා උත්තර නෞකාව තොණ්ඩමනාරු පාලම අසලදී සැකකටයුතු වෑන් රථයක් සෝදිසි කිරීමේදී එම රථයේ සඟවා තිබූ ගෝනි 02ක බහා තිබූ කේරළ ගංජා කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 51 යි ග්‍රෑම් 500 ක් පමණ සොයා ගෙන ඇත.",
        "ඒ අනුව කේරළ ගංජා සමඟ වෑන් රථයේ සිටි සැකකරුවන් 02 දෙනෙකු සහ එම නීතිවිරෝධී ක්‍රියාව සඳහා යොදා ගත් රථය නාවික හමුදාව විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගනු ලැබුවා.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් කේරළ ගංජා තොගයේ ආසන්න වශයෙන් වීදි වටිනාකම රු. මිලියන 15 කි.",
        "සැකකරුවන් සහ මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය තොගය සහ වෑන් රථය ඉදිරි විමර්ශන සඳහා අච්චුවේලි පොලිසිය වෙත භාර දීමට කටයුතු කෙරිණි.",
        "ටෝකියෝ අනෙකුත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ණය හිමියන් සමඟ ණය සම්බන්ධීකරණය කරනු ඇත"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කේරල",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mn",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තොණ්ඩමනාරු",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "51kg පමණ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා උත්තර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තොණ්ඩමනාරු පාලම",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 15 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ටෝකියෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "15 லட்சம் மதிப்புள்ள கேரள கஞ்சா பறிமுதல் செய்யப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); யாழ்ப்பாணம் தொண்டமனாறு பகுதியில் கடற்படையினரால் நேற்று (29) மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட விசேட தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையில் கேரள கஞ்சாவுடன் 02 சந்தேகநபர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்கள் சுமார் 51 கிலோ 500 கிராம் போதைப்பொருளை வேன் மூலம் கடத்திக் கொண்டிருந்த போது, ​​அவர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "போதைப்பொருள் எதிர்ப்பு நடவடிக்கைகளுக்கு விசேட கவனம் செலுத்தி, கடற்படையினர் தீவு முழுவதும் நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர். இந்த முயற்சிகளின் விரிவாக்கமாக, வடக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளையின் SLNS உத்தரா தொண்டமனாறு பாலத்தில் சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான வேன் ஒன்றை சோதனை செய்ததில், வாகனத்தில் மறைத்து வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த 02 சாக்குகளில் சுமார் 51 கிலோ 500 கிராம் கேரளா கஞ்சா மீட்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இதன்படி, கேரள கஞ்சாவுடன் வேனில் பயணித்த 02 சந்தேக நபர்களையும் சட்டவிரோத செயலுக்கு பயன்படுத்திய வாகனத்தையும் கடற்படையினர் கைது செய்துள்ளனர்.",
        "பிடிபட்ட கேரள கஞ்சாவின் தோராயமான தெரு மதிப்பு ரூ. 15 மில்லியன்.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்கள் போதைப் பொருள் மற்றும் வேன் என்பன மேலதிக விசாரணைகளுக்காக அச்சுவேலி பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "டோக்கியோ மற்ற இலங்கை கடனாளர்களுடன் கடனில் ஒருங்கிணைக்கும்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கேரளா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mn",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொண்டமானாறு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 51 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS உத்தரா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொண்டமானாறு பாலம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "டோக்கியோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}