{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78755",
  "time_ut": 1658861280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Following  dramatic arrest by CID officers aboard a flight to Dubai UAE on 26th, Dhaniz Ali remanded till 5 August by the Colombo Fort Magistrate’s Court; Suspect allegedly entered the Sri Lanka Rupavahini (Television) Corporation (SLRC) premises in Colombo 7 and interfered with its broadcasting",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Following  dramatic arrest by CID officers aboard a flight to Dubai UAE on 26th, Dhaniz Ali remanded till 5 August by the Colombo Fort Magistrate’s Court; Suspect allegedly entered the Sri Lanka Rupavahini (Television) Corporation (SLRC) premises in Colombo 7 and interfered with its broadcasting",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "A suspect named Dhaniz Ali, who is alleged to have entered the Sri Lanka Rupavahini (Television) Corporation (SLRC) premises in Colombo 7 and interfered with its broadcasting, was ordered to be remanded till 5 August by the Colombo Fort Magistrate’s Court yesterday evening following his dramatic arrest by Criminal Investigation Department (CID) officers aboard a flight to Dubai UAE on Tuesday (26).",
        "In the videos related to the incident, a group of officers of the CID who had boarded the relevant aircraft that was about to depart from the Bandaranaike International Airport (BIA) in Katunayake was seen arresting the suspect amidst opposition from the suspect himself, as well as other passengers. The other passengers who were aboard the flight were seen asking the CID officers why airport officers had cleared the suspect if there was an arrest warrant issued against him.",
        "In a press release issued by the Police Media Division (PMD) after his arrest, it was stated that the suspect was arrested for allegedly entering the SLRC premises located in the Cinnamon Garden Police area, and making a threatening statement on live television, thereby suspending its broadcasting for a certain period.",
        "The arrest of the suspect, a 31-year-old resident of the Kurunegala area was, according to the PMD, made by the officers attached to the CID unit established at the BIA.",
        "The Police further stated that the Colombo Fort Police had reported to the court regarding the suspect, as he is alleged to have engaged in a protest held blocking the gates of the Ministry of Finance on 20 June, when a delegation of the International Monetary Fund (IMF) arrived for a discussion with the representatives of the Ministry. However, the Police stated that the Colombo Fort Magistrate’s Court has issued warrants for the suspect’s arrest due to his failure to appear in court in relation to the relevant incident.",
        "In addition to this, the Police stated that the suspect was released on bail after being produced before the Colombo Fort Magistrate’s Court for allegedly causing damage to public property during a protest held in front of the Police Headquarters (HQ) on 9 June.",
        "Furthermore, it was stated that he has been identified as a suspect related to an incident in which a group of army intelligence officers were allegedly attacked and forcibly detained near the Presidential Secretariat at the Galle Face Green on 12 June.",
        "The Police also stated that the suspect has been identified as a suspect in an alleged incident of threatening and trying to forcibly evacuate a group of police officers attached to the Colombo Fort Police Station who had visited the statue of the slain Prime Minister S.W.R.D. Bandaranaike at the Galle Face Green on 20 July, on information that there was a plan to cause damage to the said statue.",
        "The Police said that he is currently in the custody of the CID officials and that further investigations are underway.",
        "However, activists at the “RanilGoGama” public protest site, who are demanding the resignation of President Wickremesinghe, are alleging that most of the allegations against the suspect, as stated by the Police, are false. There are various posts protesting his arrest on social media platforms, especially on Facebook.",
        "Following the massive protests held in Colombo on 9 July demanding the resignation of then-President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, the latter left the country. He had appointed then-Premier Wickremesinghe as the Acting President and a protest was staged in front of the Premier’s office at Flower Road in Colombo 3 on 13 July. During the protest, a group of persons entered the SLRC premises and due to the incident, the State-owned channel went off the air for some time."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CID",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dubai UAE",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "26th",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dhaniz Ali",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "5 August",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "the Colombo Fort Magistrate’s Court",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "Suspect",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "the Sri Lanka Rupavahini",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Colombo 7",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhaniz Ali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Rupavahini",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo 7",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Fort Magistrate’s",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dubai UAE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bandaranaike International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Police Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PMD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLRC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cinnamon Garden Police",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "31-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PMD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Fort Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Fort Magistrate’s",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Fort Magistrate’s Court",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Galle Face Green",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Fort Police Station",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Galle Face Green",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Flower Road",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "13 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLRC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පසුගිය 26 වැනිදා ඩුබායි එක්සත් අරාබි එමීර් රාජ්‍යයට පියාසර කරමින් තිබූ ගුවන් යානයකදී සීඅයිඩී නිලධාරීන් විසින් නාටකාකාර ලෙස අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමෙන් පසුව, කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය විසින් ඩැනිස් අලි අගෝස්තු 5 දක්වා රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාරගත කරන ලදී. කොළඹ 7 ශ්‍රී ලංකා රූපවාහිනී සංස්ථාවේ (SLRC) පරිශ්‍රයට ඇතුළු වී එහි විකාශනයට බාධා කළ බව කියන සැකකරුවෙක්",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොළඹ 7 ශ්‍රී ලංකා රූපවාහිනී සංස්ථාවේ (SLRC) පරිශ්‍රයට ඇතුළු වී එහි විකාශන කටයුතුවලට බාධා කළැයි කියන Dhaniz Ali නමැති සැකකරු අගෝස්තු 5 වැනිදා දක්වා රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාරගත කිරීමට කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය ඊයේ සවස නියෝග කළේ ඉන් අනතුරුවයි. අඟහරුවාදා (26) ඩුබායි එක්සත් අරාබි එමීර් රාජ්‍යයට පියාසර කරමින් තිබූ ගුවන් යානයකදී අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ (CID) නිලධාරීන් විසින් ඔහු නාටකාකාර ලෙස අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "සිද්ධියට අදාළ වීඩියෝ පටවල කටුනායක බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළෙන් (BIA) පිටත්වීමට නියමිතව තිබූ අදාළ ගුවන් යානයට ගොඩ වූ අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ නිලධාරීන් පිරිසක් සැකකරුගේ විරෝධය මධ්‍යයේ සැකකරු අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා අයුරු දැකගත හැකි විය. අනෙකුත් මගීන් ලෙස. සැකකරුට එරෙහිව අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමේ වරෙන්තුවක් නිකුත් කර ඇත්නම් ගුවන් තොටුපල නිලධාරීන් සැකකරු නිදහස් කළේ මන්දැයි ගුවන් යානයේ සිටි අනෙක් මගීන් රහස් පොලිස් නිලධාරීන්ගෙන් විමසා සිටිනු දක්නට ලැබිණි.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමෙන් පසු පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය කොට්ඨාශය (PMD) නිකුත් කළ මාධ්‍ය නිවේදනයක දැක්වෙන්නේ කුරුඳුවත්ත පොලිස් බල ප්‍රදේශයේ පිහිටි SLRC පරිශ්‍රයට ඇතුළු වී සජීවී රූපවාහිනියෙන් තර්ජනාත්මක ප්‍රකාශයක් කළ බව කියන සිද්ධියක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් සැකකරු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති අතර එමඟින් එය අත්හිටුවා ඇති බවයි. නිශ්චිත කාලයක් සඳහා එහි විකාශනය.",
        "BIA හි ස්ථාපිත CID ඒකකයට අනුයුක්ත නිලධාරීන් විසින් PMD ට අනුව සැකකරු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත්තේ කුරුණෑගල ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 31 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයෙකි.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නියෝජිත පිරිසක් පසුගිය ජුනි 20 වනදා මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ගේට්ටු අවහිර කරමින් පැවති විරෝධතාවයක නිරත වූ බවට චෝදනා එල්ල වන සැකකරු සම්බන්ධයෙන් කොළඹ කොටුව පොලිසිය අධිකරණයට කරුණු වාර්තා කර ඇති බවයි පොලිසිය වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් කළේ. IMF) අමාත්‍යාංශයේ නියෝජිතයන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡාවක් සඳහා පැමිණියේය. කෙසේ වෙතත්, අදාළ සිද්ධියට අදාළව සැකකරු අධිකරණයේ පෙනී නොසිටීම හේතුවෙන් කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය විසින් ඔහු අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට වරෙන්තු නිකුත් කර ඇති බව පොලීසිය ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "මීට අමතරව ජුනි 9 වනදා පොලිස් මූලස්ථානය ඉදිරිපිට පැවති විරෝධතාවයක් අතරතුරදී පොදු දේපළවලට අලාභහානි සිදුකිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සැකකරු කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුව ඇප මත මුදා හැර ඇති බවයි පොලීසිය සඳහන් කළේ.",
        "තවද, ඔහු පසුගිය ජුනි 12 වනදා ගාලුමුවදොර ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය අසලදී හමුදා බුද්ධි අංශ නිලධාරීන් පිරිසකට පහර දී බලහත්කාරයෙන් රඳවා තබා ගත් බව කියන සිද්ධියකට සම්බන්ධ සැකකරුවෙකු ලෙස හඳුනාගෙන ඇති බවද ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "ඝාතනයට ලක්වූ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය එස්.ඩබ්ලිව්.ආර්.ඩී.ගේ ප්‍රතිමාව නැරඹීමට පැමිණි කොළඹ කොටුව පොලිස් ස්ථානයට අනුයුක්ත පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් පිරිසකට තර්ජනය කර බලහත්කාරයෙන් ඉවත් කිරීමට උත්සාහ කළ බව කියන සිද්ධියක සැකකරුවෙක් බවට හඳුනාගෙන ඇති බවද පොලිසිය ප්‍රකාශ කළා. බණ්ඩාරනායක ගාලුමුවදොර පිටියේදී ජුලි 20 වැනිදා එම පිළිරුවට හානි කිරීමේ සැලසුමක් තිබෙන බවට ලැබුණු තොරතුරක් මත.",
        "ඔහු මේ වන විට අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ නිලධාරීන් භාරයේ පසුවන බවත් වැඩිදුර විමර්ශන ක්‍රියාත්මක බවත් පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බවට බලකරමින් සිටින “රනිල්ගොගම” මහජන විරෝධතා භූමියේ ක්‍රියාකාරීන් චෝදනා කරන්නේ සැකකරුට එරෙහිව පොලිසිය ප්‍රකාශ කරන චෝදනා බොහොමයක් අසත්‍ය බවයි. ඔහු අත් අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට විරෝධය පළ කරමින් සමාජ මාධ්‍ය ජාලාවල, විශේෂයෙන්ම ෆේස් බුක්හි විවිධ පෝස්ට් තිබේ.",
        "එවක ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බලකරමින් පසුගිය ජුලි 9 වැනිදා කොළඹදී පැවති දැවැන්ත විරෝධතාවයෙන් අනතුරුව ඔහු රට හැර ගියේය. ඔහු වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස එවකට අගමැති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පත් කළ අතර ඒ අනුව ජුලි 13 වැනිදා කොළඹ 3 මල් පාරේ පිහිටි අගමැති කාර්යාලය ඉදිරිපිට උද්ඝෝෂණයක් ද පැවැත්විණි. විරෝධතාව අතරතුර පුද්ගලයින් පිරිසක් SLRC පරිශ්‍රයට ඇතුළු වූ අතර, සිද්ධිය හේතුවෙන් රජයට අයත් නාලිකාව ටික වේලාවක් විකාශනය විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CID",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඩුබායි UAE",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "26 වැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ධනීස් අලි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "5 අගෝස්තු",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයේදී",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "සැකකරු",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රූපවාහිනිය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "කොළඹ 7",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ධනීස් අලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රූපවාහිනිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ 7",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි UAE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය කොට්ඨාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීඑම්ඩී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLRC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුඳුවත්ත පොලිසිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "31 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීඑම්ඩී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයේදී",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර පිටිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව පොලිස් ස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර පිටිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මල් පාර",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "13 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLRC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "26 ஆம் திகதி துபாய் ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸிற்கான விமானத்தில் சிஐடி அதிகாரிகளால் வியத்தகு முறையில் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதைத் தொடர்ந்து, தனிஸ் அலியை கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம் ஆகஸ்ட் 5 வரை விளக்கமறியலில் வைத்தது; சந்தேக நபர் கொழும்பு 7 இல் உள்ள இலங்கை ரூபவாஹினி (தொலைக்காட்சி) கூட்டுத்தாபன (SLRC) வளாகத்திற்குள் நுழைந்து அதன் ஒளிபரப்பில் குறுக்கீடு செய்ததாகக் கூறப்படுகிறது.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பு 7 இல் உள்ள இலங்கை ரூபவாஹினி (எஸ்.எல்.ஆர்.சி) நிறுவன வளாகத்திற்குள் நுழைந்து அதன் ஒளிபரப்புக்கு இடையூறு ஏற்படுத்தியதாக கூறப்படும் தனிஸ் அலி என்ற சந்தேக நபரை ஆகஸ்ட் 5 ஆம் திகதி வரை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்குமாறு கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம் நேற்று மாலை உத்தரவிட்டது. செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (26) துபாய் ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸ் செல்லும் விமானத்தில் குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை (சிஐடி) அதிகாரிகளால் வியத்தகு முறையில் கைது செய்யப்பட்டார்.",
        "சம்பவம் தொடர்பான காணொளிகளில், கட்டுநாயக்க பண்டாரநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தில் இருந்து (BIA) புறப்படவிருந்த தொடர்புடைய விமானத்தில் ஏறிய குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவின் அதிகாரிகள் குழு சந்தேக நபரின் எதிர்ப்பின் மத்தியிலும் சந்தேக நபரைக் கைது செய்வதைக் காணமுடிந்தது. மற்ற பயணிகளாக. சந்தேகத்திற்குரிய நபருக்கு எதிராக கைது வாரண்ட் பிறப்பிக்கப்பட்டிருந்தால், ஏன் விமான நிலைய அதிகாரிகள் அவரை விடுவித்தனர் என்று விமானத்தில் இருந்த மற்ற பயணிகள் சிஐடி அதிகாரிகளிடம் கேட்டதைக் காண முடிந்தது.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட பின்னர் பொலிஸ் ஊடகப் பிரிவு (PMD) வெளியிட்டுள்ள செய்திக் குறிப்பில், சந்தேகநபர் கறுவாத்தோட்டம் பொலிஸ் பகுதியில் அமைந்துள்ள SLRC வளாகத்திற்குள் நுழைந்து நேரலை தொலைக்காட்சியில் மிரட்டல் விடுத்த குற்றச்சாட்டின் பேரில் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாகக் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது. ஒரு குறிப்பிட்ட காலத்திற்கு அதன் ஒளிபரப்பு.",
        "குருநாகல் பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த 31 வயதுடைய சந்தேகநபர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக பி.ஐ.ஏ.யில் நிறுவப்பட்ட குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவின் அதிகாரிகளால் பி.எம்.டி.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் (ஜூன் 20) பிரதிநிதிகள் நிதி அமைச்சின் வாயில்களை முற்றுகையிட்டு ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டதாகக் கூறப்படும் சந்தேகநபர் தொடர்பில் கொழும்பு கோட்டை பொலிஸார் நீதிமன்றில் அறிக்கை செய்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் மேலும் தெரிவித்தனர். IMF) அமைச்சின் பிரதிநிதிகளுடன் கலந்துரையாடலுக்கு வருகை தந்தது. எவ்வாறாயினும், குறித்த சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் சந்தேகநபர் நீதிமன்றில் ஆஜராகத் தவறியமையினால் கைது செய்ய கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம் பிடியாணை பிறப்பித்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இதற்கு மேலதிகமாக, கடந்த ஜூன் மாதம் 9 ஆம் திகதி பொலிஸ் தலைமையகத்திற்கு முன்பாக இடம்பெற்ற ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தின் போது பொதுச் சொத்துக்களுக்கு சேதம் விளைவித்த குற்றச்சாட்டின் பேரில் சந்தேகநபர் கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றில் ஆஜர்படுத்தப்பட்ட பின்னர் பிணையில் விடுவிக்கப்பட்டதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "மேலும், கடந்த ஜூன் மாதம் 12ஆம் திகதி காலி முகத்திடலில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்திற்கு அருகில் இராணுவ புலனாய்வு அதிகாரிகள் குழுவொன்று தாக்கப்பட்டு பலவந்தமாக தடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்ட சம்பவத்துடன் தொடர்புடைய சந்தேக நபர் என அவர் அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "கொல்லப்பட்ட பிரதமர் எஸ்.டபிள்யூ.ஆர்.டி.யின் சிலைக்கு வருகை தந்த கொழும்பு கோட்டை பொலிஸ் நிலையத்தில் கடமையாற்றும் பொலிஸ் உத்தியோகத்தர்களை அச்சுறுத்தி பலவந்தமாக வெளியேற்ற முயற்சித்த சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் சந்தேகநபர் அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் மேலும் தெரிவித்தனர். ஜுலை 20ஆம் திகதி காலி முகத்திடலில் பண்டாரநாயக்கா சிலைக்கு சேதம் விளைவிக்க திட்டம் இருப்பதாக கிடைத்த தகவலின் பேரில்.",
        "அவர் தற்போது குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினரின் காவலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருவதாகவும் பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்கவை பதவி விலகக் கோரி “ரணில் கோகம” பொதுப் போராட்ட தளத்தில் செயற்படுபவர்கள், சந்தேகநபருக்கு எதிராக பொலிஸாரால் கூறப்பட்ட குற்றச்சாட்டுகளில் பெரும்பாலானவை பொய்யானவை என்று குற்றம் சாட்டுகின்றனர். அவரது கைதுக்கு எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவித்து சமூக வலைதளங்களில், குறிப்பாக ஃபேஸ்புக்கில் பல்வேறு பதிவுகள் வெளியாகி வருகின்றன.",
        "அன்றைய ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவை பதவி விலகக் கோரி கடந்த ஜூலை மாதம் 9 ஆம் திகதி கொழும்பில் நடைபெற்ற மாபெரும் ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தை அடுத்து, அவர் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறினார். அவர் அப்போதைய பிரதமர் விக்ரமசிங்கவை பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமித்ததுடன், ஜூலை 13 ஆம் திகதி கொழும்பு 3 மலர் வீதியில் உள்ள பிரதமரின் அலுவலகத்திற்கு முன்பாக ஆர்ப்பாட்டம் ஒன்று முன்னெடுக்கப்பட்டது. ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தின் போது, ​​ஒரு குழுவினர் SLRC வளாகத்திற்குள் நுழைந்தனர், இந்த சம்பவத்தால், அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான சேனல் சிறிது நேரம் ஒளிபரப்பப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "துபாய் யு.ஏ.இ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "26 ஆம் தேதி",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "தனிஸ் அலி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "5 ஆகஸ்ட்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம்",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "சந்தேகிக்கப்படுகிறது",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை ரூபவாஹினி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "கொழும்பு 7",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தனிஸ் அலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ரூபவாஹினி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு 7",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாயங்காலம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றவியல் புலனாய்வு திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய் யு.ஏ.இ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்கா சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொலிஸ் ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிஎம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.ஆர்.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கறுவாத்தோட்ட காவல்துறை",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "31 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிஎம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face Green",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை பொலிஸ் நிலையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face Green",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காவல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலர் சாலை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "13 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.ஆர்.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}