{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/17/no-change-in-decision-to-support-rw-says-sagara/",
  "time_ut": 1658042760,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "No change in decision to support RW, says Sagara",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "No change in decision to support RW, says Sagara",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The General Secretary of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna, Attorney-at-Law Sagara Kariyawasam says that he will reply to the letter directed by the party Chairman, Prof. G. L. Peiris, inquiring about the decision taken by the SLPP to support the Acting President, Ranil Wickremesinghe, as a Presidential Candidate.",
        "When inquired by News 1st, the General Secretary of Podujana Peramuna said that there has been no change in the decision taken by his party so far.",
        "Kariyawasam added that the majority opinion of the SLPP remains favorable to the acting President.",
        "Japan engages in high level talks with CBSL & Treasury officials"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "RW",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sagara",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "G. L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kariyawasam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBSL & Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "RWට සහය දැක්වීමේ තීරණයේ වෙනසක් නැත, සාගර පවසයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සහය දැක්වීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ගෙන ඇති තීරණය පිළිබඳව විමසා එම පක්ෂයේ සභාපති මහාචාර්ය ජී එල් පීරිස් මහතා යොමුකළ ලිපියට පිළිතුරු ලබාදෙන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් නීතීඥ සාගර කාරියවසම් මහතා පවසයි. රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂකයෙක්.",
        "News 1st කළ විමසීමකදී පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම්වරයා කියා සිටියේ තම පක්ෂය මෙතෙක් ගෙන ඇති තීරණයේ කිසිදු වෙනසක් සිදුවී නොමැති බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ බහුතර මතය වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයාට හිතකර බවද කාරියවසම් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ජපානය CBSL සහ භාණ්ඩාගාර නිලධාරීන් සමඟ ඉහළ මට්ටමේ සාකච්ඡා පවත්වයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "RW",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "සාගර",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල්. පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBSL සහ භාණ්ඩාගාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "RW ஐ ஆதரிக்கும் முடிவில் எந்த மாற்றமும் இல்லை என்கிறார் சகாரா",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஶ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பதில் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு ஆதரவளிக்க ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன எடுத்த தீர்மானம் தொடர்பில் கட்சியின் தலைவர் பேராசிரியர் ஜீ.எல்.பீரிஸ் அனுப்பியுள்ள கடிதத்திற்கு பதில் அளிப்பதாக கட்சியின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் சட்டத்தரணி சாகர காரியவசம் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, ஜனாதிபதி வேட்பாளராக.",
        "நியூஸ் 1ஸ்டிடம் வினவிய போது, ​​பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பொதுச் செயலாளர், இதுவரையில் தமது கட்சி எடுத்த தீர்மானத்தில் எந்த மாற்றமும் இல்லை என்று தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பெரும்பான்மையான கருத்து தற்போது ஜனாதிபதிக்கு சாதகமாகவே உள்ளது எனவும் காரியவசம் மேலும் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "CBSL மற்றும் கருவூல அதிகாரிகளுடன் ஜப்பான் உயர்மட்ட பேச்சுவார்த்தையில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "RW",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சாகர",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காரியவசம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.பி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBSL & கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}