{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-schedules-1-hour-20-minutes-of-power-cuts-for-aug-15-16-98544/",
  "time_ut": 1660466640,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka schedules 1 hour 20 minutes of power cuts for Aug 15, 16",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka schedules 1 hour 20 minutes of power cuts for Aug 15, 16",
      "author": "Dulya de Silva",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka will impose power cuts of one hour and 20 minutes on Monday (15) and Tuesday (16) Public Utilities Commission (PUCSL) Chairman Janaka Ratnayake said.",
        "All areas (A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, J, K, L, P, Q, R, S, T, U, V and W) will have power cuts of one hour and 20 minutes between 5.00 pm and 9.00 pm.",
        "Sri Lanka saw a lessened power cut duration due to the availability of hydroelectricity. The PUCSL has said that efforts would be made to maintain the shorter duration and to provide uninterrupted supplies of electricity on holidays.",
        "Sri Lanka hiked its electricity tariffs for the first time in 9 years last week, with an overall increase of 75%, while still providing subsidies for lower consuming groups."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "1 hour 20 minutes",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "15",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one hour and 20 minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": ") Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janaka Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "F, G, H",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "L",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one hour and 20 minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.00 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.00 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 years last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අගෝස්තු 15 සහ 16 යන දිනවල පැය 1 විනාඩි 20 ක විදුලි කප්පාදුවක් සැලසුම් කරයි",
      "author": "දුල්යා ද සිල්වා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳුදා (15) සහ අඟහරුවාදා (16) පැය එකයි විනාඩි 20 ක විදුලි කප්පාදුවක් පනවන බව මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාවේ (PUCSL) සභාපති ජනක රත්නායක මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "සියලුම ප්‍රදේශවලට (A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, J, K, L, P, Q, R, S, T, U, V and W) පැයක විදුලිය විසන්ධි වේ. සහ සවස 5.00 සිට 9.00 දක්වා විනාඩි 20 යි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජල විදුලිය තිබීම හේතුවෙන් විදුලිය විසන්ධි කිරීමේ කාලසීමාව අඩු විය. කෙටි කාලයක් පවත්වා ගෙන යාමටත් නිවාඩු දිනවල අඛණ්ඩ විදුලිය සැපයීමටත් උත්සාහ කරන බව මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිසම පවසා ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වසර 9කට පසු ප්‍රථම වතාවට විදුලි ගාස්තු ඉහළ නැංවීමට පසුගිය සතියේ කටයුතු කළ අතර, සමස්ත 75%ක වැඩිවීමක් සමඟින්, තවමත් අඩු පාරිභෝගික කණ්ඩායම් සඳහා සහනාධාර ලබාදී ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "පැය 1 විනාඩි 20 යි",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "15",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය එකයි විනාඩි 20 යි",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": ") මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජානක රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එෆ්, ජී, එච්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය එකයි විනාඩි 20 යි",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.00 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.00 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 9ක් ගිය සතියේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஆகஸ்ட் 15, 16 தேதிகளில் 1 மணி நேரம் 20 நிமிடம் மின்வெட்டுக்கு இலங்கை திட்டமிட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "துல்யா டி சில்வா",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் – இலங்கையில் திங்கள் (15) மற்றும் செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (16) ஒரு மணித்தியாலம் 20 நிமிடங்களுக்கு மின்வெட்டு அமுல்படுத்தப்படும் என பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் (PUCSL) தலைவர் ஜனக ரத்நாயக்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அனைத்து பகுதிகளிலும் (A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, J, K, L, P, Q, R, S, T, U, V and W) ஒரு மணி நேரம் மின்வெட்டு இருக்கும். மற்றும் மாலை 5.00 மணி முதல் இரவு 9.00 மணி வரை 20 நிமிடங்கள்.",
        "நீர்மின்சாரம் கிடைப்பதன் காரணமாக இலங்கையில் மின்வெட்டு காலம் குறைந்துள்ளது. குறுகிய காலத்தை பராமரிக்கவும், விடுமுறை நாட்களில் தடையின்றி மின்சாரம் வழங்கவும் முயற்சிகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்படும் என்று PUCSL தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "குறைந்த நுகர்வுக் குழுக்களுக்கு மானியங்களை வழங்கும் அதே வேளையில், ஒட்டுமொத்தமாக 75% அதிகரிப்புடன், கடந்த வாரம் 9 ஆண்டுகளில் முதல் முறையாக இலங்கை தனது மின் கட்டணத்தை உயர்த்தியது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "1 மணி 20 நிமிடங்கள்",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "15",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மணி நேரம் 20 நிமிடங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": ") பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனக ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஃப், ஜி, எச்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மணி நேரம் 20 நிமிடங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை 5.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு 9.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம் 9 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}