{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/US-donates-3-000-MT-of-food-to-feed-Lankan-school-children/56-739168",
  "time_ut": 1661539719,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "US donates 3,000 MT of food to feed Lankan school children",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "US donates 3,000 MT of food to feed Lankan school children",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The US, through the US Department of Agriculture (USDA) and in partnership with Save the Children, has received 320 metric tons of split yellow peas to nourish school children across Sri Lanka.",
        "The donation is part of a larger one of 3,000 metric tons of food, the US Embassy said.",
        "US Ambassador Julie Chung, Education Minister Dr. Susil Premajayantha, and representatives from the Ministry of Health, the National Planning Department, and Save the Children attended the hand-over ceremony Friday.",
        "“This donation from the American people targets the most vulnerable Sri Lankans – children – and enables them to focus on their schooling rather than on their hunger. Every nourishing meal will be a testament to the US’ commitment to helping all Sri Lankans emerge from the worst economic crisis since the country’s independence,” said Ambassador Julie Chung.",
        "The shipment is part of the USDA McGovern-Dole International Food for Education and Child Nutrition Program, a five-year $ 26 million project aimed at providing immediate emergency assistance to the food insecure to improve literacy and attendance by reducing hunger.",
        "The USDA and its partner Save the Children work with the Sri Lankan government and local communities to ensure food reaches those most in need.",
        "Between June 2021 and January 2022 alone, the project, called Promoting Autonomy for Literacy and Attentiveness through Market Alliances (PALAM/A), provided protein supplements twice in the form of split yellow peas and Alaskan pink salmon to more than 105,000 children and their families – more than 460,000 Sri Lankans in total - during COVID-19 lockdowns. As of Mid-August, PALAM/A has provided supplemental nutrition to approximately 50,000 schoolchildren.",
        "The donation reflects the US’ larger efforts to scale up food security operations worldwide to provide record amounts of immediate emergency assistance in order to save lives and alleviate suffering.",
        "Food security programs are just one component of the longstanding partnership between the American and Sri Lankan people to support Sri Lanka’s development journey and promote economic sustainability.",
        "In addition to ongoing projects PALAM/A, the United States has announced more than $ 179 million in new assistance to Sri Lanka this year, including nearly $ 32 million in new humanitarian and technical assistance since June alone."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Lankan",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the US Department of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Save the Children",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "320 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the US Embassy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Education",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Susil Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Planning Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Save the Children",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "American",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "five-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 26 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "USDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Save the Children",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Between June 2021 and January 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alaskan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 105,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 460,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mid-August",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PALAM/A",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "approximately 50,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "American",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PALAM/A",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than $ 179 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly $ 32 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පාසල් දරුවන් පෝෂණය කිරීම සඳහා එක්සත් ජනපදය ආහාර මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 3000ක් පරිත්‍යාග කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "එක්සත් ජනපදයේ කෘෂිකර්ම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව (USDA) හරහා සහ සේව් ද චිල්ඩ්රන් සමඟ එක්ව, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පුරා පාසල් ළමුන් පෝෂණය කිරීම සඳහා බෙදූ කහ කඩල මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 320ක් එක්සත් ජනපදයට ලැබී ඇත.",
        "මෙම පරිත්‍යාගය ආහාර මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 3,000කින් විශාල ප්‍රමාණයක කොටසක් බව එක්සත් ජනපද තානාපති කාර්යාලය පවසයි.",
        "එක්සත් ජනපද තානාපතිනි ජුලී චුන්ග්, අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍ය වෛද්‍ය සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත, සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය, ජාතික සැලසුම් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සහ සේව් ද චිල්ඩ්‍රන් යන ආයතනවල නියෝජිතයන් සිකුරාදා මෙම භාරදීමේ උත්සවයට සහභාගි වූහ.",
        "“ඇමරිකානු ජනතාවගේ මෙම පරිත්‍යාගය වඩාත් අවදානමට ලක්විය හැකි ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් - ළමයින් - ඉලක්ක කර ගන්නා අතර ඔවුන්ගේ කුසගින්න කෙරෙහි වඩා ඔවුන්ගේ පාසල් අධ්‍යාපනය කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු කිරීමට ඔවුන්ට හැකි වේ. සෑම පෝෂ්‍යදායී ආහාර වේලක්ම, රට නිදහස ලැබීමෙන් පසු ඇති වූ දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් මිදීමට සියලුම ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින්ට උපකාර කිරීමට එක්සත් ජනපදයේ කැපවීම පිළිබඳ සාක්ෂියක් වනු ඇත, ”තානාපති ජුලී චුන්ග් පැවසීය.",
        "මෙම නැව්ගත කිරීම USDA McGovern-Dole International Food for Education and Child Nutrition වැඩසටහනේ කොටසකි, කුසගින්න අඩු කිරීම මගින් සාක්ෂරතාවය සහ පැමිණීම වැඩි දියුණු කිරීම සඳහා ආහාර අනාරක්ෂිත ආහාර සඳහා ක්ෂණික හදිසි ආධාර සැපයීම ඉලක්ක කරගත් පස් අවුරුදු $ මිලියන 26 ක ව්‍යාපෘතියකි.",
        "USDA සහ එහි හවුල්කරු සේව් ද චිල්ඩ්රන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය සහ ප්‍රාදේශීය ප්‍රජාවන් සමඟ ආහාර අවශ්‍යතා ඇති අයට ළඟාවීම සහතික කිරීම සඳහා කටයුතු කරයි.",
        "2021 ජූනි සිට 2022 ජනවාරි දක්වා කාලය තුළ පමණක්, වෙළඳපල සන්ධාන හරහා සාක්ෂරතාවය සහ අවධානය සඳහා ස්වයං පාලනයක් ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීම (PALAM/A) නමින් හැඳින්වෙන ව්‍යාපෘතිය, 105,000 කට අධික ළමුන් සහ ඔවුන්ගේ පවුල්වලට බෙදුණු කහ කඩල සහ ඇලස්කන් රෝස සැමන් ආකාරයෙන් දෙවරක් ප්‍රෝටීන් අතිරේක ලබා දෙන ලදී. - COVID-19 අගුලු දැමීම් අතරතුර - සමස්ත ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් 460,000 කට වඩා. අගෝස්තු මැද වන විට, PALAM/A විසින් ආසන්න වශයෙන් 50,000 පාසල් ළමුන් සඳහා අතිරේක පෝෂණය ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "ජීවිත බේරා ගැනීමට සහ දුක් වේදනා සමනය කිරීම සඳහා වාර්තාගත හදිසි හදිසි ආධාර සැපයීම සඳහා ලොව පුරා ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතා මෙහෙයුම් ඉහළ නැංවීමට එක්සත් ජනපදය දරන විශාල උත්සාහයන් පරිත්‍යාගයෙන් පිළිබිඹු වේ.",
        "ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතා වැඩසටහන් යනු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංවර්ධන ගමනට සහය වීමට සහ ආර්ථික තිරසාරත්වය ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමට ඇමරිකානු සහ ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනතාව අතර දිගුකාලීන හවුල්කාරිත්වයේ එක් අංගයක් පමණි.",
        "දැනට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන PALAM/A ව්‍යාපෘතිවලට අමතරව, ජුනි මාසයේ සිට පමණක් ඩොලර් මිලියන 32කට ආසන්න නව මානුෂීය සහ තාක්ෂණික ආධාර ඇතුළුව, එක්සත් ජනපදය විසින් මේ වසරේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඩොලර් මිලියන 179කට වැඩි නව ආධාර ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3,000 කි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ලාංකික",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද කෘෂිකර්ම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දරුවන් බේරා ගන්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්රික් ටොන් 320 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 3,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්යාපන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්ය අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික සැලසුම් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දරුවන් බේරා ගන්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පස් අවුරුදු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 26 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "USDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දරුවන් බේරා ගන්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජුනි 2021 සහ ජනවාරි 2022 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇලස්කන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "105,000 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "460,000 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු මැද",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාලම/ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසන්න වශයෙන් 50,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාලම/ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 179 කට වඩා",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 32 කට ආසන්න",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கைப் பள்ளிக் குழந்தைகளுக்கு உணவளிக்க அமெரிக்கா 3,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் உணவை வழங்குகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அமெரிக்க விவசாயத் திணைக்களம் (USDA) மற்றும் Save the Children உடன் இணைந்து, இலங்கை முழுவதும் உள்ள பாடசாலை மாணவர்களை போஷிப்பதற்காக 320 மெட்ரிக் தொன் பிரித்த மஞ்சள் பட்டாணியை அமெரிக்கா பெற்றுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த நன்கொடையானது 3,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் உணவின் ஒரு பகுதியாகும் என்று அமெரிக்க தூதரகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அமெரிக்கத் தூதுவர் ஜூலி சுங், கல்வி அமைச்சர் டாக்டர் சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த மற்றும் சுகாதார அமைச்சு, தேசிய திட்டமிடல் திணைக்களம் மற்றும் சேவ் தி சில்ட்ரன் ஆகியவற்றின் பிரதிநிதிகள் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை கையளிக்கும் நிகழ்வில் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "\"அமெரிக்க மக்களின் இந்த நன்கொடையானது மிகவும் பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடிய இலங்கையர்களை - குழந்தைகளை - குறிவைக்கிறது மற்றும் அவர்களின் பசியைக் காட்டிலும் அவர்களின் பள்ளிப் படிப்பில் கவனம் செலுத்த அவர்களுக்கு உதவுகிறது. நாட்டின் சுதந்திரத்திற்குப் பின்னர் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் இருந்து மீள அனைத்து இலங்கையர்களுக்கும் உதவுவதற்கான அமெரிக்காவின் அர்ப்பணிப்புக்கு ஒவ்வொரு ஊட்டமளிக்கும் உணவும் ஒரு சான்றாக இருக்கும்” என தூதுவர் ஜூலி சுங் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த ஏற்றுமதி USDA McGovern-Dole International Food for Education and Child Nutrition திட்டத்தின் ஒரு பகுதியாகும், இது ஐந்தாண்டு $26 மில்லியன் திட்டமாகும், இது உணவு பாதுகாப்பற்ற உணவுக்கு உடனடி அவசர உதவியை வழங்குவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டது.",
        "USDA மற்றும் அதன் பங்காளியான Save the Children இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் மற்றும் உள்ளூர் சமூகங்களுடன் இணைந்து உணவு தேவைப்படுபவர்களை சென்றடைவதை உறுதிசெய்கிறது.",
        "ஜூன் 2021 மற்றும் ஜனவரி 2022 க்கு இடையில் மட்டும், சந்தைக் கூட்டணிகள் மூலம் கல்வியறிவு மற்றும் கவனிப்புக்கான தன்னாட்சியை ஊக்குவித்தல் (PALAM/A) என்ற திட்டம், 105,000 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட குழந்தைகள் மற்றும் அவர்களது குடும்பங்களுக்கு பிளவுபட்ட மஞ்சள் பட்டாணி மற்றும் அலாஸ்கன் பிங்க் சால்மன் வடிவில் இரண்டு முறை புரதச் சத்துக்களை வழங்கியது. – மொத்தமாக 460,000 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட இலங்கையர்கள் - COVID-19 பூட்டுதல்களின் போது. ஆகஸ்ட் நடுப்பகுதி வரை, PALAM/A ஆனது தோராயமாக 50,000 பள்ளி மாணவர்களுக்கு கூடுதல் ஊட்டச்சத்தை வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த நன்கொடையானது உயிர்களைக் காப்பாற்றுவதற்கும் துன்பங்களைக் குறைப்பதற்கும் உடனடி அவசர உதவிகளை பதிவு செய்ய உலகளவில் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பு நடவடிக்கைகளை அதிகரிக்க அமெரிக்காவின் பெரிய முயற்சிகளை பிரதிபலிக்கிறது.",
        "உணவுப் பாதுகாப்புத் திட்டங்கள் என்பது இலங்கையின் அபிவிருத்திப் பயணத்திற்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதற்கும் பொருளாதார நிலைத்தன்மையை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கும் அமெரிக்க மற்றும் இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு இடையிலான நீண்டகால கூட்டாண்மையின் ஒரு அங்கமாகும்.",
        "PALAM/A திட்டங்களுக்கு மேலதிகமாக, அமெரிக்கா இந்த ஆண்டு இலங்கைக்கு $179 மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான புதிய உதவிகளை அறிவித்துள்ளது, இதில் ஜூன் மாதத்தில் இருந்து மட்டும் கிட்டத்தட்ட $32 மில்லியன் புதிய மனிதாபிமான மற்றும் தொழில்நுட்ப உதவிகள் அடங்கும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க விவசாயத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழந்தைகளை காப்பாற்றுங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "320 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்வி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய திட்டமிடல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழந்தைகளை காப்பாற்றுங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 26 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "USDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழந்தைகளை காப்பாற்றுங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 2021 மற்றும் ஜனவரி 2022 க்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலாஸ்கன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "105,000க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "460,000க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் நடுப்பகுதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாலம்/ஏ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தோராயமாக 50,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாலம்/ஏ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 179 மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமாக",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட $32 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}