{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ගෝඨා-අල්ලන්නැයි-සිංගප්පූරු-නීතිපතිට-පැමිණිල්ලක්/1-616956",
  "time_ut": 1658680856,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ගෝඨා අල්ලන්නැයි සිංගප්පූරු නීතිපතිට පැමිණිල්ලක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Complaint to the Singapore Attorney General to arrest Gota",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Foreign media reported that a group of lawyers from the International Truth and Justice Project (ITJP) filed a complaint with the Attorney General of Singapore demanding the immediate arrest of former President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa.",
        "The complaint has been filed alleging that former President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa committed war crimes in violation of the Geneva Convention when he was the Defense Secretary.",
        "The 63-page complaint alleges violations of the Geneva Conventions, international humanitarian law and international criminal law during the 2009 LTTE conflict."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Singapore",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Truth",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Geneva Convention",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defense",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "63",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Geneva Conventions",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගෝඨා අල්ලන්නැයි සිංගප්පූරු නීතිපතිට පැමිණිල්ලක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා වහාම අත් අඩංගුවට ගන්නා ලෙස ඉල්ලමින් ජාත්‍යන්තර සත්‍ය සහ යුක්තිය ව්‍යාපෘතියේ (ITJP) නීතිඥයන් පිරිසක සිංගප්පූරුවේ නීතිපතිවරයා වෙත පැමිණිල්ලක් ගොනු කර ඇතැයි විදෙස් මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ආරක්ෂක ලේකම්වරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කළ කාලයේ ජිනීවා සම්මුතිය උල්ලංඝනය කරමින් යුද අපරාධ සිදු කළා යැයි චෝදනා කරමින් පැමිණිල්ල ගොනු කර ඇත.",
        "2009 එල්.ටී.ටී.ඊ ගැටුම් පැවති සමයේදී ජිනීවා සම්මුතිය උල්ලංඝනය කළ බවත් ජාත්‍යන්තර මානුෂීය නීතිය සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර අපරාධ නීතිය කඩ කළ බවත් පිටු 63 කින් යුත් පැමිණිල්ලේ සටහන් වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර සත්‍යය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිනීවා සම්මුතිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "63",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිනීවා සම්මුතීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோட்டாவை கைது செய்ய சிங்கப்பூர் அட்டர்னி ஜெனரலிடம் புகார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவை உடனடியாக கைது செய்யுமாறு கோரி சர்வதேச உண்மை மற்றும் நீதித் திட்டத்தின் (ITJP) சட்டத்தரணிகள் குழுவொன்று சிங்கப்பூர் சட்டமா அதிபரிடம் முறைப்பாடு செய்துள்ளதாக வெளிநாட்டு ஊடகங்கள் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளன.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ பாதுகாப்பு செயலாளராக இருந்த போது ஜெனிவா உடன்படிக்கையை மீறி போர்க்குற்றத்தில் ஈடுபட்டதாக முறைப்பாடு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "2009 விடுதலைப் புலிகளின் மோதலின் போது ஜெனிவா உடன்படிக்கைகள், சர்வதேச மனிதாபிமான சட்டம் மற்றும் சர்வதேச குற்றவியல் சட்டங்கள் மீறப்பட்டதாக 63 பக்கங்கள் கொண்ட புகாரில் குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச உண்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெனிவா ஒப்பந்தம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "63",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெனிவா ஒப்பந்தங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}