{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132246",
  "time_ut": 1658745773,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இலங்கையுடனான உறவுகளை மேலும் வலுப்படுத்த புதிய ஜனாதிபதியின் ஒத்துழைப்புக்களை எதிர்பார்க்கின்றோம் - ரஷ்ய ஜனாதிபதி",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "We look forward to the cooperation of the new President - Russian President - to further strengthen relations with Sri Lanka",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "Russian President Vladimir Putin has said that he expects the cooperation of the new President Ranil Wickremesinghe to further strengthen the relations between Russia and Sri Lanka.",
        "He has expressed his confidence in his congratulatory letter to President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "The Russian Ambassador to Sri Lanka met President Ranil Wickremesinghe on Monday. During this meeting, he also handed over a congratulatory letter from Russian President Vladimir Putin.",
        "In a letter sent by the Russian President to President Ranil Wickremesinghe, the Russian President has expressed hope for further strengthening of relations between the two countries.",
        "\"I look forward to your activities as head of state to further develop constructive bilateral cooperation in various fields in the interests of the Russian people and in the interest of strengthening regional stability and security,\" Russian President Vladimir Putin added in his letter."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Russian",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ සබඳතා තවදුරටත් ශක්තිමත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා නව ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ - රුසියානු ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ සහයෝගීතාව අපි අපේක්ෂා කරමු",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "රුසියාව සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර සබඳතා තවදුරටත් ශක්තිමත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා නව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ සහයෝගය අපේක්ෂා කරන බව රුසියානු ජනාධිපති ව්ලැදිමීර් පුටින් මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ඔහු ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වෙත සිය සුබපැතුම් ලිපිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් විශ්වාසය පළ කර තිබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රුසියානු තානාපතිවරයා සඳුදා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ හමුවිය. මෙම හමුවේදී ඔහු රුසියානු ජනාධිපති ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්ගේ සුබපැතුම් ලිපියක් ද භාර දුන්නේය.",
        "රුසියානු ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ වෙත යවන ලද ලිපියක රුසියානු ජනාධිපතිවරයා දෙරට අතර සබඳතා තවදුරටත් ශක්තිමත් කර ගැනීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව සඳහන් කර ඇත.",
        "\"රුසියානු ජනතාවගේ අවශ්‍යතා සහ කලාපීය ස්ථාවරත්වය සහ ආරක්ෂාව ශක්තිමත් කිරීම සඳහා විවිධ ක්ෂේත්‍රවල නිර්මාණාත්මක ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සහයෝගීතාව තවදුරටත් වර්ධනය කිරීමට රාජ්‍ය නායකයා ලෙස ඔබගේ ක්‍රියාකාරකම් මම බලාපොරොත්තු වෙමි,\" රුසියානු ජනාධිපති ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින් සිය ලිපියේ වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රුසියානු",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையுடனான உறவுகளை மேலும் வலுப்படுத்த புதிய ஜனாதிபதியின் ஒத்துழைப்புக்களை எதிர்பார்க்கின்றோம் - ரஷ்ய ஜனாதிபதி",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "ரஷ்யா - இலங்கைக்கு இடையிலான உறவுகளை மேலும் வலுப்படுத்துவதற்கு புதிய ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் ஒத்துழைப்புக்களை எதிர்பார்ப்பதாக ரஷ்ய ஜனாதிபதி விளாமிர் புட்டின் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு அனுப்பி வைத்துள்ள வாழ்த்து கடிதத்திலேயே அவர் இவ்வாறு நம்பிக்கை வெளியிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான ரஷ்ய தூதுவர் நேற்று திங்கட்கிழமை ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை சந்தித்துள்ளார். இந்த சந்திப்பின் போதே ரஷ்ய ஜனாதிபதி விளாடிமிர் புட்டினுடைய வாழ்த்து கடிதத்தினையும் கையளித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவிற்கு ரஷ்ய ஜனாதிபதி அனுப்பியுள்ள கடிதத்தில், இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையிலான உறவுகளை மேலும் வலுப்படுத்துவதற்கு ரஷ்ய ஜனாதிபதி நம்பிக்கை வெளியிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "'ரஷ்ய மக்களின் நலன்களுக்காகவும், பிராந்திய ஸ்திரத்தன்மை மற்றும் பாதுகாப்பை வலுப்படுத்தும் நலனுக்காகவும் பல்வேறு துறைகளில் ஆக்கபூர்வமான இருதரப்பு ஒத்துழைப்பை மேலும் மேம்படுத்துவதற்கு அரச தலைவர் என்ற முறையில் உங்களது செயல்பாடுகளை நான் எதிர்பார்க்கிறேன்' என்று ரஷ்ய ஜனாதிபதி விளாடிமிர் புடின் அவரது கடிதத்தில் மேலும் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளாடிமிர் புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளாடிமிர் புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளாடிமிர் புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}