{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/25/deputy-police-chief-testifies-in-probe-on-assault-on-journalists/",
  "time_ut": 1661425560,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Deputy Police Chief testifies in probe on assault on journalists",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Deputy Police Chief testifies in probe on assault on journalists",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Deputy Inspector General of Police Damayantha Wijaya Sri testified at the Human Rights Commission of Sri Lanka on Thursday (25) with regard to the attack on News 1st Journalists close to Ranil Wickremesinghe's private residence in Colombo on the 9th of July 2022.",
        "DIG Damayantha Wijaya Sri in his testimony said that on the day of the attack on the News 1st journalists, it was then-Prime Minister's Head of Security SSP Nizam Jamaldeen who was in charge of the security of the area in question.",
        "The DIG told the Human Rights Commission that Sri Lanka Police, Special Task Force, Police Officers attached to the Prime Minister's Security Division, and a Special Team from the Sri Lanka Air Force were under SSP Nizam Jamaldeen on that day.",
        "He said that officers attached to all four aforementioned security divisions reported to SSP Nizam Jamaldeen, and acted on his orders.",
        "Deputy Police Chief testifies in probe on assault on journalists",
        "Multiple unapproved Fuel Storage Tanks at business premises – Kanchana",
        "Senior Citizen beaten to death with motorcycle helmet in Kandana"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Human Rights Commission of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Human Rights Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Special Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Security Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SSP Nizam Jamaldeen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "that day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SSP Nizam Jamaldeen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fuel Storage Tanks",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Citizen",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandana",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහරදීමේ සිද්ධියේ විමර්ශනයේදී නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති සාක්ෂි දෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 2022 ජුලි මස 09 වැනි දින රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ කොළඹ පෞද්ගලික නිවස ආසන්නයේ පිහිටි News 1st මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහරදීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති දමයන්ත විජය ශ්‍රී මහතා බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (25) ශ්‍රී ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිෂන් සභාවේදී සාක්ෂි ලබා දුන්නේය.",
        "නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති දමයන්ත විජය ශ්‍රී සාක්ෂි දෙමින් කියා සිටියේ News 1st මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට ප්‍රහාරයක් එල්ල වූ දිනයේ අදාළ ප්‍රදේශයේ ආරක්ෂාව භාරව සිටියේ එවකට අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ ආරක්ෂක ප්‍රධානී ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නිසාම් ජමාල්ඩීන් බවයි.",
        "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නිසාම් ජමාල්ඩීන් යටතේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය, විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකාය, අගමැති ආරක්‍ෂක කොට්ඨාශයට අනුයුක්ත පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාවේ විශේෂ කණ්ඩායමක් එදින සිටි බව නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පතිවරයා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසමට පැවසීය.",
        "ඉහත කී ආරක්ෂක අංශ හතරටම අනුයුක්ත නිලධාරීන් ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නිසාම් ජමාල්ඩීන් වෙත වාර්තා කළ බවත්, ඔහුගේ නියෝග මත ක්‍රියා කළ බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහරදීමේ සිද්ධියේ විමර්ශනයේදී නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති සාක්ෂි දෙයි",
        "ව්‍යාපාරික ස්ථානවල අනුමත නොකළ ඉන්ධන ගබඩා ටැංකි කිහිපයක් - කාංචන",
        "කඳානේදී ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පුරවැසියෙකු යතුරුපැදි හිස්වැස්මකින් පහරදී ඝාතනය කරයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නිසාම් ජමාල්ඩීන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නිසාම් ජමාල්ඩීන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්ධන ගබඩා ටැංකි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචනා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුරවැසියා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කඳාන",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மீதான தாக்குதல் தொடர்பான விசாரணையில் பிரதிப் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் சாட்சியமளித்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜூலை மாதம் 9 ஆம் திகதி கொழும்பில் உள்ள ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்திற்கு அருகில் உள்ள News 1st ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் தாக்கப்பட்டமை தொடர்பில் பிரதிப் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் தமயந்த விஜய ஸ்ரீ வியாழக்கிழமை (25) இலங்கை மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழுவில் சாட்சியமளித்தார்.",
        "நியூஸ் 1ஸ்ட் ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் தாக்கப்பட்ட தினத்தன்று, குறித்த பிரதேசத்தின் பாதுகாப்புப் பொறுப்பில் அப்போதைய பிரதமரின் பாதுகாப்புத் தலைவரான எஸ்.எஸ்.பி நிசாம் ஜமால்தீன் இருந்ததாக பிரதி பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் தமயந்த விஜய ஸ்ரீ சாட்சியமளித்தார்.",
        "சிறிலங்கா பொலிஸ், விசேட அதிரடிப்படை, பிரதமரின் பாதுகாப்புப் பிரிவின் பொலிஸ் அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் இலங்கை விமானப்படையின் விசேட குழுவொன்று அன்றைய தினம் எஸ்.எஸ்.பி நிசாம் ஜமால்டீனின் கீழ் இருந்ததாக மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழுவிடம் பிரதி பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மேற்கூறிய நான்கு பாதுகாப்புப் பிரிவுகளிலும் உள்ள அதிகாரிகள் SSP நிஜாம் ஜமால்தீனிடம் புகார் அளித்து, அவரது உத்தரவின் பேரில் செயல்பட்டதாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மீதான தாக்குதல் தொடர்பான விசாரணையில் பிரதிப் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் சாட்சியமளித்தார்",
        "வணிக வளாகத்தில் பல அங்கீகரிக்கப்படாத எரிபொருள் சேமிப்பு தொட்டிகள் - காஞ்சனா",
        "கந்தானையில் மூத்த பிரஜை ஒருவர் மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் ஹெல்மெட்டால் அடித்து கொலை"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறப்பு அதிரடிப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்எஸ்பி நிஜாம் ஜமால்தீன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்எஸ்பி நிஜாம் ஜமால்தீன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "எரிபொருள் சேமிப்பு தொட்டிகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குடிமகன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கந்தனை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}