{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Plans-afoot-to-provide-free-mid-day-meal-to-schoolchildren-Susil/108-243928",
  "time_ut": 1661754409,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Plans afoot to provide free mid-day meal to schoolchildren: Susil",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Plans afoot to provide free mid-day meal to schoolchildren: Susil",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A task plan to provide free mid-day meals for all schoolchildren will be included in the budget for next year, Leader of the House Susil Premajanyantha told Parliament today.",
        "Responding to a query raised by Leader of Opposition Sajith Premadasa, Minister Premajayantha said that arrangements will be made to provide mid-day meals for all schoolchildren through the next year’s budget.",
        "Mr. Premadasa actually requested that the mid-day meal program should be resumed considering the UNICEF report which said Sri Lanka is in the 6th slot when it comes to countries with highest malnutrition among children.",
        "“We will focus on this report and provide free mid-day meals for all schoolchildren through the 2023 budget,” Mr. Premajayantha said.",
        "“A consignment of yellow lentils have been delivered from the USA and 10,000 tonnes of rice from China, which will be distributed among the poor,” he added.",
        "In addition he said a private company, Lions Club and Save the Children Organization have undertaken the task of looking after schoolchildren.",
        "Also he said that Health Minister Keheliya Rambukwella will make a statement in Parliament on the UNICEF report shortly. (Yohan Perera and Ajith Siriwardana)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "mid-day",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "mid-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Leader of Opposition Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "mid-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next year’s",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "mid-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "mid-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "USA",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000 tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lions Club and Save the Children Organization",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Keheliya Rambukwella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yohan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Siriwardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාසල් සිසුන්ට දවල් කෑම නොමිලයේ ලබාදීමට සැලසුම්: සුසිල්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සියලුම පාසල් සිසුන් සඳහා නොමිලේ දිවා ආහාරය ලබාදීමේ කාර්ය සැලැස්මක් ලබන වසර සඳහා වන අයවැයට ඇතුළත් කරන බව සභානායක සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජන්යන්ත මහතා අද පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "විපක්‍ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ඇසූ ප්‍රශ්නයකට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් අමාත්‍ය ප්‍රේමජයන්ත මහතා පැවැසුවේ ලබන වසරේ අයවැයෙන් සියලුම පාසල් සිසුන්ට දහවල් ආහාරය ලබාදීමට කටයුතු කරන බවයි.",
        "ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම ඉල්ලා සිටියේ ළමා මන්දපෝෂණය ඉහළම රටවල් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව 6 වැනි ස්ථානයේ සිටින යුනිසෙෆ් වාර්තාව සලකා බලා දවල් ආහාර වැඩසටහන නැවත ආරම්භ කළ යුතු බවයි.",
        "\"අපි මෙම වාර්තාව කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු කර 2023 අයවැය හරහා සියලුම පාසල් සිසුන් සඳහා නොමිලේ දිවා ආහාරය ලබා දෙන්නෙමු,\" ප්‍රේමජයන්ත මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "\"ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදයෙන් කහ පරිප්පු තොගයක් සහ චීනයෙන් සහල් ටොන් 10,000 ක් ලබා දී ඇති අතර ඒවා දුප්පතුන් අතර බෙදා හරිනු ඇත,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ඊට අමතරව පෞද්ගලික සමාගමක්, සිංහ සමාජය සහ සේව් ද චිල්ඩ්‍රන් සංවිධානය පාසල් දරුවන් බලාගැනීමේ කාර්යය භාරගෙන ඇති බවද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "එමෙන්ම යුනිසෙෆ් වාර්තාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය කෙහෙළිය රඹුක්වැල්ල මහතා ඉදිරියේදී පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී ප්‍රකාශයක් සිදුකිරීමට නියමිත බවද ඔහු කියා සිටියා. (යොහාන් පෙරේරා සහ අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මැද භාගයේ",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මැද භාගයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැද භාගයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැද භාගයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැද භාගයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇඑජ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 10,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංහ සමාජය සහ ළමා සුරැකීමේ සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්යය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙහෙළිය රඹුක්වැල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යොහාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பள்ளி மாணவர்களுக்கு இலவச மதிய உணவு வழங்க திட்டம்: சுசில்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அனைத்துப் பாடசாலை மாணவர்களுக்கும் இலவச மதிய உணவு வழங்கும் பணித்திட்டம் அடுத்த வருடத்திற்கான வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தில் உள்ளடக்கப்படும் என அவைத்தலைவர் சுசில் பிரேமஜன்யந்த இன்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச எழுப்பிய கேள்விக்கு பதிலளித்த அமைச்சர் பிரேமஜயந்த, அடுத்த வருட வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தில் அனைத்துப் பாடசாலை மாணவர்களுக்கும் மதிய உணவு வழங்க ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்படும் என தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "குழந்தைகள் மத்தியில் அதிக ஊட்டச்சத்து குறைபாடு உள்ள நாடுகளில் இலங்கை 6வது இடத்தில் இருப்பதாக யுனிசெஃப் அறிக்கையை கருத்தில் கொண்டு மதிய உணவு திட்டத்தை மீண்டும் தொடங்க வேண்டும் என்று திரு. பிரேமதாச உண்மையில் கோரிக்கை விடுத்தார்.",
        "\"நாங்கள் இந்த அறிக்கையின் மீது கவனம் செலுத்துவோம் மற்றும் 2023 வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தின் மூலம் அனைத்து பள்ளி மாணவர்களுக்கும் இலவச மதிய உணவை வழங்குவோம்\" என்று திரு. பிரேமஜயந்த கூறினார்.",
        "\"அமெரிக்காவிலிருந்து ஒரு மஞ்சள் பருப்பும், சீனாவில் இருந்து 10,000 டன் அரிசியும் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளன, அவை ஏழைகளுக்கு விநியோகிக்கப்படும்,\" என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "மேலும், தனியார் நிறுவனமான லயன்ஸ் கிளப் மற்றும் சேவ் தி சில்ட்ரன் அமைப்பு ஆகியவை பள்ளிக் குழந்தைகளைக் கவனிக்கும் பணியை மேற்கொண்டுள்ளன என்றார்.",
        "யுனிசெப் அறிக்கை தொடர்பில் சுகாதார அமைச்சர் கெஹலிய ரம்புக்வெல்ல விரைவில் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் அறிக்கையொன்றை வெளியிடுவார் எனவும் அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். (யோஹான் பெரேரா மற்றும் அஜித் சிறிவர்தன)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மத்தியானம்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்தியானம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்தியானம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்தியானம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்தியானம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000 டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லயன்ஸ் கிளப் மற்றும் சேவ் தி சில்ட்ரன் அமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆரோக்கியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெஹலிய ரம்புக்வெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோஹான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}