{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78309",
  "time_ut": 1656697920,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "“Canada supports the reconciliation process in Sri Lanka, as well as the empowerment of women and marginalized communities, whose success is integral to that of the country”- Canadian Envoy David McKinnon",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "“Canada supports the reconciliation process in Sri Lanka, as well as the empowerment of women and marginalized communities, whose success is integral to that of the country”- Canadian Envoy David McKinnon",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "(Text of Message from David McKinnon the High Commissioner of Canada  in Colombo, Sri Lanka , on the occasion of Canada Day – July 1, 2022)",
        "Happy Canada Day! Today, Canadians celebrate together our country’s achievements and hopefully have some fun doing it. We also reflect on the challenges that we face as we look to build a better Canada.",
        "Canada Day is typically celebrated informally, with a focus on family, friends, and community. This reflects Canadians’ inclusive sense of nationalism, enabling our diverse citizenry to integrate the various layers of their personal identities into an overarching sense of what it is to be Canadian, under the maple leaf.",
        "While the acute phase of the pandemic is, thankfully, behind us, the world faces different and complex challenges that once again require us to work together in our response. Major crises with global consequences have emerged around the world, most notably the Russian invasion of Ukraine.",
        "In Sri Lanka, the economic crisis has been exacerbated by these external shocks, and it is wrenching to see the adversity ordinary Sri Lankans endure every day as a result. As we did during the pandemic and for nearly 70 years before that, Canadians have extended their support to Sri Lanka in these difficult times.",
        "In collaboration with the World Health Organization, we are funding the procurement of essential medicines and supplies. Canada is also working with the World Food Program to purchase urgently needed rice stocks for the National School Meal Program. As the crisis deepens, we are looking how we can best respond to the recent flash appeals by the UN and the International Federation of Red Cross/Red Crescent Societies.",
        "I admire the desire of so many Sri Lankans to turn these challenging times into an opportunity to build a more stable, prosperous and inclusive society that can harness the enormous potential of this remarkable country and its talented people.",
        "Though under different circumstances, in Canada we, too, are striving to build a better future for all by advancing reconciliation with Indigenous peoples, including by recognizing and ending a legacy of injustice. We want to make sure the descendants of the first inhabitants of our beautiful land are acknowledged and celebrated fully in Canadian society even as we continue to welcome hundreds of thousands immigrants each year from around the world. Consistent with this, Canada supports the reconciliation process in Sri Lanka, as well as the empowerment of women and marginalized communities, whose success is integral to that of the country. This builds on our extensive people-to-people links and longstanding economic ties.",
        "Amidst the many challenges the world is facing, we cannot forget the most profound of all – the climate crisis. Both Sri Lanka and Maldives are experiencing the impacts of climate change; Maldives even more so due to its geography.  Climate and environmental action remain a priority for Canada and we continue to contribute to the Global Environment Facility and the Green Climate Fund, which benefit both Sri Lanka and Maldives.",
        "In recent years, we have also increased our support for local environmental initiatives. In Maldives, we will be expanding our assistance further this year through the deployment of Canadian experts to support the Maldivian government’s efforts to mitigate the effects of climate change and preserve the environment.",
        "I would be remiss if I did not end with a note about the many Canadians of Sri Lankan and Maldivian heritage who continue to shape and improve Canada. They exemplify why Canada Day is a day on which we celebrate diversity, solidarity and hope for an ever more inclusive future."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Canada",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "country”-",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Canadian",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "David McKinnon",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "David McKinnon",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canada Day",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 1, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Canada Day!",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canadians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Canada Day",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canadian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "every day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly 70 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canadians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the World Health Organization",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Food Program",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National School Meal Program",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Federation of Red Cross/Red Crescent Societies",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canadian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "hundreds of thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Global Environment Facility",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Green Climate Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "recent years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canadian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldivian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maldivian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canada Day",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "“ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රතිසන්ධාන ක්‍රියාවලියට මෙන්ම, රටේ සාර්ථකත්වයට අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වන කාන්තාවන් සහ ආන්තික ප්‍රජාවන් සවිබල ගැන්වීමට කැනඩාව සහාය වේ” - කැනේඩියානු නියෝජිත ඩේවිඩ් මැකිනන්",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "(2022 ජූලි 1 වන දින කැනඩා දිනය නිමිත්තෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කොළඹ කැනඩාවේ මහ කොමසාරිස් ඩේවිඩ් මැකිනන් විසින් පණිවිඩයේ පෙළ)",
        "සුභ කැනඩා දිනයක්! අද, කැනේඩියානුවන් එක්ව අපේ රටේ ජයග්‍රහණ සමරන අතර එය කිරීමට යම් විනෝදයක් ලබා ගැනීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වේ. වඩා හොඳ කැනඩාවක් ගොඩනැගීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන විට අප මුහුණ දෙන අභියෝග ගැන ද අපි ආවර්ජනය කරමු.",
        "කැනඩා දිනය සාමාන්‍යයෙන් අවිධිමත් ලෙස සමරනු ලබන්නේ පවුල, මිතුරන් සහ ප්‍රජාව කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු කරමිනි. මෙය කැනේඩියානුවන්ගේ ජාතිකත්වය පිළිබඳ හැඟීම පිළිබිඹු කරයි, අපගේ විවිධ පුරවැසියන්ට ඔවුන්ගේ පුද්ගලික අනන්‍යතාවල විවිධ ස්ථර මේපල් කොළ යටතේ කැනේඩියානු විය යුත්තේ කුමක්ද යන්න පිළිබඳ පුළුල් හැඟීමකට ඒකාබද්ධ කිරීමට හැකි වේ.",
        "වසංගතයේ උග්‍ර අවධිය, ස්තූතිවන්ත වන පරිදි, අපට පිටුපසින් සිටින අතර, ලෝකය විවිධ හා සංකීර්ණ අභියෝගවලට මුහුණ දී සිටින අතර, අපගේ ප්‍රතිචාරයේ දී එකට වැඩ කිරීමට නැවත වරක් අවශ්‍ය වේ. ගෝලීය ප්‍රතිවිපාක සහිත ප්‍රධාන අර්බුද ලොව පුරා මතුව ඇත, විශේෂයෙන් යුක්රේනය රුසියානු ආක්‍රමණය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ, මෙම බාහිර කම්පන නිසා ආර්ථික අර්බුදය උග්‍ර වී ඇති අතර, එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස සාමාන්‍ය ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් දිනපතා විඳදරාගන්නා දුෂ්කරතා දැකීම කම්පා කරවන සුළුය. වසංගත කාලවලදී සහ ඊට පෙර වසර 70 කට ආසන්න කාලයක් අප කළාක් මෙන්, කැනේඩියානුවන් මෙම දුෂ්කර කාලවලදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඔවුන්ගේ සහයෝගය ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානය සමඟ එක්ව අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ඖෂධ සහ සැපයුම් ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා අපි අරමුදල් සපයනවා. ජාතික පාසල් ආහාර වැඩසටහන සඳහා කඩිනමින් අවශ්‍ය සහල් තොග මිලදී ගැනීමට කැනඩාව ලෝක ආහාර වැඩසටහන සමඟ එක්ව කටයුතු කරයි. අර්බුදය උග්‍ර වන විට, එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර රතු කුරුස/රතු චන්ද්‍ර සංගම් සම්මේලනයේ මෑත කාලීන ෆ්ලෑෂ් අභියාචනාවලට අපට හොඳම ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්විය හැක්කේ කෙසේදැයි අපි සොයමින් සිටිමු.",
        "මෙම අභියෝගාත්මක කාලය මෙම සුවිශේෂී රටෙහි සහ එහි දක්ෂ පුද්ගලයින්ගේ අතිවිශාල හැකියාවන් උපයෝගී කර ගත හැකි වඩාත් ස්ථාවර, සමෘද්ධිමත් සහ සියල්ලන් ඇතුළත් සමාජයක් ගොඩනැගීමේ අවස්ථාවක් බවට පත් කිරීමට බොහෝ ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ගේ ආශාව මම අගය කරමි.",
        "විවිධ තත්වයන් යටතේ වුවද, කැනඩාවේ අපිද, අසාධාරණයේ උරුමයක් හඳුනාගෙන අවසන් කිරීම ඇතුළුව ආදිවාසී ජනතාව සමඟ සංහිඳියාව ඉදිරියට ගෙන යමින් සැමට යහපත් අනාගතයක් ගොඩනැගීමට උත්සාහ කරන්නෙමු. අපි සෑම වසරකම ලොව පුරා සිටින ලක්ෂ සංඛ්‍යාත සංක්‍රමණිකයන් සාදරයෙන් පිළිගන්නා අතරම, අපගේ සුන්දර භූමියේ පළමු වැසියන්ගෙන් පැවත එන්නන් කැනේඩියානු සමාජය තුළ පිළිගෙන පූර්ණ ලෙස සමරනු ලබන බවට සහතික කර ගැනීමට අපට අවශ්‍යය. මෙයට අනුකූලව, කැනඩාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රතිසන්ධාන ක්‍රියාවලියට මෙන්ම, රටේ සාර්ථකත්වයට අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වන කාන්තාවන් සහ ආන්තික ප්‍රජාවන් සවිබල ගැන්වීමට සහාය දක්වයි. මෙය ගොඩනැගෙන්නේ අපගේ පුලුල් පුද්ගල සම්බන්ධතා සහ දිගුකාලීන ආර්ථික බැඳීම් මතය.",
        "ලෝකය මුහුණ දී සිටින බොහෝ අභියෝග මධ්‍යයේ, අපට සියල්ලටම වඩා ගැඹුරු දේශගුණික අර්බුදය අමතක කළ නොහැක. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ මාලදිවයින යන රටවල් දෙකම දේශගුණික විපර්යාසවල බලපෑම් අත්විඳිමින් සිටිති; මාලදිවයින ඊටත් වඩා එහි භූගෝලීය පිහිටීම නිසා. දේශගුණික සහ පාරිසරික ක්‍රියාකාරකම් කැනඩාව සඳහා ප්‍රමුඛතාවයක් ලෙස පවතින අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ මාලදිවයින යන දෙඅංශයටම ප්‍රතිලාභ ලබා දෙන ගෝලීය පාරිසරික පහසුකම සහ හරිත දේශගුණික අරමුදල සඳහා අපි දිගටම දායක වන්නෙමු.",
        "මෑත වසරවලදී, අපි දේශීය පාරිසරික මුලපිරීම් සඳහා අපගේ සහයෝගය ද වැඩි කර ඇත. මාලදිවයිනේ, දේශගුණික විපර්යාසවල බලපෑම් අවම කිරීමට සහ පරිසරය සුරැකීමට මාලදිවයින් රජය දරන ප්‍රයත්නයන්ට සහාය වීම සඳහා කැනේඩියානු විශේෂඥයින් යෙදවීම හරහා අපි මේ වසරේ අපගේ ආධාර තවදුරටත් පුළුල් කරන්නෙමු.",
        "කැනඩාව හැඩගස්වා වැඩිදියුණු කරන ශ්‍රී ලංකා සහ මාලදිවයින් උරුමයන් සහිත බොහෝ කැනේඩියානුවන් පිළිබඳ සටහනකින් මා අවසන් නොකළේ නම් මට පසුබට වනු ඇත. කැනඩා දිනය අපි විවිධත්වය, සහයෝගීතාවය සහ තව තවත් ඇතුළත් අනාගතයක් සඳහා බලාපොරොත්තු වන දිනයක් වන්නේ මන්දැයි ඔවුන් නිදසුන් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කැනඩාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "රට\"-",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "කැනේඩියානු",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඩේවිඩ් මැකිනන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩේවිඩ් මැකිනන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩා දිනය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 1, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කැනඩා දිනය!",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනේඩියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කැනඩා දිනය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනේඩියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෑම දිනම",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර 70 කට ආසන්න කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනේඩියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක සෞඛ්ය සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක ආහාර වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික පාසල් ආහාර වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එ.ජා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර රතු කුරුස/රතු ක්‍රෙසන්ට් සමිති සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනේඩියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිය දහස් ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝලීය පරිසර පහසුකම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරිත දේශගුණික අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසරවල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනේඩියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩා දිනය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"இலங்கையில் நல்லிணக்கச் செயற்பாடுகளை கனடா ஆதரிக்கிறது, அத்துடன் பெண்கள் மற்றும் ஓரங்கட்டப்பட்ட சமூகங்களின் வலுவூட்டலை ஆதரிக்கிறது, அதன் வெற்றி நாட்டின் ஒருங்கிணைந்ததாகும்\" - கனேடிய தூதுவர் டேவிட் மெக்கின்னன்",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "(கனடா தினத்தை முன்னிட்டு, இலங்கையின் கொழும்பில் உள்ள கனடாவின் உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் டேவிட் மெக்கின்னனின் செய்தி - ஜூலை 1, 2022)",
        "கனடா தின வாழ்த்துக்கள்! இன்று, கனேடியர்கள் நம் நாட்டின் சாதனைகளை ஒன்றாகக் கொண்டாடுகிறார்கள், அதைச் செய்து மகிழ்வார்கள். சிறந்த கனடாவைக் கட்டியெழுப்புவதற்கு நாம் எதிர்நோக்கும் சவால்களைப் பற்றியும் சிந்திக்கிறோம்.",
        "கனடா தினம் பொதுவாக குடும்பம், நண்பர்கள் மற்றும் சமூகத்தை மையமாகக் கொண்டு முறைசாரா முறையில் கொண்டாடப்படுகிறது. இது கனடியர்களின் தேசியவாதத்தை உள்ளடக்கிய உணர்வை பிரதிபலிக்கிறது, நமது பலதரப்பட்ட குடிமக்கள் தங்கள் தனிப்பட்ட அடையாளங்களின் பல்வேறு அடுக்குகளை மேப்பிள் இலையின் கீழ் கனடியனாக இருக்க வேண்டும் என்ற மேலோட்டமான உணர்வில் ஒருங்கிணைக்க உதவுகிறது.",
        "தொற்றுநோயின் கடுமையான கட்டம், அதிர்ஷ்டவசமாக, நமக்குப் பின்னால் இருக்கும்போது, ​​​​உலகம் வேறுபட்ட மற்றும் சிக்கலான சவால்களை எதிர்கொள்கிறது, அது மீண்டும் நமது பதிலில் நாம் ஒன்றிணைந்து செயல்பட வேண்டும். உலகளாவிய விளைவுகளைக் கொண்ட பெரிய நெருக்கடிகள் உலகம் முழுவதும் தோன்றியுள்ளன, குறிப்பாக உக்ரைன் மீதான ரஷ்ய படையெடுப்பு.",
        "இலங்கையில், இந்த வெளிப்புற அதிர்ச்சிகளால் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி தீவிரமடைந்துள்ளது, இதன் விளைவாக சாதாரண இலங்கையர்கள் அன்றாடம் அனுபவிக்கும் இன்னல்களைப் பார்ப்பது வேதனை அளிக்கிறது. தொற்றுநோய் காலத்திலும் அதற்கு முன்னரும் சுமார் 70 வருடங்களாக நாம் செய்ததைப் போலவே, இந்த இக்கட்டான காலங்களில் கனேடியர்கள் இலங்கைக்கு தமது ஆதரவை வழங்கியுள்ளனர்.",
        "உலக சுகாதார நிறுவனத்துடன் இணைந்து, அத்தியாவசிய மருந்துகள் மற்றும் பொருட்களை வாங்குவதற்கு நிதியுதவி செய்து வருகிறோம். தேசிய பள்ளி உணவு திட்டத்திற்காக அவசரமாக தேவைப்படும் அரிசி இருப்புகளை வாங்குவதற்கு கனடா உலக உணவு திட்டத்துடன் இணைந்து செயல்படுகிறது. நெருக்கடி ஆழமடைகையில், ஐ.நா மற்றும் சர்வதேச செஞ்சிலுவைச் சங்கம்/செஞ்சிலுவைச் சங்கங்களின் சமீபத்திய ஃபிளாஷ் முறையீடுகளுக்கு எவ்வாறு சிறந்த முறையில் பதிலளிப்பது என்று பார்க்கிறோம்.",
        "இந்த சவாலான காலகட்டத்தை, இந்த குறிப்பிடத்தக்க நாட்டின் மற்றும் திறமையான மக்களின் மகத்தான ஆற்றலைப் பயன்படுத்தக்கூடிய மிகவும் நிலையான, வளமான மற்றும் அனைவரையும் உள்ளடக்கிய சமூகத்தை கட்டியெழுப்புவதற்கான வாய்ப்பாக மாற்றுவதற்கான பல இலங்கையர்களின் விருப்பத்தை நான் பாராட்டுகிறேன்.",
        "வெவ்வேறு சூழ்நிலைகளில், கனடாவில் நாமும், பழங்குடி மக்களுடன் நல்லிணக்கத்தை முன்னெடுத்து, அநீதியின் மரபை அங்கீகரித்து முடிவுக்கு கொண்டு வருவதன் மூலம் அனைவருக்கும் சிறந்த எதிர்காலத்தை கட்டியெழுப்ப பாடுபடுகிறோம். உலகெங்கிலும் இருந்து ஒவ்வொரு ஆண்டும் நூறாயிரக்கணக்கான புலம்பெயர்ந்தோரை நாங்கள் தொடர்ந்து வரவேற்றாலும், எங்கள் அழகான நிலத்தின் முதல் குடிமக்களின் சந்ததியினர் கனேடிய சமுதாயத்தில் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்டு முழுமையாகக் கொண்டாடப்படுவதை உறுதிசெய்ய விரும்புகிறோம். இதற்கு இணங்க, கனடா இலங்கையில் நல்லிணக்க செயல்முறையை ஆதரிக்கிறது, அத்துடன் பெண்கள் மற்றும் ஓரங்கட்டப்பட்ட சமூகங்களின் வலுவூட்டலை ஆதரிக்கிறது, அதன் வெற்றி நாட்டின் ஒருங்கிணைந்ததாகும். இது நமது விரிவான மக்களிடையேயான தொடர்புகள் மற்றும் நீண்டகால பொருளாதார உறவுகளை உருவாக்குகிறது.",
        "உலகம் எதிர்கொள்ளும் பல சவால்களுக்கு மத்தியில், எல்லாவற்றையும் விட மிக ஆழமான காலநிலை நெருக்கடியை நாம் மறந்துவிட முடியாது. இலங்கை மற்றும் மாலைதீவு ஆகிய இரண்டும் காலநிலை மாற்றத்தின் தாக்கங்களை அனுபவித்து வருகின்றன; மாலத்தீவு அதன் புவியியல் காரணமாக இன்னும் அதிகமாக உள்ளது. காலநிலை மற்றும் சுற்றாடல் செயற்பாடுகள் கனடாவின் முன்னுரிமையாக உள்ளது மேலும் இலங்கை மற்றும் மாலைதீவு ஆகிய இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் பயனளிக்கும் உலகளாவிய சுற்றுச்சூழல் வசதி மற்றும் பசுமை காலநிலை நிதியத்திற்கு நாங்கள் தொடர்ந்து பங்களிக்கிறோம்.",
        "சமீபத்திய ஆண்டுகளில், உள்ளூர் சுற்றுச்சூழல் முன்முயற்சிகளுக்கான எங்கள் ஆதரவையும் அதிகரித்துள்ளோம். மாலத்தீவில், காலநிலை மாற்றத்தின் விளைவுகளைத் தணிக்கவும் சுற்றுச்சூழலைப் பாதுகாக்கவும் மாலத்தீவு அரசாங்கத்தின் முயற்சிகளுக்கு ஆதரவளிக்க கனேடிய நிபுணர்களை அனுப்புவதன் மூலம் இந்த ஆண்டு எங்கள் உதவியை மேலும் விரிவுபடுத்துவோம்.",
        "கனடாவை தொடர்ந்து வடிவமைத்து மேம்படுத்தும் இலங்கை மற்றும் மாலத்தீவு பாரம்பரியத்தை கொண்ட பல கனேடியர்களைப் பற்றி ஒரு குறிப்புடன் முடிக்கவில்லை என்றால் நான் நிராகரிப்பேன். கனடா தினம் ஏன் பன்முகத்தன்மை, ஒற்றுமை மற்றும் எப்போதும் உள்ளடங்கிய எதிர்காலத்திற்கான நம்பிக்கையைக் கொண்டாடும் ஒரு நாள் என்பதை அவை எடுத்துக்காட்டுகின்றன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கனடா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "நாடு\"-",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "கனடியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "டேவிட் மெக்கின்னன்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "டேவிட் மெக்கின்னன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா தினம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 1, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கனடா தினம்!",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கனடா தினம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினமும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 70 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உலக சுகாதார நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக உணவு திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பள்ளி உணவு திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செஞ்சிலுவைச் சங்கம்/செஞ்சிலுவைச் சங்கங்களின் சர்வதேச கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நூறாயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலகளாவிய சுற்றுச்சூழல் வசதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசுமை காலநிலை நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமீபத்திய ஆண்டுகளில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவு",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா தினம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}