{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/அவசரகாலச்-சட்டத்தை-எதிர்த்து-வாக்களிக்க-சஜித்-அணி-முடிவு/175-301161",
  "time_ut": 1658830359,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "அவசரகாலச் சட்டத்தை எதிர்த்து வாக்களிக்க சஜித் அணி முடிவு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sajith's team decided to vote against the Emergency Act",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Parliamentary Committee and Executive Committee Meeting of United People's Power and United People's Alliance met today (26.07.2022) and reached the following conclusions.",
        "01). It was unanimously decided to vote against the Emergency Act, which was brought in to suppress the right to freedom of expression, the right to protest and the rights of people to protest against issues they face on a daily basis.",
        "02). It was decided not to collude with an oppressive government that directly and indirectly unleashed state terror without providing real solutions to people's problems.",
        "03). It was decided to support the establishment of a committee system in the Parliament to resolve the day-to-day problems of the people in the parliamentary democratic system."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sajith",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "the Emergency Act",
          "label": "LAW"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Parliamentary Committee and Executive Committee Meeting",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "United People's Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "United People's Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26.07.2022",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Emergency Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හදිසි නීතියට විරුද්ධව ඡන්දය දීමට සජිත්ගේ කණ්ඩායම තීරණය කළේය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "එක්සත් ජනතා බලය සහ එක්සත් ජනතා සන්ධානයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කාරක සභාව සහ විධායක කමිටු රැස්වීම අද (2022.07.26) රැස් වූ අතර එහිදී පහත නිගමනවලට එළැඹිණි.",
        "01) ප්‍රකාශනයේ අයිතිය, විරෝධතා දැක්වීමේ අයිතිය සහ දෛනිකව මුහුණ දෙන ප්‍රශ්නවලට විරෝධතා දැක්වීමේ අයිතිය යටපත් කිරීම සඳහා ගෙන එන ලද හදිසි නීතියට එරෙහිව ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට ඒකමතිකව තීරණය විය.",
        "02) ජනතා ප්‍රශ්නවලට සැබෑ විසඳුම් ලබා නොදී ඍජුව සහ වක්‍රව රාජ්‍ය භීෂණය මුදාහරින පීඩාකාරී ආණ්ඩුවක් සමඟ හවුල් නොවීමට තීරණය කළා.",
        "03). පාර්ලිමේන්තු ප‍්‍රජාතන්ත‍්‍රවාදී ක‍්‍රමය තුළ ජනතාවගේ එදිනෙදා ගැටලූ විසඳීම සඳහා කමිටු ක‍්‍රමයක් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව තුළ ස්ථාපිත කිරීමට සහය දැක්වීමට තීරණය කෙරුණා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සජිත්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "හදිසි නීතිය",
          "label": "LAW"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු කාරක සභාව සහ විධායක කමිටු රැස්වීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනතා බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනතා සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022.07.26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හදිසි නීතිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அவசரகாலச் சட்டத்தை எதிர்த்து வாக்களிக்க சஜித் அணி முடிவு",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தி மற்றும் ஐக்கிய மக்கள் கூட்டணியின் பாராளுமன்றக் குழுக்கூட்டம் மற்றும் செயற்குழுக் கூட்டம் என்பன இன்று (26.07.2022) கூடி பின்வரும் முடிவுகளை எட்டின.",
        "01). கருத்துத் தெரிவிக்கும் உரிமை போராட்டம் நடத்துவதற்கான உரிமை மற்றும் மக்கள் அன்றாடம் சந்திக்கும் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு எதிராக போராட்டம் நடத்தும் உரிமைகளை ஒடுக்கும் நோக்கில் கொண்டு வரப்பட்ட அவசரகாலச் சட்டத்திற்கு எதிராக வாக்களிக்க ஏகமனதாக தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "02). மக்கள் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு உண்மையான தீர்வுகளை வழங்காமல் அரச பயங்கரவாதத்தை நேரடியாகவும் மறைமுகமாகவும் கட்டவிழ்த்துவிடும் அடக்குமுறை அரசாங்கத்துடன் கூட்டுச் சேராதிருப்பதாக தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "03). பாராளுமன்ற ஜனநாயக அமைப்பில் மக்களின் அன்றாடப் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு தீர்வு காணும் முகமாக பாராளுமன்றத்தில் குழு முறைமையொன்று ஸ்தாபிக்கப்பட்டால், அதற்கு ஆதரவளிப்பது என தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சஜித்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "அவசர சட்டம்",
          "label": "LAW"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற குழு மற்றும் செயற்குழு கூட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய மக்கள் கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26.07.2022",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அவசர சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}