{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/කබ්රාල්ගේ-විදෙස්-තහනම-තවදුරටත්-දීර්ඝ-කරයි/1-616969",
  "time_ut": 1658723634,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කබ්රාල්ගේ විදෙස් තහනම තවදුරටත් දීර්ඝ කරයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Cabral's foreign ban is extended",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Colombo Additional Magistrate Harshana Kekunawela today (25) ordered to extend the ban of former Central Bank Governor Mr. Ajith Nivard Cabral, who is banned from traveling abroad in connection with the alleged bond fraud incident, until the 26th of October.",
        "These facts were presented when the Magistrate's inquiry related to this incident was called before the court again.",
        "President's lawyer Shavendra Fernando appeared before the court on behalf of the former central bank governor.",
        "A personal complaint related to this incident was presented before the court by Mr. Rajith Keerthi Tennakoon, a resident of Rajagiriya, who served as the Governor of the Southern and Central Provinces.",
        "The plaintiff informed the court through an affidavit that former Central Bank Governor Ajit Nivard Cabral was charged with criminal breach of trust, criminal breach of trust by a banker, dishonest and misappropriation of money, bearing No. 07 of 1937. (Amended) Ordinance No. 56 (a) (1) (a) that an offense has been committed."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo Additional Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harshana Kekunawela",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Nivard",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 26th of October",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shavendra Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajith Keerthi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tennakoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajagiriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southern",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "07 of 1937",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කබ්රාල්ගේ විදෙස් තහනම තවදුරටත් දීර්ඝ කරයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "බැඳුම්කර වංචාවක් සිදුකලැයි කියන සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයක් විදෙස් ගමන් තහනම් කර සිටින හිටපු මහ බැංකු අධිපති අජිත් නිවාඩ් කබ්රාල් මහතාගේ එම තහනම ලබන ඔක්තෝම්බර් මස 26 වැනිදා තෙක් දීර්ඝ කිරීමට කොළඹ අතිරේක මහේස්ත්‍රාත් හර්ෂණ කැකුණවෙල මහතා අද (25) නියෝග කෙළේය.",
        "මෙම සිද්ධියට අදාළ මහේස්ත්‍රාත් පරීක්ෂණය යළි අධිකරණය හමුවේ කැඳවූ අවස්ථාවේදී මෙම කරුණු ඉදිරිපත් විණි .",
        "හිටපු මහ බැංකු අධිපතිවරයා වෙනුවෙන් ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ ශවේන්ද්‍ර ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා අධිකරණය හමුවේ පෙනී සිටියේය.",
        "මෙම සිද්ධියට අදාළව පෞද්ගලික පැමිණිල්ලක් අධිකරණය හමුවේ ඉදිරිපත් කරනු ලැබ තිබුණේ දකුණු හා මධ්‍යම පළාත් වල ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කළ රාජගිරිය පදිංචි රජිත් කීර්ති තෙන්නකෝන් මහතා විසිනි.",
        "පැමිණිලිකරු විසින් දිවුරුම් ප්‍රකාශයක් මගින් අධිකරණයට දැනුම් දෙනු ලැබ තිබුණේ, හිටපු මහ බැංකු අධිපති වන අජිත් නිවාඩ් කබ්රාල් යන අය සාපරාධි විස්වාසය කඩ කිරීම, බැංකු කරුවෙකු විසින් සිදු කරණු ලබන සාපරාධි විස්වාසය කඩ කිරීම, මුදල් වංක ලෙස හා සාවද්‍ය ලෙස පරිහරණය කිරීම, 1937 අංක 07 දරණ (සංශෝධිත) ආඥා පනතේ අංක 56 (අ) (1) (අ) යටතේ වරදක් සිදු කර ඇති බවටය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අතිරේක මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂණ කැකුණවෙල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් නිවාඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔක්තෝබර් 26 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශවේන්ද්‍ර ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජිත් කීර්ති",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙන්නකෝන් ය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජගිරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1937 07",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கப்ராலின் வெளிநாட்டுத் தடை நீட்டிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிணைமுறி மோசடி சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் வெளிநாடு செல்ல தடை விதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள மத்திய வங்கியின் முன்னாள் ஆளுநர் திரு.அஜித் நிவார்ட் கப்ராலின் தடையை எதிர்வரும் ஒக்டோபர் 26 ஆம் திகதி வரை நீடிக்க கொழும்பு மேலதிக நீதவான் ஹர்ஷன கெகுணாவெல இன்று (25) உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இந்த சம்பவம் தொடர்பிலான நீதவான் விசாரணை மீண்டும் நீதிமன்றில் முன்னிலைப்படுத்தப்பட்ட போதே இந்த உண்மைகள் முன்வைக்கப்பட்டன.",
        "மத்திய வங்கியின் முன்னாள் ஆளுனர் சார்பில் ஜனாதிபதியின் சட்டத்தரணி சவேந்திர பெர்னாண்டோ நீதிமன்றத்தில் ஆஜராகியிருந்தார்.",
        "இச்சம்பவம் தொடர்பான தனிப்பட்ட முறைப்பாடு ஒன்று தென் மற்றும் மத்திய மாகாண ஆளுநராக கடமையாற்றிய ராஜகிரிய பிரதேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்த திரு.ரஜித் கீர்த்தி தென்னகோனால் நீதிமன்றில் முன்வைக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "மத்திய வங்கியின் முன்னாள் ஆளுநர் அஜித் நிவார்ட் கப்ரால் மீது குற்றவியல் நம்பிக்கை மீறல், வங்கியாளரால் கிரிமினல் நம்பிக்கை மீறல், நேர்மையற்ற மற்றும் துஷ்பிரயோகம் செய்தல், 1937 ஆம் ஆண்டின் 07 ஆம் இலக்கத்துடன் தொடர்புடைய குற்றங்கள் சுமத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாக மனுதாரர் வாக்குமூலம் மூலம் நீதிமன்றத்திற்கு தெரிவித்தார். (திருத்தப்பட்ட) கட்டளை எண். 56 (அ) (1) (அ) குற்றம் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு மேலதிக நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷன கெகுனாவெல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் நிவார்ட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அக்டோபர் 26 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சவேந்திர பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஜித் கீர்த்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்னகோன்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜகிரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "07 இன் 1937",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}