{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83561/sonia-gandhi-expresses-solidarity-with-sri-lanka-hopes-india-will-continue-to-assist",
  "time_ut": 1657456200,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sonia Gandhi expresses solidarity with Sri Lanka, hopes India will continue to assist",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sonia Gandhi expresses solidarity with Sri Lanka, hopes India will continue to assist",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Indian National Congress on Sunday expressed solidarity with Sri Lanka and its people in this moment of crisis and hoped that India will continue to assist the neighbouring country in dealing with the current situation.",
        "Congress president Sonia Gandhi in a message said the Indian National Congress has been following with concern the evolving political situation in Sri Lanka.",
        "She said the economic challenges, rising prices and shortage of food, fuel and essential commodities have caused enormous hardships and distress among the people there.",
        "“The Congress party expresses its solidarity with Sri Lanka and its people in this moment of grave crisis and hopes they will be able to overcome it,” Gandhi said in a statement.",
        "“We hope that India will continue to assist the people and government of Sri Lanka as they deal with the difficulties of the current situation,” she also said.",
        "Gandhi said the Congress party also urges the international community to extend all assistance and support to Sri Lanka.",
        "Anti-government protesters in Sri Lanka on Sunday continued to occupy the residences of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, a day after they stormed into the premises and set on fire one of the buildings protesting over the nation’s severe economic crisis."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sonia Gandhi",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Indian National Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sonia Gandhi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian National Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gandhi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gandhi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "a day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සෝනියා ගාන්ධි ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ සහයෝගීතාවය ප්‍රකාශ කරයි, ඉන්දියාව දිගටම සහාය වනු ඇතැයි බලාපොරොත්තු වේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දීය ජාතික කොංග්‍රසය ඉරිදා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ එහි ජනතාව සමඟ මෙම අර්බුදකාරී මොහොතේ සහයෝගීතාව ප්‍රකාශ කළ අතර වත්මන් තත්ත්වය සමඟ කටයුතු කිරීමේදී අසල්වැසි රටට ඉන්දියාව අඛණ්ඩව සහාය වනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කළේය.",
        "කොංග්‍රස් පක්ෂ සභාපති සෝනියා ගාන්ධි පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විකාශනය වන දේශපාලන තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව ඉන්දීය ජාතික කොංග්‍රසය අවධානයෙන් පසුවන බවයි.",
        "ආර්ථික අභියෝග, මිල ඉහළ යාම සහ ආහාර, ඉන්ධන සහ අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය භාණ්ඩ හිඟය හේතුවෙන් එහි ජනතාව විශාල දුෂ්කරතා සහ පීඩාවන් ඇති කර ඇති බව ඇය පැවසුවාය.",
        "\"කොංග්‍රස් පක්ෂය මෙම බරපතල අර්බුදයේ මේ මොහොතේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ එහි ජනතාව සමඟ සිය සහයෝගීතාවය ප්‍රකාශ කරන අතර එය ජය ගැනීමට ඔවුන්ට හැකි වනු ඇතැයි බලාපොරොත්තු වේ\" යනුවෙන් ගාන්ධි ප්‍රකාශයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "\"වර්තමාන තත්වයේ දුෂ්කරතා සමඟ කටයුතු කිරීමේදී ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවට සහ රජයට අඛණ්ඩව සහාය වනු ඇතැයි අපි බලාපොරොත්තු වෙමු,\" ඇය පැවසුවාය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සියලු ආධාර සහ සහාය ලබා දෙන ලෙස කොංග්‍රස් පක්ෂය ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාවෙන් ද ඉල්ලා සිටින බව ගාන්ධි පැවසීය.",
        "ජාතියේ උග්‍ර ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් විරෝධතාවයේ නිරත වූ එක් ගොඩනැගිල්ලකට ගිනි තබා දිනකට පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආණ්ඩු විරෝධී විරෝධතාකරුවන් ඉරිදා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ නිවෙස් අල්ලාගෙන සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සෝනියා ගාන්ධි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය ජාතික කොංග්‍රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොංග්රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝනියා ගාන්ධි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය ජාතික කොංග්‍රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොංග්රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාන්ධි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාන්ධි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොංග්රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சோனியா காந்தி இலங்கையுடன் ஒற்றுமையை வெளிப்படுத்துகிறார், இந்தியா தொடர்ந்து உதவும் என்று நம்புகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்த நெருக்கடியான தருணத்தில் இலங்கைக்கும் அதன் மக்களுக்கும் இந்திய தேசிய காங்கிரஸ் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை ஒருமைப்பாட்டை வெளிப்படுத்தியது மற்றும் தற்போதைய சூழ்நிலையை கையாள்வதில் அண்டை நாட்டிற்கு இந்தியா தொடர்ந்து உதவும் என்று நம்புகிறது.",
        "காங்கிரஸ் தலைவர் சோனியா காந்தி விடுத்துள்ள செய்தியில், இலங்கையில் உருவாகி வரும் அரசியல் சூழ்நிலையை இந்திய தேசிய காங்கிரஸ் கவலையுடன் பின்பற்றுகிறது.",
        "பொருளாதார சவால்கள், விலைவாசி உயர்வு மற்றும் உணவு, எரிபொருள் மற்றும் அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களின் பற்றாக்குறை ஆகியவை அங்குள்ள மக்களிடையே பெரும் சிரமங்களையும் துயரங்களையும் ஏற்படுத்தியுள்ளன.",
        "“இந்தக் கடுமையான நெருக்கடியான தருணத்தில் இலங்கை மற்றும் அதன் மக்களுடன் காங்கிரஸ் கட்சி தனது ஒற்றுமையை வெளிப்படுத்துகிறது, மேலும் அவர்களால் அதைச் சமாளிக்க முடியும் என்று நம்புகிறோம்,” என்று காந்தி ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"தற்போதைய சூழ்நிலையின் சிரமங்களைக் கையாள்வதில் இலங்கை மக்களுக்கும் அரசாங்கத்திற்கும் இந்தியா தொடர்ந்து உதவி செய்யும் என்று நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம்,\" என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கு அனைத்து உதவிகளையும் ஆதரவையும் வழங்குமாறு சர்வதேச சமூகத்தையும் காங்கிரஸ் கட்சி வலியுறுத்துகிறது என்றார் காந்தி.",
        "இலங்கையில் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை அரசாங்க எதிர்ப்பு ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச மற்றும் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கே ஆகியோரின் இல்லங்களை ஆக்கிரமித்துள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சோனியா காந்தி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய தேசிய காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோனியா காந்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய தேசிய காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காந்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காந்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}