{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/විමල්ට-එරෙහි-නඩුවක්-දෙසැම්බරයට-කල්-යයි/101-618946",
  "time_ut": 1661759730,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "විමල්ට එරෙහි නඩුවක් දෙසැම්බරයට කල් යයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A case against Vimal is adjourned to December",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Colombo Chief Magistrate Nandana Amarasinghe today (29) adjourned the hearing of the case against former Minister Wimal Weerawansa and six defendants, including former Minister Wimal Weerawansa, to the 12th of December in relation to an incident that allegedly caused public oppression by protesting the arrival of former United Nations Human Rights Commissioner Prince Al Hussain to Sri Lanka. ) ordered.",
        "This order was issued when the defendants related to this incident appeared before the court on bail.",
        "In 2016, when the former United Nations Human Rights Commissioner, Prince Said Al Hussain, visited Sri Lanka, the police had reported to the court that these defendants had protested in front of the United Nations office in Colombo by blocking the highway and causing public distress.",
        "Former Minister Wimal Weerawansa, State Minister Jayantha Samaraweera, Member of Parliament Mohammad Mussammil National Freedom Front members Weerakumara Dissanayake, Piyasiri Wijenayake, and Roger Seneviratne are the other defendants here."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Vimal",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "December",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandana Amarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 12th of December",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "United Nations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prince Al Hussain",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "United Nations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Said Al Hussain",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "United Nations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayantha Samaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament Mohammad Mussammil National Freedom Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerakumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Piyasiri Wijenayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Roger Seneviratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විමල්ට එරෙහි නඩුවක් දෙසැම්බරයට කල් යයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ හිටපු මානව හිමිකම් කොමසාරිස් අල් හුසේන් කුමරු මෙරටට පැමිණීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් උද්ඝෝෂණයක් කරමින් මහජන පීඩාවක් ඇති කළැයි කියන සිද්ධියකට අදාළව හිටපු අමාත්‍ය විමල් වීරවංශ මහතා ඇතුළු විත්තිකරුවන් හය දෙනකුට එරෙහි නඩුවේ විභාගය ලබන දෙසැම්බර් 12 වැනි දා තෙක් කල් තැබීමට කොළඹ ප්‍රධාන මහේස්ත්‍රාත් නන්දන අමරසිංහ මහතා අද (29) නියෝග කළේය.",
        "මෙම සිද්ධියට අදාළ විත්තිකරුවන් ඇප මත සිටිමින් අධිකරණය හමුවේ පෙනී සිටි අවස්ථාවේදී මෙම නියෝගය නිකුත් විණි.",
        "ඉකුත් 2016 වර්ෂයේ දී එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ හිටපු මානව හිමිකම් කොමසාරිස් සෙයිද් අල් හුසේන් කුමරු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංචාරය කළ අවස්ථාවේදී මෙම විත්තිකරුවන් කොළඹ පිහිටි එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ කාර්යාලය ඉදිරිපිට මහා මාර්ගය අවහිර කරමින් මහජන පීඩාවක් ඇති වන ආකාරයෙන් උද්ඝෝෂණයක් කල බව පොලිසිය අධිකරණයට කරුණු වාර්තා කර තිබිණි.",
        "හිටපු අමාත්‍ය විමල් වීරවංශ, රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය ජයන්ත සමරවීර, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මොහොමඩ් මුසම්මිල් ජාතික නිදහස් පෙරමුණේ සාමාජිකයින් වන වීරකුමාර දිසානායක, පියසිරි විජේනායක, සහ රොජර් සෙනෙවිරත්න යන අයවලුන් මෙහි අනෙකුත් විත්තිකරුවෝ වෙති."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "විමල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "දෙසැම්බර්",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දන අමරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙසැම්බර් 12 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල් හුසේන් කුමරු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල් හුසේන් පැවසීය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ත සමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මොහොමඩ් මුසම්මිල් ජාතික නිදහස් පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරකුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පියසිරි විජේනායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොජර් සෙනෙවිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "விமல் மீதான வழக்கு டிசம்பருக்கு ஒத்திவைக்கப்படுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் விமல் வீரவன்ச மற்றும் முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் விமல் வீரவன்ச உள்ளிட்ட 6 பிரதிவாதிகளுக்கு எதிரான வழக்கு விசாரணையை எதிர்வரும் டிசம்பர் மாதம் 12ஆம் திகதிக்கு கொழும்பு பிரதான நீதவான் நந்தன அமரசிங்க ஒத்திவைத்தார். ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபையின் முன்னாள் மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணையாளர் இளவரசர் அல் ஹுசைன் இலங்கைக்கு) உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இந்த சம்பவத்துடன் தொடர்புடைய பிரதிவாதிகள் பிணையில் நீதிமன்றில் முன்னிலையான போதே இந்த உத்தரவு பிறப்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "2016 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபையின் முன்னாள் மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணையாளர் இளவரசர் சைட் அல் ஹுசைன் இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்த போது, ​​பிரதிவாதிகள் கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபையின் அலுவலகத்திற்கு முன்பாக நெடுஞ்சாலையை மறித்து பொதுமக்களுக்கு இடையூறு விளைவித்து ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டதாக பொலிஸார் நீதிமன்றில் தெரிவித்திருந்தனர். .",
        "முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் விமல் வீரவன்ச, இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர் ஜயந்த சமரவீர, பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மொஹமட் முஸ்ஸம்மில் தேசிய சுதந்திர முன்னணி உறுப்பினர்களான வீரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க, பியசிறி விஜேநாயக்க மற்றும் ரொஜர் செனவிரத்ன ஆகியோர் இங்கு பிரதிவாதிகளாக உள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "விமல்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "டிசம்பர்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தன அமரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிசம்பர் 12 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இளவரசர் அல் ஹுசைன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அல் ஹுசைன் கூறினார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜயந்த சமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் முகம்மட் முஸம்மில் தேசிய சுதந்திர முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பியசிறி விஜேநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோஜர் செனவிரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}