{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/එජාප-උපන්-දිනේ-ඉහලින්-සමරන්න-යයි/1-618847",
  "time_ut": 1661608834,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "එජාප උපන් දිනේ ඉහලින් සමරන්න යයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "UNP is going to celebrate its birthday in a big way",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The United National Party 76th anniversary is scheduled to be held at Sugathadasa Stadium in Colombo on September 06 under the theme \"Ekwemu\".",
        "The anniversary convention will be held under the chairmanship of the UNP leader, President Ranil Wickramasinghe.",
        "The United National Party is holding this year's conference under a president of the party after 28 years. They held an anniversary conference in 1993 under a United National Party President. After that, a party anniversary will be held under a president this year."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "UNP",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "76th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sugathadasa Stadium",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "එජාප උපන් දිනේ ඉහලින් සමරන්න යයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ 76 වන සංවත්සරය “එක්වෙමු“ යන තේමාව යටතේ ලබන සැප්තැම්බර් 06 ද කොළඹ සුගතදාස ක්‍රිඩාංගනයේදි පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතය.",
        "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ නායක, ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් මෙම සංවත්සර සම්මේලනය පැවැත්වේ.",
        "පක්ෂයේ ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු යටතේ එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය මෙවර සමුළුව පවත්වන්නේ වසර 28 කට පසුවය. එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු යටතේ ඔවුන් සංවත්සර සමුළුවක් පවත්වා ඇත්තේ 1993 දීය. ඉන් පසු පක්ෂ සංවත්සරයක් ජනාධිපතිවරයකු යටතේ පවත්වන්නේ මෙවරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එජාප",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "76 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුගතදාස ක්‍රීඩාංගණය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 28 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சி தனது பிறந்தநாளை வெகு விமரிசையாகக் கொண்டாடவுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் 76ஆவது ஆண்டு நிறைவு விழா எதிர்வரும் செப்டெம்பர் 06ஆம் திகதி கொழும்பு சுகததாச விளையாட்டரங்கில் “எக்வேமு” எனும் தொனிப்பொருளில் நடைபெறவுள்ளது.",
        "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தலைவர் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தலைமையில் ஆண்டு நிறைவு விழா நடைபெறவுள்ளது.",
        "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சி 28 வருடங்களின் பின்னர் கட்சியின் தலைவர் ஒருவரின் கீழ் இவ்வருட மாநாட்டை நடத்துகிறது. அவர்கள் 1993 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தலைவரின் கீழ் ஆண்டு நிறைவு மாநாட்டை நடத்தினர். அதன்பிறகு, இந்த ஆண்டு குடியரசுத் தலைவர் தலைமையில் கட்சியின் ஆண்டு விழா நடைபெறும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "76வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகததாச மைதானம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}