{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Travel-ban-on-Cabraal-further-extended-till-October-26/108-241739",
  "time_ut": 1658726592,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Travel ban on Cabraal further extended till October 26",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Travel ban on Cabraal further extended till October 26",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Colombo Chief Magistrate's court today further extended its order preventing former Central Bank Governor Ajith Nivard Cabraal from leaving the country until October 26.",
        "Meanwhile, Colombo Additional Magistrate Harshana Kekunawala ordered to re-issue notices on former Central Bank Governor to appear in court on October 26.",
        "The Court made this order consequent to a request made by former Southern Province Governor Rajith Keerthi Thennakoon through a private plaint filed in terms of section 136(1)(a) of the Code of Criminal Procedure Act.(Lakmal Sooriyagoda)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Cabraal",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "October 26",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Nivard Cabraal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "October 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo Additional Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harshana Kekunawala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "October 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southern Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "section 136(1)(a",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කබ්රාල්ට පනවා තිබූ සංචාරක තහනම ඔක්තෝබර් 26 දක්වා දීර්ඝ කෙරේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු මහ බැංකු අධිපති අජිත් නිවාඩ් කබ්රාල්ට රටින් පිටවීම වළක්වාලමින් ලබාදුන් නියෝගය ඔක්තෝබර් 26 වැනිදා දක්වා දීර්ඝ කිරීමට කොළඹ ප්‍රධාන මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය අද නියෝග කළා.",
        "මේ අතර හිටපු මහ බැංකු අධිපතිවරයාට ඔක්තෝබර් 26 වැනිදා අධිකරණයේ පෙනී සිටින ලෙස යළි නොතීසි නිකුත් කරන ලෙස කොළඹ අතිරේක මහේස්ත්‍රාත් හර්ෂණ කැකුණවල මහතා නියෝග කළේය.",
        "අපරාධ නඩු විධාන සංග්‍රහයේ 136(1)(අ) වගන්තිය ප්‍රකාරව ගොනු කළ පෞද්ගලික පැමිණිල්ලක් මගින් දකුණු පළාත් හිටපු ආණ්ඩුකාර රජිත් කීර්ති තෙන්නකෝන් මහතා විසින් කරන ලද ඉල්ලීමකට අනුව අධිකරණය මෙම නියෝගය කළේය.(ලක්මාල් සූරියගොඩ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කබ්රාල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඔක්තෝබර් 26",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් නිවාඩ් කබ්රාල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔක්තෝබර් 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අතිරේක මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂණ කැකුණවල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔක්තෝබර් 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "වගන්තිය 136(1)(අ",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கப்ராலின் பயணத் தடை அக்டோபர் 26 வரை நீட்டிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மத்திய வங்கியின் முன்னாள் ஆளுநர் அஜித் நிவாட் கப்ரால் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறுவதைத் தடுக்கும் உத்தரவை எதிர்வரும் ஒக்டோபர் 26 ஆம் திகதி வரை கொழும்பு பிரதான நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம் இன்று மேலும் நீடித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதேவேளை, மத்திய வங்கியின் முன்னாள் ஆளுநரை எதிர்வரும் ஒக்டோபர் 26ஆம் திகதி நீதிமன்றில் ஆஜராகுமாறு மீண்டும் நோட்டீஸ் பிறப்பிக்குமாறு கொழும்பு மேலதிக நீதவான் ஹர்ஷன கெகுனாவல உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "குற்றவியல் நடைமுறைச் சட்டத்தின் 136(1)(a) பிரிவின் பிரகாரம், தென் மாகாண முன்னாள் ஆளுநர் ரஜித் கீர்த்தி தென்னகோன் தனிப்பட்ட முறையொன்றின் மூலம் தாக்கல் செய்த கோரிக்கைக்கு அமைய நீதிமன்றம் இந்த உத்தரவை பிறப்பித்துள்ளது.(லக்மால் சூரியகொட)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கப்ரால்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "அக்டோபர் 26",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் நிவார்ட் கப்ரால்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அக்டோபர் 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு மேலதிக நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷன கெகுனாவல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அக்டோபர் 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிவு 136(1)(ஏ",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}