{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83982/all-party-govt-the-best-way-to-resolve-crisis-situation-president",
  "time_ut": 1659184380,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "All-party govt, the best way to resolve crisis situation - President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "All-party govt, the best way to resolve crisis situation - President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The best way to resolve the current crisis situation in the country is an all-party government, President Ranil Wickremesinghe says.",
        "He made this remark delivering a special statement while at the President’s House in Kandy this evening (July 30).",
        "The Head of State, who is currently on a visit to Kandy, also paid homage to Sri Dalada Maligawa. This marks his first visit to the historic landmark site after taking office as the President of Sri Lanka last week.",
        "On Friday (July 29), President Wickremesinghe extended an invitation to all Members of Parliament to join discussions on forming an all-party government to create economic and social stability in the country."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Dalada Maligawa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Friday (July 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අර්බුදකාරී තත්ත්වය විසඳීමට හොඳම ක්‍රමය සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවයි - ජනපති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රට තුළ මතුව ඇති අර්බුදකාරී තත්ත්වය විසඳීමට ඇති හොඳම මාර්ගය සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පවසයි.",
        "අද (ජුලි 30) සවස මහනුවර ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ දී විශේෂ ප්‍රකාශයක් කරමින් ඔහු මේ බව සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මේ දිනවල මහනුවර ප්‍රදේශයේ සංචාරයක නිරත වන රාජ්‍ය නායකයා ශ්‍රී දළදා මාලිගාව වැඳපුදා ගත්තා. පසුගිය සතියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපති ධූරයට පත්වීමෙන් පසු ඔහු එම ඓතිහාසික සන්ධිස්ථානය වෙත පැමිණි පළමු අවස්ථාව මෙයයි.",
        "රට තුළ ආර්ථික හා සමාජීය ස්ථාවරත්වයක් ඇති කිරීම සඳහා සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡාවලට එක්වන ලෙස සිකුරාදා (ජූලි 29) ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සියලුම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට ආරාධනා කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී දළදා මාලිගාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා (ජූලි 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கமே நெருக்கடி நிலையைத் தீர்க்க சிறந்த வழி - ஜனாதிபதி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டில் தற்போது ஏற்பட்டுள்ள நெருக்கடி நிலையைத் தீர்ப்பதற்கு சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கமே சிறந்த வழி என ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இன்று (ஜூலை 30) மாலை கண்டியில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் வைத்து விசேட அறிக்கையொன்றை ஆற்றிய போதே அவர் இதனைக் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "தற்போது கண்டிக்கு விஜயம் மேற்கொண்டுள்ள அரச தலைவர், ஸ்ரீ தலதா மாளிகைக்கும் அஞ்சலி செலுத்தினார். இலங்கையின் ஜனாதிபதியாக கடந்த வாரம் பதவியேற்றதன் பின்னர், வரலாற்றுச் சிறப்புமிக்க இடத்துக்கு அவர் மேற்கொண்ட முதலாவது விஜயம் இதுவாகும்.",
        "வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (ஜூலை 29), நாட்டில் பொருளாதார மற்றும் சமூக ஸ்திரத்தன்மையை உருவாக்குவதற்காக அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பது தொடர்பான கலந்துரையாடலில் பங்கேற்குமாறு அனைத்து நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுக்கும் ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க அழைப்பு விடுத்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ தலதா மாளிகை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (ஜூலை 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}