{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Protesters-enter-Presidents-House-in-Fort/108-240705",
  "time_ut": 1657352888,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Protesters enter President’s House in Fort",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Protesters enter President’s House in Fort",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The protesters who have broken the police baricades at Chatham street in Colombo Fort have entered the President's House a short while ago.",
        "Police used tear gas and water Cannons and opened fired to disperse protesters this morning to prevent protesters from entering.",
        "However, the protesters entered the President's House after putting down the baricades.",
        "However the President has already been vacated from the premises before the protests began in Colombo.",
        "Meanwhile, at least 30 persons including two police officers were injured during ongoing protests and were admitted to the National Hospital in Colombo.(DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "House",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Fort",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Chatham street",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Fort",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "at least 30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo.(DSB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විරෝධතාකරුවෝ කොටුවේ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට ඇතුළු වෙති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොළඹ කොටුව චැතම් වීදියේ පොලිස් බාධක බිඳ දැමූ විරෝධතාකරුවන් මීට සුළු මොහොතකට පෙර ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට ඇතුළු වී තිබේ.",
        "විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට ඇතුළුවීම වැළැක්වීම සඳහා අද පෙරවරුවේ විරෝධතාකරුවන් විසුරුවා හැරීමට පොලීසිය කඳුළු ගෑස් සහ ජල ප්‍රහාර එල්ල කළ අතර වෙඩි ප්‍රහාරයක් ද එල්ල කළේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, විරෝධතාකරුවන් බාධක පුවරු දමා ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට ඇතුළු විය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් කොළඹ විරෝධතා ආරම්භ වීමටත් පෙර ජනාධිපතිවරයා එම පරිශ්‍රයෙන් ඉවත්ව ගොස් තිබේ.",
        "මේ අතර, අඛණ්ඩ විරෝධතා අතරතුරදී පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් දෙදෙනෙකු ඇතුළු අවම වශයෙන් පුද්ගලයින් 30 දෙනෙකු තුවාල ලබා කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කර ඇත.(DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නිවස",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "බලකොටුව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චැතම් වීදිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් 30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ.(ඩී.එස්.බී",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோட்டையில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்குள் போராட்டக்காரர்கள் நுழைந்தனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பு கோட்டை சத்தம் வீதியில் பொலிஸ் தடுப்புகளை உடைத்த ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் சற்று முன்னர் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்குள் பிரவேசித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இன்று காலை போராட்டக்காரர்கள் உள்ளே நுழைவதை தடுக்கும் வகையில் போலீசார் கண்ணீர்புகை மற்றும் தண்ணீர் பீரங்கிகளை பயன்படுத்தி போராட்டக்காரர்களை கலைக்க துப்பாக்கிச்சூடு நடத்தினர்.",
        "ஆனால், பேரிகார்டுகளை போட்டுவிட்டு போராட்டக்காரர்கள் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்குள் நுழைந்தனர்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், கொழும்பில் போராட்டம் தொடங்குவதற்கு முன்பே ஜனாதிபதி வளாகத்தில் இருந்து வெளியேற்றப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, இடம்பெற்று வரும் போராட்டங்களின் போது இரண்டு பொலிஸ் அதிகாரிகள் உட்பட குறைந்தது 30 பேர் காயமடைந்து கொழும்பில் உள்ள தேசிய வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.(DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வீடு",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "கோட்டை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சாத்தம் தெரு",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு.(டி.எஸ்.பி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}