{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Ready-even-to-beg-to-provide-free-meals-to-school-children-Susil/342-244132",
  "time_ut": 1662014736,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ready even to beg to provide free meals to school children: Susil",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ready even to beg to provide free meals to school children: Susil",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Whilst stating that there is nothing wrong in getting assistance from foreign countries and international organizations to provide free meals to school children, the Minister of Education Susil Premajayantha today and he also said the opposition members should come forward to meet foreign diplomats and seek assistance for the nation.",
        "Minister Premajayantha was referring to the reports which said he had even begged for assistance from the USA to feed the school children.",
        "“I am prepared to beg from foreign nations and international institutions to provide free mid-day meals for the schoolchildren. I also request the opposition parties to meet the foreign diplomats and do their best for Sri Lanka,” he said.",
        "“The yellow split lentils and canned fish donated by the US Department of agriculture will be provided to school children shortly. This program will be monitored by the 'Save the Children' organization,” he added.",
        "He recalled that Sri Lanka was donated a consignment of rice from China as well. (Yohan Perera and Ajith Siriwardana)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Susil Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "USA",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "mid-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the US Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 'Save the Children'",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yohan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Siriwardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාසල් දරුවන්ට නොමිලේ කෑම දෙන්න හිඟා කන්නත් සූදානම් : සුසිල්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාසල් සිසුන්ට නොමිලේ ආහාර ලබාදීම සඳහා විදේශ රටවලින් සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර සංවිධානවලින් ආධාර ලබා ගැනීමේ වරදක් නොමැති බව පවසන අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍ය සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත මහතා අද විදේශ රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රිකයින් හමුවී ඒ සඳහා සහාය ලබා ගැනීමට විපක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ඉදිරිපත් විය යුතු බව ද පැවසීය. ජාතිය.",
        "අමාත්‍ය ප්‍රේමජයන්ත මේ බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේ පාසල් දරුවන්ට ආහාර ලබාදීම සඳහා ඇමරිකාවෙන් පවා ආධාර ඉල්ලා ඇති බවට පළ වූ වාර්තා පිළිබඳවයි.",
        "“පාසල් දරුවන්ට නොමිලයේ දිවා ආහාරය ලබා දෙන ලෙස විදේශ රටවලින් සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර ආයතනවලින් ඉල්ලා සිටීමට මම සූදානම්. ඒ වගේම විදේශ රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රිකයන් හමුවී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වෙනුවෙන් උපරිමයෙන් කටයුතු කරන ලෙස මම විරුද්ධ පක්ෂවලින් ඉල්ලා සිටිනවා.",
        "“එක්සත් ජනපද කෘෂිකර්ම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව මගින් පරිත්‍යාග කරන ලද කහ බෙදුණු පරිප්පු සහ ටින් මාළු ළඟදීම පාසල් සිසුන්ට ලබා දෙනවා. මෙම වැඩසටහන ‘සේව් ද චිල්ඩ්රන්’ සංවිධානය විසින් අධීක්ෂණය කරනු ලබනවා,” ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "චීනයෙන් ද ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහල් තොගයක් පරිත්‍යාග කළ බව ඔහු සිහිපත් කළේය. (යොහාන් පෙරේරා සහ අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇඑජ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැද භාගයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "'දරුවන් සුරකින්න'",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යොහාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பள்ளி மாணவர்களுக்கு இலவச உணவு வழங்க பிச்சை எடுக்க கூட தயார்: சுசில்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாடசாலை மாணவர்களுக்கு இலவச உணவு வழங்குவதற்கு வெளிநாடுகள் மற்றும் சர்வதேச அமைப்புகளின் உதவிகளைப் பெறுவதில் தவறில்லை எனத் தெரிவித்த கல்வி அமைச்சர் சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த, வெளிநாட்டு இராஜதந்திரிகளைச் சந்தித்து உதவிகளைப் பெற எதிர்க்கட்சி உறுப்பினர்கள் முன்வர வேண்டும் எனவும் அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். நாடு.",
        "அமைச்சர் பிரேமஜயந்த, பாடசாலை மாணவர்களுக்கு உணவு வழங்குவதற்கு அமெரிக்காவிடம் உதவி கோருவதாகவும் வெளியான செய்திகள் தொடர்பில் சுட்டிக்காட்டியிருந்தார்.",
        "“பள்ளி மாணவர்களுக்கு இலவச மதிய உணவை வழங்குமாறு வெளிநாடுகள் மற்றும் சர்வதேச நிறுவனங்களிடம் மன்றாட நான் தயாராக இருக்கிறேன். வெளிநாட்டு இராஜதந்திரிகளைச் சந்தித்து இலங்கைக்கு தங்களால் இயன்றதைச் செய்யுமாறு எதிர்க்கட்சிகளையும் கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறேன்” என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "“அமெரிக்க வேளாண்மைத் துறையால் வழங்கப்பட்ட மஞ்சள் பிளவு பயறு மற்றும் டின் மீன் விரைவில் பள்ளி மாணவர்களுக்கு வழங்கப்படும். இந்த நிகழ்ச்சியை ‘சேவ் தி சில்ட்ரன்’ அமைப்பு கண்காணிக்கும்,” என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "சீனாவில் இருந்தும் இலங்கைக்கு ஒரு தொகை அரிசி நன்கொடையாக கிடைத்ததை அவர் நினைவு கூர்ந்தார். (யோஹான் பெரேரா மற்றும் அஜித் சிறிவர்தன)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்தியானம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "'குழந்தைகளைக் காப்பாற்றுங்கள்'",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோஹான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}