{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/02/heavy-showers-to-be-expected-today-2/",
  "time_ut": 1659407820,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Heavy showers to be expected today (2)",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Heavy showers to be expected today (2)",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Department of Meteorology says that showery and windy conditions are expected to continue in the western and southern sea areas and over the southwest quarter of the island with the strengthening of the Southwest Monsoon.",
        "Showers or thundershowers will occur at times in Western, Sabaragamuwa, Central, Northern, and North-Western provinces and Galle and Matara districts.",
        "Heavy falls above 100 mm can be expected at some places in aforesaid areas.",
        "Several spells of showers may occur in North -Central province.",
        "Strong winds of about 50 kmph can be expected at times along the western slopes of the Central hills and in the North-central, Western, North-western, and Southern provinces."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the southwest quarter",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Southwest Monsoon",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Northern",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "North-Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100 mm",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "North -Central",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 50 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southern",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අද (2) තද වැසි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); නිරිතදිග මෝසම ශක්තිමත් වීමත් සමඟ දිවයිනේ බස්නාහිර සහ දකුණු මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල සහ දිවයිනේ නිරිතදිග කාර්තුවේ වැසි සහ සුළං තත්ත්වය තවදුරටත් අපේක්ෂා කරන බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "බස්නාහිර, සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම, උතුර සහ වයඹ පළාත්වලත් ගාල්ල සහ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් විටින් විට වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇති වේ.",
        "ඉහත ප්‍රදේශවල ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලිමීටර් 100 ට වැඩි තද වැසි අපේක්ෂා කළ හැක.",
        "උතුරු-මැද පළාතේ වැසි වාර කිහිපයක් ඇති විය හැක.",
        "මධ්‍යම කඳුකරයේ බටහිර බෑවුම් ප්‍රදේශවල සහ උතුරු-මැද, බස්නාහිර, වයඹ සහ දකුණු පළාත්වල විටින් විට පැ.කි.මී.50ක පමණ තද සුළං බලාපොරොත්තු විය හැක."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිරිතදිග කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිරිතදිග මෝසම",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උතුරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100 මි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උතුරු මැද",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 kmph පමණ වේ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இன்று (2) பலத்த மழை பெய்யும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); தென்மேற்கு பருவக்காற்று வலுவடைவதால், மேற்கு மற்றும் தெற்கு கடற்பரப்புகளிலும், தீவின் தென்மேற்கு பகுதியிலும் மழை மற்றும் காற்றுடன் கூடிய காலநிலை தொடரும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுவதாக வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மேல், சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய, வடக்கு மற்றும் வடமேல் மாகாணங்களிலும் காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறை மாவட்டங்களிலும் அவ்வப்போது மழை அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை பெய்யும்.",
        "மேற்குறிப்பிட்ட பிரதேசங்களில் சில இடங்களில் 100 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கு மேல் பலத்த வீழ்ச்சியை எதிர்பார்க்கலாம்.",
        "வடமத்திய மாகாணத்தில் பல தடவைகள் மழை பெய்யக்கூடும்.",
        "மத்திய மலைநாட்டின் மேற்கு சரிவுகளிலும் வடமத்திய, மேற்கு, வடமேற்கு மற்றும் தென் மாகாணங்களிலும் அவ்வப்போது மணித்தியாலத்துக்கு 50 கிலோமீற்றர் வேகத்தில் பலத்த காற்று வீசக்கூடும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்மேற்கு காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்மேற்கு பருவமழை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடமேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100 மி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வட-மத்திய",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 50 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}