{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Canadian-High-Commissioner-calls-on-President-McKinnon-expresses-support/56-737209",
  "time_ut": 1657234556,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Canadian High Commissioner calls on President; McKinnon expresses support",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Canadian High Commissioner calls on President; McKinnon expresses support",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Canadian High Commissioner David McKinnon called on President Gotabaya Rajapaksa yesterday and discussed a number of bilateral matters and ways and means of further strengthening diplomatic relations between the two countries.",
        "Post-meeting via a tweet Mackinnon said during the meeting with Rajapaksa he discussed the economic and political crisis including the hardships so many Sri Lankans are facing.",
        "“Canada is committed to support SL in line with IMF policies, to enable an early return to macroeconomic stability and growth. Canada strongly supports the political and economic reform necessary for a peaceful, reconciled, and prosperous Sri Lanka. Particularly at this sensitive time, the democratic right to peaceful protest must be respected throughout the country,” McKinnon aid.",
        "“Canada will continue to support Sri Lankans during this crisis, including ongoing assistance to procure medicine and strengthen food security via UN SriLanka, other agencies, and the Canada Fund,” he added."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Canadian",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Canadian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "David McKinnon",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mackinnon",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Canada Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කැනේඩියානු මහ කොමසාරිස් ජනපති හමුවෙයි; McKinnon සහයෝගය ප්රකාශ කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "කැනේඩියානු මහ කොමසාරිස් ඩේවිඩ් මැකිනොන් මහතා ඊයේ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා හමුවූ අතර දෙරට අතර රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික සබඳතා තවදුරටත් ශක්තිමත් කර ගැනීමේ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික කරුණු සහ ක්‍රම සහ විධි රැසක් පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කළේය.",
        "ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් හරහා පශ්චාත් රැස්වීමක් පවත්වමින් මැකිනොන් කියා සිටියේ රාජපක්ෂ සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවේදී බොහෝ ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් මුහුණ දෙන දුෂ්කරතා ඇතුළු ආර්ථික හා දේශපාලන අර්බුදය පිළිබඳව තමා සාකච්ඡා කළ බවයි.",
        "“සාර්ව ආර්ථික ස්ථාවරත්වයට සහ වර්ධනයට ඉක්මනින් නැවත පැමිණීමට හැකිවන පරිදි IMF ප්‍රතිපත්තිවලට අනුකූලව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය වීමට කැනඩාව කැපවී සිටී. සාමකාමී, සංහිඳියා සහ සමෘද්ධිමත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවක් සඳහා අවශ්‍ය දේශපාලන හා ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සඳහා කැනඩාව දැඩි ලෙස සහාය දක්වයි. විශේෂයෙන්ම මෙම සංවේදී අවස්ථාවේදී, රට පුරා සාමකාමී විරෝධතා දැක්වීමේ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී අයිතියට ගරු කළ යුතුය,” මැකිනන් ආධාර කරයි.",
        "\"එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව, අනෙකුත් ආයතන සහ කැනඩා අරමුදල හරහා ඖෂධ ලබා ගැනීම සහ ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතාව ශක්තිමත් කිරීම සඳහා අඛණ්ඩ ආධාර ඇතුළුව, මෙම අර්බුදය තුළ කැනඩාව ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින්ට අඛණ්ඩව සහාය වනු ඇත,\" ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කැනේඩියානු",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කැනේඩියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේවිඩ් මැකිනන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැකිනොන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එ.ජා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩා අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கனேடிய உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு அழைப்பு; McKinnon ஆதரவு தெரிவிக்கிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கனேடிய உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் டேவிட் மெக்கின்னன் நேற்று ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை சந்தித்து இருதரப்பு விவகாரங்கள் மற்றும் இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையிலான இராஜதந்திர உறவுகளை மேலும் வலுப்படுத்துவதற்கான வழிமுறைகள் மற்றும் வழிமுறைகள் குறித்து கலந்துரையாடினார்.",
        "ராஜபக்சேவுடனான சந்திப்பின் போது, ​​இலங்கையர்கள் எதிர்கொள்ளும் இன்னல்கள் உள்ளிட்ட பொருளாதார மற்றும் அரசியல் நெருக்கடிகள் குறித்து விவாதித்ததாக ட்வீட் மூலம் மெக்கினன் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"கனடா IMF கொள்கைகளுக்கு ஏற்ப SL ஐ ஆதரிக்க உறுதிபூண்டுள்ளது, இது மேக்ரோ பொருளாதார ஸ்திரத்தன்மை மற்றும் வளர்ச்சிக்கு முன்கூட்டியே திரும்புவதற்கு உதவுகிறது. அமைதியான, நல்லிணக்க மற்றும் வளமான இலங்கைக்கு தேவையான அரசியல் மற்றும் பொருளாதார சீர்திருத்தத்தை கனடா வலுவாக ஆதரிக்கிறது. குறிப்பாக இந்த முக்கியமான நேரத்தில், அமைதியான போராட்டத்திற்கான ஜனநாயக உரிமை நாடு முழுவதும் மதிக்கப்பட வேண்டும்,” என்று மெக்கின்னன் உதவுகிறார்.",
        "\"இந்த நெருக்கடியின் போது இலங்கையர்களுக்கு கனடா தொடர்ந்து ஆதரவளிக்கும், இதில் மருந்துகளை வாங்குவதற்கும், உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பை வலுப்படுத்துவதற்கும் ஐ.நா. ஸ்ரீலங்கா, பிற முகவர் நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் கனடா நிதியம் ஆகியவற்றின் மூலம் உதவிகள் வழங்கப்படுகின்றன\" என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கனடியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கனடியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "டேவிட் மெக்கின்னன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாக்கினான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}