{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Wanted-Nigerian-national-fleeing-with-forged-passport-nabbed-at-BIA/342-239895",
  "time_ut": 1656344468,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Wanted Nigerian national fleeing with forged passport nabbed at BIA",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Wanted Nigerian national fleeing with forged passport nabbed at BIA",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "He was ordered not to leave the country due to two pending cases at Colombo High Court and Colombo Chief Magistrate’s Court over financial scams",
        "The passenger was stopped at the Immigration counters as his passport looked dodgy",
        "A Nigerian national wanted for two Court cases in Colombo and who had tried to flee the country to Cambodia via Malaysia and Singapore with a forged Seychelles passport was nabbed by the immigration officials at the Bandaranaike International Airport (BIA) on Sunday night.",
        "The suspect had tried to board a Malaysian Airlines flight MH 178 bound for Kuala Lumpur around 10.30pm Sunday with two boarding passes for KL and Singapore, the Immigration sources told the Daily Mirror.",
        "Although, he had managed to pass through the check-in counters the passenger was stopped at the Immigration counters as his passport looked dodgy. The Immigration Officer at the counter who felt suspicious about the passenger had referred him to the Chief Immigration Officer for further inquiries.",
        "There the suspect was questioned but the latter was somewhat unruly and arguing without cooperating with the officials and had refused to tell his actual whereabouts.",
        "The immigration officials then sought the expertise assistance of the BSU (Border Surveillance Unit) at the airport and the travel documents were subjected to a technical examination to learn that the Seychelles passport was forged.",
        "The passenger’s passport bore he was a Seychelles citizen under the name Payet Samson but officials found that he was originally a Nigerian national named Jude Chisimdiri Anyanwu of Abuja.",
        "Further the immigration system had provided details that the suspect had arrived in the country in 2018 and had been wanted by two investigations one at the Colombo High Court and the other at Colombo Chief Magistrate’s Courts over financial scams. He had been ordered not to leave the country until the cases are over and his original passport is believed to be impounded by Courts.",
        "Chief Immigration Officer C Vidanagama and Immigration Officer M A Gunawardena are conducting further inquiries.They suspect that the Seychelles passport had been forged in Sri Lanka.",
        "The suspect had been handed over to the Criminal Investigation Department officials at the BIA for further investigations. (Kurulu Koojana Kariyakarawana)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Nigerian",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo High Court and Colombo Chief Magistrate’s Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nigerian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cambodia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malaysia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seychelles",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bandaranaike International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Malaysian Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MH 178",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kuala Lumpur",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "KL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Immigration Officer",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "BSU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Border Surveillance Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seychelles",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Seychelles",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Payet Samson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nigerian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jude Chisimdiri Anyanwu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo High Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Seychelles",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurulu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Koojana Kariyakarawana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ව්‍යාජ විදේශ ගමන් බලපත්‍රයක් සමඟ පලා යාමට අවශ්‍ය නයිජීරියානු ජාතිකයෙකු BIA හිදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මූල්‍ය වංචා සම්බන්ධයෙන් කොළඹ මහාධිකරණයේ සහ කොළඹ ප්‍රධාන මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයේ විභාග වන නඩු දෙකක් හේතුවෙන් ඔහුට රටින් පිටව නොයන ලෙසට නියෝග කෙරුණා.",
        "ඔහුගේ විදේශ ගමන් බලපත්‍රය අශෝභන ලෙස දිස් වූ බැවින් මගියා ආගමන විගමන කවුන්ටරවල නතර කරන ලදී",
        "කොළඹ අධිකරණ නඩු දෙකක් සඳහා අවශ්‍යව සිටි නයිජීරියානු ජාතිකයෙකු ව්‍යාජ සීෂෙල්ස් විදේශ ගමන් බලපත්‍රයක් සමඟ මැලේසියාව සහ සිංගප්පූරුව හරහා කාම්බෝජයට පලා යාමට තැත් කළ ඉරිදා රාත්‍රියේ බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපලේදී (BIA) ආගමන විගමන නිලධාරීන් විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "සැකකරු ඉරිදා රාත්‍රී 10.30 ට පමණ ක්වාලාලම්පූර් බලා පිටත් වූ MH 178 මැලේසියානු ගුවන් යානයට KL සහ සිංගප්පූරුව සඳහා බෝඩිං බලපත්‍ර දෙකක් රැගෙන යාමට උත්සාහ කර ඇති බව ආගමන විගමන ආරංචි මාර්ග ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "ඔහු ඇතුල්වීමේ කවුන්ටර හරහා යාමට සමත් වුවද, ඔහුගේ විදේශ ගමන් බලපත්‍රය අශෝභන ලෙස පෙනුණු බැවින් මගියා ආගමන විගමන කවුන්ටරවල නතර කරන ලදී. කවුන්ටරයේ සිටි ආගමන නිළධාරියා විසින් මගියා පිළිබඳව සැකයක් ඇති වූ අතර වැඩිදුර පරීක්ෂණ සඳහා ඔහු ප්‍රධාන ආගමන නිලධාරි වෙත යොමු කර ඇත.",
        "එහිදී සැකකරුගෙන් ප්‍රශ්න කළ නමුත් සැකකරු තරමක් නොසන්සුන් වී නිලධාරීන් සමඟ සහයෝගයෙන් කටයුතු නොකර බහින්බස් වෙමින් සිටි අතර ඔහු සැබෑ ස්ථානය පැවසීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කර ඇත.",
        "අනතුරුව ආගමන විගමන නිලධාරීන් ගුවන් තොටුපළේ BSU (දේශසීමා නිරීක්ෂණ ඒකකය) හි විශේෂඥ සහාය ලබා ගත් අතර සීෂෙල්ස් විදේශ ගමන් බලපත්‍රය ව්‍යාජ එකක් බව දැන ගැනීමට සංචාරක ලියකියවිලි තාක්ෂණික පරීක්ෂණයකට භාජනය කරන ලදී.",
        "මගියාගේ විදේශ ගමන් බලපත්‍රයේ ඔහු පයෙට් සැම්සන් නමින් සීෂෙල්ස් පුරවැසියෙකු වූ නමුත් නිලධාරීන් සොයා ගත්තේ ඔහු මුලින් නයිජීරියානු ජාතිකයෙකු වන අබුජා හි ජූඩ් චිසිම්දිරි අන්යන්වු බවයි.",
        "තවද සැකකරු 2018 වසරේ මෙරටට පැමිණ ඇති බවත්, මූල්‍ය වංචා සම්බන්ධයෙන් කොළඹ මහාධිකරණයේ සහ අනෙක කොළඹ ප්‍රධාන මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයේ විමර්ශන දෙකකින් සැකකරු අවශ්‍යව සිටි බවටද ආගමන විගමන පද්ධතිය තොරතුරු සපයා තිබුණි. නඩු අවසන් වන තුරු ඔහුට රටින් පිටව නොයන ලෙසට නියෝග කර තිබූ අතර ඔහුගේ මුල් ගමන් බලපත්‍රය අධිකරණය භාරයට ගනු ඇතැයි විශ්වාස කෙරේ.",
        "ප්‍රධාන ආගමන නිලධාරි සී විදානගම සහ ආගමන විගමන නිලධාරී එම් ඒ ගුණවර්ධන යන මහත්වරු වැඩිදුර පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වති. සීෂෙල්ස් විදේශ ගමන් බලපත්‍රය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ව්‍යාජ ලෙස සකස් කර ඇති බවට ඔවුහු සැක කරති.",
        "සැකකරු වැඩිදුර විමර්ශන සඳහා BIA හි අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තු නිලධාරීන් වෙත භාර දී ඇත. (කුරුළු කූජන කාරියකරවන)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නයිජීරියානු",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ මහාධිකරණය සහ කොළඹ ප්‍රධාන මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "නයිජීරියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාම්බෝජය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැලේසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීෂෙල්ස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැලේසියානු ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MH 178",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්වාලාලම්පූර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේ.එල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආගමන නිලධාරියා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "BSU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දේශසීමා නිරීක්ෂණ ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීෂෙල්ස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සීෂෙල්ස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පයෙට් සැම්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නයිජීරියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූඩ් චිසිම්දිරි අන්යන්වු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ මහාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සීෂෙල්ස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුලු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කූජන කාරියකරවන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "போலி பாஸ்போர்ட்டுடன் தப்பியோடிய நைஜீரிய நாட்டவர் BIA இல் பிடிபட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நிதி மோசடிகள் தொடர்பில் கொழும்பு மேல் நீதிமன்றம் மற்றும் கொழும்பு பிரதான நீதவான் நீதிமன்றில் நிலுவையில் உள்ள இரண்டு வழக்குகள் காரணமாக அவர் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேற வேண்டாம் என உத்தரவிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "கடவுச்சீட்டு அடாவடியாக இருந்ததால் பயணி குடிவரவு கவுன்டர்களில் நிறுத்தப்பட்டார்",
        "கொழும்பில் இரண்டு நீதிமன்ற வழக்குகளுக்காக தேடப்பட்டு வந்த நைஜீரிய பிரஜை ஒருவர் போலியான சீஷெல்ஸ் கடவுச்சீட்டுடன் மலேசியா மற்றும் சிங்கப்பூர் ஊடாக நாட்டை விட்டு கம்போடியாவிற்கு தப்பிச் செல்ல முயன்றவர் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை இரவு பண்டாரநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தில் (BIA) குடிவரவு அதிகாரிகளால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டார்.",
        "சந்தேக நபர் KL மற்றும் சிங்கப்பூருக்கான இரண்டு போர்டிங் பாஸ்களுடன் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை இரவு 10.30 மணியளவில் கோலாலம்பூருக்குச் செல்லும் MH 178 என்ற மலேசியன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் விமானத்தில் ஏற முயன்றதாக குடிவரவு வட்டாரங்கள் டெய்லி மிரருக்கு தெரிவித்தன.",
        "அவர் செக்-இன் கவுண்டர்கள் வழியாகச் சென்றாலும், அவரது கடவுச்சீட்டு அசிங்கமாகத் தெரிந்ததால், பயணி குடிவரவு கவுன்டர்களில் நிறுத்தப்பட்டார். பயணி மீது சந்தேகம் கொண்ட கவுண்டரில் இருந்த குடிவரவு அதிகாரி, மேலதிக விசாரணைகளுக்காக அவரை தலைமை குடிவரவு அதிகாரியிடம் பரிந்துரைத்துள்ளார்.",
        "அங்கு சந்தேக நபரிடம் விசாரணை நடத்தப்பட்டது, ஆனால் அவர் அதிகாரிகளுடன் ஒத்துழைக்காமல் சற்றே கட்டுக்கடங்காமல் வாக்குவாதத்தில் ஈடுபட்டார்.",
        "குடிவரவு அதிகாரிகள் பின்னர் விமான நிலையத்தில் உள்ள BSU (எல்லை கண்காணிப்பு பிரிவு) வின் நிபுணத்துவ உதவியை நாடினர் மற்றும் செஷல்ஸ் பாஸ்போர்ட் போலியானது என்பதை அறிய பயண ஆவணங்கள் தொழில்நுட்ப பரிசோதனைக்கு உட்படுத்தப்பட்டன.",
        "பயணியின் கடவுச்சீட்டில் அவர் பேயட் சாம்சன் என்ற பெயரில் சீஷெல்ஸ் குடிமகனாக இருந்தார், ஆனால் அவர் முதலில் நைஜீரிய நாட்டைச் சேர்ந்த அபுஜாவைச் சேர்ந்த ஜூட் சிசிம்திரி அன்யான்வு என்று அதிகாரிகள் கண்டறிந்தனர்.",
        "மேலும், சந்தேக நபர் 2018 ஆம் ஆண்டு நாட்டிற்கு வந்ததாகவும், நிதி மோசடிகள் தொடர்பாக கொழும்பு மேல் நீதிமன்றத்திலும் மற்றொன்று கொழும்பு பிரதான நீதவான் நீதிமன்றிலும் இரண்டு விசாரணைகளின் மூலம் தேடப்பட்டவர் எனவும் குடிவரவு அமைப்பு விபரங்களை வழங்கியிருந்தது. வழக்குகள் முடியும் வரை அவர் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேற வேண்டாம் என்று உத்தரவிடப்பட்டது மற்றும் அவரது அசல் பாஸ்போர்ட் நீதிமன்றத்தால் பறிமுதல் செய்யப்படும் என்று நம்பப்படுகிறது.",
        "குடிவரவு குடியகழ்வு அதிகாரி சி விதானகம மற்றும் குடிவரவு குடியகழ்வு அதிகாரி எம் ஏ குணவர்தன ஆகியோர் மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்.சீஷெல்ஸ் கடவுச்சீட்டு இலங்கையில் போலியாக தயாரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அவர்கள் சந்தேகிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "சந்தேக நபர் மேலதிக விசாரணைகளுக்காக BIA இன் குற்றப் புலனாய்வு திணைக்கள அதிகாரிகளிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார். (குருலு கூஜன காரியகரவன)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நைஜீரியர்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு மேல் நீதிமன்றம் மற்றும் கொழும்பு பிரதான நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நைஜீரியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்போடியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலேசியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீஷெல்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்கா சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிறு இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மலேசியன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MH 178",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோலா லம்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கே.எல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவு அதிகாரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "BSU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்லை கண்காணிப்பு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீஷெல்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீஷெல்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பயேட் சாம்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நைஜீரியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூட் சிசிம்திரி அன்யான்வு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு உயர் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீஷெல்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருலு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கூஜன காரியகரவன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}