{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/mirror_sports_cricket/Middle-order-steers-Aussies-home-in-tense-chase/458-239730",
  "time_ut": 1656088220,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Middle order steers Aussies home in tense chase",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Middle order steers Aussies home in tense chase",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "Australia’s middle-order overcame a stern examination by Sri Lanka’s spinners on a difficult surface to win the final ODI of their five-match series versus Sri Lanka by four wickets at the R. Premadasa Stadium on Friday.",
        "Dunith Wellalage (3 for 42) and Maheesh Theekshana (2 for 26) were all over the Australian top-order who were chasing an under-par total, but Alex Carey (45 no) and Cameron Green (25 no) held their nerve to see Australia over the line and record a consolation win despite having lost the ODI series.",
        "The visitors’ chase began on a disastrous note with Captain Aaron Finch perishing after a torrid working over by Theekshana that saw him survive two close calls before eventually gloving an attempted sweep off his third ball at the crease. David Warner then followed with a leaping Danushka Gunathilaka intercepting a full-blooded crack down the ground off the bowling of Wellalage.",
        "Theekshana then had Josh Inglis on ODI debut caught at leg-slip that had the visitors floundering at 19 for 3. Mitchell Marsh fought his way to 20 but became debutant Pramod Madushan’s first international wicket in an ill-judged attempt to go aerial.",
        "A half-century stand between Marnus Labuschagne and Alex Carey helped steady the ship but Sri Lanka came roaring back into the contest courtesy Wellalage’s second spell where he produced two beautiful ripping deliveries to send Labuschagne and thereafter the dangerous Glenn Maxwell back to the pavilion.",
        "However, it was not to be for the home side as Green paired up with Carey to knock off the remaining 40 runs for victory.",
        "Batting first, the home side was in danger of failing to even make three figures before a gutsy run-a-ball knock of 75 by Chamika Karunaratne gave the total a degree of respectability.",
        "Left to bat with the tail, the right-hander manipulated the field to great effect and played several eye-catching strokes while stitching together a 58-run partnership for the ninth wicket with debutant Pramod Madushan.",
        "The pair batted through 17 overs, and while Madushan only made 15 in his 52 deliveries at the wicket, it gave Karunaratne much needed support that enabled him to record his maiden international half-century that was brought up with an authoritative pull to the mid-wicket boundary.",
        "Madushan was eventually dismissed caught and bowled by Green in the 42nd over, and left with just number 11 for company, Karunaratne decided to chance his arm. He smacked Labuschagne’s leg-spin for two powerful sixes but eventually fell trying to take on the returning Pat Cummins.",
        "Earlier, Australia’s pacemen claimed three scalps in the opening powerplay with Pathum Nissanka edging to the wicket keeper while Danuska Gunathilaka and the returning Dinesh Chandimal both hitting the ball straight to the Australian captain on the thirty-yard circle",
        "Kusal Mendis (26) appeared in fine touch, unfurling three crisp strokes through the off-side ring to start with. However, his efforts to mount a recovery with hero of the last game, Charith Asalanka, were brought to a screeching halt as the latter was run out in a dreadful mix up, which was followed by Mendis treading on his stumps the very next ball while attempting a pull.",
        "The parade of wickets continued as Wellalage injudiciously tried to hit Matt Kuhnemann over the top off just his second ball only to find Pat Cummins at mid-on. Captain Dasun Shanaka followed in the very same over with his stumps rattled by an innocuous half-volley on leg-stump, leaving Sri Lanka reeling at 62 for seven before Karunaratne and the lower-order began their recovery efforts.",
        "Following the game, loud chants of “Australia!, Australia!” were heard throughout the stadium by fans who had come largely dressed in yellow to appreciate the touring side for making the journey for an all-format tour amidst the economic crisis in Sri Lanka."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Aussies",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the R. Premadasa Stadium",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "42",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Theekshana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alex Carey",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cameron Green",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Aaron Finch",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Theekshana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "David Warner",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Danushka Gunathilaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Theekshana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Josh Inglis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mitchell Marsh",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pramod Madushan’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "half-century",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marnus Labuschagne",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alex Carey",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wellalage",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Labuschagne",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Glenn Maxwell",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Green",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Carey",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chamika Karunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "58",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pramod Madushan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Madushan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "half-century",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Madushan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "42nd",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karunaratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Labuschagne",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pat Cummins",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pathum Nissanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Danuska Gunathilaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandimal",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "thirty-yard",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kusal Mendis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Charith Asalanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mendis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Matt Kuhnemann",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pat Cummins",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dasun Shanaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "an innocuous half",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "62",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karunaratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මැදපෙළ ආතති හඹා යෑමෙන් ඔස්ට්‍රේලියානුවන් ගෙදර ගෙන යයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඔස්ට්‍රේලියානු මැදපෙළ ශ්‍රී ලංකා දඟපන්දු යවන්නන්ගේ දැඩි පරීක්ෂණයකින් මිදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට එරෙහිව සිකුරාදා ආර්. ප්‍රේමදාස ක්‍රීඩාංගණයේ පැවැති තරග පහකින් සමන්විත එක්දින තරගාවලියේ අවසන් එක්දින තරගය කඩුලු හතරකින් ජය ගැනීමට සමත් විය.",
        "දුනිත් වෙල්ලාලගේ (42ට 3) සහ මහේෂ් තීක්ෂණ (26ට 2) ඕස්ටේ‍්‍රලියානු පිලේ මුල් පෙළේ මුළු ලකුණු සංඛ්‍යාව අඩු ලකුණු සංඛ්‍යාවක් හඹා ගිය නමුත් ඇලෙක්ස් කේරි (නොදැවී 45) සහ කැමරන් ග‍්‍රීන් (නොදැවී 25) ඔවුන්ගේ නොසන්සුන්තාව රඳවා ගත්හ. ඕස්ටේ‍්‍රලියාව බලන්න සහ එක්දින තරඟාවලිය පැරදුනත් සැනසිලිදායක ජයක් වාර්තා කරන්න.",
        "නරඹන්නන්ගේ ලුහුබැඳීම ආරම්භ වූයේ විනාශකාරී සටහනකින් නායක ආරොන් ෆින්ච් ක්‍රීඩා කළ තීක්ෂණගේ දැඩි ක්‍රියාකලාපයකින් පසු ඔහු මිය යාමත් සමඟින්, ඔහු සමීප ඇමතුම් දෙකකින් බේරී සිටිනු දුටු අතර අවසානයේ ඔහුගේ තෙවැනි පන්දුවෙන් ක්‍රීස් එකේ ස්වීප් කිරීමේ උත්සාහය අත් නොහළේය. ඩේවිඩ් වෝනර් පසුව පිම්මක් සමඟින් පැමිණි ධනුෂ්ක ගුණතිලක වෙල්ලාලගේගේ පන්දුවක් හමුවේ බිම පතිත වූ සම්පූර්ණ ඉරිතැලීමකට බාධා කළේය.",
        "ඉන්පසුව තීක්ෂණ එක්දින මංගල තරගයේදීම ජෝෂ් ඉන්ග්ලිස්ව ලෙග් ස්ලිප්හිදී දැවී ගියේය. එය නරඹන්නන් කඩුලු 3කට ලකුණු 19ක් ලබා සිටියදී දැවී ගියේය. මිචෙල් මාෂ් ලකුණු 20කට සටන් වැදුණද ආරම්භක පිතිකරු ප්‍රමෝද් මධුෂාන්ගේ පළමු ජාත්‍යන්තර කඩුල්ල බවට පත්වූයේ ගුවනට යාමේ වැරදි ප්‍රයත්නයකදීය.",
        "Marnus Labuschagne සහ Alex Carey අතර අර්ධ ශතක සබඳතාවයක් නැව ස්ථාවර කිරීමට උපකාරී වූ නමුත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව නැවතත් තරඟයට අවතීර්ණ වූයේ වෙල්ලාලගේගේ දෙවන අක්ෂර වින්‍යාසය අනුග්‍රහයෙනි, එහිදී ඔහු ලබුස්චේන් යැවීමට අලංකාර රිපිං පන්දු දෙකක් ඉදිරිපත් කළ අතර පසුව භයානක ග්ලෙන් මැක්ස්වෙල්ව නැවත මණ්ඩපයට ගෙන ගියේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ජයග්‍රහණය සඳහා ඉතිරි ලකුණු 40 දවාලීමට ග්‍රීන් කේරි සමඟ එක් වූ හෙයින් එය මව්බිමට නොවිය යුතුය.",
        "පළමුවෙන් පන්දුවට පහර දුන් චාමික කරුණාරත්නගේ පන්දුවකට කඩුල්ලක් දැවී ලකුණු 75ක් ලබා ගැනීමට පෙර ලකුණු 3ක් ලබා ගැනීමට හෝ අපොහොසත් වීමේ අවධානමකට ලක් විය.",
        "වලිගය සමඟින් පන්දුවට පහර දීමට ඉතිරිව සිටි දකුණත් පිතිකරුවා පිටිය මනාව හසුරුවමින් නෙත් සිත් ඇදගන්නා පහර කිහිපයක්ම ක්‍රීඩා කරමින් නවවැනි කඩුල්ලට මංගල ක්‍රීඩක ප්‍රමෝද් මධුෂාන් සමගින් ලකුණු 58ක සබඳතාවක් ගොඩනැගුවේය.",
        "මෙම යුගලය ඕවර 17ක් පුරා පන්දුවට පහර දුන් අතර, මධුෂාන් ඔහුගේ පන්දු 52කදී කඩුල්ලට ලකුණු 15ක් පමණක් ලබා ගත් අතර, එය කරුණාරත්නට අවශ්‍ය සහය ලබා දුන් අතර, එය ඔහුගේ මංගල ජාත්‍යන්තර අර්ධ ශතකය වාර්තා කිරීමට ඔහුට හැකි විය. කඩුලු සීමාව.",
        "අවසානයේ 42 වැනි ඕවරයේදී ග්‍රීන් අතට උඩපන්දුවක් දෙමින් මධුෂාන් දැවී ගිය අතර, ඔහු සමඟින් ලකුණු 11ක් පමණක් ලබාගෙන සිටි අතර, කරුණාරත්න ඔහුගේ හස්තය ලබා ගැනීමට තීරණය කළේය. ඔහු Labuschagne ගේ පා ​​දඟ පන්දු ප්‍රබල හයේ පහර දෙකකට පහර දුන් නමුත් අවසානයේ ආපසු පැමිණි Pat Cummins වෙත ලබා ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කරමින් ඇද වැටුනි.",
        "මීට පෙර, ඔස්ට්‍රේලියානු වේගපන්දු යවන්නන් ආරම්භක පිතිකරණයේ දී පැතුම් නිශ්ශංක කඩුලු රකින ක්‍රීඩකයා වෙත දවා ගැනීමත් සමඟ කඩුලු ත්‍රිත්වයකට හිමිකම් කී අතර, ධනුස්ක ගුණතිලක සහ ආපසු පැමිණි දිනේෂ් චන්දිමාල් යන දෙදෙනාම යාර තිහ කවයේ දී ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු නායකයා වෙත පන්දුව කෙළින්ම එල්ල කළහ.",
        "කුසල් මෙන්ඩිස් (26) හොඳ ස්පර්ශයකින් පෙනී සිටි අතර, ආරම්භය සඳහා ඕෆ් සයිඩ් වළල්ල හරහා හැපෙනසුළු පහර තුනක් එල්ල කළේය. කෙසේ වෙතත්, අවසන් තරගයේ වීරයා වූ චරිත් අසලංක සමඟින් ගොඩ ඒමට ඔහු දැරූ උත්සාහය බිඳවැටුණු අතර, ඔහු බිහිසුණු මිශ්‍රණයකින් දැවී ගිය අතර, ඊළඟ පන්දුවේදී මෙන්ඩිස් ඔහුගේ කඩුල්ල පාගාගෙන ගියේය. ඇද ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කිරීම.",
        "වෙල්ලාලගේ ඔහුගේ දෙවැනි පන්දුවෙන් මැට් කුනමන්ව උඩ පන්දුවට පහර දීමට අයුතු ලෙස උත්සාහ කළ අතර, පැට් කමින්ස් මිඩ්-ඕන් හි දී සොයා ගන්නා ලදී. නායක දසුන් ශානක එම ඕවරයේදීම ඔහුගේ කඩුල්ල ලෙග්-ස්ටම්ප් එක මත එල්ල කළ අහිංසක හාෆ්-වොලි පහරකින් ඔහුගේ කඩුල්ල රැව් පිළිරැව් දුන් අතර, කරුණාරත්නට පෙර ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කඩුලු 7ක් දැවී ලකුණු 62ක් ලබා සිටි අතර පහළ පෙළේ ක්‍රීඩකයෝ ඔවුන්ගේ ප්‍රකෘතිමත් වීමේ උත්සාහයන් ආරම්භ කළහ.",
        "ක්‍රීඩාවෙන් පසුව, “ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව!, ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව!” යනුවෙන් උස් හඬින් ගායනා කිරීම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික අර්බුද මධ්‍යයේ සියලු ආකාරයේ සංචාරයක් සඳහා පැමිණි සංචාරක කණ්ඩායම අගය කිරීමට බොහෝ දුරට කහ පැහැති ඇඳුමින් සැරසී පැමිණ සිටි ක්‍රීඩා ලෝලීන්ගෙන් ක්‍රීඩාංගනය පුරා අසන්නට ලැබුණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානුවන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්. ප්‍රේමදාස ක්‍රීඩාංගණයේදී",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "42",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තීක්ෂණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇලෙක්ස් කේරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැමරන් ග්රීන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරොන් ෆින්ච්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තීක්ෂණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේවිඩ් වෝනර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධනුෂ්ක ගුණතිලක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තීක්ෂණ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොෂ් ඉන්ග්ලිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිචෙල් මාෂ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රමෝද් මධුෂාන්ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අර්ධ ශතකය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marnus Labuschagne",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇලෙක්ස් කේරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙල්ලාලගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලැබුස්චේන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ග්ලෙන් මැක්ස්වෙල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හරිත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චාමික කරුණාරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "58",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රමෝද් මධුෂාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධුෂාන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කරුණාරත්න ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අර්ධ ශතකය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මධුෂාන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "42 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කරුණාරත්න ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලැබුස්චේන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැට් කමින්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැතුම් නිශ්ශංක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධනුස්ක ගුණතිලක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්දිමාල්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිස් යාර",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුසල් මෙන්ඩිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චරිත් අසලංක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙන්ඩිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Matt Kuhnemann",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැට් කමින්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දසුන් ශානක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අහිංසක භාගයක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "62",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කරුණාරත්න ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மிடில் ஆர்டர் பதற்றமான சேஸிங்கில் ஆஸி",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "வெள்ளியன்று R. பிரேமதாச மைதானத்தில் இலங்கைக்கு எதிரான ஐந்து போட்டிகள் கொண்ட தொடரின் இறுதி ஒருநாள் போட்டியில் ஆஸ்திரேலியாவின் மிடில்-ஆர்டர், இலங்கையின் சுழற்பந்து வீச்சாளர்களின் கடுமையான தேர்வை முறியடித்து நான்கு விக்கெட் வித்தியாசத்தில் வெற்றி பெற்றது.",
        "துனித் வெல்லலகே (42 ரன்களுக்கு 3) மற்றும் மஹீஷ் தீக்ஷனா (26 ரன்களுக்கு 2) ஆகியோர் அவுஸ்திரேலிய டாப்-ஆர்டர் முழுவதுமாக குறைந்த எண்ணிக்கையை துரத்தினார்கள், ஆனால் அலெக்ஸ் கேரி (45 ரன்) மற்றும் கேமரூன் கிரீன் (25 ரன்) தங்கள் பதற்றத்தை தக்க வைத்துக் கொண்டனர். ஆஸ்திரேலியாவைப் பார்க்கவும், ஒருநாள் தொடரை இழந்தாலும் ஆறுதல் வெற்றியைப் பதிவு செய்யவும்.",
        "பார்வையாளர்களின் துரத்தல் ஒரு பேரழிவான குறிப்பில் தொடங்கியது, கேப்டன் ஆரோன் ஃபின்ச் தீக்ஷனாவின் கடுமையான வேலையின் பின்னர் அழிந்து போனார், அவர் இரண்டு நெருக்கமான அழைப்புகளில் இருந்து உயிர் பிழைத்ததைக் கண்டார், இறுதியில் அவரது மூன்றாவது பந்தில் ஸ்வீப் செய்ய முயற்சித்தார். பின்னர் டேவிட் வார்னர், வெல்லலகேவின் பந்துவீச்சில் தரையில் ஒரு முழு இரத்த ஓட்டத்தை இடைமறித்து தனுஷ்க குணதிலகாவைத் தடுத்தார்.",
        "தீக்ஷனா பின்னர் ஒருநாள் அரங்கில் அறிமுகமான ஜோஷ் இங்கிலிஸை லெக்-ஸ்லிப்பில் கேட்ச் செய்தார், அது பார்வையாளர்கள் 3 விக்கெட்டுக்கு 19 ரன்கள் எடுத்திருந்த நிலையில் ஆட்டமிழக்கச் செய்தது. மிட்செல் மார்ஷ் 20 ரன்களுக்குப் போராடினார், ஆனால் அறிமுக ஆட்டக்காரர் பிரமோத் மதுஷனின் முதல் சர்வதேச விக்கெட்டாக வான்வழி செல்ல ஒரு தவறான முயற்சியில் ஆனார்.",
        "Marnus Labuschagne மற்றும் Alex Carey ஆகியோருக்கு இடையேயான அரை-நூற்றாண்டு நிலை கப்பலை நிலைநிறுத்த உதவியது, ஆனால் வெல்லலகேவின் இரண்டாவது ஸ்பெல் மூலம் இலங்கை மீண்டும் போட்டிக்குள் நுழைந்தது, அங்கு அவர் இரண்டு அழகான ரிப்பிங் பந்துகளை உருவாக்கி லாபுஷானை அனுப்பினார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், வெற்றிக்காக மீதமுள்ள 40 ரன்களை கேரியுடன் கிரீன் ஜோடி வீழ்த்தியதால், அது சொந்த அணிக்காக இருக்கவில்லை.",
        "முதலில் துடுப்பெடுத்தாடிய, ஷாமிக கருணாரத்ன ஒரு பந்தில் 75 ரன்களை விளாசுவதற்கு முன், ஹோம் சைட் மூன்று புள்ளிகளை கூட செய்யத் தவறியது.",
        "வால் மூலம் துடுப்பெடுத்தாட விட்டு, வலது கை ஆட்டக்காரர் களத்தை சிறப்பாக கையாண்டார் மற்றும் அறிமுக வீரர் பிரமோத் மதுஷனுடன் ஒன்பதாவது விக்கெட்டுக்கு 58 ரன் கூட்டாண்மையை ஒன்றாக இணைத்த போது பல கண்களைக் கவரும் ஸ்ட்ரோக்குகளை விளையாடினார்.",
        "இந்த ஜோடி 17 ஓவர்கள் வரை துடுப்பெடுத்தாடியது, மதுஷன் 52 பந்துகளில் 15 ரன்களை மட்டுமே எடுத்தார், அது கருணாரத்னேவுக்கு மிகவும் தேவையான ஆதரவை வழங்கியது, இது அவரது முதல் சர்வதேச அரை சதத்தை பதிவு செய்ய அவருக்கு உதவியது, அது நடுப்பகுதிக்கு ஒரு அதிகாரபூர்வமான இழுப்புடன் கொண்டு வரப்பட்டது. விக்கெட் எல்லை.",
        "இறுதியில் 42வது ஓவரில் கிரீன் பந்துவீச்சில் மதுஷான் கேட்ச் மற்றும் பந்துவீச்சில் ஆட்டமிழந்தார், மேலும் நிறுவனத்தின் 11வது இலக்கத்துடன் வெளியேற, கருணாரத்னே தனது கைக்கு வாய்ப்பளிக்க முடிவு செய்தார். அவர் இரண்டு சக்திவாய்ந்த சிக்ஸர்களுக்கு லாபுசாக்னேவின் லெக்-ஸ்பின்னை அடித்து நொறுக்கினார், ஆனால் இறுதியில் திரும்பிய பாட் கம்மின்ஸை எடுக்க முயன்றார்.",
        "முன்னதாக, அவுஸ்திரேலியாவின் வேகப்பந்து வீச்சாளர்கள் ஆரம்ப பவர்பிளேயில் பதும் நிஸ்ஸங்கவை விக்கெட் கீப்பரை எட்ஜிங் செய்தார், அதே நேரத்தில் தனுஸ்க குணதிலக மற்றும் திரும்பிய தினேஷ் சண்டிமால் இருவரும் முப்பது யார்டு வட்டத்தில் ஆஸ்திரேலிய கேப்டனிடம் பந்தை நேராக அடித்தனர்.",
        "குசல் மெண்டிஸ் (26) நன்றாகத் தொடர்பு கொண்டு, ஆஃப்-சைட் ரிங் வழியாக மூன்று மிருதுவான ஸ்ட்ரோக்குகளை வீசினார். எவ்வாறாயினும், கடைசி ஆட்டத்தின் நாயகனான சரித் அசலங்காவுடன் மீண்டு வருவதற்கான அவரது முயற்சிகள் ஒரு பயங்கரமான கலவையில் ரன் அவுட் ஆனதால், அடுத்த பந்தில் மெண்டிஸ் தனது ஸ்டம்பில் மிதித்தார். இழுக்க முயற்சிக்கிறது.",
        "வெல்லலேஜ் தனது இரண்டாவது பந்தில் பாட் கம்மின்ஸை மிட்-ஆனில் கண்டுபிடிக்க மாட் குஹ்னெமனை அநியாயமாக தாக்க முயன்றதால் விக்கெட்டுகளின் அணிவகுப்பு தொடர்ந்தது. அதே ஓவரில் கேப்டன் தசுன் ஷனக தனது ஸ்டம்புகளை லெக்-ஸ்டம்பில் ஒரு பாதிப்பில்லாத அரை-வாலியால் துரத்தினார், கருணாரத்னே மற்றும் கீழ்-வரிசை தங்கள் மீட்பு முயற்சிகளை தொடங்குவதற்கு முன், இலங்கை ஏழு விக்கெட்டுக்கு 62 ரன்கள் எடுத்தது.",
        "ஆட்டத்தைத் தொடர்ந்து, \"ஆஸ்திரேலியா!, ஆஸ்திரேலியா!\" என்ற உரத்த கோஷங்கள் இலங்கையில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு மத்தியில் சகல வடிவ சுற்றுப்பயணத்திற்கான பயணத்தை மேற்கொண்டதற்காக சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளை பாராட்டுவதற்காக பெருமளவில் மஞ்சள் நிற ஆடை அணிந்து வந்திருந்த ரசிகர்களால் மைதானம் முழுவதும் கேட்கப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஆஸி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர். பிரேமதாச மைதானம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "42",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தீக்ஷனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலெக்ஸ் கேரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேமரூன் கிரீன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆரோன் பிஞ்ச்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தீக்ஷனா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டேவிட் வார்னர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனுஷ்க குணதிலக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தீக்ஷனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜோஷ் இங்கிலிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிட்செல் மார்ஷ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரமோத் மதுஷனின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரை நூற்றாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்னஸ் லாபுசாக்னே",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலெக்ஸ் கேரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெல்லலகே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லாபுசேன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிளென் மேக்ஸ்வெல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பச்சை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாமிக்க கருணாரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "58",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரமோத் மதுஷன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதுஷன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருணாரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரை நூற்றாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மதுஷன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "42வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருணாரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லாபுசேன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாட் கம்மின்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாத்தும் நிஸ்ஸங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனுஸ்க குணதிலக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சண்டிமால்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "முப்பது கெஜம்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குசல் மெண்டிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரித் அசலங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெண்டிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாட் குஹ்னேமன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாட் கம்மின்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தசுன் ஷனக",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு பாதிப்பில்லாத பாதி",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "62",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருணாரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Middle order steers Aussies home in tense chase",
  "body_lines": [
    "Australia’s middle-order overcame a stern examination by Sri Lanka’s spinners on a difficult surface to win the final ODI of their five-match series versus Sri Lanka by four wickets at the R. Premadasa Stadium on Friday.",
    "Dunith Wellalage (3 for 42) and Maheesh Theekshana (2 for 26) were all over the Australian top-order who were chasing an under-par total, but Alex Carey (45 no) and Cameron Green (25 no) held their nerve to see Australia over the line and record a consolation win despite having lost the ODI series.",
    "The visitors’ chase began on a disastrous note with Captain Aaron Finch perishing after a torrid working over by Theekshana that saw him survive two close calls before eventually gloving an attempted sweep off his third ball at the crease. David Warner then followed with a leaping Danushka Gunathilaka intercepting a full-blooded crack down the ground off the bowling of Wellalage.",
    "Theekshana then had Josh Inglis on ODI debut caught at leg-slip that had the visitors floundering at 19 for 3. Mitchell Marsh fought his way to 20 but became debutant Pramod Madushan’s first international wicket in an ill-judged attempt to go aerial.",
    "A half-century stand between Marnus Labuschagne and Alex Carey helped steady the ship but Sri Lanka came roaring back into the contest courtesy Wellalage’s second spell where he produced two beautiful ripping deliveries to send Labuschagne and thereafter the dangerous Glenn Maxwell back to the pavilion.",
    "However, it was not to be for the home side as Green paired up with Carey to knock off the remaining 40 runs for victory.",
    "Batting first, the home side was in danger of failing to even make three figures before a gutsy run-a-ball knock of 75 by Chamika Karunaratne gave the total a degree of respectability.",
    "Left to bat with the tail, the right-hander manipulated the field to great effect and played several eye-catching strokes while stitching together a 58-run partnership for the ninth wicket with debutant Pramod Madushan.",
    "The pair batted through 17 overs, and while Madushan only made 15 in his 52 deliveries at the wicket, it gave Karunaratne much needed support that enabled him to record his maiden international half-century that was brought up with an authoritative pull to the mid-wicket boundary.",
    "Madushan was eventually dismissed caught and bowled by Green in the 42nd over, and left with just number 11 for company, Karunaratne decided to chance his arm. He smacked Labuschagne’s leg-spin for two powerful sixes but eventually fell trying to take on the returning Pat Cummins.",
    "Earlier, Australia’s pacemen claimed three scalps in the opening powerplay with Pathum Nissanka edging to the wicket keeper while Danuska Gunathilaka and the returning Dinesh Chandimal both hitting the ball straight to the Australian captain on the thirty-yard circle",
    "Kusal Mendis (26) appeared in fine touch, unfurling three crisp strokes through the off-side ring to start with. However, his efforts to mount a recovery with hero of the last game, Charith Asalanka, were brought to a screeching halt as the latter was run out in a dreadful mix up, which was followed by Mendis treading on his stumps the very next ball while attempting a pull.",
    "The parade of wickets continued as Wellalage injudiciously tried to hit Matt Kuhnemann over the top off just his second ball only to find Pat Cummins at mid-on. Captain Dasun Shanaka followed in the very same over with his stumps rattled by an innocuous half-volley on leg-stump, leaving Sri Lanka reeling at 62 for seven before Karunaratne and the lower-order began their recovery efforts.",
    "Following the game, loud chants of “Australia!, Australia!” were heard throughout the stadium by fans who had come largely dressed in yellow to appreciate the touring side for making the journey for an all-format tour amidst the economic crisis in Sri Lanka."
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Middle order steers Aussies home in tense chase",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "Australia’s middle-order overcame a stern examination by Sri Lanka’s spinners on a difficult surface to win the final ODI of their five-match series versus Sri Lanka by four wickets at the R. Premadasa Stadium on Friday.",
        "Dunith Wellalage (3 for 42) and Maheesh Theekshana (2 for 26) were all over the Australian top-order who were chasing an under-par total, but Alex Carey (45 no) and Cameron Green (25 no) held their nerve to see Australia over the line and record a consolation win despite having lost the ODI series.",
        "The visitors’ chase began on a disastrous note with Captain Aaron Finch perishing after a torrid working over by Theekshana that saw him survive two close calls before eventually gloving an attempted sweep off his third ball at the crease. David Warner then followed with a leaping Danushka Gunathilaka intercepting a full-blooded crack down the ground off the bowling of Wellalage.",
        "Theekshana then had Josh Inglis on ODI debut caught at leg-slip that had the visitors floundering at 19 for 3. Mitchell Marsh fought his way to 20 but became debutant Pramod Madushan’s first international wicket in an ill-judged attempt to go aerial.",
        "A half-century stand between Marnus Labuschagne and Alex Carey helped steady the ship but Sri Lanka came roaring back into the contest courtesy Wellalage’s second spell where he produced two beautiful ripping deliveries to send Labuschagne and thereafter the dangerous Glenn Maxwell back to the pavilion.",
        "However, it was not to be for the home side as Green paired up with Carey to knock off the remaining 40 runs for victory.",
        "Batting first, the home side was in danger of failing to even make three figures before a gutsy run-a-ball knock of 75 by Chamika Karunaratne gave the total a degree of respectability.",
        "Left to bat with the tail, the right-hander manipulated the field to great effect and played several eye-catching strokes while stitching together a 58-run partnership for the ninth wicket with debutant Pramod Madushan.",
        "The pair batted through 17 overs, and while Madushan only made 15 in his 52 deliveries at the wicket, it gave Karunaratne much needed support that enabled him to record his maiden international half-century that was brought up with an authoritative pull to the mid-wicket boundary.",
        "Madushan was eventually dismissed caught and bowled by Green in the 42nd over, and left with just number 11 for company, Karunaratne decided to chance his arm. He smacked Labuschagne’s leg-spin for two powerful sixes but eventually fell trying to take on the returning Pat Cummins.",
        "Earlier, Australia’s pacemen claimed three scalps in the opening powerplay with Pathum Nissanka edging to the wicket keeper while Danuska Gunathilaka and the returning Dinesh Chandimal both hitting the ball straight to the Australian captain on the thirty-yard circle",
        "Kusal Mendis (26) appeared in fine touch, unfurling three crisp strokes through the off-side ring to start with. However, his efforts to mount a recovery with hero of the last game, Charith Asalanka, were brought to a screeching halt as the latter was run out in a dreadful mix up, which was followed by Mendis treading on his stumps the very next ball while attempting a pull.",
        "The parade of wickets continued as Wellalage injudiciously tried to hit Matt Kuhnemann over the top off just his second ball only to find Pat Cummins at mid-on. Captain Dasun Shanaka followed in the very same over with his stumps rattled by an innocuous half-volley on leg-stump, leaving Sri Lanka reeling at 62 for seven before Karunaratne and the lower-order began their recovery efforts.",
        "Following the game, loud chants of “Australia!, Australia!” were heard throughout the stadium by fans who had come largely dressed in yellow to appreciate the touring side for making the journey for an all-format tour amidst the economic crisis in Sri Lanka."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Aussies",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the R. Premadasa Stadium",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "42",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Theekshana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alex Carey",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cameron Green",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Aaron Finch",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Theekshana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "David Warner",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Danushka Gunathilaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Theekshana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Josh Inglis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mitchell Marsh",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pramod Madushan’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "half-century",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marnus Labuschagne",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alex Carey",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wellalage",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Labuschagne",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Glenn Maxwell",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Green",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Carey",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chamika Karunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "58",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pramod Madushan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Madushan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "half-century",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Madushan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "42nd",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karunaratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Labuschagne",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pat Cummins",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pathum Nissanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Danuska Gunathilaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandimal",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "thirty-yard",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kusal Mendis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Charith Asalanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mendis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Matt Kuhnemann",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pat Cummins",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dasun Shanaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "an innocuous half",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "62",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karunaratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මැදපෙළ ආතති හඹා යෑමෙන් ඔස්ට්‍රේලියානුවන් ගෙදර ගෙන යයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඔස්ට්‍රේලියානු මැදපෙළ ශ්‍රී ලංකා දඟපන්දු යවන්නන්ගේ දැඩි පරීක්ෂණයකින් මිදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට එරෙහිව සිකුරාදා ආර්. ප්‍රේමදාස ක්‍රීඩාංගණයේ පැවැති තරග පහකින් සමන්විත එක්දින තරගාවලියේ අවසන් එක්දින තරගය කඩුලු හතරකින් ජය ගැනීමට සමත් විය.",
        "දුනිත් වෙල්ලාලගේ (42ට 3) සහ මහේෂ් තීක්ෂණ (26ට 2) ඕස්ටේ‍්‍රලියානු පිලේ මුල් පෙළේ මුළු ලකුණු සංඛ්‍යාව අඩු ලකුණු සංඛ්‍යාවක් හඹා ගිය නමුත් ඇලෙක්ස් කේරි (නොදැවී 45) සහ කැමරන් ග‍්‍රීන් (නොදැවී 25) ඔවුන්ගේ නොසන්සුන්තාව රඳවා ගත්හ. ඕස්ටේ‍්‍රලියාව බලන්න සහ එක්දින තරඟාවලිය පැරදුනත් සැනසිලිදායක ජයක් වාර්තා කරන්න.",
        "නරඹන්නන්ගේ ලුහුබැඳීම ආරම්භ වූයේ විනාශකාරී සටහනකින් නායක ආරොන් ෆින්ච් ක්‍රීඩා කළ තීක්ෂණගේ දැඩි ක්‍රියාකලාපයකින් පසු ඔහු මිය යාමත් සමඟින්, ඔහු සමීප ඇමතුම් දෙකකින් බේරී සිටිනු දුටු අතර අවසානයේ ඔහුගේ තෙවැනි පන්දුවෙන් ක්‍රීස් එකේ ස්වීප් කිරීමේ උත්සාහය අත් නොහළේය. ඩේවිඩ් වෝනර් පසුව පිම්මක් සමඟින් පැමිණි ධනුෂ්ක ගුණතිලක වෙල්ලාලගේගේ පන්දුවක් හමුවේ බිම පතිත වූ සම්පූර්ණ ඉරිතැලීමකට බාධා කළේය.",
        "ඉන්පසුව තීක්ෂණ එක්දින මංගල තරගයේදීම ජෝෂ් ඉන්ග්ලිස්ව ලෙග් ස්ලිප්හිදී දැවී ගියේය. එය නරඹන්නන් කඩුලු 3කට ලකුණු 19ක් ලබා සිටියදී දැවී ගියේය. මිචෙල් මාෂ් ලකුණු 20කට සටන් වැදුණද ආරම්භක පිතිකරු ප්‍රමෝද් මධුෂාන්ගේ පළමු ජාත්‍යන්තර කඩුල්ල බවට පත්වූයේ ගුවනට යාමේ වැරදි ප්‍රයත්නයකදීය.",
