{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/21/egg-prices-discussions-between-minister-polutry-businessmen-tomorrow-22/",
  "time_ut": 1661062020,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Egg prices: Discussions between Minister & Poultry Businessmen tomorrow (22)",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Egg prices: Discussions between Minister & Poultry Businessmen tomorrow (22)",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); A meeting between Poultry Businessmen's Association and Minister of Trade, Commerce and Food Security, Nalin Fernando is due to be held at the Ministry Trade, Commerce and Food Security, tomorrow (22).",
        "The Trade Minister stated that the discussion will be held in response to a request made by the Poultry Businessmen's Association.",
        "A special gazette notification was issued setting a maximum retail price as Rs. 43/- for a white egg and Rs. 45/- for brown and red eggs with effect from midnight yesterday (20).",
        "Ajith Gunasekara, the President of the Poultry Businessmen's Association stated that the release of eggs to the market was suspended in protest of imposition of the MRP.",
        "When inquired, Trade Minister  Nalin Fernando said that manufacturers and traders should comply with the gazette notification.",
        "The minister also mentioned that appropriate action will be taken against them if they do not act in line with the gazette.",
        "Egg prices: Discussions between Minister & Poultry Businessmen tomorrow (22)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Minister & Poultry Businessmen",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "tomorrow",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "22",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poultry Businessmen's Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry Trade, Commerce and Food Security",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Poultry Businessmen's Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "43/-",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "midnight yesterday",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ajith Gunasekara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Poultry Businessmen's Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MRP",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nalin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Minister & Poultry Businessmen",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බිත්තර මිල: ඇමති සහ කුකුළු ව්‍යාපාරිකයන් අතර සාකච්ඡාවක් හෙට (22)",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); කුකුළු ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්ගේ සංගමය සහ වෙළෙඳ, වාණිජ හා ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතා අමාත්‍ය නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා අතර හමුවක් හෙට (22) වෙළෙඳ, වාණිජ හා ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතා අමාත්‍යාංශයේදී පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතය.",
        "කුකුළු ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්ගේ සංගමය කළ ඉල්ලීමකට අනුව මෙම සාකච්ඡාව පැවැත්වෙන බවයි වෙළඳ අමාත්‍යවරයා සඳහන් කළේ.",
        "එහි උපරිම සිල්ලර මිල රු. 43/- සුදු බිත්තරයක් රු. 45/- දුඹුරු සහ රතු බිත්තර සඳහා ඊයේ (20) මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වේ.",
        "කුකුළු ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති අජිත් ගුණසේකර මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ MRP බදු පැනවීමට විරෝධය පළ කරමින් බිත්තර වෙළෙඳපොළට නිකුත් කිරීම අත්හිටුවූ බවයි.",
        "කළ විමසීමකදී වෙළඳ අමාත්‍ය  නලීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු කියා සිටියේ නිෂ්පාදකයින් සහ වෙළඳුන් ගැසට් නිවේදනයට අනුකූල විය යුතු බවයි.",
        "ගැසට් පත්‍රයට අනුව කටයුතු නොකරන්නේ නම් ඔවුන්ට එරෙහිව නිසි ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගන්නා බව ද අමාත්‍යවරයා සඳහන් කළා.",
        "බිත්තර මිල: ඇමති සහ කුකුළු ව්‍යාපාරිකයන් අතර සාකච්ඡාවක් හෙට (22)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඇමති සහ කුකුළු ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "හෙට",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "22",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුකුළු ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙළඳ, වාණිජ හා ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතා අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුකුළු ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "43/-",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අජිත් ගුණසේකර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුකුළු ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MRP",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇමති සහ කුකුළු ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முட்டை விலை: அமைச்சர் மற்றும் கோழி வியாபாரிகளிடையே நாளை (22) கலந்துரையாடல்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); கோழிப்பண்ணை வியாபாரிகள் சங்கத்திற்கும் வர்த்தக, வர்த்தக மற்றும் உணவு பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சர் நளின் பெர்னாண்டோவிற்கும் இடையிலான சந்திப்பொன்று நாளை (22) வர்த்தக, வர்த்தக மற்றும் உணவு பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சில் நடைபெறவுள்ளது.",
        "கோழிப்பண்ணை வியாபாரிகள் சங்கம் விடுத்த கோரிக்கைக்கு அமைய இந்த கலந்துரையாடல் இடம்பெறவுள்ளதாக வர்த்தக அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அதிகபட்ச சில்லறை விலையை ரூ.5 ஆக நிர்ணயித்து சிறப்பு வர்த்தமானி அறிவிப்பு வெளியிடப்பட்டது. 43/- வெள்ளை முட்டை ரூ. நேற்று (20) நள்ளிரவு முதல் அமுலுக்கு வரும் வகையில் பழுப்பு மற்றும் சிவப்பு நிற முட்டைகளுக்கு 45/-.",
        "MRP விதிப்புக்கு எதிர்ப்புத் தெரிவித்து சந்தைக்கு முட்டைகளை வெளியிடுவது இடைநிறுத்தப்பட்டதாக கோழி வியாபாரிகள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் அஜித் குணசேகர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "வினவியபோது, ​​வர்த்தக அமைச்சர்  நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ, உற்பத்தியாளர்கள் மற்றும் வர்த்தகர்கள் வர்த்தமானி அறிவித்தலுக்கு இணங்க வேண்டும் என்று கூறினார்.",
        "வர்த்தமானிக்கு அமைவாக செயற்படாவிட்டால் அவர்களுக்கு எதிராக உரிய நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்படும் எனவும் அமைச்சர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "முட்டை விலை: அமைச்சர் மற்றும் கோழி வியாபாரிகளிடையே நாளை (22) கலந்துரையாடல்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அமைச்சர் & கோழி வணிகர்கள்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "நாளை",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "22",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோழி வியாபாரிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வர்த்தகம், வணிகம் மற்றும் உணவு பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோழி வணிகர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "43/-",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று நள்ளிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அஜித் குணசேகர",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோழி வணிகர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.ஆர்.பி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சர் & கோழி வணிகர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}