{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Resolving-economic-crisis-President-stresses-special-focus-on-agriculture/108-243433",
  "time_ut": 1661062945,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Resolving economic crisis : President stresses special focus on agriculture",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Resolving economic crisis : President stresses special focus on agriculture",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "More focus should be made on agriculture when it comes to resolving the current economic crisis, President Ranil Wickremesinghe said.",
        "Wickremesinghe made this remark when he met the Chief Incumbent of Atamasthana and Chief Sanganayaka of North Central region of Somapali Maha Nikaya affiliated to Malwathu Maha Vihamra Venerable Pallegama Siriniwasa Thera in Anurdhapura on Saturday according to the President’s office.",
        "The President assured that the government will provide fertilizer needed for the Maha Season.",
        "“We have already begun providing fertilizer for Coconut, Tea and Rubber plantations while focus is also made on promoting the cultivation of maize. Maize is essential as chicken feed and we hope to revive the poultry industry which has come to a standstill as a result of non availability of animal feed,” the President said.",
        "He said the task of resolving issues in Anurdhapura District will be assigned to MPs in the district.",
        "Also, the President informed the Thera that the government intends to promote historical Maha Vihara where excavations are done at the moment as a tourist attraction. (Yohan Perera)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Atamasthana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chief Sanganayaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "North Central",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Somapali Maha Nikaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malwathu Maha Vihamra Venerable",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Siriniwasa Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anurdhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Maha Season",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tea",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maize",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anurdhapura District",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maha Vihara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yohan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට විසඳුම් : කෘෂිකර්මාන්තය කෙරෙහි ජනපති විශේෂ අවධානය යොමු කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදය විසඳීමේදී කෘෂිකර්මාන්තය කෙරෙහි වැඩි අවධානයක් යොමු කළ යුතු බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පවසයි.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මේ බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේ සෙනසුරාදා ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේදී අනුරාධපුරයේදී මල්වතු මහා විහාරයට අනුබද්ධ සෝමපාලි මහා නිකායේ අටමස්ථානාධිපති සහ උතුරුමැද ප්‍රදේශයේ මහා සංඝනායක පූජ්‍ය පල්ලේගම සිරිනිවාස හිමියන් බැහැදුටු අවස්ථාවේදීය.",
        "මහ කන්නයට අවශ්‍ය පොහොර රජයෙන් ලබාදෙන බවට ජනාධිපතිතුමා සහතික විය.",
        "“අපි දැනටමත් පොල්, තේ සහ රබර් වගාවන් සඳහා පොහොර ලබාදීම ආරම්භ කර ඇති අතර බඩ ඉරිඟු වගාව ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීම කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු කර තිබෙනවා. කුකුල් ආහාර ලෙස බඩඉරිඟු අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වන අතර සත්ව ආහාර නොලැබීම හේතුවෙන් ඇණහිට ඇති කුකුළු කර්මාන්තය යළි නගා සිටුවීමට අපි බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා” යැයි ද ජනාධිපතිතුමා පැවසීය.",
        "අනුරාධපුර දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ ගැටලු විසඳීම එම දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට පවරන බවද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "එමෙන්ම මේ වන විට කැණීම් සිදුකරන ඓතිහාසික මහා විහාරය සංචාරක ආකර්ෂණයක් ලෙස ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමට රජය අපේක්ෂා කරන බවද ජනාධිපතිවරයා මෙහිදී උන්වහන්සේට දැනුම් දුන්නා. (යොහාන් පෙරේරා)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අටමස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රධාන සංඝනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු මැද",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝමපාලි මහා නිකාය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මල්වතු මහා විහාරයාණන් වහන්ස",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරිනිවාස හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ කන්නය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බඩ ඉරිඟු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හිමියෝය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහා විහාරය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යොහාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வு: விவசாயத்தில் விசேட கவனம் செலுத்துமாறு ஜனாதிபதி வலியுறுத்தினார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வு காணும் போது விவசாயம் தொடர்பில் அதிக கவனம் செலுத்த வேண்டும் என ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மல்வத்து மகா விஹாம்ர வணக்கத்துக்குரிய பல்லேகம சிறினிவாச தேரரின் அட்டமஸ்தான பீடாதிபதியும், சோமபாலி மகா நிகாயாவின் வடமத்திய பிரதேசத்தின் பிரதம சங்கநாயக்கருமான அநுர்தபுரத்தில் சனிக்கிழமை சந்தித்த போதே விக்கிரமசிங்க இதனைத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மகா பருவத்திற்கு தேவையான உரங்களை அரசாங்கம் வழங்குவதாக ஜனாதிபதி உறுதியளித்தார்.",
        "“நாங்கள் ஏற்கனவே தென்னை, தேயிலை மற்றும் இறப்பர் தோட்டங்களுக்கு உரங்களை வழங்க ஆரம்பித்துள்ளோம் அதேவேளையில் சோளம் பயிரிடுவதை ஊக்குவிப்பதிலும் கவனம் செலுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது. கோழித் தீவனமாக மக்காச்சோளம் இன்றியமையாதது மற்றும் கால்நடைத் தீவனம் கிடைக்காததன் விளைவாக ஸ்தம்பிதமடைந்துள்ள கோழிப்பண்ணை தொழில்துறையை புத்துயிர் பெற நம்புகிறோம்” என ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அநுர்தபுரம் மாவட்டத்தில் உள்ள பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு தீர்வு காணும் பணி அந்த மாவட்டத்திலுள்ள பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு ஒதுக்கப்படும் என்றார்.",
        "அத்துடன், தற்போது அகழ்வு பணிகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்படும் வரலாற்று சிறப்புமிக்க மகா விகாரையை சுற்றுலா தலமாக மேம்படுத்த அரசாங்கம் உத்தேசித்துள்ளதாக ஜனாதிபதி தேரருக்கு தெரிவித்தார். (யோஹான் பெரேரா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அதமஸ்தானா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமை சங்கநாயகம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட மத்திய",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோமபாலி மஹா நிகாயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மல்வத்து மகா விஹம்ர வணக்கத்திற்குரியவர்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறினிவாச தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர்தபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மகா பருவம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேநீர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுர்தபுரம் மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகா விகாரை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோஹான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}