{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Cops-who-took-photos-seated-on-Presidents-chair-face-probe-Police-tell-court/108-243796",
  "time_ut": 1661533480,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Cops who took photos seated on President’s chair face probe - Police tell court",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Cops who took photos seated on President’s chair face probe - Police tell court",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "An investigation is underway to find out the policemen who took photographs while sitting on the President's chair and several other locations inside President's House, police informed Colombo Fort Magistrate.",
        "The Colombo Central Division Criminal Investigation Unit made this revelation before Magistrate Thilina Gamage in response to an allegation made by President's Counsel Maithri Gunaratne. (Lakmal Sooriyagoda)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Fort Magistrate",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Colombo Central Division Criminal Investigation Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magistrate Thilina Gamage",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Counsel Maithri Gunaratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakmal Sooriyagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපති පුටුවේ ඉඳගෙන ඡායාරූප ගත් පොලිස් නිලධාරින් පරීක්ෂණයක් - පොලිසිය අධිකරණයට කියයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ සහ තවත් ස්ථාන කිහිපයක ජනාධිපති පුටුවේ වාඩි වී ඡායාරූප ගත් පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් සොයා විමර්ශනයක් ආරම්භ කර ඇති බව පොලිසිය කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයාට දැනුම් දුන්නා.",
        "ජනාධිපති නීතීඥ මෛත්‍රී ගුණරත්න කළ චෝදනාවකට ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වමින් කොළඹ මධ්‍යම කොට්ඨාශ අපරාධ විමර්ශන ඒකකය මහේස්ත්‍රාත් තිළිණ ගමගේ මහතා හමුවේ මේ බව අනාවරණය කළේය. (ලක්මාල් සූරියගොඩ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඒ කොළඹ මධ්‍යම කොට්ඨාශ අපරාධ විමර්ශන ඒකකයටයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්‍රාත් තිළිණ ගමගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නීතීඥ මෛත්‍රී ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්මාල් සූරියගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி நாற்காலியில் அமர்ந்து புகைப்படம் எடுத்த பொலிஸார் முகநூல் விசாரணை – நீதிமன்றில் பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் ஜனாதிபதி நாற்காலி மற்றும் பல இடங்களில் அமர்ந்து புகைப்படம் எடுத்த பொலிஸாரைக் கண்டறிவதற்கான விசாரணைகள் முன்னெடுக்கப்பட்டு வருவதாக கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவானிடம் பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி மைத்திரி குணரத்ன முன்வைத்த குற்றச்சாட்டிற்கு பதிலளிக்கும் போதே கொழும்பு மத்திய பிரிவு குற்றப்புலனாய்வு பிரிவினர் நீதவான் திலின கமகே முன்னிலையில் இந்த தகவலை வெளியிட்டுள்ளனர். (லக்மால் சூரியகொட)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு மத்திய பிரிவு குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதவான் திலின கமகே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சட்டத்தரணி மைத்திரி குணரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்மால் சூரியகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}