{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84327/fifa-suspends-all-india-football-federation-due-to-third-party-influence",
  "time_ut": 1660617960,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "FIFA suspends All India Football Federation due to third party influence",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "FIFA suspends All India Football Federation due to third party influence",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "FIFA on Monday announced the suspension of All India Football Federation (AIFF) citing “undue influence from third parties, which constitutes a serious violation of the FIFA Statutes.”",
        "The announcement was made on their website which stated that FIFA would lift the suspension “once an order to set up a committee of administrators to assume the powers of the AIFF Executive Committee has been repealed and the AIFF administration regains full control of the AIFF’s daily affairs.”",
        "The suspension has subsequently threatened India hosting the Under-17 Women’s World Cup which is slated to begin from October 11 onwards. FIFA revealed that they are assessing the next steps with regard to the tournament.",
        "The suspension has other implications as well for Indian football which includes the fact the domestic tournaments now staged will not be recognised by either Asian Football Confederation (AFC) or FIFA, while the national teams will not be able to play any international matches.",
        "FIFA said the suspension was effective immediately and that the transgression “constitutes a serious violation of the FIFA Statutes.”",
        "“The suspension will be lifted once an order to set up a committee of administrators to assume the powers of the AIFF executive committee has been repealed and the AIFF administration regains full control of the AIFF’s daily affairs,” FIFA said.",
        "The Under-17 Women’s World Cup “cannot currently be held in India as planned,” FIFA said.",
        "“FIFA is in constant constructive contact with the Ministry of Youth Affairs and Sports in India and is hopeful that a positive outcome to the case may still be achieved.”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "FIFA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "All India Football Federation",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "third",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "All India Football Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Women’s World Cup",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "October 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asian Football Confederation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AIFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Women’s World Cup",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Youth Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sports",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තුන්වන පාර්ශ්වයේ බලපෑම හේතුවෙන් FIFA විසින් සමස්ත ඉන්දීය පාපන්දු සම්මේලනය අත්හිටුවයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "FIFA සඳුදා නිවේදනය කළේ සමස්ත ඉන්දීය පාපන්දු සම්මේලනය (AIFF) \"තෙවන පාර්ශ්වයන්ගේ අනිසි බලපෑම්, FIFA ප්‍රඥප්ති බරපතල ලෙස උල්ලංඝනය කිරීමක්\" උපුටා දක්වමින්.",
        "AIFF විධායක කමිටුවේ බලතල භාර ගැනීම සඳහා පරිපාලකයින්ගේ කමිටුවක් පිහිටුවීමේ නියෝගය අවලංගු කර ඇති අතර AIFF පරිපාලනය AIFF හි දෛනික කටයුතුවල පූර්ණ පාලනය නැවත ලබා ගත් පසු FIFA අත්හිටුවීම ඉවත් කරන බව ඔවුන්ගේ වෙබ් අඩවියේ නිවේදනය කර ඇත. .”",
        "මෙම අත්හිටුවීම පසුව ඔක්තෝබර් 11 සිට ආරම්භ වීමට නියමිත වයස අවුරුදු 17 න් පහළ කාන්තා ලෝක කුසලානයේ සත්කාරකත්වය ඉන්දියාවට තර්ජනයක් වී තිබේ. තරඟාවලිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉදිරි පියවර තක්සේරු කරමින් සිටින බව FIFA අනාවරණ කළා.",
        "මෙම අත්හිටුවීම ඉන්දියානු පාපන්දු ක්‍රීඩාවට වෙනත් ඇඟවුම් ඇති අතර, දැන් පැවැත්වෙන දේශීය තරඟාවලි ආසියානු පාපන්දු සම්මේලනය (AFC) හෝ FIFA විසින් පිළි නොගන්නා අතර ජාතික කණ්ඩායම්වලට කිසිදු ජාත්‍යන්තර තරඟයක් ක්‍රීඩා කිරීමට නොහැකි වනු ඇත.",
        "FIFA පැවසුවේ අත්හිටුවීම වහාම ක්‍රියාත්මක වූ අතර එම උල්ලංඝනය “FIFA ප්‍රඥප්ති බරපතල ලෙස උල්ලංඝනය කිරීමක්” බවයි.",
        "\"AIFF විධායක කමිටුවේ බලතල උපකල්පනය කිරීම සඳහා පරිපාලකයින්ගේ කමිටුවක් පිහිටුවීමේ නියෝගය අවලංගු කර ඇති අතර AIFF පරිපාලනය AIFF හි දෛනික කටයුතුවල පූර්ණ පාලනය නැවත ලබා ගත් පසු අත්හිටුවීම ඉවත් කරනු ලැබේ,\" FIFA පැවසීය.",
        "වයස අවුරුදු 17 න් පහළ කාන්තා ලෝක කුසලානය \"සැලසුම් කර ඇති පරිදි දැනට ඉන්දියාවේ පැවැත්විය නොහැක\" යනුවෙන් FIFA පවසයි.",
        "\"FIFA ඉන්දියාවේ යෞවන කටයුතු සහ ක්‍රීඩා අමාත්‍යාංශය සමඟ නිරන්තර නිර්මාණාත්මක සම්බන්ධතා පවත්වමින් සිටින අතර නඩුවට ධනාත්මක ප්‍රතිඵලයක් තවමත් ලබා ගත හැකි වනු ඇතැයි බලාපොරොත්තු වේ.\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "FIFA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "සමස්ත ඉන්දීය පාපන්දු සම්මේලනය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "තෙවන",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමස්ත ඉන්දීය පාපන්දු සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාන්තා ලෝක කුසලානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔක්තෝබර් 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු පාපන්දු සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AIFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාන්තා ලෝක කුසලානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යෞවන කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්රීඩා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மூன்றாம் தரப்பு செல்வாக்கு காரணமாக அகில இந்திய கால்பந்து கூட்டமைப்பை FIFA இடைநீக்கம் செய்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "FIFA திங்களன்று அகில இந்திய கால்பந்து கூட்டமைப்பை (AIFF) \"மூன்றாம் தரப்பினரின் தேவையற்ற செல்வாக்கை மேற்கோள் காட்டி இடைநீக்கம் செய்வதாக அறிவித்தது, இது FIFA சட்டங்களை கடுமையாக மீறுவதாகும்.\"",
        "AIFF நிர்வாகக் குழுவின் அதிகாரங்களை ஏற்க நிர்வாகிகள் குழுவை அமைப்பதற்கான உத்தரவு ரத்து செய்யப்பட்டவுடன், AIFF நிர்வாகம் AIFF இன் தினசரி விவகாரங்களில் முழுக் கட்டுப்பாட்டை மீண்டும் பெற்றவுடன், FIFA இடைநீக்கத்தை நீக்கும் என்று அவர்களின் இணையதளத்தில் அறிவிப்பு வெளியிடப்பட்டது. .\"",
        "இந்த இடைநீக்கம் அக்டோபர் 11 முதல் தொடங்க உள்ள 17 வயதுக்குட்பட்ட பெண்கள் உலகக் கோப்பையை நடத்தும் இந்தியாவை அச்சுறுத்தியது. போட்டிகள் தொடர்பான அடுத்த கட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளை மதிப்பீடு செய்து வருவதாக ஃபிஃபா தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்த இடைநீக்கம் இந்திய கால்பந்தாட்டத்திற்கும் பிற தாக்கங்களைக் கொண்டுள்ளது, இதில் இப்போது நடத்தப்படும் உள்நாட்டுப் போட்டிகள் ஆசிய கால்பந்து கூட்டமைப்பு (AFC) அல்லது FIFA ஆகியவற்றால் அங்கீகரிக்கப்படாது, அதே நேரத்தில் தேசிய அணிகள் எந்த சர்வதேச போட்டிகளிலும் விளையாட முடியாது.",
        "இந்த இடைநீக்கம் உடனடியாக அமலுக்கு வந்தது என்றும், இந்த மீறல் \"FIFA சட்டங்களை கடுமையாக மீறுவதாகும்\" என்றும் FIFA கூறியது.",
        "\"AIFF நிர்வாகக் குழுவின் அதிகாரங்களை ஏற்றுக்கொள்வதற்கு நிர்வாகிகள் குழுவை அமைப்பதற்கான உத்தரவு ரத்துசெய்யப்பட்டதும், AIFF நிர்வாகம் AIFF இன் தினசரி விவகாரங்களில் முழுக் கட்டுப்பாட்டையும் திரும்பப் பெற்றவுடன் இடைநீக்கம் நீக்கப்படும்\" என்று FIFA தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "17 வயதுக்குட்பட்ட பெண்கள் உலகக் கோப்பையை \"தற்போது இந்தியாவில் திட்டமிட்டபடி நடத்த முடியாது\" என்று ஃபிஃபா தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "\"இந்தியாவில் இளைஞர் விவகாரங்கள் மற்றும் விளையாட்டு அமைச்சகத்துடன் FIFA தொடர்ந்து ஆக்கபூர்வமான தொடர்பில் உள்ளது, மேலும் இந்த வழக்கில் இன்னும் சாதகமான முடிவு எட்டப்படலாம் என்று நம்புகிறது.\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "FIFA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "அகில இந்திய கால்பந்து கூட்டமைப்பு",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "மூன்றாவது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அகில இந்திய கால்பந்து கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெண்கள் உலகக் கோப்பை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அக்டோபர் 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய கால்பந்து கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AIFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெண்கள் உலகக் கோப்பை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FIFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இளைஞர் விவகார அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளையாட்டு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}