{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/රටේ-ආර්ථිකය-කඩා-වැටුණේ-රජයන්-තුනක-වරදින්/1-618516",
  "time_ut": 1661144504,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රටේ ආර්ථිකය කඩා වැටුණේ රජයන් තුනක වරදින්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The country's economy collapsed due to the fault of three governments",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Member of Parliament Acharya Nalaka Godaheva said that the country's economy did not collapse during the reign of Mr. Gotabhaya Rajapaksa, and that all the three governments that came to power after the war should be held responsible for it.",
        "During 2009-2015, the country's debt increased from 2200 billion rupees to 7400 billion rupees, the MP said, adding that it was the Rajapaksa government that started taking short-term commercial loans at high interest rates.",
        "Mr. Godaheva mentioned that the government of Mr. Mahinda Rajapaksa continued to take loans and implemented development projects that did not generate income and that there was a lot of waste and corruption behind the infrastructure development.",
        "He said that the Maithripala Sirisena and Ranil Wickremesinghe governments that came to power and the previous government committed more waste and corruption than the previous government, and during that time the debt increased from 7400 billion rupees to 13,000 billion rupees.",
        "The MP said that the group that worked hard to bring Mr. Gotabhaya Rajapaksa to power had prepared an economic management plan, but after he came to power, the people who prepared the plan were forgotten and the economy was handed over to the same people who had managed the country's economy before 2015, so the desired goals were not achieved."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalaka Godaheva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2009-2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2200 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "7400 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Godaheva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "7400 billion rupees to",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "13,000 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රටේ ආර්ථිකය කඩා වැටුණේ රජයන් තුනක වරදින්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රටේ ආර්ථිකය කඩා වැටුණේ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ පාලන සමයේ නොවන බවත්, යුද්ධයෙන් පසු බලයට ආ රජයන් තුනම ඊට වග කිව යුතු බවත් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ආචාර්‍ය නාලක ගොඩහේවා මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "2009 -2015 කාලය තුල රටේ ණය බර රුපියල් බිලියන 2200 සිට බිලියන 7400 දක්වා වැඩි වූ බව කී මන්ත්‍රීවරයා ඉහල පොලී වලට කෙටි කාලීන වානිජ ණය ගැනීම ආරම්භ කළේ රාජපක්ෂ ආණ්ඩුව බව ද සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ආණ්ඩුව දිගින් දිගටම ණය ගනිමින් ආදායම් නොලැබෙන සංවර්ධන ව්‍යාපෘතීන් ක්‍රියාත්මක කළ බවත් එම යටිතල පහසුකම් සංවර්ධනය පිටුපස විශාල නාස්තියක් හා දූෂණයක් තිබූ බවත් ගොඩහේවා මහතා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ඉන්පසු බලයට ආ මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන, රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ආණ්ඩුවද පෙර පැවති රජයටත් වඩා නාස්තිය දූෂණය සිදු කළ බවත්, එම කාලයේදී ණය බර රුපියල් බිලියන 7400 සිට රුපියල් බිලියන 13,000 ට වැඩි වූ බවත් හෙතෙම පැවසීය.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා බලයට ගෙන ඒමට මහන්සි වූ කණ්ඩායම් ආර්ථික කළමණාකරන සැලැස්මක් සකසා තිබුණත් ඔහු බලයට ආ පසු සැලැස්ම සකස් කල පිරිස අමතක කර 2015 ට පෙර රටේ ආර්ථිකය කළමනාකරණය කල පිරිසටම ආර්ථිකය බාරදීම නිසා අපේක්ෂිත අරමුණු ඉටු නොවූ බව මන්ත්‍රීවරයා කීවේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාලක ගොඩහේවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2009-2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 2200 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 7400 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගොඩහේවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල් බිලියන 7400 දක්වා",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 13,000 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மூன்று அரசுகளின் தவறால் நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரம் சரிந்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "திரு.கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் ஆட்சிக்காலத்தில் நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரம் வீழ்ச்சியடையவில்லை எனவும், யுத்தத்தின் பின்னர் ஆட்சிக்கு வந்த மூன்று அரசாங்கங்களும் இதற்கு பொறுப்பேற்க வேண்டும் எனவும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஆச்சார்ய நாலக கொடஹேவா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "2009-2015 காலப்பகுதியில் நாட்டின் கடன் 2200 பில்லியன் ரூபாவில் இருந்து 7400 பில்லியன் ரூபாவாக அதிகரித்துள்ளதாக தெரிவித்த எம்.பி., அதிக வட்டிக்கு குறுகிய கால வர்த்தக கடன்களை பெற்றுக்கொள்ள ஆரம்பித்தது ராஜபக்ச அரசாங்கமே எனவும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மகிந்த ராஜபக்சவின் அரசாங்கம் தொடர்ந்தும் கடன்களை பெற்று வருமானத்தை ஈட்டாத அபிவிருத்தி திட்டங்களை அமுல்படுத்தி வருவதாகவும், உட்கட்டமைப்பு அபிவிருத்திக்கு பின்னால் பல வீண் விரயங்களும் ஊழல்களும் இருப்பதாகவும் திரு.கொடஹேவா குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "ஆட்சிக்கு வந்த மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன மற்றும் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க அரசாங்கங்களும், முன்னைய அரசாங்கமும் கடந்த அரசாங்கத்தை விட அதிகளவு வீண், ஊழல்களை செய்ததாகவும், அக்காலப்பகுதியில் கடன் 7400 பில்லியன் ரூபாவிலிருந்து 13,000 பில்லியன் ரூபாவாக அதிகரித்துள்ளதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை ஆட்சிக்கு கொண்டுவர கடுமையாக உழைத்த குழுவினர் பொருளாதார முகாமைத்துவத் திட்டத்தை தயாரித்துள்ளதாகவும், ஆனால் அவர் ஆட்சிக்கு வந்த பின்னர் அந்த திட்டத்தை தயாரித்தவர்களை மறந்துவிட்டு அதே மக்களிடம் பொருளாதாரம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் எம்.பி. 2015 ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கு முன்னர் நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரத்தை நிர்வகித்திருந்ததால், விரும்பிய இலக்குகள் அடையப்படவில்லை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாலக கொடஹேவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2009-2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2200 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "7400 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோதாஹேவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "7400 பில்லியன் ரூபாய்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "13,000 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}