{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/31/12-more-arrests-for-9th-may-violence/",
  "time_ut": 1661932320,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "12 more arrests for 9th May violence",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "12 more arrests for 9th May violence",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka Police arrested 12 more suspects in connection to the violence that broke out on the 9th of May 2022.",
        "04 suspects were arrested by the Kegalle police in connection with the attack on the residence and office of parliamentarian Tharaka Balasuriya in Kegalle.",
        "A 58-year-old suspect was arrested in connection with the attacks on the residences of Parliamentarians Rohitha Abeygunawardena and Johnston Fernando.",
        "Two residents of Mahawa and Kahatagasdigiliya areas were arrested in connection with an incident of assaulting the Chairman of the Elahera Pradeshiya Sabha.",
        "Another suspect was arrested for damaging the residence of MP Vidura Wickramanayake, while one suspect was arrested for causing damages to the residences of Arundhika Fernando, and the Chairperson of the Mahara Pradeshiya Sabha.",
        "One-month-old infant abandoned at a motor garage with a letter",
        "Are you a victim of Cyber Crime? Police Unit ready to crackdown crime in the cyberspace"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "12",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "May",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegalle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tharaka Balasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegalle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "58-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rohitha Abeygunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Johnston Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahawa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kahatagasdigiliya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Elahera Pradeshiya Sabha",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vidura Wickramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One-month-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cyber Crime",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මැයි 9 ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වයට තවත් 12ක් අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 2022 මැයි 9 වන දින ඇති වූ ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වයට සම්බන්ධ තවත් සැකකරුවන් 12 දෙනෙකු ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී තාරක බාලසූරියගේ කෑගල්ලේ පිහිටි නිවසට සහ කාර්යාලයට පහරදීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් සැකකරුවන් 04 දෙනෙකු කෑගල්ල පොලීසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන රෝහිත අබේගුණවර්ධන සහ ජොන්ස්ටන් ප්‍රනාන්දු යන අයගේ නිවෙස්වලට පහරදීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් 58 හැවිරිදි සැකකරුවෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "ඇලහැර ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාවේ සභාපතිවරයාට පහරදීමේ සිද්ධියක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් මහව සහ කහටගස්දිගිලිය ප්‍රදේශවල පදිංචිකරුවන් දෙදෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී විදුර වික්‍රමනායක මහතාගේ නිවසට අලාභහානි සිදුකිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් තවත් සැකකරුවෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති අතර, අරුන්දික ප්‍රනාන්දු සහ මහර ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාවේ සභාපතිනියගේ නිවෙස්වලට අලාභ හානි සිදුකිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් එක් සැකකරුවෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "ලිපියක් සමඟ මෝටර් රථ ගරාජයක දමා ගිය මාසයක් වයසැති ළදරුවා",
        "ඔබ සයිබර් අපරාධයට ගොදුරු වූවෙක්ද? සයිබර් අවකාශයේ සිදුවන අපරාධ මර්දනයට පොලිස් ඒකකය සූදානම්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "12",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "මැයි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තාරක බාලසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "58 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෝහිත අබේගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොන්ස්ටන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කහටගස්දිගිලිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇලහැර ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදුර වික්‍රමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාසයක් වයසැති",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සයිබර් අපරාධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மே 9 வன்முறையில் மேலும் 12 பேர் கைது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு மே மாதம் 9 ஆம் திகதி இடம்பெற்ற வன்முறைச் சம்பவத்துடன் தொடர்புடைய மேலும் 12 சந்தேக நபர்களை இலங்கை பொலிஸார் கைது செய்துள்ளனர்.",
        "நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் தாரக பாலசூரியவின் கேகாலையில் உள்ள வீடு மற்றும் அலுவலகம் மீது தாக்குதல் நடத்தப்பட்ட சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் 04 சந்தேகநபர்கள் கேகாலை பொலிஸாரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான ரோஹித அபேகுணவர்தன மற்றும் ஜோன்ஸ்டன் பெர்னாண்டோ ஆகியோரின் வீடுகள் மீதான தாக்குதல்கள் தொடர்பில் 58 வயதுடைய சந்தேக நபர் ஒருவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "எலஹெர பிரதேச சபையின் தலைவரை தாக்கிய சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் மஹவ மற்றும் கஹட்டகஸ்திகிலிய பிரதேசங்களை சேர்ந்த இருவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் விதுர விக்கிரமநாயக்கவின் வீட்டிற்கு சேதம் விளைவித்த குற்றச்சாட்டின் பேரில் மற்றுமொரு சந்தேகநபர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதுடன், மஹர பிரதேச சபையின் தவிசாளர் அருந்திகா பெர்னாண்டோவின் வீடுகளுக்கு சேதம் விளைவித்த குற்றச்சாட்டில் ஒரு சந்தேகநபர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "கடிதத்துடன் மோட்டார் கேரேஜில் கைவிடப்பட்ட ஒரு மாத கைக்குழந்தை",
        "நீங்கள் சைபர் கிரைம் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவரா? சைபர்ஸ்பேஸ் குற்றங்களை ஒடுக்க போலீஸ் பிரிவு தயார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "12",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "மே",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாரக பாலசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "58 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோஹித அபேகுணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜோன்ஸ்டன் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹாவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கஹடகஸ்திகிலிய",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எலஹெர பிரதேச சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விதுர விக்கிரமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாத வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சைபர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}