{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/30/lanka-ioc-tankers-to-report-to-work/",
  "time_ut": 1656586200,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Lanka IOC Tankers to report to work",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Lanka IOC Tankers to report to work",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); All fuel transport vehicles of Lanka IOC have been informed to report into service.",
        "The Chairman of the Lanka IOC Tanker Owners’ Association Kusum Sadanayake said that at present between 75 and 100 vehicles are being operated daily, and IOC owns about 160 tanks.",
        "Meanwhile, the General Secretary of the Petroleum Private Tanker Owners’ Association Shantha Silva said that NO fuel transport vehicles will travel to the Ceypetco filling stations on Thursday (30).",
        "IMF Staff Concludes Visit to Sri Lanka; discussions will continue towards reaching a staff-level agreement"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "IOC Tankers",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Lanka IOC Tanker Owners’ Association Kusum Sadanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "between 75 and 100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IOC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 160",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Petroleum Private Tanker Owners’ Association Shantha Silva",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceypetco",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF Staff Concludes Visit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලංකා IOC ටැංකි සේවයට වාර්තා කිරීමට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ලංකා IOC සමාගමේ සියලුම ඉන්ධන ප්‍රවාහන වාහන සේවයට වාර්තා කරන ලෙස දැනුම් දී ඇත.",
        "ලංකා IOC ටැංකි රථ හිමියන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති කුසුම් සදනායක කියා සිටියේ මේ වන විට දිනකට වාහන 75ත් 100ත් අතර ප්‍රමාණයක් ධාවනය වන අතර IOC සතුව ටැංකි 160ක් පමණ පවතින බවයි.",
        "මේ අතර, ඛනිජ තෙල් පෞද්ගලික ටැංකි හිමියන්ගේ සංගමයේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් ශාන්ත සිල්වා කියා සිටියේ බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (30) දිනයේදී කිසිදු ඉන්ධන ප්‍රවාහන වාහනයක් සිපෙට්කෝ ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් වෙත ගමන් නොකරන බවයි.",
        "IMF කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංචාරය අවසන් කරයි; කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමකට එළඹීම සඳහා සාකච්ඡා දිගටම කරගෙන යනු ඇත"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "IOC ටැංකි",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා IOC ටැංකි හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය කුසුම් සදනායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 සහ 100 අතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයි.ඕ.සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "160 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශාන්ත සිල්වා ඛනිජ තෙල් පෞද්ගලික ටැංකි හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිපෙට්කෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය සංචාරය අවසන් කරයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "லங்கா ஐஓசி டேங்கர்கள் பணிக்கு அறிக்கை அளிக்க வேண்டும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); லங்கா ஐஓசியின் அனைத்து எரிபொருள் போக்குவரத்து வாகனங்களும் சேவையில் ஈடுபடுமாறு அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "லங்கா ஐஓசி டேங்கர் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் குசும் சதநாயக்க கூறுகையில், தற்போது நாளாந்தம் 75 முதல் 100 வாகனங்கள் இயக்கப்படுவதாகவும், ஐஓசிக்கு சுமார் 160 டாங்கிகள் சொந்தமாக இருப்பதாகவும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, வியாழக்கிழமை (30) சிபெட்கோ எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையங்களுக்கு எரிபொருள் போக்குவரத்து வாகனங்கள் செல்லாது என பெற்றோலிய தனியார் தாங்கி உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கத்தின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் சாந்த சில்வா தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பணியாளர்கள் இலங்கை விஜயத்தை முடித்துள்ளனர்; ஊழியர்கள் அளவிலான ஒப்பந்தத்தை எட்டுவது தொடர்பாக விவாதங்கள் தொடரும்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "IOC டேங்கர்கள்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "லங்கா ஐஓசி டேங்கர் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம் குசும் சதநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 மற்றும் 100 இடையே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐஓசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 160",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோலிய தனியார் டேங்கர் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம் சாந்த சில்வா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சைபெட்கோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF ஊழியர்கள் வருகையை முடித்தனர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}