{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Chinese-Company-refuses-to-refund-or-substitute-chemical-fertilizer-Amaraweera/342-243662",
  "time_ut": 1661362126,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Chinese Company refuses to refund or substitute chemical fertilizer: Amaraweera",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Chinese Company refuses to refund or substitute chemical fertilizer: Amaraweera",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Chinese fertilizer Company Seawin Biotech refused to refund the money paid for the controversial organic fertilizer shipment or provide chemical fertilizer in place of the ordered organic fertilizer, Agricultural Minister Mahinda Amaraweera said today.",
        "He told a news conference at the Government Information Department that the Chinese Company was insisting that Sri Lanka should procure the organic fertilizer as ordered.",
        "The Minister said a team headed by an additional secretary to the Agricultural Ministry was continuing discussions with the Chinese Company with regard to the fertilizer shipment.",
        "“I looked into the possibility of reclaiming the US Dollars 6.9 million paid to the Chinese Company or obtaining chemical fertilizer to allow for the paid amount. However, the Company objected to both requests. They insist that we should obtain organic fertilizer as originally ordered. We risk losing both money and fertilizer,’ he said.",
        "The Minister said Sri Lanka was not having standards for organic fertilizer and that he instructed the Sri Lanka Standard Institute to prepare standards required for organic fertilizer.",
        "“The Chinese Company said they could not provide organic fertilizer on par with the standards set by Sri Lanka's National Plant Quarantine Services (NPQS),” he said.",
        "The Minister said there was an ongoing court case with regard to the said shipment and added that the Ministry was waiting for the ruling of the court case to decide on further steps.(Ajith Siriwardana)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Chinese Company",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Amaraweera",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Company Seawin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Government Information Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Chinese Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Agricultural Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Chinese Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the US Dollars 6.9 million",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Chinese Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Standard Institute",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Chinese Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Plant Quarantine Services",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPQS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Siriwardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීන සමාගම රසායනික පොහොර ආපසු ගෙවීම හෝ ආදේශ කිරීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරයි: අමරවීර",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආන්දෝලනාත්මක කාබනික පොහොර තොගය සඳහා ගෙවූ මුදල් ආපසු ගෙවීම හෝ ඇණවුම් කළ කාබනික පොහොර වෙනුවට රසායනික පොහොර ලබාදීම චීන පොහොර සමාගමක් වන සීවින් බයෝටෙක් ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළ බව කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතා පවසයි.",
        "රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ පැවති ප්‍රවෘත්ති සාකච්ඡාවකදී ඔහු කියා සිටියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කාබනික පොහොර ඇණවුම් කළ පරිදි මිලදී ගත යුතු බවට චීන සමාගම අවධාරණය කරන බවයි.",
        "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශයේ අතිරේක ලේකම්වරයෙකුගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් යුත් කණ්ඩායමක් පොහොර ප්‍රවාහනය සම්බන්ධයෙන් චීන සමාගම සමඟ අඛණ්ඩව සාකච්ඡා කරමින් සිටින බව අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "“චීන සමාගමට ගෙවා ඇති ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 6.9ක මුදල නැවත ලබා ගැනීමට හෝ ගෙවන මුදලට ඉඩ සැලසීම සඳහා රසායනික පොහොර ලබා ගැනීමට ඇති හැකියාව මම සොයා බැලුවා. කෙසේ වෙතත්, සමාගම ඉල්ලීම් දෙකටම විරුද්ධ විය. අපි මුලින් ඇණවුම් කළ පරිදි කාබනික පොහොර ලබා ගත යුතු බව ඔවුහු අවධාරණය කරති. අපට මුදල් සහ පොහොර යන දෙකම අහිමි වීමේ අවදානමක් තිබෙනවා.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කාබනික පොහොර සඳහා ප්‍රමිතීන් නොමැති බවත් කාබනික පොහොර සඳහා අවශ්‍ය ප්‍රමිතීන් සකස් කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රමිති ආයතනයට උපදෙස් දුන් බවත් අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාතික ශාක නිරෝධායන සේවා (NPQS) විසින් නියම කර ඇති ප්‍රමිතීන්ට සමගාමීව කාබනික පොහොර ලබා දිය නොහැකි බව චීන සමාගම ප්‍රකාශ කළේය,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "එම නැව්ගත කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් උසාවියේ නඩුවක් පවතින බව පැවසූ අමාත්‍යවරයා, ඉදිරි පියවර පිළිබඳව තීරණය කිරීම සඳහා අධිකරණ නඩුවේ තීන්දුව ලැබෙන තෙක් අමාත්‍යාංශය බලා සිටින බවද පැවසීය.(අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීන සමාගම",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අමරවීර",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාගම සීවින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලර් මිලියන 6.9 කි",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සම්මත ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ශාක නිරෝධායන සේවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPQS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சீன நிறுவனம் இரசாயன உரத்தை திருப்பிச் செலுத்தவோ அல்லது மாற்றாகவோ மறுக்கிறது: அமரவீர",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சீன உர நிறுவனமான சீவின் பயோடெக் சர்ச்சைக்குரிய கரிம உர ஏற்றுமதிக்காக செலுத்தப்பட்ட பணத்தை மீள வழங்கவோ அல்லது ஆர்டர் செய்யப்பட்ட கரிம உரத்திற்கு பதிலாக இரசாயன உரங்களை வழங்கவோ மறுத்துள்ளதாக விவசாய அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களத்தில் நடைபெற்ற செய்தியாளர் மாநாட்டில் அவர் கூறுகையில், இலங்கையின் கட்டளைக்கு அமைவாக இந்த கரிம உரத்தை கொள்வனவு செய்ய வேண்டும் என சீன நிறுவனம் வலியுறுத்துகிறது.",
        "உர ஏற்றுமதி தொடர்பாக விவசாய அமைச்சின் மேலதிக செயலாளர் தலைமையிலான குழு சீன நிறுவனத்துடன் தொடர்ந்தும் கலந்துரையாடி வருவதாக அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "“சீன நிறுவனத்திற்கு செலுத்தப்பட்ட 6.9 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களை மீளப் பெறுவது அல்லது செலுத்தப்பட்ட தொகையை அனுமதிக்க இரசாயன உரத்தைப் பெறுவதற்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகளை நான் ஆராய்ந்தேன். இருப்பினும், இரண்டு கோரிக்கைகளுக்கும் நிறுவனம் எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவித்தது. ஆர்கானிக் உரத்தை முதலில் ஆர்டர் செய்தபடியே பெற வேண்டும் என வலியுறுத்துகின்றனர். பணம் மற்றும் உரம் இரண்டையும் இழக்கும் அபாயம் உள்ளது,'' என்றார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் கரிம உரங்களுக்கான தரநிலைகள் இல்லை எனவும், கரிம உரத்திற்கு தேவையான தரங்களை தயாரிக்குமாறு இலங்கை தரநிலை நிறுவனத்திற்கு பணிப்புரை வழங்கியதாகவும் அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"இலங்கையின் தேசிய தாவர தனிமைப்படுத்தல் சேவைகள் (NPQS) நிர்ணயித்த தரங்களுக்கு இணையாக கரிம உரங்களை வழங்க முடியாது என்று சீன நிறுவனம் கூறியது,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "மேற்படி ஏற்றுமதி தொடர்பில் நீதிமன்றில் வழக்கு தொடரப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தெரிவித்த அமைச்சர், மேலதிக நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்து முடிவெடுக்க நீதிமன்ற வழக்கின் தீர்ப்புக்காக அமைச்சு காத்திருப்பதாகவும் தெரிவித்தார்.(அஜித் சிறிவர்தன)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீன நிறுவனம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "அமரவீர",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிறுவனம் சீவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் 6.9 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலையான நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய தாவர தனிமைப்படுத்தப்பட்ட சேவைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPQS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}