{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ප්‍රාදේශීය-ලේකම්-සිර-කළාට-ප්‍ර-ලේ-සේවකයෝ-විරෝධය-පාති/101-615465",
  "time_ut": 1656311346,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් සිර කළාට ප්‍ර.ලේ සේවකයෝ විරෝධය පාති",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Divisional Secretary's imprisoned Divisional Secretariat employees protest",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Employees of the Matara Divisional Secretariat went on strike today in protest of the detention of Matara Divisional Secretary Kaushalya Kumari who had gone to the Matara General Hospital for medical treatment.",
        "Due to this the people who came to get the services faced severe difficulties.",
        "Employees who marched in front of the Matara District Secretariat requested the Matara Government Agent to provide a just solution to this problem.",
        "Accordingly, several delegates were granted permission to meet the Chief Government Agent of Matara, Mr. Y. Wickramarasiri."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Divisional Secretariat",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kaushalya Kumari",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Matara General Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Secretariat",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Y. Wickramarasiri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් සිර කළාට ප්‍ර.ලේ සේවකයෝ විරෝධය පාති",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "වෛද්‍ය ප්‍රතිකාර ලබා ගැනීමට මාතර මහ රෝහලට ගිය මාතර ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කෞෂල්‍යා කුමාරි මහත්මියට ප්‍රතිකාර ලබා නොදී සිර කර තබා ගැනීමේ සිද්ධියට විරෝධය පල කරමින් මාතර ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේ සේවක සේවිකාවෝ වැඩ වර්ජනය කරමින් අද විරෝධතායක නිරත වූහ.",
        "මේ නිසා සේවා ලබා ගැනීමට පැමිණී ජනතාව දැඩි දුෂ්කරතාවන්ට මුහුණ දුන්නේය.",
        "විරෝධතා පා ගමනකින් මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික් ලේකම් කාර්යාලය ඉදිරිපිටට පැමිණි සේවක සේවිකාවන් මෙම ගැටලුවට සාධාරණ විසදුමක් ලබා දෙන ලෙසට මාතර මහ දිසාපතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "ඒ අනුව නියෝජිතයින් කිහිප දෙනකුට මාතර මහ දිසාපති වයි.වික්‍රමසිරි මහතා හමු වී සාකච්ඡාවක් කිරීමට අවසර හිමි විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෞශල්‍යා කුමාරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර මහ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයි වික්‍රමසිරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரதேச செயலாளரின் சிறைபிடிக்கப்பட்ட பிரதேச செயலக ஊழியர்கள் ஆர்ப்பாட்டம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மருத்துவ சிகிச்சைக்காக மாத்தறை பொது வைத்தியசாலைக்கு சென்ற மாத்தறை பிரதேச செயலாளர் கௌசல்ய குமாரியை தடுத்து வைத்தமைக்கு எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவித்து மாத்தறை பிரதேச செயலக ஊழியர்கள் இன்று பணிப்புறக்கணிப்பில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இதனால் சேவைகளைப் பெற வந்த மக்கள் கடும் சிரமத்துக்குள்ளாகினர்.",
        "மாத்தறை மாவட்ட செயலகத்திற்கு முன்பாக பேரணியாக சென்ற ஊழியர்கள், இந்த பிரச்சினைக்கு நியாயமான தீர்வை வழங்குமாறு மாத்தறை அரசாங்க அதிபரிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்தனர்.",
        "இதன்படி, மாத்தறை பிரதான அரசாங்க அதிபர் திரு.வை.விக்ரமரசிறியை சந்திப்பதற்கு பல பிரதிநிதிகளுக்கு அனுமதி வழங்கப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பிரதேச செயலகம்",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கௌசல்யா குமாரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை பொது வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செயலகம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வை.விக்கிரமரசிறி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}