{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Namal-Rajapaksa-assumes-head-hunter-role/56-738779",
  "time_ut": 1660688482,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Namal Rajapaksa assumes head-hunter role",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Namal Rajapaksa assumes head-hunter role",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Proposes two names for CEO post of Geological Survey and Mines Bureau subsidiary",
        "President sets up Committee to require prior approval for appointments in State sector",
        "In an apparent head-hunter role, Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna MP Namal Rajapaksa has written to Environment Minister Naseer Ahamed, recommending at least two persons for the post of CEO of GSMB Technical Services Ltd., a subsidiary company of the Geological Survey and Mines Bureau.",
        "GSMB Technical Services Ltd. is registered as a fully Government-owned Ltd. company which undertakes projects facilitating engineering geology and assessment of mineral resources.",
        "In a document now circulating widely, on 6 August Rajapaksa had written to the Minister on a Parliament of Sri Lanka letterhead proposing the name of M.H.D.P. Karunaratne of Tangalle for the post claiming he had the requisite qualifications for the position. The other person proposed is revealed to be G.G.M. Ishara Hemantha, a Pradeshiya Sabha member and a former Private Secretary of MP D.V. Chanaka.",
        "Following Rajapaksa’s letter to Minister Ahamed, M.H.D.P. Karunaratne has been appointed as the CEO of GSMB Technical Services Ltd. with effect from 11 August according to sources.",
        "Amidst these moves, President Ranil Wickremesinghe yesterday appointed a Committee that will have to be consulted for prior approval when appointing or changing Chairmen, Director for Public Corporations, and Statutory Boards. It has been suggested the President has made this decision following the recent revelations relating to GSMB Technical Services Ltd.",
        "This Committee will be headed by Secretary to the President Saman Ekanayake and will include Secretary to the Prime Minister Anura Dissanayake, and Secretary to the Cabinet W.M.D.J. Fernando. Additional Secretary to the President Daminda Kularatne will serve as the Secretary to the Committee."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Rajapaksa",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mines Bureau",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Namal Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Naseer Ahamed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "at least two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "GSMB Technical Services Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mines Bureau",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "GSMB Technical Services Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6 August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "a Parliament of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "M.H.D.P. Karunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ishara Hemantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pradeshiya Sabha",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Private",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "D.V. Chanaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ahamed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "M.H.D.P. Karunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "GSMB Technical Services Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chairmen",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Statutory Boards",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "GSMB Technical Services Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saman Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cabinet W.M.D.J. Fernando",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daminda Kularatne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ හිස දඩයම් කිරීමේ භූමිකාව භාර ගනී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "භූ විද්‍යා සමීක්ෂණ සහ පතල් කාර්යාංශයේ අනුබද්ධ ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී තනතුර සඳහා නම් දෙකක් යෝජනා කරයි",
        "රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ පත්වීම් සඳහා පූර්ව අනුමැතිය අවශ්‍ය කිරීමට ජනාධිපති කමිටුවක් පත් කරයි",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතා, භූ විද්‍යා සමීක්ෂණ හා පතල් කාර්යාංශයට අනුබද්ධිත සමාගමක් වන සීමාසහිත GSMB ටෙක්නිකල් සර්විසස් හි ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී තනතුර සඳහා අවම වශයෙන් පුද්ගලයන් දෙදෙනෙකු නිර්දේශ කරමින් පරිසර අමාත්‍ය නසීර් අහමඩ් වෙත ලිඛිතව දන්වා ඇත. .",
        "GSMB ටෙක්නිකල් සර්විසස් ලිමිටඩ් සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම රජයට අයත් ලිමිටඩ් සමාගමක් ලෙස ලියාපදිංචි වී ඇති අතර එය ඉංජිනේරු භූ විද්‍යාව සහ ඛනිජ සම්පත් තක්සේරු කිරීම සඳහා පහසුකම් සපයන ව්‍යාපෘති භාර ගනී.",
        "දැන් පුළුල් ලෙස සංසරණය වන ලේඛනයක, අගෝස්තු 6 වන දින රාජපක්ෂ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ලිපි ශීර්ෂයක එම්.එච්.ඩී.පී.ගේ නම යෝජනා කරමින් අමාත්‍යවරයාට ලියා තිබුණි. තංගල්ලේ කරුණාරත්න මහතා එම තනතුර සඳහා අවශ්‍ය සුදුසුකම් ඇති බව පවසමිනි. යෝජිත අනෙක් පුද්ගලයා ජී.ජී.එම්. ප්‍රාදේශීය සභා මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු වන ඉෂාර හේමන්ත, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයාගේ හිටපු පෞද්ගලික ලේකම්වරයෙකු වන ඩී.වී. චානක.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ අමාත්‍ය අහමඩ් වෙත යැවූ ලිපියෙන් පසුව එම්.එච්.ඩී.පී. කරුණාරත්න සීමාසහිත GSMB ටෙක්නිකල් සර්විසස් හි ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරියා ලෙස අගෝස්තු 11 සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි පත් කර ඇති බව ආරංචි මාර්ග පවසයි.",
        "මෙම පියවරයන් මධ්‍යයේ ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් රාජ්‍ය සංස්ථා සහ ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත මණ්ඩල සඳහා සභාපතිවරුන්, අධ්‍යක්ෂවරුන් පත්කිරීමේදී හෝ වෙනස් කිරීමේදී පූර්ව අනුමැතිය සඳහා උපදෙස් ලබාගත යුතු කමිටුවක් ඊයේ පත් කළේය. සීමාසහිත ජීඑස්එම්බී ටෙක්නිකල් සර්විසස් සමාගමට අදාළව මෑතක දී හෙළිදරව් වීමත් සමඟ ජනාධිපතිවරයා මෙම තීරණය ගෙන ඇති බවට යෝජනා වී තිබේ.",
        "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් සමන් ඒකනායක මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් යුත් මෙම කමිටුවට අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ලේකම් අනුර දිසානායක, අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩල ලේකම් ඩබ්ලිව්.එම්.ඩී.ජේ. ප්‍රනාන්දු. එම කමිටුවේ ලේකම්වරයා ලෙස ජනාධිපති අතිරේක ලේකම් දමින්ද කුලරත්න මහතා කටයුතු කරනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පතල් කාර්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කමිටුවක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නසීර් අහමඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් දෙකක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "GSMB තාක්ෂණික සේවා ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පතල් කාර්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "GSMB තාක්ෂණික සේවා ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවකි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.එච්.ඩී.පී. කරුණාරත්න ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉෂාර හේමන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුද්ගලික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.වී. චානක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අහමඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.එච්.ඩී.පී. කරුණාරත්න ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "GSMB තාක්ෂණික සේවා ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමිටුවක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සභාපතිවරු",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාපිත මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "GSMB තාක්ෂණික සේවා ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමන් ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය ඩබ්ලිව්.එම්.ඩී.ජේ. ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දමින්ද කුලරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමිටුවක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாமல் ராஜபக்ச தலைமை வேட்டையாடுகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "புவியியல் ஆய்வு மற்றும் சுரங்கப் பணியகத்தின் துணை நிறுவனங்களின் CEO பதவிக்கு இரண்டு பெயர்களை முன்மொழிகிறது",
        "அரசுத் துறையில் நியமனங்களுக்கு முன் அனுமதி பெறுவதற்கு ஜனாதிபதி குழுவை அமைக்கிறார்",
        "புவியியல் ஆய்வு மற்றும் சுரங்கப் பணியகத்தின் துணை நிறுவனமான GSMB Technical Services Ltd. இன் பிரதம நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரி பதவிக்கு குறைந்தது இரண்டு பேரையாவது சிபாரிசு செய்யுமாறு, ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் நாமல் ராஜபக்ஷ, சுற்றாடல் அமைச்சர் நசீர் அஹமட்டுக்கு கடிதம் எழுதியுள்ளார். .",
        "ஜிஎஸ்எம்பி டெக்னிக்கல் சர்வீசஸ் லிமிடெட், முழுமையாக அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான லிமிடெட் நிறுவனமாக பதிவு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது, இது பொறியியல் புவியியல் மற்றும் கனிம வளங்களை மதிப்பிடுவதற்கான திட்டங்களை மேற்கொள்கிறது.",
        "இப்போது பரவலாக புழக்கத்தில் உள்ள ஒரு ஆவணத்தில், ஆகஸ்ட் 6 ஆம் தேதி ராஜபக்ச இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் கடிதத் தலைப்பில் M.H.D.P இன் பெயரை முன்மொழிந்து அமைச்சருக்கு எழுதியிருந்தார். தங்காலையைச் சேர்ந்த கருணாரத்ன அந்தப் பதவிக்கு தேவையான தகுதிகள் தனக்கு இருப்பதாகக் கூறி அந்தப் பதவிக்கு வந்தார். முன்மொழியப்பட்ட மற்றொரு நபர் ஜி.ஜி.எம். இஷார ஹேமந்த, பிரதேச சபை உறுப்பினரும், பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினரின் முன்னாள் பிரத்தியேக செயலாளருமான டி.வி. சானகா.",
        "அமைச்சர் அகமதுவுக்கு ராஜபக்சே எழுதிய கடிதத்தைத் தொடர்ந்து, எம்.எச்.டி.பி. கருணாரத்ன GSMB டெக்னிக்கல் சர்வீசஸ் லிமிடெட் நிறுவனத்தின் பிரதம நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரியாக ஆகஸ்ட் 11 ஆம் திகதி முதல் அமுலுக்கு வரும் வகையில் நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இந்த நகர்வுகளுக்கு மத்தியில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நேற்று ஒரு குழுவொன்றை நியமித்துள்ளார். இது பொது கூட்டுத்தாபனங்கள் மற்றும் சட்ட சபைகளுக்கான தலைவர்கள், பணிப்பாளர்களை நியமிக்கும் போது அல்லது மாற்றும் போது முன் அனுமதி பெற வேண்டும். GSMB டெக்னிக்கல் சர்வீசஸ் லிமிடெட் தொடர்பான சமீபத்திய வெளிப்பாடுகளை அடுத்து ஜனாதிபதி இந்த முடிவை எடுத்துள்ளார் என்று கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "இந்தக் குழுவில் ஜனாதிபதியின் செயலாளர் சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க தலைமையில் பிரதமரின் செயலாளர் அனுர திஸாநாயக்க மற்றும் அமைச்சரவை செயலாளர் டபிள்யூ.எம்.டி.ஜே. பெர்னாண்டோ. ஜனாதிபதியின் மேலதிக செயலாளர் தமிந்த குலரத்ன இந்த குழுவின் செயலாளராக கடமையாற்றுவார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுரங்கப் பணியகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாமல் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நசீர் அகமது",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜிஎஸ்எம்பி டெக்னிக்கல் சர்வீசஸ் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுரங்கப் பணியகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜிஎஸ்எம்பி டெக்னிக்கல் சர்வீசஸ் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6 ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.எச்.டி.பி. கருணாரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஷாரா ஹேமந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரதேச சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனியார்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.வி. சானகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அகமது",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.எச்.டி.பி. கருணாரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜிஎஸ்எம்பி டெக்னிக்கல் சர்வீசஸ் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைவர்கள்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "சட்டப்பூர்வ வாரியங்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜிஎஸ்எம்பி டெக்னிக்கல் சர்வீசஸ் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சரவை டபிள்யூ.எம்.டி.ஜே. பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிந்த குலரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}