{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Imithiaz-calls-out-President-on-his-duplicity-concerning-the-Aragalaya/56-739001",
  "time_ut": 1661202027,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Imithiaz calls out President on his duplicity concerning the ‘Aragalaya’",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Imithiaz calls out President on his duplicity concerning the ‘Aragalaya’",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) MP Imthiaz Bakeer Markar has called out President Ranil Wickremesinghe on his duplicity relating to the Aragalaya and its peaceful protestors. “Once he was appointed, he created a sense of hope by claiming he was not against the citizen’s struggle. He even promised to appoint a committee to look into their needs and not repress the people’s right to protest peacefully.",
        "“He included a politician, the Municipal Council and even the Police into the Committee and claimed all necessary facilities to continue the struggle will be provided,” Markar said. “He said this in words but he is doing something drastically different through his actions today,” Makar pointed out.",
        "The MP made these comments during a press conference held by the SJB in Colombo yesterday.",
        "“If he was truly a democratic leader he would have not signed these detention orders under the Prevention of Terrorism Act and allowed for the arrests of innocent and peaceful students activists under a law that is meant for those carrying out crimes against the State,” Markar said.",
        "“There is a great contradiction between what was said and what is being done today,” he noted. According to Markar, the President is attempting to deceive the people. Markar called on the people to not fall for the fairy tales spun by Wickremesinghe. “We will have to answer to the International Human Rights Organisations in the end,” he said.",
        "“This will not only be a threat to the country’s democracy but it will also threaten our economic state. The country was severely affected by the loss of the GSP+ concession. Where are we heading now? None of the criticisms against the country by international organisations is being reported in the media,” he said.",
        "Markar accused a possible cat’s paw of influencing the media. “Head of media organisations, swimming champions, student’s activists and others are being summoned to the CID. What is the aim of these actions? The message is that the Government is ready to hunt anyone opposing them or attempting to obstruct the revival of those who caused this economic collapse. The people must understand this. Repression of those opposing the Government cannot take place without the blessings of the President,” Markar added."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "the ‘Aragalaya’",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Imthiaz Bakeer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Markar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Municipal Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Markar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Makar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "democratic",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Prevention of Terrorism Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Markar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Markar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Markar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Human Rights Organisations",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Markar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Markar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘අරගලය’ සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජනපතිගේ දෙබිඩි පිළිවෙත ගැන ඉමිතියාස් කියයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අරගලය සහ එහි සාමකාමී විරෝධතාකරුවන් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ දෙබිඩි පිළිවෙත සම්බන්ධයෙන් සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ (SJB) පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඉමිතියාස් බාකීර් මාකර් මහතාගෙන් ඉල්ලා තිබේ. \"ඔහු පත් වූ පසු, ඔහු පුරවැසි අරගලයට විරුද්ධ නොවන බව පවසමින් බලාපොරොත්තුවේ හැඟීමක් ඇති කළේය. ඔවුන්ගේ අවශ්‍යතා සොයා බැලීමට කමිටුවක් පත් කරන බවටත් සාමකාමීව විරෝධතා දැක්වීමට ජනතාවට ඇති අයිතිය යටපත් නොකරන බවටත් ඔහු පොරොන්දු විය.",
        "\"ඔහු දේශපාලනඥයෙකු, නගර සභාව සහ පොලිසිය පවා කමිටුවට ඇතුළත් කළ අතර අරගලය දිගටම කරගෙන යාමට අවශ්‍ය සියලු පහසුකම් ලබා දෙන බව කියා සිටියේය,\" මාකර් පැවසීය. \"ඔහු මෙය වචන වලින් පැවසුවද අද ඔහුගේ ක්‍රියාවන් හරහා ඔහු කරන්නේ ඊට හාත්පසින්ම වෙනස් දෙයක්\" මාකාර් පෙන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "මන්ත‍්‍රීවරයා මේ අදහස් පළ කළේ ඊයේ කොළඹදී පැවති SJB ප‍්‍රවෘත්ති සාකච්ඡාවකට එක්වෙමින්.",
        "\"ඔහු සැබවින්ම ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී නායකයෙකු නම්, ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැලැක්වීමේ පනත යටතේ මෙම රැඳවුම් නියෝගවලට අත්සන් නොතබන අතර, රාජ්‍යයට එරෙහි අපරාධ සිදු කරන්නන් සඳහා වන නීතියක් යටතේ අහිංසක සහ සාමකාමී ශිෂ්‍ය ක්‍රියාකාරීන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට ඉඩ නොදෙනු ඇත,\" මාකර් කිව්වා.",
        "\"කියපු දේ සහ අද කරන දේ අතර ලොකු පරස්පරයක් තියෙනවා\" ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය. මාකර්ට අනුව ජනාධිපතිවරයා උත්සාහ කරන්නේ ජනතාව රැවටීමටය. වික්‍රමසිංහ විසින් ගෙතුනු සුරංගනා කතාවලට නොරැවටෙන ලෙස මාකර් ජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. \"අවසානයේදී අපට ජාත්‍යන්තර මානව හිමිකම් සංවිධානවලට පිළිතුරු දීමට සිදුවනු ඇත,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "“මෙය රටේ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදයට තර්ජනයක් පමණක් නොව අපේ ආර්ථික තත්ත්වයට ද තර්ජනයක් වනු ඇත. GSP+ සහනය අහිමිවීම නිසා රටට දැඩි බලපෑමක් එල්ල වුණා. අපි දැන් කොහෙද යන්නේ? ජාත්‍යන්තර සංවිධාන රටට එරෙහිව කරන කිසිම විවේචනයක් මාධ්‍යවල වාර්තා වෙන්නේ නැහැ,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මාකර් මාධ්‍යයට බලපෑම් කළ හැකි බළල් අතක් චෝදනා කළේය. “මාධ්‍ය සංවිධාන ප්‍රධානීන්, පිහිනුම් ශූරයන්, ශිෂ්‍ය ක්‍රියාකාරීන් ඇතුළු තවත් පිරිසක් අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට කැඳවනවා. මෙම ක්රියාවන්ගේ අරමුණ කුමක්ද? මෙම ආර්ථික කඩාවැටීමට හේතුවූ අයගේ පුනර්ජීවනයට බාධා කිරීමට හෝ ඔවුන්ට විරුද්ධ වන ඕනෑම අයෙකු දඩයම් කිරීමට රජය සූදානම් බව එම පණිවිඩයයි. ජනතාව මෙය තේරුම් ගත යුතුයි. ජනාධිපතිතුමාගේ ආශිර්වාදය නැතිව ආණ්ඩුවට විරුද්ධ අය මර්දනය කරන්න බැහැ,” මාකර් වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "'අරගලය'",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉමිතියාස් බාකීර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නගර සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමිටුවක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මකාර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්රජාතන්ත්රවාදී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මානව හිමිකම් සංවිධාන",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "‘அரகலயா’ விவகாரத்தில் ஜனாதிபதியின் போலித்தனம் குறித்து இமிதியாஸ் அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரகலய மற்றும் அதன் அமைதியான போராட்டக்காரர்கள் தொடர்பில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் போலித்தனம் குறித்து சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் இம்தியாஸ் பாக்கீர் மார்க்கர் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். \"அவர் நியமிக்கப்பட்டவுடன், அவர் குடிமக்களின் போராட்டத்திற்கு எதிரானவர் அல்ல என்று கூறி நம்பிக்கை உணர்வை உருவாக்கினார். அவர்களின் தேவைகளை ஆராய ஒரு குழுவை நியமிப்பதாகவும், அமைதியான முறையில் போராட்டம் நடத்தும் மக்களின் உரிமையை ஒடுக்கக் கூடாது என்றும் அவர் உறுதியளித்தார்.",
        "\"அவர் ஒரு அரசியல்வாதி, மாநகர சபை மற்றும் காவல்துறையினரைக் கூட குழுவில் சேர்த்தார், மேலும் போராட்டத்தைத் தொடர தேவையான அனைத்து வசதிகளும் வழங்கப்படும்\" என்று மார்கர் கூறினார். \"அவர் இதை வார்த்தைகளில் கூறினார், ஆனால் அவர் இன்று தனது செயல்களின் மூலம் முற்றிலும் மாறுபட்ட ஒன்றைச் செய்கிறார்\" என்று மகர் சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "SJB கொழும்பில் நேற்று நடத்திய ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பின் போதே பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"அவர் உண்மையிலேயே ஒரு ஜனநாயகத் தலைவராக இருந்திருந்தால், பயங்கரவாதத் தடுப்புச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் இந்த தடுப்புக் காவல் உத்தரவுகளில் கையெழுத்திட்டிருக்க மாட்டார், மேலும் அரசுக்கு எதிரான குற்றங்களைச் செய்பவர்களுக்கான சட்டத்தின் கீழ் அப்பாவி மற்றும் அமைதியான மாணவர் ஆர்வலர்களைக் கைது செய்ய அனுமதித்திருக்க மாட்டார்\" என்று மார்கர் கூறினார். கூறினார்.",
        "\"சொல்லப்பட்டதற்கும் இன்று செய்யப்படுவதற்கும் இடையே பெரும் முரண்பாடு உள்ளது\" என்று அவர் குறிப்பிட்டார். மர்க்கரின் கூற்றுப்படி, ஜனாதிபதி மக்களை ஏமாற்ற முயற்சிக்கிறார். விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் விசித்திரக் கதைகளுக்கு மக்கள் விழ வேண்டாம் என்று மார்க்கர் அழைப்பு விடுத்தார். \"இறுதியில் நாம் சர்வதேச மனித உரிமை அமைப்புகளுக்கு பதிலளிக்க வேண்டும்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "“இது நாட்டின் ஜனநாயகத்துக்கு மட்டும் அச்சுறுத்தலாக அமையாது, நமது பொருளாதார நிலைக்கும் அச்சுறுத்தலாக அமையும். GSP+ சலுகையை இழந்ததால் நாடு கடுமையாகப் பாதிக்கப்பட்டது. நாம் இப்போது எங்கே செல்கிறோம்? சர்வதேச அமைப்புகளால் நாட்டுக்கு எதிரான விமர்சனங்கள் எதுவும் ஊடகங்களில் வெளியிடப்படுவதில்லை,'' என்றார்.",
        "ஒரு பூனையின் பாதம் ஊடகங்களில் செல்வாக்கு செலுத்துவதாக மார்க்கர் குற்றம் சாட்டினார். “ஊடக நிறுவனங்களின் தலைவர்கள், நீச்சல் சாம்பியன்கள், மாணவர் ஆர்வலர்கள் மற்றும் பலர் CIDக்கு அழைக்கப்படுகிறார்கள். இந்த நடவடிக்கைகளின் நோக்கம் என்ன? இந்தப் பொருளாதாரச் சரிவுக்குக் காரணமானவர்களின் மறுமலர்ச்சியைத் தடுக்கும் முயற்சியோ அல்லது எதிர்த்தோ யாரையும் வேட்டையாடுவதற்கு அரசாங்கம் தயாராக உள்ளது என்பதுதான் செய்தி. இதை மக்கள் புரிந்து கொள்ள வேண்டும். அரசாங்கத்தை எதிர்ப்பவர்கள் மீதான அடக்குமுறை ஜனாதிபதியின் ஆசீர்வாதமின்றி நடைபெறாது” என்று மார்க்கர் மேலும் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "'அரகலயா'",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இம்தியாஸ் பகீர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்க்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாநகர சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்க்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயக",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்க்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்க்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்க்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச மனித உரிமைகள் அமைப்புகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மார்க்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்க்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}