{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/මෝටර්-රථය-ගසක-හැපී-තරුණයෙකු-මරුට/11-396893",
  "time_ut": 1662361474,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මෝටර් රථය ගසක හැපී තරුණයෙකු මරුට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The car crashed into a tree and a young man was killed",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Bibila police say that a nineteen-year-old young man died and his father was seriously injured and admitted to Badulla General Hospital yesterday evening at about 6.45 pm when a car ran off the road and hit a tree in Puwakpale area of ​​Bibila road.",
        "E.H.M., who was residing in Padiyathalawa High Street, died in the accident. A nineteen-year-old named Salinda Sitmina studied at Bibila Wellassa College.",
        "A religious preacher who conducts external graduate support classes has been seriously injured in the accident.",
        "While these two were coming home from Bibili, a wild elephant jumped on the road in the Puakpale Reserve and once the vehicle could not be stopped and the vehicle ran off the road and crashed into a bamboo tree. As two wild elephants roamed nearby, the injured had to wait for the Bibila police to take them to the hospital.",
        "The seriously injured person was transferred to Bibila Hospital and then to Monaragala Sirigala Hospital and then to Badulla General Hospital for further treatment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Bibila",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "nineteen-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Badulla General Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 6.45 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puwakpale",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "E.H.M.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Padiyathalawa High Street",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "nineteen-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Salinda Sitmina",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bibila Wellassa College",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bibili",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Puakpale Reserve",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bibila",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bibila Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monaragala Sirigala Hospital",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Badulla General Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මෝටර් රථය ගසක හැපී තරුණයෙකු මරුට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "බිබිල  පදියතලාව  මාර්ගයේ  පුවක්පැලේ පුදේශයේ දී  ඊයේ සවස 6.45 ට පමණ මෝටර් රථයක් පාරෙන් ඉවතට පැන ගසක හැපීමෙන් එහි ගමන් ගත් දහ නව හැවිරිදි තරුණයෙක්  මිය ගොස් ඔහුගේ  පියාට බරපතළ  තුවාල ලබා බදුල්ල  මහ රෝහලට  ඇතුලත් කර ඇතැයි  බිබිල පොලිසිය  පවසයි.",
        "අනතුරින්  මියගොස් ඇත්තේ පදියතලාව  ඉහල වීදියේ පදිංචිව සිටි  ඊ.එච්.එම්. සාලින්ද සිත්මිණ නැමැති දහ නව හැවිරිදි  බිබිල වෙල්ලස්ස  විද්‍යාලයේ  ඉගෙනුම  ලැබූ අයෙකි.",
        "අනතුරින් බරපතළ තුවාල ලබා ඇත්තේ බාහිර උපාධි උපකාරක පංති  පවත්වන පුසිද්ධ  දේශකයෙකි.",
        "මෙම දෙදෙනා බිබිලෙන් පිටත්ව නිවෙස් බලා පැමිණෙමින් සිටියදී පුවක්පැලේ රක්ෂිත පුදේශයේ දී  එක වරම වල් අලියෙකු මාර්ගයට පැන ඇති අතර එක් වරම රථය  නවතා ගැනීමට නොහැකිව  වාහනය මාර්ගයෙන් ඉවතට පැන බුළු ගසක හැපී ඇත. වල් අලි දෙදෙනෙකු ඒ  අසල ගැවසීම නිසා  තුවාල ලැබූවන් රෝහල් ගත කිරීමට  බිබිල පොලිසිය  එනතුරු සිටීමට සිදූ වී ඇත.",
        "බරපතල තුවාල ලැබූ  පුද්ගලයා  බිබිල රෝහලටත් අනතුරුව  මොණරාගල සිරිගල  රෝහලටත් පසුව වැඩිදුර පුතිකාර සදහා  බදුල්ල මහ රෝහලට මාරු කර  යවා ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බිබිල",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහනව හැවිරිදි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදුල්ල මහ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස 6.45ට පමණ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුවක්පලේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊ.එච්.එම්.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පදියතලාව මහා වීදිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහනව හැවිරිදි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාලින්ද සිත්මිනා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිබිල වෙල්ලස්ස විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිබිලි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puakpale රක්ෂිතය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිබිල",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බිබිල රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොනරාගල සිරිගල රෝහල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදුල්ල මහ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கார் மரத்தில் மோதியதில் இளைஞர் ஒருவர் உயிரிழந்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நேற்று மாலை 6.45 மணியளவில் பிபில வீதியின் புவக்பலே பகுதியில் கார் ஒன்று வீதியை விட்டு விலகி மரத்தில் மோதியதில் பத்தொன்பது வயதுடைய இளைஞன் ஒருவர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளதுடன் அவரது தந்தை படுகாயமடைந்து பதுளை பொது வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பிபில பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர். .",
        "விபத்தில் உயிரிழந்த பதியத்தலாவ மேட்டுத்தெருவில் வசிக்கும் ஈ.எச்.எம். பிபில வெல்லஸ்ஸ கல்லூரியில் பத்தொன்பது வயதுடைய சாலிந்த சித்மினா கல்வி பயின்றார்.",
        "இந்த விபத்தில் வெளி பட்டதாரி ஆதரவு வகுப்புகளை நடத்தும் மத போதகர் ஒருவர் பலத்த காயம் அடைந்துள்ளார்.",
        "இவர்கள் இருவரும் பிபிலியில் இருந்து வீட்டிற்கு வந்து கொண்டிருந்த போது, ​​புவாக்பலே காப்புக்காட்டில் ஒரு காட்டு யானை சாலையில் குதித்தது, ஒருமுறை வாகனத்தை நிறுத்த முடியாமல் வாகனம் சாலையை விட்டு விலகி மூங்கில் மரத்தில் மோதியது. இரண்டு காட்டு யானைகள் அருகில் சுற்றித் திரிந்ததால், காயமடைந்தவர்களை பிபில பொலிசார் மருத்துவமனைக்கு கொண்டு செல்லும் வரை காத்திருக்க வேண்டியிருந்தது.",
        "படுகாயமடைந்த நபர் பிபில வைத்தியசாலைக்கு மாற்றப்பட்டு மொனராகலை சிறிகல வைத்தியசாலைக்கு மாற்றப்பட்டு மேலதிக சிகிச்சைக்காக பதுளை பொது வைத்தியசாலைக்கு மாற்றப்பட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பிபிலா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தொன்பது வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதுளை பொது வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாயங்காலம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை சுமார் 6.45 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "புவக்பலே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இ.எச்.எம்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதியத்தலாவ உயர் வீதி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தொன்பது வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாலிண்டா சிட்மினா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிபில வெல்லஸ்ஸ கல்லூரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிபிலி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புவாக்பலே ரிசர்வ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிபிலா",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிபிலா மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொனராகலை சிறிகல வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதுளை பொது வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}