{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/පාස්කු-ප්‍රහාරය:-ජනපති-රනිල්-වගඋත්තරකාරභවින්-ඉවත්-කරනවාද-නැද්ද-:-තීරණය-කල්යයි/101-617469",
  "time_ut": 1659439104,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පාස්කු ප්‍රහාරය: ජනපති රනිල් වගඋත්තරකාරභවින් ඉවත් කරනවාද නැද්ද?: තීරණය කල්යයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Easter Attack: Will President Ranil be removed from accountability or not?: The decision is overdue",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The seven-judge bench postponed until today (02) the announcement of the order on whether or not the current President Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe, who is named as a respondent in the fundamental rights petitions filed regarding the inevitability of the Easter Sunday attacks, will be removed from being a respondent in those petitions.",
        "These petitions were filed by Chief Justice Jayantha Jayasuriya, Bhuvaneka Aluvihare, Priyantha Jayawardena, L. T. B. Dehideniya, Mild Fernando, S. These matters were presented during the hearing today (02) in front of a Supreme Court bench consisting of Mr. Turai Raja and Mr. Gamini Amarasekara.",
        "When this case was called, lawyer Mr. Suren Fernando, who appeared for the respondent President Ranil Wickramasinghe, stated that since the former Prime Minister Ranil Wickramasinghe has been named as a respondent and has been elected as the current President, he informed the court that he should be removed as a respondent in these petitions.",
        "President's lawyer Salia Piris, President of the Sri Lanka Bar Association, who protested against it, stated that according to the 19th Amendment of the Constitution, the President has immunity only in civil and criminal cases and since these petitions are fundamental rights petitions, the existing cases against him should be continued. and that",
        "Mr. Shamil Perera, the President's lawyer who appeared in the court for Malcolm Cardinal Ranjith, the Archbishop of Colombo, stated that he agrees with the facts of the President's lawyer, Salia Peiris, and accordingly, the case against President Ranil Wickremesinghe should be continued.",
        "Additional Solicitor General Priyantha Nawana, who appeared in court on behalf of the Governor-General, stated that since the President is entitled to immunity under Article 35 (1) of the Constitution, he cannot be prosecuted either on an official or private level. Accordingly, the Additional Solicitor General further informed the court that the President named as the respondent in this petition should be released.",
        "Taking into consideration the facts presented, the court informed that the announcement of the order will be postponed until later."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Easter Attack",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Easter",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayantha Jayasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aluvihare",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Priyantha Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mild Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "S.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Turai Raja",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gamini Amarasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Suren Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Salia Piris",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Bar Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shamil Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malcolm Cardinal Ranjith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Salia Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Priyantha Nawana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 35",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Additional Solicitor General",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාස්කු ප්‍රහාරය: ජනපති රනිල් වගඋත්තරකාරභවින් ඉවත් කරනවාද නැද්ද?: තීරණය කල්යයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාස්කු ඉරුදින ප්‍රහාර නොවැළැක්වීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ගොනුකර ඇති මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් පෙත්සම්වල වගඋත්තරකරුවකු ලෙස නම්කර සිටින වත්මන් ජනපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා එම පෙත්සම්වල වගඋත්තරකාර භාවයෙන් ඉවත්කරනවාද නැද්ද යන්න පිළිබද නියෝගය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කිරීම සත්පුද්ගල විනිසුරු මඩුල්ල අද (02) පසුවට කල් තැබීය.",
        "මෙම පෙත්සම් අගවිනිසුරු ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය, බුවනෙක අලුවිහාරේ, ප්‍රියන්ත ජයවර්ධන, එල්. ටී. බී. දෙහිදෙණීය, මෘදු ප්‍රනාන්දු, එස්. තුරෙයි රාජා සහ ගාමිණී අමරසේකර යන මහත්ම මහත්මීන්ගෙන් සමන්විත ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ විනිසුරු මඩුල්ලක් හමුවේ අද (02) විභාගයට ගත් අවස්ථාවේදි මෙම කරුණු ඉදිරිපත් විණී.",
        "මෙම නඩුව කැදවූ අවස්ථාවේදී වගඋත්තරකාර ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි නිතීඥ සුරේන් ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කර සිටියේ මෙහි වගඋත්තරකරුවකු වශයෙන් නම් කර හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වත්මන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා වශයෙන් තේරී පත්වී ඇති බැවින් ඒ මහතා මෙම පෙත්සම්වල වගඋත්තරකාර භාවයෙන් ඉවත් කළ යුතු බව අධිකරණයට දැනුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "ඊට විරෝධය දක්වමින් කරුණු දැක්වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිතීඥ සංගමයේ සභාපති ජනාධිපති නිතීඥ සාලිය පිරීස් මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කර සිටියේ, ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 19 වන සංශෝධනය අනුව ජනාධිපතිවරයාට මුක්තිය ඇත්තේ සිවිල් සහ අපරාධ නඩු සම්බන්ධයෙන් පමණක් බවත් මෙය පෙත්සම් මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් පෙත්සම් බැවින් ඔහුට එරෙහිව පවතින නඩු දිගටම පවත්වාගෙන යා යුතුව ඇති බවත්ය.",
        "මැල්කම් කාදිනල් රංජිත් කොළඹ අගරදගුරු වෙනුවෙන් අධිකරණයේ පෙනී සිටි ජනාධිපති නිතීඥ ශමිල් පෙරේරා මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කර සිටියේ, ජනාධිපති නිතීඥ සාලිය පීරිස් මහතාගේ කරුණුවලට එකගවන බවත්, ඒ අනුව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට එරෙහි නඩුව දිගටම පවත්වාගෙන යා යුතුව ඇති බවත්ය.",
        "නිතිපතිවරයා වෙනුවෙන් අධිකරණයේ පෙනී සිටි අතිරේක සොලිසිටර් ජනරාල් ප්‍රියන්ත නවාන මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කර සිටියේ ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 35 (1) වගන්තිය යටතේ ජනාධිපතිවරයාට මුක්තිය හිමිව ඇති බැවින් ඊට එරෙහිව නිල මට්ටමෙන් හෝ පෞද්ගලික මට්ටමෙන් නඩු කටයුත්තක් පවත්වාගෙන යා නොහැකි බවත්ය. ඒ අනුව මෙම පෙත්සමේ වගඋත්තරකරු වශයෙන් නම් කර සිටින ජනාධිපතිවරයා නිදහස් කළ යුතුව ඇති බව ද අතිරේක සොලිසිටර් ජනරාල්වරයා වැඩිදුරටත් අධිකරණයට දැනුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "ඉදිරිපත් වූ කරුණු සැලකිල්ලට ගත් අධිකරණය මෙහි නියෝගය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කිරීම පසුවට කල් තබන බවට දැනුම් දුන්නේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාස්කු ප්‍රහාරය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලුවිහාරේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රියන්ත ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞම්‍ය ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුරෙයි රාජා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාමිණී අමරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුරේන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සාලිය පීරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශමිල් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැල්කම් කාදිනල් රංජිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාලියා පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රියන්ත නාවන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "35 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "අතිරේක සොලිසිටර් ජනරාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஈஸ்டர் தாக்குதல்: பொறுப்புக்கூறலில் இருந்து ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் நீக்கப்படுவாரா இல்லையா?: முடிவு காலதாமதமானது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு தாக்குதல் தவிர்க்க முடியாதது தொடர்பாக தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ள அடிப்படை உரிமை மீறல் மனுக்களில் பிரதிவாதியாக குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ள தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் உத்தரவை அறிவிப்பதை ஏழு நீதிபதிகள் கொண்ட அமர்வு இன்று (02) ஒத்திவைத்தது. அந்த மனுக்களில் எதிர்மனுதாரராக இருந்து நீக்க வேண்டும்.",
        "இந்த மனுக்களை பிரதம நீதியரசர் ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய, புவனேகா அலுவிஹாரே, பிரியந்த ஜயவர்தன, எல். டி. பி. தெஹிதெனிய, மைல்ட் பெர்னாண்டோ, எஸ். துரைராஜா மற்றும் காமினி அமரசேகர ஆகியோர் அடங்கிய உச்ச நீதிமன்ற அமர்வு முன்னிலையில் இன்று (02) இந்த விடயங்கள் விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக்கொள்ளப்பட்டன.",
        "இந்த வழக்கு விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக்கொள்ளப்பட்ட போது, ​​முன்னாள் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பிரதிவாதியாக குறிப்பிடப்பட்டு தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதியாக தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதால், பிரதிவாதியான ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க சார்பில் ஆஜரான சட்டத்தரணி சுரேன் பெர்னாண்டோ, நீதிமன்றத்திற்கு அறிவித்தார். இந்த மனுக்களில் அவரை எதிர்மனுதாரராக நீக்க வேண்டும்.",
        "இதற்கு எதிர்ப்புத் தெரிவித்த இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி சாலியா பீரிஸ், அரசியலமைப்பின் 19ஆவது திருத்தத்தின் பிரகாரம் சிவில் மற்றும் குற்றவியல் வழக்குகளில் மாத்திரமே ஜனாதிபதிக்கு விலக்குரிமை உள்ளதாகவும், இந்த மனுக்கள் அடிப்படை உரிமை மனுக்கள் என்பதால் தற்போதுள்ள அவர் மீதான வழக்குகள் தொடர வேண்டும்",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் சட்டத்தரணி சாலியா பீரிஸின் உண்மைகளுடன் தாம் உடன்படுவதாகவும், அதனடிப்படையில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு எதிரான வழக்கை தொடருமாறும் கொழும்பு பேராயர் மல்கம் கர்தினால் ரஞ்சித்துக்காக நீதிமன்றத்தில் ஆஜரான ஜனாதிபதியின் சட்டத்தரணி ஷமில் பெரேரா தெரிவித்தார். .",
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் 35 (1) பிரிவின் கீழ் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு விலக்குரிமை உள்ளதால், அவருக்கு எதிராக உத்தியோகபூர்வ அல்லது தனிப்பட்ட மட்டத்தில் வழக்குத் தொடர முடியாது என ஆளுநர் நாயகம் சார்பில் நீதிமன்றில் ஆஜரான மேலதிக சொலிசிட்டர் ஜெனரல் பிரியந்த நவன தெரிவித்தார். இதன்படி, இந்த மனுவில் பிரதிவாதியாக குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ள ஜனாதிபதியை விடுவிக்குமாறு மேலதிக சொலிசிட்டர் ஜெனரல் நீதிமன்றத்திற்கு மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட உண்மைகளை கருத்திற்கொண்ட நீதிமன்றம், உத்தரவு அறிவிப்பை பின்னர் ஒத்திவைப்பதாக அறிவித்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஈஸ்டர் தாக்குதல்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலுவிஹாரே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரியந்த ஜயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லேசான பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துரை ராஜா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமினி அமரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுரேன் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாலியா பிரிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஷமில் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மால்கம் கார்டினல் ரஞ்சித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாலியா பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரியந்த நவன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுரை 35",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "கூடுதல் சொலிசிட்டர் ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}