{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132175",
  "time_ut": 1658674605,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ரணிலின் ஆலோசகராகிறார் காமினி செனரத்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Gamini Senarath becomes Ranil's advisor",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "It is learned that former Presidential Secretary Kamini Senarath will be appointed as an advisor to President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Kamini Senarath served as Presidential Secretary during the tenure of Ranil Wickremesinghe as Acting President and during the tenure of former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa.",
        "Following Ranil Wickremesinghe's inauguration as the 8th Executive President and the appointment of Saman Ekanayake as his secretary, it is understood that the President has decided to appoint Kamini Senarat, a 35-year civil service officer, as an advisor.",
        "It is noteworthy that Kamini Senarath has a long experience of serving as President's Secretary and Prime Minister's Secretary."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gamini Senarath",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Presidential",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kamini Senarath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kamini Senarath",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kamini Senarat",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "35-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kamini Senarath",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගාමිණී සෙනරත් රනිල්ගේ උපදේශක වෙයි",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාමිණී සෙනරත් මහතා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ උපදේශකවරයෙකු ලෙස පත්කිරීමට නියමිත බව දැනගන්නට ඇත.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති ධූරය දරන සමයේ සහ හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ පාලන සමයේ ජනාධිපති ලේකම් ලෙස කාමිණී සෙනරත් මහතා කටයුතු කළේය.",
        "8 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා දිවුරුම් දීමත් සමඟ සමන් ඒකනායක මහතා ලේකම්වරයා ලෙස පත්කිරීමත් සමඟ වසර 35ක සිවිල් සේවා නිලධාරිනියක් වන කාමිණී සෙනරත් මහත්මිය උපදේශක තනතුරකට පත් කිරීමට ජනාධිපතිවරයා තීරණය කර ඇති බව දැනගන්නට ඇත.",
        "කාමිණී සෙනරත් මහතා ජනාධිපති ලේකම් සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ලේකම්වරයා ලෙස දීර්ඝ කාලයක් කටයුතු කර තිබීම විශේෂත්වයකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගාමිණී සෙනරත්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාමිණී සෙනරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාමිණී සෙනරත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාමිණී සෙනරත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 35",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාමිණී සෙනරත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரணிலின் ஆலோசகராகிறார் காமினி செனரத்",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி செயலர் காமினி செனரத்,  ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் ஆலோசகராக நியமிக்கப்படவுள்ளதாக அறிய முடிகிறது.",
        "ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக இருந்த காலப்பகுதியிலும், முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் காலப்பகுதியிலும் ஜனாதிபதி செயலராக காமினி செனரத் கடமையாற்றியிருந்தார்.",
        "8 ஆவது நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பதவியேற்றதும் அவரது செயலராக  சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க நியமிக்கப்பட்டதை தொடர்ந்து, 35 வருட கால  அரச நிர்வாக சேவை அதிகாரியான காமினி செனரத்தை ஆலோசகராக நியமித்துக்கொள்ள ஜனாதிபதி தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக அறிய முடிகிறது.",
        "காமினி செனரத், ஜனாதிபதி செயலராகவும், பிரதமரின் செயலராகவும் கடமையாற்றிய நீண்ட அனுபவம் உடையவர் என்பது குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "காமினி செனரத்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமினி செனரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காமினி செனரத்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமினி செனரத்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "35-ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காமினி செனரத்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}