{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/කෝටි-17ක-කේරළ-ගංජා-සමග-02ක්-මාට්ටූ/11-395605",
  "time_ut": 1658380730,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කෝටි 17ක කේරළ ගංජා සමග 02ක් මාට්ටූ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "02 killed with Kerala ganja worth 17 crores",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Navy says that two suspects were arrested yesterday (20th) along with 575 kilos of Kerala Ganja worth over 172 million rupees along with 600 grams of Kerala Ganja worth over 172 million rupees in the sea area off old Kasiruna Veralathira in Jaffna Karainagar area.",
        "A group of officers belonging to the Northern Naval Command launched a special search operation in the sea off the old Kasurina beach in Karainagar, where a suspicious dinghy was spotted and the vessel was chased and raided.",
        "There, 575 kilos of 600 grams of Kerala ganja were found in 17 parcels hidden in the dinghy and the Navy took steps to arrest two suspects who were driving the dinghy.",
        "The traffickers have been arrested while bringing these Kerala ganja stocks from India by sea to sell to other parts of the island.",
        "The arrested suspects, aged 42 and 51, are residents of Jaffna Madagall areas and the Navy added that they have taken steps to hand over the suspects and the Kerala Ganja stock to Kites Police for further investigations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kerala",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "17",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "575",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala Ganja",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 172 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "600 grams",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala Ganja",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 172 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kasiruna Veralathira",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna Karainagar",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Northern Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kasurina beach",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karainagar",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "575",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "600 grams",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "42",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "51",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna Madagall",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala Ganja",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කෝටි 17ක කේරළ ගංජා සමග 02ක් මාට්ටූ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "යාපනය කරෙයිනගර් ප්‍රදේශයේ පැරණි කසිරුණා වෙරලතීරයට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ මුහුදු තීරයේදී රුපියල් මිලියන 172 කට අධික වටිනාකමින් යුතු කේරල ගංජා කිලෝ 575 ග්‍රෑම් 600 ක ප්‍රමාණයක් සමග සැකකරුවන් දෙදෙනෙකු ඊයේ (20දා)  අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බවට නාවික හමුදාව පවසයි.",
        "උතුරු නාවික විධානයට අයත් නිලධාරීන් පිරිසක් විසින් කරෙයිනගර් පැරණි කසුරිනා වෙරල තීරයට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ මුහුදු තීරයේදී විශේෂ සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමක් දියත් කරන ලද අතර එහිදී සැකකටයුතු ඩිංගි යාත්‍රාවක් නිරීක්ෂණය වීමෙන් අනතරුව අදාල යාත්‍රාව පසුපස හඹා ගොස් වැටලීම සිදුකරන ලදි.",
        "එහිදී ඩිංගි යාත්‍රාව තුල සඟවා තිබූ පාර්සල් 17 ක කේරල ගංජා කිලෝ 575 ග්‍රෑම් 600 ක ප්‍රමාණයක් තිබී සොයාගනු ලැබූ අතර ඩිංගි යාත්‍රාව පැදවූ සැකකරුවන් දෙදෙනෙකුද අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට නාවික හමුදාව පියවර ගන්නා ලදි.",
        "මෙම කේරල ගංජා තොගයන් ඉන්දියාවේ සිට මුහුදු මාර්ගයෙන් රැගෙනවිත් දිවයිනේ වෙනත් ප්‍රදේශයන් වෙතට අලෙවි කිරීම සඳහා රැගෙන එමින් සිටයදී ජාවාරම් කරුවන් මෙලෙස අත්අඩංගුවට පත්ව ඇත.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරුවන් අවුරුදු 42 ක් සහ 51 යන වයස්හි පසුවන යාපනය මාදගල් ප්‍රදේශයන්හි පදිංචිකරුවන් වන අතර සැකකරුවන් සහ කේරලගංජා තොගයන් වැඩිදුර පරික්ෂණ කටයුතු සඳහා කයිට්ස් පොලීසියට භාරදීමට පියවර ගත් බවට නාවික හමුදාව වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කේරල",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "17",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "575",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරළ ගංජා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 172 ඉක්මවයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ග්රෑම් 600 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරළ ගංජා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 172 ඉක්මවයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කසිරුන වෙරලතිර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය කරෙයිනගර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උතුරු නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කසුරිනා වෙරළ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කරෙයිනගර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "575",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ග්රෑම් 600 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "42",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "51",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය මඩගල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරළ ගංජා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "17 கோடி பெறுமதியான கேரள கஞ்சாவுடன் 02 பேர் பலி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "யாழ்ப்பாணம் காரைநகர் பகுதியில் உள்ள பழைய காசிருணை வெரளதிரை கடற்பரப்பில் வைத்து 172 மில்லியன் ரூபா பெறுமதியான 575 கிலோ கேரள கஞ்சா மற்றும் 172 மில்லியன் ரூபா பெறுமதியான 600 கிராம் கேரளா கஞ்சாவுடன் இரண்டு சந்தேகநபர்கள் நேற்று (20) கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக கடற்படை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "வடக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளைக்கு உட்பட்ட அதிகாரிகள் குழு காரைநகர் பழைய கசுரினா கடற்கரைக்கு அப்பால் உள்ள கடலில் சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான டிங்கி படகு ஒன்று கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டு கப்பல் துரத்திச் சென்று சோதனையிட்டது.",
        "அங்கு டிங்கி படகில் மறைத்து வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த 17 பார்சல்களில் 575 கிலோ 600 கிராம் கேரள கஞ்சா கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டதுடன், டிங்கி படகு ஓட்டிச் சென்ற இரு சந்தேக நபர்களை கைது செய்ய கடற்படையினர் நடவடிக்கை எடுத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்த கேரளா கஞ்சாவை இந்தியாவில் இருந்து கடல் மார்க்கமாக கொண்டு வந்து தீவின் மற்ற பகுதிகளுக்கு விற்பனை செய்யும் போதே கடத்தல்காரர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேகநபர்கள் 42 மற்றும் 51 வயதுடைய யாழ்ப்பாணம் மடகல் பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள் எனவும், சந்தேகநபர்கள் மற்றும் கேரள கஞ்சாவை மேலதிக விசாரணைகளுக்காக கைட்ஸ் பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்க நடவடிக்கை எடுத்துள்ளதாகவும் கடற்படையினர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கேரளா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "17",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "575",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரள கஞ்சா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "172 மில்லியனுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "600 கிராம்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரள கஞ்சா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "172 மில்லியனுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கசிருன வெரலதிர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாணம் காரைநகர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கசுரினா கடற்கரை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காரைநகர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "575",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "600 கிராம்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "42",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "51",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாணம் மடகல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரள கஞ்சா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}