{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/25/ranjan-sends-an-affidavit-apologizing-for-contempt-of-court/",
  "time_ut": 1661423820,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ranjan sends an affidavit apologizing for contempt of court",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ranjan sends an affidavit apologizing for contempt of court",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Former State Minister Ranjan Ramanayake who is serving time for contempt of court apologized to the court via an affidavit on Thursday (25).",
        "The affidavit produced to the court on Thursday (25) notes that Ranjan Ramanayake apologizes to the court with regard to both contempt of court cases filed against him.",
        "It added that Ranjan Ramanayake accepts that his statement was wrong, and it caused disrespect to the Chief Justice and the Legal Fraternity.",
        "Ranjan Ramanayake's affidavit also says that his statements were untrue, and he would withdraw those comments, and would not make such comments in the future",
        "Deputy Police Chief testifies in probe on assault on journalists",
        "Multiple unapproved Fuel Storage Tanks at business premises – Kanchana",
        "Senior Citizen beaten to death with motorcycle helmet in Kandana"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranjan",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Legal Fraternity",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fuel Storage Tanks",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Citizen",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandana",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සමාව ඉල්ලා රන්ජන් දිවුරුම් ප්‍රකාශයක් එවයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමේ චෝදනාව මත බන්ධනාගාර ගතව සිටින හිටපු රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය රන්ජන් රාමනායක බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (25) දිවුරුම් ප්‍රකාශයක් මගින් අධිකරණයෙන් සමාව අයැද සිටියේය.",
        "තමාට එරෙහිව පවරා ඇති අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමේ නඩු දෙකම සම්බන්ධයෙන් රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා අධිකරණයෙන් සමාව ඉල්ලා සිටින බව බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (25) අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කළ දිවුරුම් ප්‍රකාශයේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "තමන් කළ ප්‍රකාශය වැරදි බව රන්ජන් රාමනායක පිළිගන්නා බවත්, එය අගවිනිසුරුවරියට සහ නීති සහෝදරත්වයට අගෞරවයක් වීමට හේතු වූ බවත් එහි වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් වේ.",
        "තමන් කරන ප්‍රකාශ අසත්‍ය බවත්, එම අදහස් ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගන්නා බවත්, මින් ඉදිරියට එවැනි ප්‍රකාශ සිදු නොකරන බවත් රන්ජන් රාමනායක දිවුරුම් ප්‍රකාශයේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහරදීමේ සිද්ධියේ විමර්ශනයේදී නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති සාක්ෂි දෙයි",
        "ව්‍යාපාරික ස්ථානවල අනුමත නොකළ ඉන්ධන ගබඩා ටැංකි කිහිපයක් - කාංචන",
        "කඳානේදී ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පුරවැසියෙකු යතුරුපැදි හිස්වැස්මකින් පහරදී ඝාතනය කරයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රන්ජන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නීති සහෝදරත්වය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායකගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්ධන ගබඩා ටැංකි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචනා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුරවැසියා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කඳාන",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நீதிமன்ற அவமதிப்புக்கு மன்னிப்பு கேட்டு ரஞ்சன் பிரமாணப் பத்திரம் அனுப்பினார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); நீதிமன்ற அவமதிப்பு வழக்கில் தண்டனை பெற்று வரும் முன்னாள் இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க வியாழன் (25) வாக்குமூலம் மூலம் நீதிமன்றில் மன்னிப்பு கோரினார்.",
        "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க தமக்கு எதிராக தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட இரண்டு நீதிமன்ற அவமதிப்பு வழக்குகள் தொடர்பாக நீதிமன்றில் மன்னிப்பு கோருவதாக வியாழக்கிழமை (25) நீதிமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்ட வாக்குமூலத்தில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க தனது அறிக்கை தவறானது என்பதை ஏற்றுக்கொண்டதாகவும், அது பிரதம நீதியரசர் மற்றும் சட்டத்துறைக்கு அவமரியாதையை ஏற்படுத்தியதாகவும் அதில் மேலும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவின் வாக்குமூலத்தில் அவர் கூறியது உண்மைக்குப் புறம்பானது என்றும், அந்தக் கருத்துக்களைத் திரும்பப் பெறுவதாகவும், எதிர்காலத்தில் அவ்வாறான கருத்துக்களை வெளியிடப் போவதில்லை என்றும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மீதான தாக்குதல் தொடர்பான விசாரணையில் பிரதிப் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் சாட்சியமளித்தார்",
        "வணிக வளாகத்தில் பல அங்கீகரிக்கப்படாத எரிபொருள் சேமிப்பு தொட்டிகள் - காஞ்சனா",
        "கந்தானையில் மூத்த பிரஜை ஒருவர் மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் ஹெல்மெட்டால் அடித்து கொலை"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரஞ்சன்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சட்ட சகோதரத்துவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "எரிபொருள் சேமிப்பு தொட்டிகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குடிமகன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கந்தனை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}