{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/No-action-against-arrested-undergrads-under-PTA-Govt-assures/108-244071",
  "time_ut": 1661933208,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "No action against arrested undergrads under PTA: Govt. assures",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "No action against arrested undergrads under PTA: Govt. assures",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The government today assured that the group of university students who were arrested yesterday during a protest would not be dealt with Prevention of Terrorism Act (PTA).",
        "Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena gave this assurance in response to a question raised by Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa.",
        "The Opposition Leader said a group of 25 university students of the Inter University Student Federation (IUSF) have been arrested during a protest and questioned as to whether they would be detained under PTA.",
        "He said university students had not caused any damages to state or private property and that they had only exercised their right to protest.",
        "\"The government has unleashed state terrorism against the protesters. Have people been scrapped of their political rights, right to dissent? he questioned. The Prime Minister said the government was not hoping to take action against the arrested students inder PTA and that action would be taken against them under the general laws. (Ajith Siriwardana and Yohan Perera)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "PTA",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Inter University Student Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Siriwardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yohan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත යටතේ අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් උපාධිධාරීන්ට එරෙහිව ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයක් නැත: රජය සහතික කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "විරෝධතාවයක් අතරතුර ඊයේ අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල සිසුන් පිරිසට ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත (PTA) සම්බන්ධයෙන් ක්‍රියා නොකරන බවට රජය අද සහතික විය.",
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ඇසූ ප්‍රශ්නයකට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා මෙම සහතිකය ලබා දුන්නේය.",
        "විරෝධතාවයක් අතරතුර අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බලමණ්ඩලයේ (අවිශිබම) විශ්වවිද්‍යාල සිසුන් 25 දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් කණ්ඩායමක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති බව පැවසූ විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා ඔවුන්ව ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත යටතේ රඳවා ගන්නේ දැයි ප්‍රශ්න කළේය.",
        "විශ්වවිද්‍යාල සිසුන් රාජ්‍ය හෝ පෞද්ගලික දේපළවලට කිසිදු හානියක් සිදු කර නොමැති බවත්, ඔවුන් කළේ විරෝධතා දැක්වීමේ අයිතිය භාවිත කිරීම පමණක් බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "\"ආණ්ඩුව විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට එරෙහිව රාජ්‍ය ත්‍රස්තවාදය මුදා හැර තිබේ. මිනිසුන්ගේ දේශපාලන අයිතිවාසිකම්, විරුද්ධ වීමට ඇති අයිතිය ඉවත් කර තිබේද?\" ඔහු ප්‍රශ්න කළේය. අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සිසුන්ට එරෙහිව ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත යටතේ ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගැනීමට රජය බලාපොරොත්තු නොවන බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය. සාමාන්‍ය නීතිය යටතේ ඔවුන්ට එරෙහිව ගෙන ඇත.(අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන සහ යොහාන් පෙරේරා)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "PTA",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යොහාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பயங்கரவாத தடைச்சட்டத்தின் கீழ் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட இளங்கலை மாணவர்கள் மீது நடவடிக்கை இல்லை: அரசு உறுதியளிக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தின் போது நேற்று கைது செய்யப்பட்ட பல்கலைக்கழக மாணவர்கள் குழு மீது பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டம் (PTA) கையாளப்பட மாட்டாது என அரசாங்கம் இன்று உறுதியளித்துள்ளது.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச எழுப்பிய கேள்விக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் போதே பிரதமர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தன மேற்கண்டவாறு உறுதியளித்தார்.",
        "அனைத்து பல்கலைக்கழக மாணவர் சம்மேளனத்தின் (IUSF) 25 பேர் கொண்ட பல்கலைக்கழக மாணவர்கள் போராட்டத்தின் போது கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தெரிவித்த எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் அவர்கள் பயங்கரவாத தடைச்சட்டத்தின் கீழ் தடுத்து வைக்கப்படுவார்களா என கேள்வி எழுப்பியுள்ளார்.",
        "பல்கலைக்கழக மாணவர்கள் அரச அல்லது தனியார் சொத்துக்களுக்கு எவ்வித சேதமும் ஏற்படுத்தவில்லை எனவும், ஆர்ப்பாட்டம் செய்வதற்கான உரிமையை மாத்திரமே அவர்கள் பயன்படுத்தியதாகவும் அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"போராட்டக்காரர்களுக்கு எதிராக அரசு அரச பயங்கரவாதத்தை கட்டவிழ்த்து விட்டது. மக்களின் அரசியல் உரிமைகள், கருத்து வேறுபாடு உரிமைகள் பறிக்கப்பட்டதா?\" என்று அவர் கேள்வி எழுப்பினார். கைது செய்யப்பட்ட மாணவர்கள் மீது பயங்கரவாத தடைச்சட்டத்தின் கீழ் நடவடிக்கை எடுக்க அரசாங்கம் நம்பிக்கை இல்லை என்றும், நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்படும் என்றும் பிரதமர் கூறினார். பொதுச் சட்டங்களின் கீழ் அவர்களுக்கு எதிராக நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.(அஜித் சிறிவர்தன மற்றும் யோஹான் பெரேரா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "PTA",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோஹான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}