{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78666",
  "time_ut": 1658343960,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ranil Wickremesinghe Sworn in as 8th Executive President of Sri Lanka;Old cabinet to continue until opposition ‘ready’ to cooperate in all-party govt;Dinesh Gunawardena Likely to be Prime Ministe",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ranil Wickremesinghe Sworn in as 8th Executive President of Sri Lanka;Old cabinet to continue until opposition ‘ready’ to cooperate in all-party govt;Dinesh Gunawardena Likely to be Prime Ministe",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe, who was sworn in President of Sri Lanka on Thursday, is expected to appoint long-time Rajapaksa loyalist and senior politician Dinesh Gunawardena as Prime Minister, a source close to the President’s office told  The Hindu.",
        "Further, Mr. Wickremesinghe will continue with the last-appointed Cabinet until Opposition parties are “ready to cooperate” in an all-party government, the source said, requesting anonymity.",
        "President Wickremesinghe, who faces fierce public criticism for joining the discredited Rajapaksa government earlier, has invited all parties to join his government to combat the national economic crisis, which set off political upheaval and led to changes at the island nation’s helm. Opposition parties are yet to signal their willingness.",
        "Following a party leaders’ meeting on Thursday, Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa said in a tweet: “Met with President @RW_UNP [Ranil Wickremesinghe] at the party leaders’ meeting today. Had a cordial and frank exchange of ideas. Reiterated the opposition’s determination to provide constructive support to avert misery and disaster.”",
        "Mr. Premadasa said he proposed to strengthen the committee system in Parliament to achieve national consensus “rather than dishing out ministerial portfolios to political opportunists resulting in a drain of scarce national resources.”",
        "Mr. Wickremesinghe, who served as Prime Minister — his sixth stint in the office — since May and Acting President more recently, rose to Presidencyafter winning a key parliamentary vote on Wednesday, following mass protests that ousted Gotabaya Rajapaksa from the country’s highest office last week. The deposed leader fled the country and is now said to be in Singapore."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe Sworn",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "8th",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka;Old",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "Gunawardena Likely",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "@RW_UNP",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "sixth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Presidencyafter",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ 8 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දෙයි; සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවට සහයෝගය දැක්වීමට විපක්ෂය සූදානම් වන තුරු පැරණි කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය ඉදිරියට; දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධනට අගමැති වීමට ඉඩ තිබේ.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දුන් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා දීර්ඝ කාලීන රාජපක්ෂ හිතවාදියෙකු මෙන්ම ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ දේශපාලනඥයෙකු වූ දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස පත් කරනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කරන බව ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයට සමීප මූලාශ්‍රයක් ද හින්දු පුවත්පතට පැවසීය.",
        "තවද, සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් තුළ විරුද්ධ පක්ෂ \"සහයෝගීව කටයුතු කිරීමට සූදානම්\" වන තුරු වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අවසන් වරට පත් කරන ලද කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය සමඟ දිගටම කටයුතු කරනු ඇති බව එම මූලාශ්‍රය විසින් නිර්නාමිකභාවය ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "මීට පෙර අපකීර්තිමත් රාජපක්ෂ රජයට එක්වීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් දැඩි මහජන විවේචනවලට මුහුණ දෙන ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ, දේශපාලන පෙරළියකට තුඩු දුන් සහ දිවයිනේ සුක්කානම වෙනස් කිරීමට තුඩු දුන් ජාතික ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට එරෙහිව සටන් කිරීමට තම රජයට එක්වන ලෙස සියලු පාර්ශවයන්ට ආරාධනා කර තිබේ. විරුද්ධ පක්ෂ තවමත් ඔවුන්ගේ කැමැත්ත සංඥා කර නැත.",
        "බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා පැවති පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමකින් අනතුරුව විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ, “අද පැවති පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදී ජනාධිපති @RW_UNP [රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ] හමුවිය. සුහදව හා අවංකව අදහස් හුවමාරු කර ගත්තා. දුක්ඛිත හා ව්යසනයන් වළක්වා ගැනීම සඳහා ඵලදායී සහාය ලබා දීමට විපක්ෂයේ අධිෂ්ඨානය නැවත අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ජාතික සම්මුතිය සාක්ෂාත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කාරක සභා ක්‍රමය ශක්තිමත් කිරීමට තමන් යෝජනා කළේ “දේශපාලන අවස්ථාවාදීන්ට අමාත්‍ය ධූර බෙදා හැරීමට වඩා හිඟ ජාතික සම්පත් කාණුවක් වන” බවයි.",
        "පසුගිය සතියේ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා රටේ ඉහළම තනතුරෙන් නෙරපා හරින ලද මහජන විරෝධතාවලින් පසුව, මැයි මාසයේ සිට සහ වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති ධුරයේ හයවන වරටත් - අගමැති ලෙස කටයුතු කළ වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා, බදාදා ප්‍රධාන පාර්ලිමේන්තු ඡන්දයකින් ජයග්‍රහණය කිරීමෙන් පසු ජනාධිපති ධුරයට පත් විය. . බලයෙන් පහකළ නායකයා රටින් පැනගොස් දැන් සිංගප්පූරුවේ සිටින බව පැවසේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ දිවුරුම් දෙයි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "8 වැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව; පැරණි",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "ගුණවර්ධන විය හැකිය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "@RW_UNP",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය වන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති පදවියෙන් පසු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் 8வது நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரம் கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பதவியேற்றார்; அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கத்திற்கு ஒத்துழைக்க எதிர்க்கட்சி தயாராகும் வரை பழைய அமைச்சரவை தொடரும்; தினேஷ் குணவர்தன பிரதமராக வாய்ப்பு",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை அதிபராக வியாழன் அன்று பதவியேற்ற ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கே, நீண்டகால ராஜபக்சே விசுவாசியும் மூத்த அரசியல்வாதியுமான தினேஷ் குணவர்தனவை பிரதமராக நியமிப்பார் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது என்று ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலக வட்டாரம் தி ஹிந்துவிடம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மேலும், அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கத்தில் எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் \"ஒத்துழைக்கத் தயாராக\" இருக்கும் வரை, திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்க கடைசியாக நியமிக்கப்பட்ட அமைச்சரவையில் தொடர்வார் என்று அந்த வட்டாரம் தெரிவித்தது.",
        "முன்னதாக ராஜபக்ச அரசாங்கத்தில் இணைந்து கொண்டதற்காக கடுமையான பொது விமர்சனங்களை எதிர்கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க, அரசியல் எழுச்சியை ஏற்படுத்திய மற்றும் தீவு தேசத்தின் தலைமையில் மாற்றங்களுக்கு வழிவகுத்த தேசிய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை எதிர்த்து தனது அரசாங்கத்தில் சேருமாறு அனைத்து கட்சிகளையும் அழைத்துள்ளார். எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் தங்கள் விருப்பத்தை இன்னும் தெரிவிக்கவில்லை.",
        "வியாழன் அன்று நடைபெற்ற கட்சித் தலைவர்களின் கூட்டத்தைத் தொடர்ந்து, எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச தனது டுவிட்டர் பதிவில், “இன்று நடைபெற்ற கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி @RW_UNP [ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க] அவர்களைச் சந்தித்தார். ஒரு அன்பான மற்றும் வெளிப்படையான கருத்து பரிமாற்றம் இருந்தது. துயரம் மற்றும் பேரழிவைத் தவிர்க்க ஆக்கபூர்வமான ஆதரவை வழங்க எதிர்க்கட்சிகளின் உறுதியை மீண்டும் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "\"அரசியல் சந்தர்ப்பவாதிகளுக்கு அமைச்சுப் பதவிகளை வழங்குவதற்குப் பதிலாக, பற்றாக்குறையான தேசிய வளங்களை வடிகட்டுவதற்குப் பதிலாக\" தேசிய ஒருமித்த கருத்தைப் பெறுவதற்காக நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் குழு அமைப்பைப் பலப்படுத்த தாம் முன்மொழிந்ததாக திரு. பிரேமதாச கூறினார்.",
        "கடந்த வாரம் நாட்டின் அதியுயர் பதவியில் இருந்து கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவை வெளியேற்றிய பாரிய ஆர்ப்பாட்டங்களைத் தொடர்ந்து, பிரதமராக பதவி வகித்த திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்க, மே மாதம் முதல், ஜனாதிபதி பதவியில் ஆறாவது தடவையாக பதவியேற்றார். . பதவி நீக்கம் செய்யப்பட்ட தலைவர் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறி தற்போது சிங்கப்பூரில் இருப்பதாக கூறப்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பதவியேற்றார்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "8வது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை;பழைய",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "குணவர்தன வாய்ப்புள்ளது",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "@RW_UNP",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு பின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}