{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/රාජපක්ෂලාගේ-කුණු-අදින-ලොරි-බවට-සජබ-කිසිවකු-පත්-වන්නෙ-නෑ/1-618121",
  "time_ut": 1660545475,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රාජපක්ෂලාගේ කුණු අදින ලොරි බවට සජබ කිසිවකු පත් වන්නෙ නෑ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "No one will become Rajapaksa's garbage truck",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Sajith Premadasa, the opposition leader, said that it was the Rajapaksa regime that brought the country to such a precipice, and that no one in Samagi Janbalawega will become the Rajapaksa's garbage truck.",
        "The opposition leader said that today the whole country is facing an economic socio-political tragedy, and the reason for this is that the people took the wrong path instead of the right path in two elections in 2019 and 2020.",
        "He said this while attending the Constituency Committee meeting organized by Rakwana Samagi Janabalawega's organizer Mr. BK Ariyawansa.",
        "The leader of the opposition said that the latest miracle happening in the bankrupt country is the all-party government and what the country needs is not a country that wears ministerial gifts and goes behind the posts.",
        "Mr. Sajith Premadasa, the opposition leader, further said that there is no solution as an election should be held immediately and the people's decision should be sought."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Rajapaksa",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Constituency Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rakwana Samagi Janabalawega's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "BK",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ariyawansa",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රාජපක්ෂලාගේ කුණු අදින ලොරි බවට සජබ කිසිවකු පත් වන්නෙ නෑ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රට මෙතරම් ප්‍රපාතයකට ඇද දැමුවේ  රාජපක්ෂ පාලනය බවත්, ඒ රාජපක්ෂලාගේ කුණු අදින කුණු ලොරි බවට සමගි ජනබලවේගයේ කිසිවකු පත් නොවන බවත් විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "අද මුළු රටම ආර්ථික සමාජ දේශපාලනික ඛේදවාචකයකට ලක්ව ඇති බවත්,ඊට හේතුව 2019 සහ 2020 මැතිවරණ දෙකකදී ජනතාව විසින් හරි පාර වෙනුවට වැරදි පාර උරා ගැනීමේ හේතුව බවත් විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "රක්වාන සමගි ජනබලවේගයේ සංවිධායක බී.කේ ආරියවංශ මහතා සංවිධානය කරනු ලැබූ ආසන බල මණ්ඩල රැස්වීමට එක්වෙමින්  ඔහු මේ බව කීවේය.",
        "බංකොලොත් වී ඇති රට තුළ දැන් සිදුවෙමින් පවතින අලුත්ම විජ්ජාව වන්නේ සර්වපාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩු ගුණ්ඩුව බවත්  රටට අවශ්‍ය වන්නේ ඇමති වරදාන පළඳවා ගනිමින් තනතුරු පිටුපස යන රටක් නොවන බවත් විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා එහිදී පැවසීය.",
        "දැන් වහාම සිදු කළ යුත්තේ මැතිවරණයක් පවත්වා ජනතා තීන්දුව විමසීම බැවින් ඉන් මෙහා විසඳුමක් නැතැයිද විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා තවදුරටත් කීවේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආසන කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රක්වාන සමගි ජනබලවේගගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.කේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරියවංශ",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ராஜபக்சவின் குப்பை வண்டியாக யாரும் மாற மாட்டார்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ராஜபக்ச ஆட்சிதான் நாட்டை இவ்வளவு அதலபாதாளத்திற்கு கொண்டு சென்றது என்றும், சமகி ஜனபலவேகவில் யாரும் ராஜபக்சவின் குப்பை வண்டியாக மாற மாட்டார்கள் என்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் திரு.சஜித் பிரேமதாச தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இன்று முழு நாடும் பொருளாதார சமூக அரசியல் அவலத்தை எதிர்நோக்கி வருவதாகவும், 2019 மற்றும் 2020 ஆகிய இரண்டு தேர்தல்களிலும் மக்கள் சரியான பாதைக்கு பதிலாக தவறான பாதையை எடுத்ததே இதற்குக் காரணம் என்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் கூறினார்.",
        "ரக்வான சமகி ஜனபலவேகவின் அமைப்பாளர் திரு.பி.கே.ஆரியவன்சவின் ஏற்பாட்டில் நடைபெற்ற தொகுதிக் குழுக் கூட்டத்தில் கலந்து கொண்ட போதே அவர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "வங்குரோத்து நாட்டில் நிகழும் அண்மைய அதிசயம் சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் எனவும் நாட்டுக்கு தேவை அமைச்சுப் பரிசுகளை அணிந்துகொண்டு பதவிக்குப் பின்னால் செல்லும் நாடு அல்ல எனவும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "உடனடியாக தேர்தலை நடத்தி மக்களின் தீர்வை பெற்றுக்கொள்ள வேண்டும் என எதிர்கட்சி தலைவர் திரு.சஜித் பிரேமதாச மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தொகுதிக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரக்வானா சமகி ஜனபாலவேகவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பி.கே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆரியவன்ச",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}