{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83381/second-phase-of-ol-paper-marking-temporarily-halted",
  "time_ut": 1656750540,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Second phase of O/L paper marking temporarily halted",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Second phase of O/L paper marking temporarily halted",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Department of Examinations has decided to temporarily call off the second phase of 2021 G.C.E. Ordinary Level paper marking due to the prevailing fuel crisis.",
        "A total of 517,496 candidates faced the exam, which was held from May 23 to June 01 at 3,844 centres island-wide. Some 407,129 of them are school candidates while 110,367 are private applicants.",
        "Meanwhile, Lanka IOC, the subsidiary of Indian Oil Corporation in Sri Lanka, said it has deployed bowser trucks from its terminal in Trincomalee to distribute fuel to 94 of its filling stations island-wide.",
        "Long queues are seen near Lanka IOC filling stations, as fuel volumes at Ceypetco filling stations have run dry."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Second",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department of Examinations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "517,496",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 23 to June 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,844",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Some 407,129",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "110,367",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lanka IOC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian Oil Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "94",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceypetco",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සාමාන්‍ය පෙළ ප්‍රශ්න පත්‍ර ලකුණු කිරීමේ දෙවන අදියර තාවකාලිකව නවතා ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "2021 අධ්‍යයන පොදු සහතික පත්‍ර දෙවන අදියර තාවකාලිකව අත්හිටුවීමට විභාග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව තීරණය කර තිබේ. පවතින ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් සාමාන්‍ය පෙළ ප්‍රශ්න පත්‍ර ලකුණු කිරීම.",
        "මැයි 23 සිට ජූනි 01 දක්වා දිවයින පුරා මධ්‍යස්ථාන 3,844කදී පැවති විභාගය සඳහා අයදුම්කරුවන් 517,496 දෙනෙකු මුහුණ දුන්හ. ඔවුන්ගෙන් 407,129 ක් පාසල් අයදුම්කරුවන් වන අතර 110,367 ක් පෞද්ගලික අයදුම්කරුවන් වේ.",
        "මේ අතර, ඉන්දියන් ඔයිල් කෝපරේෂන් හි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අනුබද්ධිත ලංකා IOC සමාගම පැවසුවේ, දිවයින පුරා පිහිටි ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් 94 කට ඉන්ධන බෙදා හැරීම සඳහා ත්‍රිකුණාමලයේ පිහිටි සිය පර්යන්තයේ සිට බවුසර් ට්‍රක් රථ යොදවා ඇති බවයි.",
        "ලංකා IOC ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් අසල දිගු පෝලිම් දක්නට ලැබේ, සිපෙට්කෝ පිරවුම්හල්වල ඉන්ධන පරිමාව සිඳී ගොස් ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙවැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "විභාග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "517,496 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 23 සිට ජූනි 01 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,844 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "407,129 පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "110,367 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා IOC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු තෙල් සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "94",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිපෙට්කෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "O/L தாள் குறியிடுதலின் இரண்டாம் கட்டம் தற்காலிகமாக நிறுத்தப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "2021 G.C.E இரண்டாம் கட்டத்தை தற்காலிகமாக நிறுத்துவதற்கு பரீட்சைகள் திணைக்களம் தீர்மானித்துள்ளது. நிலவும் எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடி காரணமாக சாதாரண தர தாள் குறியிடல்.",
        "மே 23 முதல் ஜூன் 01 வரை நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் 3,844 மையங்களில் நடைபெற்ற இந்த பரீட்சைக்கு மொத்தம் 517,496 பரீட்சார்த்திகள் முகம்கொடுத்தனர். அவர்களில் 407,129 பேர் பள்ளி மாணவர்கள் மற்றும் 110,367 பேர் தனியார் விண்ணப்பதாரர்கள்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், இலங்கையில் உள்ள இந்தியன் ஆயில் கார்ப்பரேஷனின் துணை நிறுவனமான லங்கா ஐஓசி, திருகோணமலையில் உள்ள அதன் முனையத்திலிருந்து பவுசர் டிரக்குகளை நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் உள்ள 94 எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையங்களுக்கு எரிபொருளை விநியோகித்துள்ளதாக தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "சிபெட்கோ நிரப்பு நிலையங்களில் எரிபொருள் அளவு வறண்டு போனதால், லங்கா ஐஓசி எரிபொருள் நிரப்பும் நிலையங்களுக்கு அருகில் நீண்ட வரிசைகள் காணப்படுகின்றன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டாவது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பரீட்சைகள் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "517,496",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 23 முதல் ஜூன் 01 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,844",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சில 407,129",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "110,367",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லங்கா ஐ.ஓ.சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன் ஆயில் கார்ப்பரேஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "94",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சைபெட்கோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}