{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/1924--පසුව-පොලිසියේ-සිදුවූ-වෙනස/11-396617",
  "time_ut": 1661443301,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "1924  පසුව පොලිසියේ සිදුවූ වෙනස",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The change in the police after 1924",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Two female Deputy Inspector Generals of Police have been appointed as the Chairmanship of the Governing Committee of the Police Savings Association and as Committee Secretary.",
        "The 95th general meeting of the association was held today, where these appointments were made. This association was established in 1924 and since its inception, senior DIGs and DIGs have been appointed as the chairman of the governing committee.",
        "However, for the first time, Deputy Inspector General of Police Padmini Weerasuriya has been appointed as the Chairman of the Governing Committee of the Police Savings Association and Deputy Inspector General of Police Renuka Jayasundara has been appointed as the Committee Secretary.",
        "Mr. Police Inspector N. Priyadarshana is the administrative secretary of this association and he is the first police officer to hold the position of administrative secretary."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "1924",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Police Savings Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "95th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1924",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Governing Committee of the Police Savings Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Deputy Inspector General of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Renuka Jayasundara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Police",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "N. Priyadarshana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "1924  පසුව පොලිසියේ සිදුවූ වෙනස",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පොලිස් ඉතිරි කිරිමේ සංගමයේ පාලන කමිටු සභාපතිත්වයට හා කමිටු ලේකම් තනතුරු වලට කාන්තා නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පතිවරියන් දෙදෙනෙක්  පත්ව තිබේ.",
        "එම සංගමය් 95 වැනි මහා සභා රැස්වීම අද පැවැති අතර එහිදී මෙම පත්වීම් සිදුකර තිබේ. මෙම සංගමය 1924දීී ආරම්භ කර ඇති අතර එය ආරම්භ කළ දා සිට පාලන කමිටු සභාපති තනතුරට ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පතිවරරු හා නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පතිවරු පත්වී ඇත.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් එම සංගමයේ ප්‍රථමවරට පොලිස් ඉතිරි කිරිමේ සංගමයේ පාලන කමිටු සභාපතිත්වයට නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති පද්මිණී වීරසූරිය  මහත්මියත්  කමිටු ලේකම් තනතුරට නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති  රේණුකා ජයසුන්දර මහත්මිය පත්ව තිබේ.",
        "මෙම සංගමයේ පාලන ලේකම් ලෙස පොලිස් පරීීක්ෂක එන්.ප්‍රියදර්ශන මහතා කටයුතු කරනඅතර එහි පාලන ලේකම් තනතුරට පත්වූ පළමු පොලිස් නිලධාරියා ඔහු වෙයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "1924",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් ඉතිරිකිරීමේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමිටුවක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "95 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1924",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් ඉතිරිකිරීමේ සංගමයේ පාලක කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රේණුකා ජයසුන්දර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමිටුවක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොලිසිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන් ප්‍රියදර්ශන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "1924க்குப் பிறகு காவல்துறையில் மாற்றம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "காவல்துறை சேமிப்புக் கழகத்தின் ஆட்சிக் குழுவின் தலைவராகவும், குழுச் செயலாளராகவும் இரு பெண் காவல் துணைக் கண்காணிப்பாளர்கள் நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்த நியமனங்கள் வழங்கப்பட்ட சங்கத்தின் 95வது பொதுக்குழு கூட்டம் இன்று நடைபெற்றது. இந்த சங்கம் 1924 இல் நிறுவப்பட்டது மற்றும் அதன் தொடக்கத்தில் இருந்து, மூத்த டிஐஜிக்கள் மற்றும் டிஐஜிக்கள் ஆளும் குழுவின் தலைவராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், பொலிஸ் சேமிப்புச் சங்கத்தின் ஆளும் குழுவின் தலைவராக முதன்முறையாக பிரதிப் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் பத்மினி வீரசூரியவும், குழுச் செயலாளராக பிரதிப் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் ரேணுகா ஜயசுந்தரவும் நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "திரு. பொலிஸ் பரிசோதகர் என்.பிரியதர்ஷனா இந்த சங்கத்தின் நிர்வாகச் செயலாளர் மற்றும் நிர்வாகச் செயலாளர் பதவியை வகிக்கும் முதல் பொலிஸ் அதிகாரி."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "1924",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "போலீஸ் சேமிப்பு சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "95வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1924",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காவல்துறை சேமிப்புக் கழகத்தின் ஆட்சிக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரதி பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரேணுகா ஜயசுந்தர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காவல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்.பிரியதர்ஷனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}