{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/24/g-l-thanks-india-for-extensive-support/",
  "time_ut": 1656075660,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "G.L. thanks India for extensive support",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "G.L. thanks India for extensive support",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Foreign Minister of Sri Lanka, Prof. G.L. Peiris held a bilateral discussion with the Minister of External Affairs of India Dr. S. Jaishankar on 23rd June on the sidelines of the CHOGM Summit in Kigali, Rwanda.",
        "Foreign Minister Peiris expressed his appreciation for the very extensive support extended to Sri Lanka by India at this time of difficulty.",
        "The Foreign Minister also mentioned that this assistance has helped Sri Lanka face this extremely challenging period, while the two Ministers also discussed future collaboration in a variety of fields.",
        "Committee probing recent riots obtains statement from fmr Army Commander"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "G.L.",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "External Affairs of India",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "23rd June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the CHOGM Summit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kigali",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rwanda",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "G.L. ඉන්දියාවට පුලුල් සහයෝගයට ස්තුති කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); රුවන්ඩාවේ කිගාලි නුවර පැවැත්වෙන CHOGM සමුළුවට සමගාමීව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදේශ අමාත්‍ය මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්. පීරිස් මහතා ජුනි 23 වන දින ඉන්දීය විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය ආචාර්ය එස්. ජයශංකර් මහතා සමඟ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සාකච්ඡාවක් පැවැත්වීය.",
        "මෙම දුෂ්කර අවස්ථාවේ ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබා දුන් පුළුල් සහයෝගය පිළිබඳව විදේශ අමාත්‍ය පීරිස් මහතා සිය ප්‍රසාදය පළ කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට මෙම අතිශය අභියෝගාත්මක කාල පරිච්ඡේදයට මුහුණ දීමට මෙම ආධාර උපකාර කර ඇති බව විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරයා සඳහන් කළ අතර, අමාත්‍යවරුන් දෙදෙනා විවිධ ක්ෂේත්‍රවල අනාගත සහයෝගීතාව පිළිබඳව ද සාකච්ඡා කළහ.",
        "පසුගියදා ඇති වූ කලහකාරී සිදුවීම් සොයා බලන කමිටුව Fmr යුධ හමුදාපතිගෙන් ප්‍රකාශයක් ලබා ගනී"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජී.එල්.",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාවේ විදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්. ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CHOGM සමුළුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිගාලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුවන්ඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "விரிவான ஆதரவிற்கு ஜி.எல். இந்தியாவுக்கு நன்றி",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கையின் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர், பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல். பீரிஸ், இந்திய வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் கலாநிதி எஸ். ஜெய்சங்கருடன் ஜூன் 23ஆம் திகதி ருவாண்டாவின் கிகாலியில் நடைபெற்ற பொதுநலவாய நாடுகளின் உச்சி மாநாட்டை ஒட்டி இருதரப்பு கலந்துரையாடலை நடத்தினார்.",
        "இந்த இக்கட்டான நேரத்தில் இந்தியா இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கிய விரிவான ஆதரவிற்கு வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் பீரிஸ் தனது பாராட்டுக்களை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த மிகவும் சவாலான காலகட்டத்தை எதிர்கொள்ள இந்த உதவி இலங்கைக்கு உதவியுள்ளதாக வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் குறிப்பிட்டார், அதே நேரத்தில் இரண்டு அமைச்சர்களும் பல்வேறு துறைகளில் எதிர்கால ஒத்துழைப்பு குறித்தும் விவாதித்தனர்.",
        "சமீபத்திய கலவரங்களை விசாரிக்கும் குழு எஃப்எம்ஆர் இராணுவத் தளபதியிடம் இருந்து அறிக்கையைப் பெறுகிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜி.எல்.",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியாவின் வெளிவிவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ். ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "23 ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CHOGM உச்சி மாநாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிகாலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ருவாண்டா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "G.L. thanks India for extensive support",
  "body_lines": [
    "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Foreign Minister of Sri Lanka, Prof. G.L. Peiris held a bilateral discussion with the Minister of External Affairs of India Dr. S. Jaishankar on 23rd June on the sidelines of the CHOGM Summit in Kigali, Rwanda.",
    "Foreign Minister Peiris expressed his appreciation for the very extensive support extended to Sri Lanka by India at this time of difficulty.",
    "The Foreign Minister also mentioned that this assistance has helped Sri Lanka face this extremely challenging period, while the two Ministers also discussed future collaboration in a variety of fields.",
    "Committee probing recent riots obtains statement from fmr Army Commander"
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "G.L. thanks India for extensive support",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Foreign Minister of Sri Lanka, Prof. G.L. Peiris held a bilateral discussion with the Minister of External Affairs of India Dr. S. Jaishankar on 23rd June on the sidelines of the CHOGM Summit in Kigali, Rwanda.",
        "Foreign Minister Peiris expressed his appreciation for the very extensive support extended to Sri Lanka by India at this time of difficulty.",
        "The Foreign Minister also mentioned that this assistance has helped Sri Lanka face this extremely challenging period, while the two Ministers also discussed future collaboration in a variety of fields.",
        "Committee probing recent riots obtains statement from fmr Army Commander"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "G.L.",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "External Affairs of India",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "23rd June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the CHOGM Summit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kigali",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rwanda",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "G.L. ඉන්දියාවට පුලුල් සහයෝගයට ස්තුති කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); රුවන්ඩාවේ කිගාලි නුවර පැවැත්වෙන CHOGM සමුළුවට සමගාමීව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදේශ අමාත්‍ය මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්. පීරිස් මහතා ජුනි 23 වන දින ඉන්දීය විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය ආචාර්ය එස්. ජයශංකර් මහතා සමඟ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සාකච්ඡාවක් පැවැත්වීය.",
        "මෙම දුෂ්කර අවස්ථාවේ ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබා දුන් පුළුල් සහයෝගය පිළිබඳව විදේශ අමාත්‍ය පීරිස් මහතා සිය ප්‍රසාදය පළ කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට මෙම අතිශය අභියෝගාත්මක කාල පරිච්ඡේදයට මුහුණ දීමට මෙම ආධාර උපකාර කර ඇති බව විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරයා සඳහන් කළ අතර, අමාත්‍යවරුන් දෙදෙනා විවිධ ක්ෂේත්‍රවල අනාගත සහයෝගීතාව පිළිබඳව ද සාකච්ඡා කළහ.",
        "පසුගියදා ඇති වූ කලහකාරී සිදුවීම් සොයා බලන කමිටුව Fmr යුධ හමුදාපතිගෙන් ප්‍රකාශයක් ලබා ගනී"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජී.එල්.",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාවේ විදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්. ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CHOGM සමුළුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිගාලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුවන්ඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "விரிவான ஆதரவிற்கு ஜி.எல். இந்தியாவுக்கு நன்றி",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கையின் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர், பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல். பீரிஸ், இந்திய வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் கலாநிதி எஸ். ஜெய்சங்கருடன் ஜூன் 23ஆம் திகதி ருவாண்டாவின் கிகாலியில் நடைபெற்ற பொதுநலவாய நாடுகளின் உச்சி மாநாட்டை ஒட்டி இருதரப்பு கலந்துரையாடலை நடத்தினார்.",
        "இந்த இக்கட்டான நேரத்தில் இந்தியா இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கிய விரிவான ஆதரவிற்கு வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் பீரிஸ் தனது பாராட்டுக்களை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த மிகவும் சவாலான காலகட்டத்தை எதிர்கொள்ள இந்த உதவி இலங்கைக்கு உதவியுள்ளதாக வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் குறிப்பிட்டார், அதே நேரத்தில் இரண்டு அமைச்சர்களும் பல்வேறு துறைகளில் எதிர்கால ஒத்துழைப்பு குறித்தும் விவாதித்தனர்.",
        "சமீபத்திய கலவரங்களை விசாரிக்கும் குழு எஃப்எம்ஆர் இராணுவத் தளபதியிடம் இருந்து அறிக்கையைப் பெறுகிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜி.எல்.",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியாவின் வெளிவிவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ். ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "23 ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CHOGM உச்சி மாநாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிகாலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ருவாண்டா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}