{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/නැතිවුන-පොතුයි-බුදු-පිළිමයකුයි-මා-ගාව:-දෙන්න-බයයි/1-619281",
  "time_ut": 1662293460,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "නැතිවුන පොතුයි බුදු පිළිමයකුයි මා ගාව: දෙන්න බයයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "I have lost bark and a Buddha statue: I am afraid to give",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President's Secretary Mr. Saman Ekanayake has handed over further investigation to the Secret Police regarding a phone call received by the Presidential Secretariat about a Buddha statue and a stock of books stolen from the residence of President Ranil Wickramasinghe.",
        "A call to the public telephone number of the President's office said that the Buddha statue and books were stolen on the day the President's house was set on fire and that they need to be returned.",
        "The person who made the phone call to the President's office said that keeping the stolen Buddha statue and books with them is a matter of fear and should be returned to the owner.",
        "The caller said that the Buddha statue and books are safe.",
        "He has said that he wants to call the President's Secretary and the official who took the call from the President's Office has handed over the message to the President's Secretary and handed over further investigations to the Secret Police."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Buddha",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Saman Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Secret Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Buddha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Buddha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Buddha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Secret Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නැතිවුන පොතුයි බුදු පිළිමයකුයි මා ගාව: දෙන්න බයයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ නිවසින් සොරා ගන්නා ලද බුදු පිළිමයක්,සහ පොත් පත් තොගයක් පිළිබඳ ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයට ලැබුණු දුරකථන ඇමතුමක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් වැඩිදුර පරීක්ෂණ කිරීම ජනාධිපති ලේකම් සමන් ඒකනායක මහතා විසින් රහස් පොලිසියට බාර දී තිබෙි .",
        "ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේ පොදු දුරකථන අංකයකට ලැබුණු ඇමතුමකින් පවසා ඇත්තේ ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ නිවස ගිනි තැබූ දින මෙම බුදු පිළිමය සහ පොත්පත් සොරා ගන්නා ලද බවත් එය නැවත ලබා දීමට අවශ්‍ය බවත්ය.",
        "සොරා ගන්නා ලද බුදු පිළිමය සහ පොත්පත් ළඟ තබා ගැනීම සිතට බියක් ගෙන දෙන කාරණයක් බැවින් නැවත ඒවා අයිතිකරුට ලබාදිය යුතු බව ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයට දුරකථන ඇමතුම ගත් තැනැත්තා පවසා තිබේ.",
        "බුදු පිළිමය සහ පොත්පත් සුරක්ෂිතව තිබෙන බවද දුරකථන ඇමතුම දුන් තැනැත්තා පවසා ඇත.",
        "තමාට ජනාධිපති ලේකම්වරයා ඇමතීමට අවශ්‍ය බව ඔහු පවසා ඇති අතර ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේ ඇමතුම ගත් නිලධරයා එම පණිවිඩය ජනාධිපති ලේකම්වරයාට සැල කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුව ඒ පිළිබඳ වැඩිදුර පරීක්ෂණ කටයුතු රහස් පොලිසියට බාර දී ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බුද්ධ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමන් ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රහස් පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුද්ධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බුද්ධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බුද්ධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බුද්ධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රහස් පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நான் மரப்பட்டையையும் புத்தர் சிலையையும் இழந்துவிட்டேன்: கொடுக்க நான் பயப்படுகிறேன்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் இல்லத்தில் இருந்து திருடப்பட்ட புத்தர் சிலை மற்றும் புத்தகங்கள் குறித்த தொலைபேசி அழைப்பு தொடர்பில் ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்திற்கு கிடைத்த தொலைபேசி அழைப்பு தொடர்பிலான மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை ஜனாதிபதி செயலாளர் திரு.சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க இரகசிய பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைத்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்கு தீ வைக்கப்பட்ட தினத்தில் புத்தர் சிலை மற்றும் புத்தகங்கள் திருடப்பட்டதாகவும், அவற்றை மீட்டுத்தருமாறும் ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகத்தின் பொது தொலைபேசி இலக்கத்திற்கு அழைப்பு விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "திருடப்பட்ட புத்தர் சிலை மற்றும் புத்தகங்களை தம்மிடம் வைத்திருப்பது அச்சமான விடயம் எனவும் அதனை உரிமையாளரிடம் மீள ஒப்படைக்க வேண்டும் எனவும் ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகத்திற்கு தொலைபேசி அழைப்பை மேற்கொண்ட நபர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "புத்தர் சிலை மற்றும் புத்தகங்கள் பத்திரமாக இருப்பதாக தொலைபேசியில் தெரிவித்தவர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி செயலாளருக்கு அழைப்பு விடுக்க விரும்புவதாகவும், ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்தில் இருந்து அழைப்பை பெற்றுக்கொண்ட அதிகாரி, ஜனாதிபதி செயலாளரிடம் கையளித்து மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை இரகசிய பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைத்துள்ளதாகவும் அவர் கூறியுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "புத்தர்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரகசிய போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புத்தர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புத்தர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புத்தர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரகசிய போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}