{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84283/sri-lanka-permits-much-disputed-chinese-research-vessel-to-dock",
  "time_ut": 1660389840,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka permits much-disputed Chinese research vessel to dock",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka permits much-disputed Chinese research vessel to dock",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs has allowed the Harbour Master to grant permission to the Chinese ballistic missile- and satellite-tracking vessel Yuan Wang 5 to dock at the Hambantota Port from August 16 - 22.",
        "Harbour Master Nimal P. Silva told Agence France-Presse (AFP) that he received clearance from the Foreign Ministry to let the ship to make a port call at Hambantota.",
        "“The diplomatic clearance was received by me today. We will work with the local agent appointed by the vessel to ensure logistics at the port,” he told AFP.",
        "It is reported that Colombo initially granted permission for the vessel to dock at Hambantota on July 12, a day before former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa fled the country giving in to months-long protests.",
        "According to AFP, the port officials have said the Chinese vessel was about 1,000km (620 miles) south-east of Sri Lanka as of Friday night (Aug 12) and was heading towards Hambantota.",
        "The much-disputed 730-foot-long ship was initially scheduled to dock at the Hambantota Port between August 11 and 17, however, Sri Lanka made a request from Beijing to defer the arrival.",
        "The request for deferment came after India voiced strong concerns on the matter and said it carefully monitors any developments having a bearing on its security and economic interests, and takes all necessary to safeguard them.",
        "China, in response to India’s concerns, said it hoped “relevant parties” would refrain from interfering with its legitimate maritime activities and stressed that it was “senseless to pressure” Colombo by citing the issue of security concerns.",
        "As diplomatic tensions were growing, Sri Lanka clarified that permission and clearance were given to the Chinese vessel for “replenishment”. The vessel will conduct satellite control and research tracking in the north-western part of the Indian Ocean region through August and September, the Sri Lankan government said further.",
        "Meanwhile, India on Friday (Aug 12) categorically rejected insinuation by China which claimed that Sri Lanka’s neighbour is pressuring the island nation over Chinese ballistic missile and satellite-tracking vessel’s planned visit to Hambantota.",
        "Amidst the row over the Chinese vessel, Sri Lanka allowed a Pakistani warship PNS Taimur to make a port call in Colombo on Friday. According to Sri Lanka Navy, this Pakistani-guided missile frigate built by Hudong-Zhonghua shipyard in Shanghai, is in Colombo for a formal visit."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harbour",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Hambantota Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 16 - 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nimal P. Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Agence France-Presse",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "months-long",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 1,000km",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "620 miles",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "730-foot-long",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "between August 11 and 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Ocean",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "September",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistani",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "PNS Taimur",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistani",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hudong-Zhonghua",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shanghai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බොහෝ මතභේදයට තුඩු දී ඇති චීන පර්යේෂණ යාත්‍රාවක් නැව්ගත කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අවසර දෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "චීනයේ බැලස්ටික් මිසයිල සහ චන්ද්‍රිකා ලුහුබැඳීමේ යාත්‍රාව වන යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 අගෝස්තු 16 සිට 22 දක්වා හම්බන්තොට වරායේ නැව්ගත කිරීමට අවසර ලබා දීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය විසින් Harbour Master වෙත අවසර ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "වරාය මාස්ටර් නිමල් පී සිල්වා මහතා Agence France-Presse (AFP) වෙත පැවසුවේ තමාට විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයෙන් අවසර ලැබී ඇති බව නෞකාවට හම්බන්තොට වරායට ඇමතීමට ඉඩ ලබා දුන් බවයි.",
        "“රාජ්‍යතාන්ත්‍රික අවසරය අද මට ලැබුණා. වරායේ සැපයුම් සහතික කිරීම සඳහා අපි යාත්‍රාව විසින් පත් කරන ලද දේශීය නියෝජිතයා සමඟ කටයුතු කරන්නෙමු, ”ඔහු AFP වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා මාස ගණනාවක් පුරා පැවති විරෝධතාවලට යටත්ව රටින් පැන යාමට දිනකට පෙර එනම් ජූලි 12 වැනිදා එම යාත්‍රාවට හම්බන්තොට නැංගුරම් ලෑමට කොළඹ මුලික අවසරය ලබාදුන් බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "AFP පුවත් සේවයට අනුව, චීන යාත්‍රාව සිකුරාදා (අගෝස්තු 12) රාත්‍රිය වන විට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ගිනිකොන දෙසින් කිලෝමීටර් 1,000 (සැතපුම් 620) පමණ දුරින් හම්බන්තොට දෙසට ගමන් කරමින් තිබූ බව වරාය නිලධාරීන් පවසා ඇත.",
        "බොහෝ මතභේදයට තුඩු දී ඇති අඩි 730 ක් දිග නෞකාව අගෝස්තු 11 සහ 17 අතර හම්බන්තොට වරායේ නැංගුරම් ලෑමට නියමිතව තිබූ නමුත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පැමිණීම කල් දමන ලෙස බීජිං වෙතින් ඉල්ලීමක් කළේය.",
        "කල්දැමීම සඳහා ඉල්ලීම ඉදිරිපත් වූයේ ඉන්දියාව මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් දැඩි කනස්සල්ල පළ කළ අතර එහි ආරක්ෂාව සහ ආර්ථික අවශ්‍යතා කෙරෙහි බලපාන ඕනෑම වර්ධනයක් ප්‍රවේශමෙන් නිරීක්ෂණය කරන බවත් ඒවා ආරක්ෂා කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය සියල්ල ගන්නා බවත් ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් පසුවය.",
        "චීනය, ඉන්දියාවේ උත්සුකයන්ට ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වමින්, “අදාළ පාර්ශ්වයන්” එහි නීත්‍යානුකූල නාවික කටයුතුවලට මැදිහත් වීමෙන් වළකිනු ඇතැයි තමන් බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව පැවසූ අතර, ආරක්‍ෂක ගැටලු මතුකරමින් කොළඹට බලපෑම් කිරීම තේරුමක් නැති බව අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික ආතතීන් වර්ධනය වන විට, චීන යාත්‍රාවට “නැවත පිරවීම” සඳහා අවසරය සහ අවසරය ලබා දුන් බව ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පැහැදිලි කළේය. මෙම යාත්‍රාව අගෝස්තු සහ සැප්තැම්බර් දක්වා ඉන්දියානු සාගර කලාපයේ වයඹ දිග ප්‍රදේශයේ චන්ද්‍රිකා පාලනය සහ පර්යේෂණ ලුහුබැඳීම් සිදු කරනු ඇති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "මේ අතර, චීනයේ බැලස්ටික් මිසයිල සහ චන්ද්‍රිකා ලුහුබැඳීමේ යාත්‍රාවේ හම්බන්තොට සංචාරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අසල්වැසියා දිවයිනට බලපෑම් කරන බවට චීනය විසින් කරන ලද ප්‍රකාශය ඉන්දියාව සිකුරාදා (අගෝස්තු 12) තරයේ ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය.",
        "චීන යාත්‍රාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඇති වූ ගැටුම මධ්‍යයේ, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිකුරාදා PNS Taimur පකිස්ථාන යුද නෞකාවකට කොළඹ වරායට පැමිණීමට අවසර දුන්නේය. ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාවට අනුව, ෂැංහයි හි Hudong-Zhonghua නැව් තටාකාංගනය විසින් ඉදිකරන ලද මෙම පකිස්ථානු මගපෙන්වන මිසයිල නෞකාව විධිමත් සංචාරයක් සඳහා කොළඹට පැමිණ ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වරාය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 16 - 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිමල් පී සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නියෝජිතායතනය ප්‍රංශ-ප්‍රෙස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස-දිග",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,000km පමණ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැතපුම් 620 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිග අඩි 730 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 11 සහ 17 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියන් සාගරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීඑන්එස් තයිමූර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hudong-Zhonghua",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂැංහයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மிகவும் சர்ச்சைக்குரிய சீன ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பலை நிறுத்துவதற்கு இலங்கை அனுமதி அளித்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சீனாவின் பாலிஸ்டிக் ஏவுகணை மற்றும் செயற்கைக்கோள் கண்காணிப்பு கப்பலான யுவான் வாங் 5 ஆகஸ்ட் 16 முதல் 22 வரை ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் நிறுத்துவதற்கு ஹார்பர் மாஸ்டருக்கு அனுமதி வழங்க இலங்கை வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சு அனுமதி வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தை அழைப்பதற்கு கப்பலை அனுமதிப்பதற்கு வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சிடம் இருந்து அனுமதி பெற்றதாக ஹார்பர் மாஸ்டர் நிமல் பி. சில்வா Agence France-Presse (AFP) இடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“இராஜதந்திர அனுமதி இன்று எனக்கு கிடைத்தது. துறைமுகத்தில் தளவாடங்களை உறுதி செய்வதற்காக, கப்பலால் நியமிக்கப்பட்ட உள்ளூர் முகவருடன் நாங்கள் பணியாற்றுவோம், ”என்று அவர் AFP இடம் கூறினார்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ பல மாதங்களாக நீடித்த போராட்டங்களுக்கு இணங்கி நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறுவதற்கு ஒரு நாள் முன்னதாக, ஜூலை 12 ஆம் திகதி அம்பாந்தோட்டையில் கப்பல் நிறுத்துவதற்கு கொழும்பு முதலில் அனுமதி வழங்கியதாகத் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "AFP படி, சீனக் கப்பல் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (ஆகஸ்ட் 12) இரவு இலங்கைக்கு தென்கிழக்கே சுமார் 1,000 கிமீ (620 மைல்) தொலைவில் இருந்ததாகவும், அம்பாந்தோட்டை நோக்கிச் சென்று கொண்டிருந்ததாகவும் துறைமுக அதிகாரிகள் கூறியுள்ளனர்.",
        "மிகவும் சர்ச்சைக்குரிய 730 அடி நீளமுள்ள இந்த கப்பல் முதலில் ஆகஸ்ட் 11 மற்றும் 17 க்கு இடையில் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் நிறுத்த திட்டமிடப்பட்டது, இருப்பினும், வருகையை ஒத்திவைக்க பெய்ஜிங்கிடம் இலங்கை கோரிக்கை விடுத்தது.",
        "இந்த விஷயத்தில் இந்தியா கடுமையான கவலைகளை தெரிவித்ததை அடுத்து, அதன் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் பொருளாதார நலன்களில் தாக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்தும் எந்தவொரு முன்னேற்றத்தையும் கவனமாகக் கண்காணித்து, அவற்றைப் பாதுகாக்க தேவையான அனைத்தையும் எடுத்துக்கொள்வதாகக் கூறியதை அடுத்து, ஒத்திவைப்புக்கான கோரிக்கை வந்தது.",
        "சீனா, இந்தியாவின் கவலைகளுக்குப் பதிலடி கொடுக்கும் வகையில், \"சம்பந்தப்பட்ட தரப்பினர்\" அதன் சட்டபூர்வமான கடல்சார் நடவடிக்கைகளில் தலையிடுவதைத் தவிர்ப்பார்கள் என்று நம்புவதாகக் கூறியதுடன், பாதுகாப்புக் கவலைகளை மேற்கோள்காட்டி கொழும்பிற்கு \"அழுத்தம் கொடுப்பதில் அர்த்தமற்றது\" என்று வலியுறுத்தியது.",
        "இராஜதந்திர பதட்டங்கள் அதிகரித்து வருவதால், சீனக் கப்பலுக்கு \"மறு நிரப்புதலுக்காக\" அனுமதியும் அனுமதியும் வழங்கப்பட்டதாக இலங்கை தெளிவுபடுத்தியது. இந்தக் கப்பல் ஆகஸ்ட் மற்றும் செப்டம்பர் மாதங்களில் இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல் பிராந்தியத்தின் வடமேற்குப் பகுதியில் செயற்கைக்கோள் கட்டுப்பாடு மற்றும் ஆராய்ச்சி கண்காணிப்பை மேற்கொள்ளும் என்று இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் மேலும் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், சீனாவின் பாலிஸ்டிக் ஏவுகணை மற்றும் செயற்கைக்கோள் கண்காணிப்பு கப்பலின் அம்பாந்தோட்டை விஜயம் தொடர்பாக இலங்கையின் அண்டை நாடு தீவு நாட்டிற்கு அழுத்தம் கொடுக்கிறது என்று கூறிய சீனாவின் தூண்டுதலை இந்தியா வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (ஆகஸ்ட் 12) திட்டவட்டமாக நிராகரித்தது.",
        "சீனக் கப்பல் தொடர்பான சர்ச்சைக்கு மத்தியில், பாகிஸ்தான் போர்க்கப்பலான பிஎன்எஸ் தைமூர் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை கொழும்பில் துறைமுகத்துக்கு வருவதற்கு இலங்கை அனுமதி அளித்துள்ளது. இலங்கை கடற்படையின் கூற்றுப்படி, ஷாங்காய் நகரில் Hudong-Zhonghua கப்பல் கட்டும் தளத்தால் கட்டப்பட்ட இந்த பாகிஸ்தான் வழிகாட்டுதல் ஏவுகணை போர்க்கப்பல், முறையான விஜயத்திற்காக கொழும்பு வந்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளிநாட்டு அலுவல்கள் அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 16 - 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிமல் பி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏஜென்ஸ் பிரான்ஸ்-பிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள் நீடித்தது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 1,000 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "620 மைல்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "730 அடி நீளம்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 11 மற்றும் 17 க்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிஎன்எஸ் தைமூர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hudong-Zhonghua",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷாங்காய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}