{
  "newspaper_id": "b-b-c-com-sinhala",
  "url": "https://www.bbc.com/sinhala/sri-lanka-62213049",
  "time_ut": 1658189522,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඩලස්,රනිල්,අනුර කුමාර ජනපති සටනට;සජිත් නාමයෝජනා නොදෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dallas, Ranil, Anura Kumara in the presidential battle; Sajith will not nominate",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The names of three members of parliament for the next presidential battle of the country, which all Sri Lankans are waiting for with great interest, were approved today (July 19) when the parliament met.",
        "During the 10-minute parliamentary session, opposition leader Sajith Premadasa proposed the name of Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna MP and former minister Dallas Alahaperuma for the post of President, and Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna Chairman G. L. Peirce seconded the motion.",
        "The Leader of the Parliament, Minister Dinesh Gunawardena proposed the name of Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe and it was confirmed by Samagi Jana Balawega MP Manusha Nanayakkara.",
        "National People's Force MP Vijitha Herath proposed the name of the party's leader Anura Kumara Dissanayake and MP Harini Amarasuriya seconded the proposal.",
        "Meanwhile, the General Secretary of the Parliament said that the voting will be held on Wednesday, July 20, as the names of more than one MP have been proposed for the post of President.",
        "Parliament was accordingly adjourned until 10 am on Wednesday, July 20.",
        "Before the start of the parliamentary session, opposition leader Sajith Premadasa said in a tweet, \"For the good of my beloved country and the people I love, I am withdrawing my presidential candidacy. Samagi Jana Balawegaya, our alliance and our opposition partners will work hard to win Dallas Alahaperuma.\" doing.\" Namely."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dallas",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Anura Kumara",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sajith",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10-minute",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna MP",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alahaperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "G. L. Peirce",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manusha Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "National People's Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday, July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday, July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alahaperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඩලස්,රනිල්,අනුර කුමාර ජනපති සටනට;සජිත් නාමයෝජනා නොදෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මේ වන විට සියලු ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින් දැඩි උනන්දුවකින් බලා සිටින රටේ මීළඟ  ජනපති සටනට පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් තිදෙනෙකුගේ නම් අද (ජූලි 19) පාර්ලිමේන්තුව රැස්වූ අවස්ථාවේදී යෝජනා ස්ථිර විය.",
        "විනාඩි 10ක් පැවතී පාර්ලිමේතු සභා වාරයේදී විපක්ෂ  නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රී හිටපු අමාත්‍ය ඩලස් අලහපෙරුමගේ නම ජනපතිධුරය සඳහා යෝජනා කළ අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සභාපති ජී. එල්. පීරිස් එම යෝජනාව ස්ථිර කළේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සභානායක, අමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන වැඩබලන ජනපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ නම යෝජනා කළ අතර එය ස්ථිර කරනු ලැබුවේ සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ මන්ත්‍රී මනුෂ නානයක්කාර විසිනි.",
        "ජාතික ජන බලවේගයේ මන්ත්‍රී විජිත හේරත් එම පක්ෂයේ නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායකගේ නම යෝජනා කළ අතර මන්ත්‍රීනි හරිනි අමරසූරිය එම යෝජනාව ස්ථිර කළාය.",
        "මේ අතර පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මහ ලේකම් පැවසුවේ ජනපති ධුරය සඳහා එක් මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකුට වඩා වැඩි දෙනෙකුගේ නම් යෝජනා වී ඇති නිසා ඡන්ද විමසීම ජූලි 20 වන බදාදා පැවැත්වෙන බවයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ජූලි 20 වන බදාදා උදෑසන  10 දක්වා කල් තබන ලදී.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු සභාව ආරම්භයට පෙර විපක්ෂනායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස ටුවිටර් පණිවිඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින්  පැවසුවේ \"මා ආදරය කරන මගේ රටේ සහ මා ආදරය කරන ජනතාවගේ යහපත වෙනුවෙන් මම මගේ ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂකත්වය ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගනිමි. ඩලස් අලහපෙරුම ජයග්‍රහණය කිරීමට සමගි ජන බලවේගය, අපගේ සන්ධානය සහ අපගේ විපක්ෂ හවුල්කරුවන් දැඩි ලෙස ක්‍රියා කරනවා.\" යනුවෙනි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩලස්",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "අනුර කුමාර",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "සජිත්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10-මිනිත්තු",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ පා.ම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහපෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල්. පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනූෂ නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලවේගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20 බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එකකට වඩා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙ.ව. 10",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20 බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහපෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் டலஸ், ரணில், அனுரகுமார; சஜித் முன்மொழிய மாட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையர்கள் அனைவரும் மிகுந்த ஆர்வத்துடன் எதிர்பார்த்துக் காத்திருந்த நாட்டின் அடுத்த ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலுக்கான மூன்று நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் பெயர்கள் இன்று (ஜூலை 19) நாடாளுமன்றம் கூடியபோது அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "10 நிமிட நாடாளுமன்ற அமர்வின் போது, ​​எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச, ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன எம்பியும் முன்னாள் அமைச்சருமான டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவின் பெயரையும், ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் தலைவர் ஜி. எல். பீரிஸ் பிரேரணையை உறுதிப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் பெயரை பாராளுமன்றத்தின் தலைவர் அமைச்சர் தினேஸ் குணவர்தன முன்மொழிந்ததுடன் அதனை சமகி ஜன பலவேக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மனுஷ நாணயக்கார உறுதிப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தியின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் விஜித ஹேரத், கட்சியின் தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்கவின் பெயரை முன்மொழிந்தார் மற்றும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஹரிணி அமரசூரிய இந்த பிரேரணைக்கு ஆதரவளித்தார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு ஒன்றுக்கும் மேற்பட்ட எம்.பி.க்களின் பெயர்கள் முன்மொழியப்பட்டுள்ளதால், ஜூலை 20ஆம் திகதி புதன்கிழமை வாக்கெடுப்பு நடத்தப்படும் என நாடாளுமன்ற பொதுச் செயலாளர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அதன்படி பாராளுமன்றம் ஜூலை 20 புதன்கிழமை காலை 10 மணி வரை ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "நாடாளுமன்றக் கூட்டத் தொடர் தொடங்கும் முன், எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச டுவிட்டரில், “எனது அன்புக்குரிய நாட்டிற்கும், நான் நேசிக்கும் மக்களின் நலனுக்காகவும், நான் எனது ஜனாதிபதி வேட்புமனுவை வாபஸ் பெறுகிறேன். சமகி ஜன பலவேகய, எங்கள் கூட்டணி மற்றும் எங்கள் எதிர்க்கட்சி பங்காளிகள் செயல்படுவார்கள். டலஸ் அழகபெருமாவை வெல்வது கடினம்.\" அதாவது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "அனுர குமார",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "சஜித்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10 நிமிடம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன எம்.பி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகபெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல். பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனுஷ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன், ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்றுக்கு மேற்பட்ட",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 10 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன், ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகபெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}