{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/79115",
  "time_ut": 1661194620,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "People’s Alliance on Right to Land (PARL) demands the immediate and unconditional release of Activist Chinthaka  Rajapakse and all others arrested with him at the peaceful protests on 18th August.",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "People’s Alliance on Right to Land (PARL) demands the immediate and unconditional release of Activist Chinthaka  Rajapakse and all others arrested with him at the peaceful protests on 18th August.",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "(Text  of statement issued by the  People’s Alliance on Right to Land (PARL) on 24th August, 2022)",
        "Chinthaka Rajapakse, a convenor of the Movement for Land and Agricultural Rights and Reform (MONLAR), was arrested on the 18th of August 2022 for participating in a peaceful protest organized by the Inter University Students Federation. He was arrested with 19 others. Three of these protesters have since been subjected to 90-day Detention Orders under the Prevention of Terrorism Act, which itself is a gross misuse of repressive legislation against protestors.",
        "Chinthaka and the others were produced at Colombo Magistrate Court on 19th August, where the others were granted bail, and the police requested that Chinthaka be further remanded and the Magistrate ordered that he remain in custody until the 26th of August 2022. We strongly believe that the request to prolong his custody in remand by the police was motivated as a means of punishment for Chinthaka’s long standing activism and effective mobilization of citizens to protest injustice.",
        "For decades, Chinthaka has been a stalwart supporter to movements for environmental protection and land rights of many communities in Sri Lanka. He is a close ally of farmers, especially those who have been dispossessed of their lands. He has stood by communities in the North and East who have been leading long standing struggles against militarized land grabs.",
        "Chinthaka is from a rural farming family in Buttala and is the father of three daughters. He is a second generation activist, who like his father, has dedicated his life to fight for the rights of those most marginalized in Sri Lanka. As a young man, he worked closely with Father Michael Rodrigo (OMI) who was assassinated for his social justice work in Buttala in 1988.",
        "Chinthaka is an active member of the People’s Alliance for Right to Land (PARL), a voluntary coalition of civil society organizations and individuals working across Sri Lanka on issues related to land rights of marginalised commuities, since 2011.",
        "As PARL, we condemn the arrests and intimidation of all protestors, including Chinthaka.  We see these arrests as a means to intimidate all people in this country who are thinkers, professionals and activists’ who are struggling to ensure that all those marginalized in this country are able to access their fundamental rights at all times. Further, these are part of efforts to curb the democratic right to critique and non-violently protest to hold those in power accountable.",
        "We as PARL stand firmly in support the right to dissent and consider it a significant pillar of democracy. We unequivocally condemn this state-sponsored intimidation and curbing of rights which will further tarnish the already strained claim of Sri Lanka to be a democratic nation. The attack on Chinthaka and others like him is a direct attack on all citizens who stand up to fight for the rights of the marginalized.",
        "We demand the immediate and unconditional release of Chinthaka and all those who were arrested with him at the peaceful protests on 18th August.",
        "We also call for an immediate halt to the undemocratic intimidation directed in the form of baseless investigations and arrests of citizens, including activists, people involved in community struggles and trade union members, to punish them for and prevent them from exercising their right to dissent in Sri Lanka."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "People’s Alliance on Right to Land (PARL",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Activist",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Rajapakse",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "18th August",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "People’s Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "24th August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinthaka Rajapakse",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 18th of August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Inter University Students Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "90-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Prevention of Terrorism Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinthaka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Magistrate Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19th August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinthaka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 26th of",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinthaka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinthaka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "North and East",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinthaka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buttala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Michael Rodrigo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "OMI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buttala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1988",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinthaka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the People’s Alliance for Right to Land (PARL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2011",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PARL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinthaka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinthaka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinthaka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "18th August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අගෝස්තු 18 වනදා පැවති සාමකාමී විරෝධතාවයේදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් ක්‍රියාකාරි චින්තක රාජපක්ෂ සහ ඔහු සමඟ අත් අඩංගුවට ගත් අනෙකුත් සියලු දෙනා වහාම සහ කොන්දේසි විරහිතව නිදහස් කරන ලෙස ඉඩම් අයිතිය පිළිබඳ ජනතා සන්ධානය (PARL) ඉල්ලා සිටී.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "(2022 අගෝස්තු 24 වැනි දින ඉඩම් අයිතිය පිළිබඳ ජනතා සන්ධානය (PARL) විසින් නිකුත් කරන ලද ප්‍රකාශයේ පෙළ)",
        "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බලමණ්ඩලය විසින් සංවිධානය කරන ලද සාමකාමී විරෝධතාවයකට සහභාගී වීම හේතුවෙන් ඉඩම් සහ කෘෂිකර්ම අයිතිවාසිකම් සහ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සඳහා වූ ව්‍යාපාරයේ (MONLAR) කැඳවුම්කරු චින්තක රාජපක්ෂ 2022 අගෝස්තු 18 වන දින අත්අඩංගුවට ගනු ලැබීය. ඔහු තවත් 19 දෙනෙකු සමඟ අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත. මෙම විරෝධතාකරුවන්ගෙන් තිදෙනෙකු ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැලැක්වීමේ පනත යටතේ දින 90 ක රඳවා ගැනීමේ නියෝග වලට යටත් කර ඇත, එයම විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට එරෙහි මර්දන නීති දැඩි ලෙස අනිසි ලෙස භාවිතා කිරීමකි.",
        "චින්තක ඇතුළු පිරිස අගෝස්තු 19 වැනි දින කොළඹ මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කළ අතර එහිදී සෙසු පිරිසට ඇප නියම වූ අතර එහිදී පොලිසිය චින්තක තවදුරටත් රිමාන්ඩ් භාරයේ තබන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටි අතර 2022 අගෝස්තු 26 දක්වා ඔහු අත්අඩංගුවේ පසුවන ලෙස මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා නියෝග කළේය. චින්තකගේ දීර්ඝකාලීන ක්‍රියාකාරීත්වයට සහ අසාධාරණයට විරෝධය දැක්වීම සඳහා පුරවැසියන් ඵලදායී ලෙස බලමුලු ගැන්වීමට දඬුවම් කිරීමේ මාධ්‍යයක් ලෙස පොලිසිය විසින් ඔහු රිමාන්ඩ් භාරයේ සිටින කාලය දීර්ඝ කරන ලෙස කරන ලද ඉල්ලීම පොළඹවන ලද්දකි.",
        "දශක ගණනාවක් පුරා, චින්තක ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බොහෝ ප්‍රජාවන්ගේ පාරිසරික ආරක්ෂාව සහ ඉඩම් අයිතිය සඳහා වූ ව්‍යාපාරවලට ප්‍රබල ආධාරකරුවෙකි. විශේෂයෙන්ම ඉඩම් අහිමි වූ ගොවීන්ගේ සමීප හිතවතෙකි. මිලිටරිකරණය වූ ඉඩම් කොල්ලයට එරෙහිව දීර්ඝ කාලීන අරගලවලට නායකත්වය දුන් උතුරු නැගෙනහිර ප්‍රජාවන් වෙනුවෙන් ඔහු පෙනී සිට ඇත.",
        "චින්තක බුත්තල ග්‍රාමීය ගොවි පවුලක වන අතර ඔහු දියණියන් තිදෙනෙකුගේ පියෙකි. ඔහු දෙවන පරම්පරාවේ ක්‍රියාකාරිකයෙකි, ඔහු තම පියා මෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වඩාත්ම ආන්තික වූවන්ගේ අයිතිවාසිකම් වෙනුවෙන් සටන් කිරීමට තම ජීවිතය කැප කළේය. තරුණ වියේදී ඔහු 1988 දී බුත්තලදී ඔහුගේ සමාජ සාධාරණත්වය වෙනුවෙන් ඝාතනයට ලක් වූ මයිකල් රුද්රිගෝ (OMI) පියතුමා සමඟ සමීපව කටයුතු කළේය.",
        "චින්තක 2011 වසරේ සිට ආන්තික ප්‍රජාවන්ගේ ඉඩම් අයිතිය සම්බන්ධ ගැටළු සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පුරා ක්‍රියා කරන සිවිල් සමාජ සංවිධාන සහ පුද්ගලයන්ගේ ස්වේච්ඡා සන්ධානයක් වන ඉඩම් සඳහා වූ ජනතා සන්ධානයේ (PARL) ක්‍රියාකාරී සාමාජිකයෙකි.",
        "PARL ලෙස, චින්තක ඇතුළු සියලුම විරෝධතාකරුවන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම් සහ බිය ගැන්වීම් අපි හෙළා දකිමු. මේ අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම් අපි දකින්නේ මේ රටේ ආන්තික වූ සියලු දෙනාට සෑම විටම තම මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම්වලට ප්‍රවේශ විය හැකි බව තහවුරු කිරීමට අරගල කරන මේ රටේ චින්තකයින්, වෘත්තිකයන් සහ ක්‍රියාකාරීන් වන සියලුම ජනතාව බිය ගැන්වීමේ මාධ්‍යයක් ලෙසයි. තවද, මේවා බලයේ සිටින අය වගවීම සඳහා විවේචනය කිරීමට සහ අවිහිංසාවාදීව විරෝධතා දැක්වීමට ඇති ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී අයිතිය මැඩලීමේ ප්‍රයත්නයේ කොටසකි.",
        "අපි PARL ලෙස විසම්මුතිය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමේ අයිතියට සහයෝගය දක්වන අතර එය ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදයේ වැදගත් කුළුණක් ලෙස සලකමු. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී ජාතියක් ලෙස දැනටමත් පීඩාවට පත්ව සිටින ප්‍රකාශය තවදුරටත් කැළැල් කරන මෙම රාජ්‍ය අනුග්‍රහය සහිත බිය ගැන්වීම් සහ අයිතිවාසිකම් සීමා කිරීම අපි අවිවාදයෙන් යුතුව හෙළා දකිමු. චින්තකට සහ ඔහු වැනි අයට එල්ල කරන ප්‍රහාරය ආන්තික ජනතාවගේ අයිතීන් වෙනුවෙන් සටන් කිරීමට නැගී සිටින සියලුම පුරවැසියන්ට එල්ල කරන සෘජු ප්‍රහාරයකි.",
        "අගෝස්තු 18 වෙනිදා පැවති සාමකාමී විරෝධතාවයේදී චින්තක ඇතුළු ඔහු සමඟ අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සියලු දෙනාම කොන්දේසි විරහිතව වහාම නිදහස් කරන ලෙස අපි ඉල්ලා සිටිමු.",
        "ක්‍රියාකාරීන්, ප්‍රජා අරගලවලට සම්බන්ධ පුද්ගලයින් සහ වෘත්තීය සමිති සාමාජිකයින් ඇතුළු පුරවැසියන් පදනම් විරහිත විමර්ශන සහ අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමේ ස්වරූපයෙන් මෙහෙයවන ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍ර විරෝධී බිය ගැන්වීම් වහාම නතර කරන ලෙස අපි ඉල්ලා සිටිමු. ශ්රී ලංකාව."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉඩම් අයිතිය පිළිබඳ ජනතා සන්ධානය (PARL",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ක්‍රියාකාරිකයෙක්",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "අගෝස්තු 18",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහජන සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චින්තක රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 18 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "90-දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චින්තක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චින්තක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චින්තක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දශක",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චින්තක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු නැගෙනහිර",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චින්තක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුත්තල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මයිකල් රුද්‍රිගෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "OMI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුත්තල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1988",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චින්තක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉඩම් අයිතිය සඳහා වූ ජනතා සන්ධානය (PARL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2011",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චින්තක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චින්තක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චින්තක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஓகஸ்ட் 18ஆம் திகதி நடைபெற்ற அமைதிப் போராட்டத்தில் கலந்துகொண்ட செயற்பாட்டாளர் சிந்தக ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் அவருடன் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட ஏனைய அனைவரையும் நிபந்தனையின்றி உடனடியாக விடுவிக்குமாறு காணி உரிமைக்கான மக்கள் கூட்டமைப்பு (PARL) கோருகிறது.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "(24 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022 அன்று நில உரிமைக்கான மக்கள் கூட்டணி (PARL) வெளியிட்ட அறிக்கையின் உரை)",
        "நிலம் மற்றும் விவசாய உரிமைகள் மற்றும் சீர்திருத்தத்திற்கான இயக்கத்தின் (MONLAR) அழைப்பாளரான சிந்தக ராஜபக்ஷ 2022 ஆகஸ்ட் 18 ஆம் திகதி பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் சம்மேளனத்தினால் ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்ட அமைதிப் போராட்டத்தில் கலந்துகொண்டதற்காக கைது செய்யப்பட்டார். அவர் 19 பேருடன் கைது செய்யப்பட்டார். இந்த எதிர்ப்பாளர்களில் மூன்று பேர் பயங்கரவாதத் தடுப்புச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் 90 நாள் தடுப்புக் காவலுக்கு உட்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளனர், இது எதிர்ப்பாளர்களுக்கு எதிரான அடக்குமுறைச் சட்டத்தை முற்றிலும் தவறாகப் பயன்படுத்துவதாகும்.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 19 ஆம் திகதி சிந்தக மற்றும் ஏனையவர்கள் கொழும்பு நீதவான் நீதிமன்றில் ஆஜர்படுத்தப்பட்டு, ஏனையவர்களுக்கு பிணை வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளதுடன், பொலிசார் சிந்தகவை மேலும் விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்குமாறு கோரியதுடன், அவரை 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் 26 ஆம் திகதி வரை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்குமாறு நீதவான் உத்தரவிட்டார். காவல்துறையினரால் காவலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள அவரது காவலை நீடிக்க வேண்டும் என்ற கோரிக்கையானது, சிந்தகவின் நீண்டகால செயற்பாடு மற்றும் அநீதிக்கு எதிராக குடிமக்களை திறம்பட அணிதிரட்டுவதற்கான தண்டனைக்கான வழிமுறையாக உந்துதல் பெற்றது.",
        "பல தசாப்தங்களாக, இலங்கையில் உள்ள பல சமூகங்களின் சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் நில உரிமைகளுக்கான இயக்கங்களுக்கு சிந்தக ஒரு உறுதியான ஆதரவாளராக இருந்து வருகிறார். குறிப்பாக நிலம் பறிக்கப்பட்ட விவசாயிகளின் நெருங்கிய கூட்டாளி. இராணுவ மயமாக்கப்பட்ட நில அபகரிப்புகளுக்கு எதிராக நீண்டகால போராட்டங்களை முன்னெடுத்து வரும் வடக்கு மற்றும் கிழக்கில் சமூகங்களுக்கு ஆதரவாக அவர் நின்றுள்ளார்.",
        "புத்தல கிராமப்புற விவசாயக் குடும்பத்தைச் சேர்ந்த சிந்தக மூன்று பெண் பிள்ளைகளின் தந்தையாவார். அவர் இரண்டாம் தலைமுறை செயற்பாட்டாளர், அவர் தனது தந்தையைப் போலவே, இலங்கையில் மிகவும் ஒதுக்கப்பட்டவர்களின் உரிமைகளுக்காகப் போராடுவதற்காக தனது வாழ்க்கையை அர்ப்பணித்தவர். ஒரு இளைஞனாக, அவர் 1988 இல் புத்தளவில் சமூக நீதிக்காக படுகொலை செய்யப்பட்ட தந்தை மைக்கேல் ரோட்ரிகோவுடன் (OMI) நெருக்கமாக பணியாற்றினார்.",
        "சிந்தக 2011 ஆம் ஆண்டு முதல், விளிம்புநிலை சமூகங்களின் நில உரிமைகள் தொடர்பான பிரச்சினைகளில் இலங்கை முழுவதும் பணிபுரியும் சிவில் சமூக அமைப்புகள் மற்றும் தனிநபர்களின் தன்னார்வ கூட்டமைப்பான நிலத்திற்கான மக்கள் கூட்டணியின் (PARL) செயலில் உறுப்பினராக உள்ளார்.",
        "PARL என்ற வகையில், சிந்தக உட்பட அனைத்து போராட்டக்காரர்களின் கைது மற்றும் மிரட்டல்களை நாங்கள் கண்டிக்கிறோம். இந்த நாட்டில் விளிம்புநிலையில் உள்ள அனைவரும் தமது அடிப்படை உரிமைகளை எப்பொழுதும் பெற்றுக் கொள்ள வேண்டும் என்று போராடும் சிந்தனையாளர்கள், தொழில் வல்லுநர்கள், செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் என அனைத்து மக்களையும் பயமுறுத்துவதற்கான ஒரு வழிமுறையாகவே இந்த கைதுகளை நாம் பார்க்கிறோம். மேலும், இவை அதிகாரத்தில் உள்ளவர்களை பொறுப்புக்கூற வைப்பதற்காக விமர்சனம் செய்வதற்கும் வன்முறையற்ற முறையில் எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவிப்பதற்குமான ஜனநாயக உரிமையை தடுப்பதற்கான முயற்சிகளின் ஒரு பகுதியாகும்.",
        "நாங்கள் கருத்து வேறுபாடு உரிமைக்கு ஆதரவாக உறுதியாக நிற்கிறோம் மற்றும் ஜனநாயகத்தின் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க தூணாக கருதுகிறோம். சிறிலங்கா ஒரு ஜனநாயக தேசம் என்ற கோரிக்கையை மேலும் களங்கப்படுத்தும் இந்த அரச ஆதரவுடன் மிரட்டல் மற்றும் உரிமைகளை முடக்குவதை நாங்கள் சந்தேகத்திற்கு இடமின்றி கண்டிக்கிறோம். சிந்தக மற்றும் அவரைப் போன்றவர்கள் மீதான தாக்குதல், விளிம்புநிலை மக்களின் உரிமைகளுக்காகப் போராடும் அனைத்து குடிமக்கள் மீதான நேரடித் தாக்குதலாகும்.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 18 அன்று நடைபெற்ற அமைதிப் போராட்டத்தில் சிந்தக மற்றும் அவருடன் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட அனைவரையும் நிபந்தனையின்றி உடனடியாக விடுதலை செய்யுமாறு நாங்கள் கோருகிறோம்.",
        "அடிப்படையற்ற விசாரணைகள் மற்றும் குடிமக்கள், சமூகப் போராட்டங்களில் ஈடுபட்டவர்கள் மற்றும் தொழிற்சங்க உறுப்பினர்கள் உள்ளிட்ட குடிமக்கள் மீது அடிப்படையற்ற விசாரணைகள் மற்றும் கைதுகள் வடிவில் இயக்கப்படும் ஜனநாயக விரோத மிரட்டல்களை உடனடியாக நிறுத்துமாறு கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறோம். இலங்கை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நில உரிமைக்கான மக்கள் கூட்டணி (PARL",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "செயற்பாட்டாளர்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 18",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிந்தக ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 18, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "90-நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிந்தகா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிந்தகா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிந்தகா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பத்தாண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிந்தகா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு மற்றும் கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிந்தகா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைக்கேல் ரோட்ரிகோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "OMI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1988",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிந்தகா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நில உரிமைக்கான மக்கள் கூட்டணி (PARL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2011",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பார்ல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிந்தகா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிந்தகா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிந்தகா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}