{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-visited-by-top-us-treasury-state-delegation-96432/",
  "time_ut": 1656126900,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka visited by top US Treasury, State delegation",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka visited by top US Treasury, State delegation",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – A delegation of top US Treasury and State Department is visiting Sri Lanka as the country reels from a collapse of a soft-peg (flexible exchange rate) backed by conflicting monetary policy.",
        "Members of the delegation include Robert Kaproth, Deputy Assistant Secretary of Treasury for Asia, and Ambassador Kelly Keiderling, Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for South and Central Asia.",
        "“The visitors will meet with a wide range of political representatives, economists, and international organizations,” the US embassy in Colombo said in a statement.",
        "“In all their meetings, they will explore the most effective ways for the U.S. to support Sri Lankans in need, Sri Lankans working to resolve the current economic crisis, and Sri Lankans planning for a sustainable and inclusive economy for the future.”",
        "Sri Lanka which has a Latin America style  pegged central bank with extensive sterilization powers and open market operations, has entered its first default cycle in April 2022 and is casting about for foreign aid after the currency collapsed from 200 to 360 to the US dollar.",
        "Sri Lanka which has a Latin America style  pegged central bank with extensive sterilization powers and open market operations, has entered its first default cycle in April 2022 and is casting about for foreign aid after the currency collapsed from 200 to 360 to the US dollar.",
        "“This visit underscores our ongoing commitment to the security and prosperity of the Sri Lankan people,””.S. Ambassador to Sri Lanka, Julie Chung said in a statement.",
        "“As Sri Lankans endure some of the greatest economic challenges in their history, our efforts to support economic growth and strengthen democratic institutions have never been more critical.”",
        "U.S. has announced120 million in new financing for Sri Lankan small and medium-sized businesses, a 27 million dollars contribution to Sri Lanka’s dairy industry and 5.75 million in humanitarian assistance to help those hit hardest by the flexible exchange rate.",
        "The flexible exchange rate has pushed up food prices beyond the reach of the less affluent classes.",
        "“In the coming months, the U.S. will continue to support Sri Lankans as they revive their economy, combat food insecurity, and promote public health and education,” the embassy said.",
        "“The United States also strongly supports Sri Lanka’s decision to seek assistance from the International Monetary Fund, which can provide the most durable resolution to the present crisis.”",
        "Sri Lanka has gone to the IMF 16 times but has not been able to end currency crises.",
        "How Sri Lanka, Latin America was busted by Fed money doctors creating strongmen, anti-Americanism",
        "Though the IMF can help stabilize the exchange rate temporarily by smashing the domestic private sector the central bank is encouraged to return to aggressive liquidity injections (in as little as two years under flexible inflation targeting) and triggers another currency crisis.",
        "Under an IMF program there is no hope for a single anchor money regime such as inflation targeting, due to the obligation to target the exchange rate, operate a reserve collecting peg to pay back the loan to the Fund. (Colombo/June24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "US Treasury",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "State",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "US Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "State Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Robert Kaproth",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelly Keiderling",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Latin America",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "April 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 to 360",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Latin America",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "April 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 to 360",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 million dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.75 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the coming months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Latin America",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fed",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "anti-Americanism",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "as little as two years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/June24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "එක්සත් ජනපද භාණ්ඩාගාර රාජ්‍ය නියෝජිත පිරිසක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංචාරයක නිරත විය",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - පරස්පර මුදල් ප්‍රතිපත්තියේ පිටුබලය ඇතිව මෘදු-පෙග් (නම්‍යශීලී විනිමය අනුපාතිකය) බිඳවැටීමකින් රට පසුබසින විට එක්සත් ජනපදයේ ඉහළ පෙළේ භාණ්ඩාගාරයේ සහ රාජ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ නියෝජිත පිරිසක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණේ.",
        "දූත පිරිසට ආසියාව සඳහා භාණ්ඩාගාර නියෝජ්‍ය සහකාර ලේකම් Robert Kaproth සහ දකුණු සහ මධ්‍යම ආසියාව සඳහා නියෝජ්‍ය සහකාර රාජ්‍ය ලේකම් තානාපති Kelly Keiderling ඇතුළත් වේ.",
        "“ආගන්තුකයන් පුළුල් පරාසයක දේශපාලන නියෝජිතයන්, ආර්ථික විද්‍යාඥයන් සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර සංවිධාන හමුවනු ඇත,” කොළඹ එක්සත් ජනපද තානාපති කාර්යාලය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "\"ඔවුන්ගේ සියලුම රැස්වීම් වලදී, අවශ්‍යතා ඇති ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින්ට සහාය වීමට එක්සත් ජනපදයට වඩාත් ඵලදායී ක්‍රම, වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදය විසඳීමට වැඩ කරන ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් සහ අනාගතය සඳහා තිරසාර සහ සියල්ලන් ඇතුළත් ආර්ථිකයක් සඳහා සැලසුම් කරන ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් ගවේෂණය කරනු ඇත.\"",
        "ලතින් අමෙරිකානු පන්නයේ විස්තීරණ වන්ධ්‍යාකරණ බලතල සහ විවෘත වෙලඳපොල මෙහෙයුම් සමග සම්බන්ධ වූ මහ බැංකුවක් ඇති ශ්‍රී ලංකාව, 2022 අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී එහි පළමු පැහැර හැරීමේ චක්‍රයට අවතීර්ණ වී ඇති අතර මුදල් ඒකකය එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලරයට 200 සිට 360 දක්වා කඩා වැටීමෙන් පසු විදේශ ආධාර සඳහා යොමු වෙමින් සිටී.",
        "ලතින් අමෙරිකානු පන්නයේ විස්තීරණ වන්ධ්‍යාකරණ බලතල සහ විවෘත වෙලඳපොල මෙහෙයුම් සමග සම්බන්ධ වූ මහ බැංකුවක් ඇති ශ්‍රී ලංකාව, 2022 අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී එහි පළමු පැහැර හැරීමේ චක්‍රයට අවතීර්ණ වී ඇති අතර මුදල් ඒකකය එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලරයට 200 සිට 360 දක්වා කඩා වැටීමෙන් පසු විදේශ ආධාර සඳහා යොමු වෙමින් සිටී.",
        "\"මෙම සංචාරය ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනතාවගේ ආරක්ෂාව සහ සමෘද්ධිය සඳහා අපගේ අඛණ්ඩ කැපවීම අවධාරනය කරයි\". ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තානාපතිනි ජුලී චුන්ග් නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "\"ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් ඔවුන්ගේ ඉතිහාසයේ දැවැන්තම ආර්ථික අභියෝගවලට මුහුණ දෙන බැවින්, ආර්ථික වර්ධනයට සහය වීමට සහ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී ආයතන ශක්තිමත් කිරීමට අප ගන්නා උත්සාහයන් කිසිදා වඩා විවේචනාත්මක නොවීය.\"",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කුඩා හා මධ්‍යම ප්‍රමාණයේ ව්‍යාපාර සඳහා නව මූල්‍යකරණය මිලියන 120 ක්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කිරි කර්මාන්තයට ඩොලර් මිලියන 27 ක දායකත්වයක් සහ නම්‍යශීලී විනිමය අනුපාතයෙන් දැඩි ලෙස පීඩාවට පත් වූවන්ට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා මානුෂීය ආධාර මිලියන 5.75 ක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර ඇත.",
        "නම්‍යශීලී විනිමය අනුපාතිකය අඩු ධනවත් පංතිවලට ළඟාවිය නොහැකි ලෙස ආහාර මිල ඉහළ දමා ඇත.",
        "\"ඉදිරි මාසවලදී, එක්සත් ජනපදය ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින්ට ඔවුන්ගේ ආර්ථිකය පුනර්ජීවනය කිරීම, ආහාර අනාරක්ෂිතභාවයට එරෙහිව සටන් කිරීම සහ මහජන සෞඛ්‍යය සහ අධ්‍යාපනය ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීම සඳහා ඔවුන්ට අඛණ්ඩව සහාය වනු ඇත\" යනුවෙන් තානාපති කාර්යාලය පැවසීය.",
        "\"වර්තමාන අර්බුදයට වඩාත්ම කල්පවත්නා විසඳුම සැපයිය හැකි ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සහය ලබා ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ගත් තීරණයට එක්සත් ජනපදය ද දැඩි ලෙස සහාය දක්වයි.\"",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව 16 වතාවක් ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලට ගොස් ඇති නමුත් මුදල් අර්බුදය අවසන් කිරීමට නොහැකි වී තිබේ.",
        "ශ‍්‍රී ලංකාව, ලතින් ඇමරිකාව ප‍්‍රබලයින්, ඇමරිකානු විරෝධයක් ඇති කරමින් ෆෙඩරල් මුදල් වෛද්‍යවරුන් විසින් බිඳ දැමූ ආකාරය",
        "දේශීය පෞද්ගලික අංශය කඩා බිඳ දැමීමෙන් විනිමය අනුපාතිකය තාවකාලිකව ස්ථාවර කිරීමට ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලට හැකි වුවද, ආක්‍රමණශීලී ද්‍රවශීලතා එන්නත් වෙත ආපසු යාමට (නම්‍යශීලී උද්ධමන ඉලක්ක යටතේ වසර දෙකක් වැනි කෙටි කාලයක් තුළ) මහ බැංකුව දිරිමත් කර තවත් මුදල් අර්බුදයක් ඇති කරයි.",
        "IMF වැඩසටහනක් යටතේ, විනිමය අනුපාතිකය ඉලක්ක කර ගැනීමේ බැඳීම හේතුවෙන්, අරමුදලට ණය ආපසු ගෙවීම සඳහා සංචිත එකතු කිරීමේ කූඩුවක් ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම හේතුවෙන් උද්ධමනය ඉලක්ක කිරීම වැනි තනි නැංගුරම් මුදල් තන්ත්‍රයක් සඳහා බලාපොරොත්තුවක් නොමැත. (කොළඹ/ජුනි24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද භාණ්ඩාගාරය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "රජයේ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද භාණ්ඩාගාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොබට් කප්රොත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙලී කීඩර්ලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලතින් ඇමරිකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 සිට 360 දක්වා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලතින් ඇමරිකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 සිට 360 දක්වා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 27 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 5.75 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලතින් ඇමරිකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆෙඩරල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානු විරෝධය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු දෙකක් වැනි කෙටි කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජුනි24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அமெரிக்காவின் உயர்மட்ட திறைசேரி மற்றும் அரச பிரதிநிதிகள் இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்துள்ளனர்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - முரண்பட்ட நாணயக் கொள்கையின் ஆதரவுடன் ஒரு மென்மையான-பெக் (நெகிழ்வான மாற்று விகிதம்) சரிவில் இருந்து நாடு தத்தளித்து வரும் நிலையில், உயர்மட்ட அமெரிக்க கருவூலம் மற்றும் இராஜாங்கத் திணைக்களத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகள் குழு ஒன்று இலங்கைக்கு வருகை தருகிறது.",
        "தூதுக்குழுவின் உறுப்பினர்களில் ஆசியாவிற்கான துணை கருவூலத்தின் துணைச் செயலாளர் ரொபர்ட் கப்ரோத் மற்றும் தெற்கு மற்றும் மத்திய ஆசியாவிற்கான துணை இராஜாங்கத் தூதர் கெல்லி கெய்டர்லிங் ஆகியோர் அடங்குவர்.",
        "கொழும்பில் உள்ள அமெரிக்க தூதரகம் வெளியிட்டுள்ள அறிக்கையில், “வருகையாளர்கள் பலதரப்பட்ட அரசியல் பிரதிநிதிகள், பொருளாதார நிபுணர்கள் மற்றும் சர்வதேச அமைப்புகளைச் சந்திப்பார்கள்.",
        "\"அவர்களின் அனைத்து சந்திப்புகளிலும், அவர்கள் அமெரிக்காவிற்கு தேவைப்படும் இலங்கையர்களை ஆதரிப்பதற்கான மிகச் சிறந்த வழிகளை ஆராய்வார்கள், தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியைத் தீர்க்கும் இலங்கையர்கள் மற்றும் எதிர்காலத்திற்கான நிலையான மற்றும் உள்ளடக்கிய பொருளாதாரத்திற்குத் திட்டமிடும் இலங்கையர்கள்.\"",
        "இலத்தீன் அமெரிக்க பாணியில் விரிவான கருத்தடை சக்திகள் மற்றும் திறந்த சந்தை நடவடிக்கைகளுடன் மத்திய வங்கியைக் கொண்டுள்ள இலங்கை, 2022 ஏப்ரலில் தனது முதல் இயல்புநிலை சுழற்சியில் நுழைந்து, அமெரிக்க டாலருக்கு 200 முதல் 360 வரை நாணயம் சரிந்த பின்னர் வெளிநாட்டு உதவியை நாடியுள்ளது.",
        "இலத்தீன் அமெரிக்க பாணியில் விரிவான கருத்தடை சக்திகள் மற்றும் திறந்த சந்தை நடவடிக்கைகளுடன் மத்திய வங்கியைக் கொண்டுள்ள இலங்கை, 2022 ஏப்ரலில் தனது முதல் இயல்புநிலை சுழற்சியில் நுழைந்து, அமெரிக்க டாலருக்கு 200 முதல் 360 வரை நாணயம் சரிந்த பின்னர் வெளிநாட்டு உதவியை நாடியுள்ளது.",
        "\"இலங்கை மக்களின் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் செழிப்புக்கான எமது தொடர்ச்சியான அர்ப்பணிப்பை இந்த விஜயம் அடிக்கோடிட்டுக் காட்டுகிறது\". எஸ். இலங்கைக்கான தூதுவர் ஜூலி சுங் அறிக்கையொன்றில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"இலங்கையர்கள் தங்கள் வரலாற்றில் மிகப்பெரும் பொருளாதார சவால்களை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ள நிலையில், பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சியை ஆதரிப்பதற்கும் ஜனநாயக நிறுவனங்களை வலுப்படுத்துவதற்கும் நாங்கள் எடுக்கும் முயற்சிகள் மிகவும் முக்கியமானதாக இருந்ததில்லை.\"",
        "இலங்கையின் சிறிய மற்றும் நடுத்தர வர்த்தகங்களுக்கு 120 மில்லியன் புதிய நிதியுதவியையும், இலங்கையின் பால் உற்பத்தித் தொழிலுக்கு 27 மில்லியன் டாலர் பங்களிப்பையும், நெகிழ்வான மாற்று விகிதத்தால் கடுமையாக பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர்களுக்கு உதவுவதற்காக 5.75 மில்லியன் மனிதாபிமான உதவிகளையும் அமெரிக்கா அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "நெகிழ்வான மாற்று விகிதம் குறைந்த வசதி படைத்த வகுப்பினருக்கு எட்டாத அளவிற்கு உணவு விலைகளை உயர்த்தியுள்ளது.",
        "\"வரும் மாதங்களில், இலங்கையர்களின் பொருளாதாரத்தை புதுப்பிக்கவும், உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பின்மையை எதிர்த்துப் போராடவும், பொது சுகாதாரம் மற்றும் கல்வியை மேம்படுத்தவும் அமெரிக்கா தொடர்ந்து ஆதரவளிக்கும்\" என்று தூதரகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "\"தற்போதைய நெருக்கடிக்கு மிகவும் நீடித்த தீர்வை வழங்கக்கூடிய சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்திடம் இருந்து உதவி பெறுவதற்கான இலங்கையின் முடிவை அமெரிக்காவும் வலுவாக ஆதரிக்கிறது.\"",
        "இலங்கை சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்திற்கு 16 தடவைகள் சென்றும் நாணய நெருக்கடியை முடிவுக்கு கொண்டுவர முடியவில்லை.",
        "இலங்கை, லத்தீன் அமெரிக்காவை பெட் பண மருத்துவர்களால் எப்படி முறியடித்தது, வலிமையானவர்களை, அமெரிக்க எதிர்ப்பை உருவாக்கியது",
        "உள்நாட்டு தனியார் துறையை நசுக்குவதன் மூலம் நாணய மாற்று விகிதத்தை தற்காலிகமாக நிலைநிறுத்த IMF உதவ முடியும் என்றாலும், மத்திய வங்கி ஆக்கிரோஷமான பணப்புழக்க ஊசிகளுக்கு (நெகிழ்வான பணவீக்க இலக்கின் கீழ் இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளுக்குள்) திரும்ப ஊக்குவிக்கப்பட்டு மற்றொரு நாணய நெருக்கடியைத் தூண்டுகிறது.",
        "IMF திட்டத்தின் கீழ், பணவீக்க இலக்கு போன்ற ஒற்றை நங்கூர பண ஆட்சிக்கு நம்பிக்கை இல்லை, பணவீக்க விகிதத்தை இலக்காகக் கொள்ள வேண்டிய கடப்பாடு காரணமாக, நிதியத்திற்கு கடனைத் திருப்பிச் செலுத்த ஒரு இருப்பு சேகரிப்பு பெக்கை இயக்குகிறது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூன்24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "அமெரிக்க கருவூலம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "நிலை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநில துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராபர்ட் கப்ரோத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெல்லி கெய்டர்லிங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைய ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லத்தீன் அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 முதல் 360 வரை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லத்தீன் அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 முதல் 360 வரை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 மில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.75 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "வரும் மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லத்தீன் அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு ஆண்டுகள் வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூன்24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Sri Lanka visited by top US Treasury, State delegation",
  "body_lines": [
    "ECONOMYNEXT – A delegation of top US Treasury and State Department is visiting Sri Lanka as the country reels from a collapse of a soft-peg (flexible exchange rate) backed by conflicting monetary policy.",
    "Members of the delegation include Robert Kaproth, Deputy Assistant Secretary of Treasury for Asia, and Ambassador Kelly Keiderling, Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for South and Central Asia.",
    "“The visitors will meet with a wide range of political representatives, economists, and international organizations,” the US embassy in Colombo said in a statement.",
    "“In all their meetings, they will explore the most effective ways for the U.S. to support Sri Lankans in need, Sri Lankans working to resolve the current economic crisis, and Sri Lankans planning for a sustainable and inclusive economy for the future.”",
    "Sri Lanka which has a Latin America style  pegged central bank with extensive sterilization powers and open market operations, has entered its first default cycle in April 2022 and is casting about for foreign aid after the currency collapsed from 200 to 360 to the US dollar.",
    "Sri Lanka which has a Latin America style  pegged central bank with extensive sterilization powers and open market operations, has entered its first default cycle in April 2022 and is casting about for foreign aid after the currency collapsed from 200 to 360 to the US dollar.",
    "“This visit underscores our ongoing commitment to the security and prosperity of the Sri Lankan people,””.S. Ambassador to Sri Lanka, Julie Chung said in a statement.",
    "“As Sri Lankans endure some of the greatest economic challenges in their history, our efforts to support economic growth and strengthen democratic institutions have never been more critical.”",
    "U.S. has announced120 million in new financing for Sri Lankan small and medium-sized businesses, a 27 million dollars contribution to Sri Lanka’s dairy industry and 5.75 million in humanitarian assistance to help those hit hardest by the flexible exchange rate.",
    "The flexible exchange rate has pushed up food prices beyond the reach of the less affluent classes.",
    "“In the coming months, the U.S. will continue to support Sri Lankans as they revive their economy, combat food insecurity, and promote public health and education,” the embassy said.",
    "“The United States also strongly supports Sri Lanka’s decision to seek assistance from the International Monetary Fund, which can provide the most durable resolution to the present crisis.”",
    "Sri Lanka has gone to the IMF 16 times but has not been able to end currency crises.",
    "How Sri Lanka, Latin America was busted by Fed money doctors creating strongmen, anti-Americanism",
    "Though the IMF can help stabilize the exchange rate temporarily by smashing the domestic private sector the central bank is encouraged to return to aggressive liquidity injections (in as little as two years under flexible inflation targeting) and triggers another currency crisis.",
    "Under an IMF program there is no hope for a single anchor money regime such as inflation targeting, due to the obligation to target the exchange rate, operate a reserve collecting peg to pay back the loan to the Fund. (Colombo/June24/2022)"
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka visited by top US Treasury, State delegation",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – A delegation of top US Treasury and State Department is visiting Sri Lanka as the country reels from a collapse of a soft-peg (flexible exchange rate) backed by conflicting monetary policy.",
        "Members of the delegation include Robert Kaproth, Deputy Assistant Secretary of Treasury for Asia, and Ambassador Kelly Keiderling, Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for South and Central Asia.",
        "“The visitors will meet with a wide range of political representatives, economists, and international organizations,” the US embassy in Colombo said in a statement.",
        "“In all their meetings, they will explore the most effective ways for the U.S. to support Sri Lankans in need, Sri Lankans working to resolve the current economic crisis, and Sri Lankans planning for a sustainable and inclusive economy for the future.”",
        "Sri Lanka which has a Latin America style  pegged central bank with extensive sterilization powers and open market operations, has entered its first default cycle in April 2022 and is casting about for foreign aid after the currency collapsed from 200 to 360 to the US dollar.",
        "Sri Lanka which has a Latin America style  pegged central bank with extensive sterilization powers and open market operations, has entered its first default cycle in April 2022 and is casting about for foreign aid after the currency collapsed from 200 to 360 to the US dollar.",
        "“This visit underscores our ongoing commitment to the security and prosperity of the Sri Lankan people,””.S. Ambassador to Sri Lanka, Julie Chung said in a statement.",
        "“As Sri Lankans endure some of the greatest economic challenges in their history, our efforts to support economic growth and strengthen democratic institutions have never been more critical.”",
        "U.S. has announced120 million in new financing for Sri Lankan small and medium-sized businesses, a 27 million dollars contribution to Sri Lanka’s dairy industry and 5.75 million in humanitarian assistance to help those hit hardest by the flexible exchange rate.",
        "The flexible exchange rate has pushed up food prices beyond the reach of the less affluent classes.",
        "“In the coming months, the U.S. will continue to support Sri Lankans as they revive their economy, combat food insecurity, and promote public health and education,” the embassy said.",
        "“The United States also strongly supports Sri Lanka’s decision to seek assistance from the International Monetary Fund, which can provide the most durable resolution to the present crisis.”",
        "Sri Lanka has gone to the IMF 16 times but has not been able to end currency crises.",
        "How Sri Lanka, Latin America was busted by Fed money doctors creating strongmen, anti-Americanism",
        "Though the IMF can help stabilize the exchange rate temporarily by smashing the domestic private sector the central bank is encouraged to return to aggressive liquidity injections (in as little as two years under flexible inflation targeting) and triggers another currency crisis.",
        "Under an IMF program there is no hope for a single anchor money regime such as inflation targeting, due to the obligation to target the exchange rate, operate a reserve collecting peg to pay back the loan to the Fund. (Colombo/June24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "US Treasury",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "State",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "US Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "State Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Robert Kaproth",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelly Keiderling",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Latin America",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "April 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 to 360",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Latin America",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "April 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 to 360",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 million dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.75 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the coming months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Latin America",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fed",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "anti-Americanism",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "as little as two years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/June24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "එක්සත් ජනපද භාණ්ඩාගාර රාජ්‍ය නියෝජිත පිරිසක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංචාරයක නිරත විය",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - පරස්පර මුදල් ප්‍රතිපත්තියේ පිටුබලය ඇතිව මෘදු-පෙග් (නම්‍යශීලී විනිමය අනුපාතිකය) බිඳවැටීමකින් රට පසුබසින විට එක්සත් ජනපදයේ ඉහළ පෙළේ භාණ්ඩාගාරයේ සහ රාජ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ නියෝජිත පිරිසක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණේ.",
        "දූත පිරිසට ආසියාව සඳහා භාණ්ඩාගාර නියෝජ්‍ය සහකාර ලේකම් Robert Kaproth සහ දකුණු සහ මධ්‍යම ආසියාව සඳහා නියෝජ්‍ය සහකාර රාජ්‍ය ලේකම් තානාපති Kelly Keiderling ඇතුළත් වේ.",
        "“ආගන්තුකයන් පුළුල් පරාසයක දේශපාලන නියෝජිතයන්, ආර්ථික විද්‍යාඥයන් සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර සංවිධාන හමුවනු ඇත,” කොළඹ එක්සත් ජනපද තානාපති කාර්යාලය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "\"ඔවුන්ගේ සියලුම රැස්වීම් වලදී, අවශ්‍යතා ඇති ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින්ට සහාය වීමට එක්සත් ජනපදයට වඩාත් ඵලදායී ක්‍රම, වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදය විසඳීමට වැඩ කරන ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් සහ අනාගතය සඳහා තිරසාර සහ සියල්ලන් ඇතුළත් ආර්ථිකයක් සඳහා සැලසුම් කරන ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් ගවේෂණය කරනු ඇත.\"",
        "ලතින් අමෙරිකානු පන්නයේ විස්තීරණ වන්ධ්‍යාකරණ බලතල සහ විවෘත වෙලඳපොල මෙහෙයුම් සමග සම්බන්ධ වූ මහ බැංකුවක් ඇති ශ්‍රී ලංකාව, 2022 අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී එහි පළමු පැහැර හැරීමේ චක්‍රයට අවතීර්ණ වී ඇති අතර මුදල් ඒකකය එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලරයට 200 සිට 360 දක්වා කඩා වැටීමෙන් පසු විදේශ ආධාර සඳහා යොමු වෙමින් සිටී.",
        "ලතින් අමෙරිකානු පන්නයේ විස්තීරණ වන්ධ්‍යාකරණ බලතල සහ විවෘත වෙලඳපොල මෙහෙයුම් සමග සම්බන්ධ වූ මහ බැංකුවක් ඇති ශ්‍රී ලංකාව, 2022 අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී එහි පළමු පැහැර හැරීමේ චක්‍රයට අවතීර්ණ වී ඇති අතර මුදල් ඒකකය එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලරයට 200 සිට 360 දක්වා කඩා වැටීමෙන් පසු විදේශ ආධාර සඳහා යොමු වෙමින් සිටී.",
        "\"මෙම සංචාරය ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනතාවගේ ආරක්ෂාව සහ සමෘද්ධිය සඳහා අපගේ අඛණ්ඩ කැපවීම අවධාරනය කරයි\". ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තානාපතිනි ජුලී චුන්ග් නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "\"ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් ඔවුන්ගේ ඉතිහාසයේ දැවැන්තම ආර්ථික අභියෝගවලට මුහුණ දෙන බැවින්, ආර්ථික වර්ධනයට සහය වීමට සහ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී ආයතන ශක්තිමත් කිරීමට අප ගන්නා උත්සාහයන් කිසිදා වඩා විවේචනාත්මක නොවීය.\"",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කුඩා හා මධ්‍යම ප්‍රමාණයේ ව්‍යාපාර සඳහා නව මූල්‍යකරණය මිලියන 120 ක්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කිරි කර්මාන්තයට ඩොලර් මිලියන 27 ක දායකත්වයක් සහ නම්‍යශීලී විනිමය අනුපාතයෙන් දැඩි ලෙස පීඩාවට පත් වූවන්ට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා මානුෂීය ආධාර මිලියන 5.75 ක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර ඇත.",
        "නම්‍යශීලී විනිමය අනුපාතිකය අඩු ධනවත් පංතිවලට ළඟාවිය නොහැකි ලෙස ආහාර මිල ඉහළ දමා ඇත.",
        "\"ඉදිරි මාසවලදී, එක්සත් ජනපදය ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින්ට ඔවුන්ගේ ආර්ථිකය පුනර්ජීවනය කිරීම, ආහාර අනාරක්ෂිතභාවයට එරෙහිව සටන් කිරීම සහ මහජන සෞඛ්‍යය සහ අධ්‍යාපනය ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීම සඳහා ඔවුන්ට අඛණ්ඩව සහාය වනු ඇත\" යනුවෙන් තානාපති කාර්යාලය පැවසීය.",
        "\"වර්තමාන අර්බුදයට වඩාත්ම කල්පවත්නා විසඳුම සැපයිය හැකි ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සහය ලබා ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ගත් තීරණයට එක්සත් ජනපදය ද දැඩි ලෙස සහාය දක්වයි.\"",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව 16 වතාවක් ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලට ගොස් ඇති නමුත් මුදල් අර්බුදය අවසන් කිරීමට නොහැකි වී තිබේ.",
        "ශ‍්‍රී ලංකාව, ලතින් ඇමරිකාව ප‍්‍රබලයින්, ඇමරිකානු විරෝධයක් ඇති කරමින් ෆෙඩරල් මුදල් වෛද්‍යවරුන් විසින් බිඳ දැමූ ආකාරය",
        "දේශීය පෞද්ගලික අංශය කඩා බිඳ දැමීමෙන් විනිමය අනුපාතිකය තාවකාලිකව ස්ථාවර කිරීමට ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලට හැකි වුවද, ආක්‍රමණශීලී ද්‍රවශීලතා එන්නත් වෙත ආපසු යාමට (නම්‍යශීලී උද්ධමන ඉලක්ක යටතේ වසර දෙකක් වැනි කෙටි කාලයක් තුළ) මහ බැංකුව දිරිමත් කර තවත් මුදල් අර්බුදයක් ඇති කරයි.",
        "IMF වැඩසටහනක් යටතේ, විනිමය අනුපාතිකය ඉලක්ක කර ගැනීමේ බැඳීම හේතුවෙන්, අරමුදලට ණය ආපසු ගෙවීම සඳහා සංචිත එකතු කිරීමේ කූඩුවක් ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම හේතුවෙන් උද්ධමනය ඉලක්ක කිරීම වැනි තනි නැංගුරම් මුදල් තන්ත්‍රයක් සඳහා බලාපොරොත්තුවක් නොමැත. (කොළඹ/ජුනි24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද භාණ්ඩාගාරය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "රජයේ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද භාණ්ඩාගාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොබට් කප්රොත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙලී කීඩර්ලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලතින් ඇමරිකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 සිට 360 දක්වා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලතින් ඇමරිකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 සිට 360 දක්වා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 27 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 5.75 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලතින් ඇමරිකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆෙඩරල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානු විරෝධය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු දෙකක් වැනි කෙටි කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජුනි24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அமெரிக்காவின் உயர்மட்ட திறைசேரி மற்றும் அரச பிரதிநிதிகள் இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்துள்ளனர்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - முரண்பட்ட நாணயக் கொள்கையின் ஆதரவுடன் ஒரு மென்மையான-பெக் (நெகிழ்வான மாற்று விகிதம்) சரிவில் இருந்து நாடு தத்தளித்து வரும் நிலையில், உயர்மட்ட அமெரிக்க கருவூலம் மற்றும் இராஜாங்கத் திணைக்களத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகள் குழு ஒன்று இலங்கைக்கு வருகை தருகிறது.",
