{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-local-government-official-stabbed-to-death-96906/",
  "time_ut": 1656937380,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka local government official stabbed to death",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka local government official stabbed to death",
      "author": "Neshella Perera",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – The chief administrative officer at a Sri Lankan Pradeshiya Sabha, a type of third tier municipality, was stabbed to death at her residence, police said.",
        "The official, attached to the Lankapura Pradeshiya Sabha in the north central district of Polonnaruwa, had been attacked by an unknown assailant around 2.45am on Monday July 04, police said.",
        "The victim had sustained critical injuries to the head and had succumbed to her wounds en route to hospital.",
        "Police said  the victim’s husband and two children had been asleep in the house, and the husband had seen a person inside their room but was unable to recognise them in the dark.",
        "The Pulasthipura police officer in charge (OIC) told EconomyNext that the two daughters, aged five and 11, are in a state of shock following the incident.",
        "Sri Lanka is going through a worsening economic crisis and there has been an apparent increase in reports of crime, though it is unclear whether this is due to an increase in media reports of such incidents or an actual statistical increase thereof. (Colombo/Jul4/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "a Sri Lankan Pradeshiya Sabha",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Lankapura Pradeshiya Sabha",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polonnaruwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday July 04",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pulasthipura",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "OIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "five and 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jul4/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පළාත් පාලන නිලධාරියෙකු පිහියෙන් ඇන ඝාතනය කරයි",
      "author": "නෙෂෙල්ලා පෙරේරා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාවක ප්‍රධාන පරිපාලන නිලධාරිනිය, තුන්වන මට්ටමේ මහ නගර සභාවක් වන අතර, ඇයගේ නිවසේදී පිහියෙන් ඇන ඝාතනය කර ඇති බව පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "පොළොන්නරුව උතුරු මැද දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ ලංකාපුර ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාවට අනුයුක්තව සේවය කරන මෙම නිලධාරියාට ජූලි 04 සඳුදා අලුයම 2.45 ට පමණ නාඳුනන ප්‍රහාරකයකු විසින් පහර දී ඇති බව පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "පහරකෑමට ලක්වූ කාන්තාවගේ හිසට බරපතළ තුවාල සිදුවී ඇති අතර, තුවාල ලබා රෝහලට රැගෙන යන විටත් ඇය මියගොස් තිබේ.",
        "පොලීසිය පැවසුවේ, වින්දිතයාගේ සැමියා සහ දරුවන් දෙදෙනා නිවසේ නිදා සිට ඇති අතර, සැමියා ඔවුන්ගේ කාමරය තුළ පුද්ගලයෙකු දැක ඇති නමුත් අඳුරේ ඔවුන් හඳුනා ගැනීමට නොහැකි විය.",
        "සිද්ධියෙන් පසු අවුරුදු පහක් සහ එකොළොස් හැවිරිදි දියණියන් දෙදෙනා දැඩි කම්පනයට පත්ව සිටින බව පුලස්තිපුර පොලිසියේ ස්ථානාධිපති (ඕඅයිසී) ඉකොනොමි නෙක්ස්ට් වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව නරක අතට හැරෙන ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකට මුහුණ දෙමින් සිටින අතර අපරාධ වාර්තාවල පෙනෙන වර්ධනයක් දක්නට ඇත, මෙයට හේතුව එවැනි සිදුවීම් පිළිබඳ මාධ්‍ය වාර්තාවල වැඩිවීමක් ද නැතහොත් එහි සත්‍ය සංඛ්‍යාලේඛන වැඩි වීමක් ද යන්න පැහැදිලි නැත. (කොළඹ/ජූලි 4/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාවකි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකාපුර ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොළොන්නරුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 04 සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුලස්තිපුර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්ථානාධිපති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ සහ 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජූලි 4/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை உள்ளூராட்சி அதிகாரி கத்தியால் குத்தி கொல்லப்பட்டார்",
      "author": "நெஷெல்லா பெரேரா",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கை பிரதேச சபையின் தலைமை நிர்வாக அதிகாரி, மூன்றாம் அடுக்கு மாநகரசபையின் ஒரு வகை, அவரது இல்லத்தில் கத்தியால் குத்திக் கொல்லப்பட்டதாக பொலிசார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "பொலன்னறுவையின் வடமத்திய மாவட்டத்திலுள்ள லங்காபுர பிரதேச சபைக்குட்பட்ட அதிகாரி, ஜூலை 04 திங்கட்கிழமை அதிகாலை 2.45 மணியளவில் இனந்தெரியாத ஒருவரால் தாக்கப்பட்டதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இதில் தலையில் பலத்த காயம் அடைந்த சிறுமி மருத்துவமனைக்கு கொண்டு செல்லும் வழியில் உயிரிழந்தார்.",
        "பாதிக்கப்பட்ட பெண்ணின் கணவரும் இரண்டு குழந்தைகளும் வீட்டில் தூங்கிக் கொண்டிருந்ததாகவும், கணவர் அவர்களின் அறைக்குள் ஒரு நபரை பார்த்ததாகவும், ஆனால் இருட்டில் அவர்களை அடையாளம் காண முடியவில்லை என்றும் போலீசார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "புலஸ்திபுர பொலிஸ் பொறுப்பதிகாரி (OIC) EconomyNext க்கு கூறுகையில், ஐந்து மற்றும் 11 வயதுடைய இரண்டு மகள்களும் சம்பவத்தைத் தொடர்ந்து அதிர்ச்சியில் உள்ளனர்.",
        "இலங்கை ஒரு மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை சந்தித்து வருகிறது மற்றும் குற்றச் செயல்கள் பற்றிய அறிக்கைகளில் வெளிப்படையான அதிகரிப்பு உள்ளது, இருப்பினும் இது போன்ற சம்பவங்களின் ஊடக அறிக்கைகளின் அதிகரிப்பு அல்லது அதன் உண்மையான புள்ளிவிவர அதிகரிப்பு என்பது தெளிவாக இல்லை. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை 4/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு இலங்கை பிரதேச சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லங்காபுர பிரதேச சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலன்னறுவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 04 திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புலஸ்திபுரா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "OIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து மற்றும் 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூலை4/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}