{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83537/will-respect-any-decision-taken-at-party-leaders-meeting-president",
  "time_ut": 1657360560,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Will respect any decision taken at party leaders’ meeting - President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Will respect any decision taken at party leaders’ meeting - President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has informed PM Ranil Wickremesinghe that he would respect any decision taken at the meeting of political party leaders, Prime Minister’s Office says.",
        "Earlier today, people in large numbers demanding the resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and the incumbent government stormed the President’s House in Colombo Fort and occupied the premises.",
        "Coinciding with the mass protests in Colombo, anti-government demonstrations were staged in many parts of the island today.",
        "As the protests make strides, PM Wickremesinghe moved to convene a special meeting of political parties to discuss the ongoing situation.",
        "He also requested Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena to summons the parliament immediately."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Earlier today",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PM Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදී ගන්නා ඕනෑම තීරණයකට ගරු කරනවා - ජනපති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දේශපාලන පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදී ගන්නා ඕනෑම තීරණයකට ගරු කරන බව ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට දැනුම් දුන් බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලය පවසයි.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට සහ වත්මන් රජයට ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බවට බලකරමින් විශාල පිරිසක් අද පෙරවරුවේ කොළඹ කොටුවේ පිහිටි ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට කඩා වැදී එම පරිශ්‍රය අත්පත් කර ගත්හ.",
        "කොළඹ පැවති මහජන විරෝධතාවලට සමගාමීව අද දිවයිනේ ප්‍රදේශ රැසක ආණ්ඩු විරෝධී උද්ඝෝෂණ පැවැත්වුණා.",
        "විරෝධතා උත්සන්න වන විට, පවතින තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා විශේෂ දේශපාලන පක්ෂ රැස්වීමක් කැඳවීමට අගමැති වික්‍රමසිංහ පියවර ගත්තේය.",
        "වහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කැඳවන ලෙසද ඔහු කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද කලින්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගමැති වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டத்தில் எடுக்கப்படும் எந்தவொரு தீர்மானத்திற்கும் மதிப்பளிப்பேன் - ஜனாதிபதி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசியல் கட்சித் தலைவர்களின் கூட்டத்தில் எடுக்கப்படும் எந்தவொரு தீர்மானத்திற்கும் மதிப்பளிப்பதாக ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ, பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம் அறிவித்துள்ளதாக பிரதமர் அலுவலகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் தற்போதைய அரசாங்கம் பதவி விலகக் கோரி இன்று அதிகாலை கொழும்பு கோட்டையில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையை முற்றுகையிட்டு பெருமளவான மக்கள் ஆக்கிரமித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "கொழும்பில் இடம்பெற்ற பாரியளவிலான ஆர்ப்பாட்டங்களுக்கு இணையாக, தீவின் பல பாகங்களிலும் இன்று அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிரான ஆர்ப்பாட்டங்கள் முன்னெடுக்கப்பட்டன.",
        "போராட்டங்கள் முன்னேறி வரும் நிலையில், தற்போதைய நிலைமை குறித்து விவாதிக்க பிரதமர் விக்ரமசிங்க அரசியல் கட்சிகளின் சிறப்பு கூட்டத்தை கூட்டினார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தை உடனடியாக கூட்டுமாறு சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தனவிடம் அவர் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முன்னதாக இன்று",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பி.எம். விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}