{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84620/japan-hands-over-food-donation-to-help-sri-lanka-respond-to-rising-food-insecurity",
  "time_ut": 1661798280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Japan hands over food donation to help Sri Lanka respond to rising food insecurity",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Japan hands over food donation to help Sri Lanka respond to rising food insecurity",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The first tranche of food assistance pledged by the Government of Japan earlier this year has been provided through the United Nations World Food Programme (WFP) to Sri Lanka, where more than 6 million people – nearly 30 percent of the population, are facing a worsening food crisis.",
        "Ambassador of Japan to Sri Lanka Mizukoshi Hideaki handed over the donation to Minister of Trade, Commerce and Food Security Nalin Fernando in the presence of WFP Representative and Country Director Abdur Rahim Siddiqui, during a ceremony held at the Ministry of Trade, Commerce and Food Security on Monday.",
        "This first tranche forms part of the donation consisting of rice, lentils, and oil, and valued at US$1.5 million, which will be distributed by WFP to approximately 15,000 people in both urban and rural areas and 380,000 schoolchildren.",
        "Ambassador of Japan to Sri Lanka, Mizukoshi Hideaki said, “It is our great honour that we are able to handover the first tranche of essential food supplies today with the rapid procurement of WFP, which will be delivered to vulnerable families and children across the island who are facing extreme hardship, amidst prevailing food shortages and soaring food prices during this unprecedented economic crisis. We sincerely hope that this humanitarian assistance will provide relief to all the people in need and help them meet their daily nutritional requirement.”",
        "“I thank the people of Japan for this timely contribution. The Japanese Government was one of the first to pledge support to WFP’s appeal. The donation will go a long way in addressing Sri Lanka’s growing food insecurity while shortages of food and other essentials and skyrocketing prices continue to impact millions of people’s ability to maintain an adequate and nutritious diet,” said WFP’s Siddiqui.",
        "A recent survey by WFP and FAO indicates that many of the households – over 60 percent – are resorting to coping mechanisms, such as reducing portion sizes and eating less nutritious food, which could aggravate the already-high malnutrition rates among women and children.",
        "In response, WFP is mobilizing funds and support to provide emergency assistance to 3.4 million people, including 1.4 million people who are in dire need of emergency food assistance, through food, cash or voucher assistance as well one million schoolchildren and one million pregnant and breastfeeding women by supporting the existing national social safety net programmes."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "earlier this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations World Food Programme",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 6 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly 30 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP Representative",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abdur Rahim Siddiqui",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Trade, Commerce and Food Security",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$1.5 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "approximately 15,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "380,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mizukoshi Hideaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Japanese Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "millions",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FAO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "60 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉහළ යන ආහාර අනාරක්ෂිතභාවයට ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා ජපානය ආහාර පරිත්‍යාගයක් භාර දෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මේ වසර මුලදී ජපාන රජය විසින් පොරොන්දු වූ ආහාර ආධාරයේ පළමු වාරිකය එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ලෝක ආහාර වැඩසටහන (WFP) හරහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබා දී ඇති අතර, මිලියන 6 කට වැඩි ජනතාවක් - ජනගහනයෙන් සියයට 30 කට ආසන්න පිරිසක් නරක අතට හැරීමට මුහුණ දී සිටිති. ආහාර අර්බුදය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජපාන තානාපති Mizukoshi Hideaki විසින් වෙළඳ, වාණිජ හා ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතා අමාත්‍ය නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු වෙත මෙම පරිත්‍යාගය WFP නියෝජිත සහ රටේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ අබ්දුර් රහීම් සිද්ධික් මහතා ඉදිරියේ වෙළඳ, වාණිජ හා ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතා අමාත්‍යාංශයේ පැවති උත්සවයකදී භාර දෙන ලදී. සඳුදා.",
        "මෙම පළමු වාරිකය සහල්, පරිප්පු සහ තෙල් වලින් සමන්විත පරිත්‍යාගයේ කොටසක් වන අතර එහි වටිනාකම ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 1.5 ක් වන අතර එය WFP මගින් නාගරික සහ ග්‍රාමීය ප්‍රදේශවල 15,000 කට ආසන්න පිරිසකට සහ පාසල් සිසුන් 380,000 කට බෙදා දෙනු ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජපාන තානාපති Mizukoshi Hideaki මහතා පැවසුවේ, “WFP වේගවත් ප්‍රසම්පාදනය සමඟ අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ආහාර සැපයුම්වල පළමු වාරිකය අද දිනයේදී දිවයින පුරා අවදානමට ලක්විය හැකි පවුල් සහ ළමුන් වෙත ලබා දීමට හැකිවීම අපට මහත් ගෞරවයක්. මෙම පෙර නොවූ විරූ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය තුළ පවතින ආහාර හිඟය සහ ආහාර මිල ඉහළ යාම මධ්‍යයේ දැඩි දුෂ්කරතාවන්ට මුහුණ දී සිටින අය. මෙම මානුෂීය ආධාර මගින් අවශ්‍යතා ඇති සියලුම ජනතාවට සහන සැලසීමට සහ ඔවුන්ගේ දෛනික පෝෂණ අවශ්‍යතා සපුරාලීමට උපකාරී වනු ඇතැයි අපි අවංකවම බලාපොරොත්තු වෙමු.",
        "“මේ කාලෝචිත දායකත්වය වෙනුවෙන් මම ජපානයේ ජනතාවට ස්තූතිවන්ත වෙනවා. WFP හි අභියාචනයට සහය දැක්වීමට ප්‍රථමයෙන් ප්‍රතිඥා දුන්නේ ජපන් රජයයි. ආහාර සහ අනෙකුත් අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය හිඟය සහ අහස උසට නැඟෙන මිල ගණන් ප්‍රමාණවත් හා පෝෂ්‍යදායී ආහාර වේලක් පවත්වා ගැනීමට මිලියන සංඛ්‍යාත ජනතාවට ඇති හැකියාව කෙරෙහි දිගින් දිගටම බලපෑම් කරන අතරම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වර්ධනය වන ආහාර අනාරක්ෂිත භාවයට පිළියම් යෙදීම සඳහා මෙම පරිත්‍යාගය දිගු ගමනක් යනු ඇත.",
        "WFP සහ FAO විසින් මෑතකදී කරන ලද සමීක්ෂණයකින් පෙන්නුම් කරන්නේ බොහෝ කුටුම්භ - සියයට 60 ට වැඩි - කොටස් ප්‍රමාණය අඩු කිරීම සහ අඩු පෝෂ්‍යදායී ආහාර අනුභව කිරීම වැනි, කාන්තාවන් සහ ළමුන් අතර දැනටමත් ඉහළ මන්දපෝෂණ අනුපාතයන් උග්‍ර කළ හැකි යාන්ත්‍රණයන්ට මුහුණ දෙන බවයි.",
        "ඊට ප්‍රතිචාර වශයෙන්, හදිසි ආහාර ආධාර අවශ්‍ය මිලියන 1.4 ක ජනතාවක් ඇතුළුව, ආහාර, මුදල් හෝ වවුචර් ආධාර මෙන්ම පාසල් ළමුන් මිලියනයක් සහ මිලියනයක් ගැබිනි සහ මව්කිරි දීම හරහා මිලියන 3.4 ක ජනතාවකට හදිසි ආධාර සැපයීමට WFP අරමුදල් සහ සහාය ලබා ගනී. දැනට පවතින ජාතික සමාජ ආරක්ෂණ ජාල වැඩසටහන්වලට සහාය දීමෙන් කාන්තාවන්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීට පෙර මෙම වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ලෝක ආහාර වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 6 කට වඩා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 30කට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP නියෝජිත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබ්දුර් රහීම් සිද්දිකි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙළඳ, වාණිජ හා ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතා අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 1.5 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසන්න වශයෙන් 15,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "380,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mizukoshi Hideaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන් රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FAO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 60 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 3.4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියනයක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියනයක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அதிகரித்து வரும் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பின்மைக்கு பதிலளிக்க இலங்கைக்கு உதவ ஜப்பான் உணவு நன்கொடையை வழங்கியுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்த ஆண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில் ஜப்பான் அரசாங்கத்தால் உறுதியளிக்கப்பட்ட உணவு உதவியின் முதல் தவணை ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் உலக உணவுத் திட்டத்தின் (WFP) மூலம் இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது, அங்கு 6 மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான மக்கள் - கிட்டத்தட்ட 30 சதவீத மக்கள், மோசமான நிலையை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளனர். உணவு நெருக்கடி.",
        "வர்த்தக, வர்த்தக மற்றும் உணவு பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சில் நடைபெற்ற நிகழ்வின் போது, ​​இலங்கைக்கான ஜப்பான் தூதுவர் Mizukoshi Hideaki, WFP பிரதிநிதி மற்றும் நாட்டின் பணிப்பாளர் அப்துர் ரஹீம் சித்திக் முன்னிலையில், வர்த்தக, வர்த்தக மற்றும் உணவு பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சர் நலின் பெர்னாண்டோவிடம் நன்கொடையை கையளித்தார். திங்களன்று.",
        "இந்த முதல் தவணை அரிசி, பருப்பு மற்றும் எண்ணெய் ஆகியவற்றை உள்ளடக்கிய நன்கொடையின் ஒரு பகுதியாகும், மேலும் US$1.5 மில்லியன் மதிப்புடையது, இது WFP மூலம் நகர்ப்புற மற்றும் கிராமப்புறங்களில் உள்ள சுமார் 15,000 பேருக்கும் 380,000 பள்ளி மாணவர்களுக்கும் விநியோகிக்கப்படும்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான ஜப்பான் தூதுவர் Mizukoshi Hideaki, “WFP இன் விரைவான கொள்முதல் மூலம் அத்தியாவசிய உணவுப் பொருட்களின் முதல் தவணையை இன்று கையளிப்பது எமக்கு கிடைத்த பெருமையாகும். இந்த முன்னோடியில்லாத பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியின் போது, ​​நிலவும் உணவுப் பற்றாக்குறை மற்றும் உணவுப் பொருட்களின் விலை உயர்வுக்கு மத்தியில், மிகுந்த சிரமத்தை எதிர்கொள்பவர்கள். இந்த மனிதாபிமான உதவியானது தேவைப்படும் அனைத்து மக்களுக்கும் நிவாரணம் வழங்குவதோடு அவர்களின் அன்றாட ஊட்டச்சத்து தேவையை பூர்த்தி செய்ய உதவும் என்று நாங்கள் உண்மையிலேயே நம்புகிறோம்.",
        "“இந்த சரியான நேரத்தில் பங்களிப்பு செய்த ஜப்பான் மக்களுக்கு நான் நன்றி கூறுகிறேன். WFPயின் முறையீட்டிற்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதாக முதலில் உறுதியளித்தவர்களில் ஜப்பானிய அரசும் ஒன்று. இந்த நன்கொடையானது இலங்கையில் அதிகரித்து வரும் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பின்மையை நிவர்த்தி செய்வதில் நீண்ட தூரம் செல்லும் அதேவேளை உணவு மற்றும் இதர அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களின் தட்டுப்பாடு மற்றும் விலைவாசி உயர்வு ஆகியவை மில்லியன் கணக்கான மக்களின் போதுமான மற்றும் சத்தான உணவைப் பராமரிக்கும் திறனைத் தொடர்ந்து பாதிக்கின்றன\" என்று WFP இன் சித்திக் கூறினார்.",
        "WFP மற்றும் FAO இன் சமீபத்திய கணக்கெடுப்பு, பல குடும்பங்கள் - 60 சதவீதத்திற்கும் அதிகமானவை - பகுதி அளவைக் குறைத்தல் மற்றும் குறைவான சத்தான உணவை உட்கொள்வது போன்ற சமாளிப்பதற்கான வழிமுறைகளை நாடுகின்றன, இது ஏற்கனவே பெண்கள் மற்றும் குழந்தைகளிடையே அதிக ஊட்டச்சத்து குறைபாடு விகிதங்களை மோசமாக்கும்.",
        "இதற்குப் பதிலளிக்கும் விதமாக, அவசர உணவு உதவி தேவைப்படும் 1.4 மில்லியன் மக்கள் உட்பட, உணவு, பணம் அல்லது வவுச்சர் உதவி மற்றும் ஒரு மில்லியன் பள்ளிக் குழந்தைகள் மற்றும் ஒரு மில்லியன் கர்ப்பிணி மற்றும் தாய்ப்பால் ஊடாக 3.4 மில்லியன் மக்களுக்கு அவசர உதவி வழங்க WFP நிதி மற்றும் ஆதரவைத் திரட்டுகிறது. தற்போதுள்ள தேசிய சமூக பாதுகாப்பு திட்டங்களுக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதன் மூலம் பெண்கள்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் உலக உணவு திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமானவை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 30 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP பிரதிநிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அப்துர் ரஹீம் சித்திக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வர்த்தகம், வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் உணவு பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$1.5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தோராயமாக 15,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "380,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mizukoshi Hideaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானிய அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மில்லியன்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FAO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "60 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.4 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.4 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}