{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lankas-dhammika-perera-sworn-in-as-minister-of-investment-promotion-96426/",
  "time_ut": 1656077520,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s Dhammika Perera sworn in as Minister of Investment Promotion",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s Dhammika Perera sworn in as Minister of Investment Promotion",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lankan business tycoon Dhammika Perera, who recently entered parliament on the ruling Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) national list, has been appointed Minister of Investment Promotion.",
        "Perera was sworn in before President Gotabaya Rajapaksa Friday June 24 evening, the president’s office said.",
        "Perera entered parliament mid June replacing former Finance Minister Basil Rajapaksa on the SLPP national list. (Colombo/Jun24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dhammika Perera",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday June 24 evening",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "mid June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jun24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ධම්මික පෙරේරා ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දෙයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආර්ථීකය - පාලක ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවෙන් මෑතකදී පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පිවිසි ශ්‍රී ලංකා ව්‍යාපාරික ධම්මික පෙරේරා ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස පත් කර ඇත.",
        "පෙරේරා ජූනි 24 සිකුරාදා සවස ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන් බව ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලය පවසයි.",
        "පෙරේරා ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවෙන් හිටපු මුදල් අමාත්‍ය බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ වෙනුවට ජූනි මස මැදදී පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පිවිසියේය. (කොළඹ/ජුනි24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 24 සිකුරාදා සවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි මැද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජුනි24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு அமைச்சராக இலங்கையின் தம்மிக்க பெரேரா பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - அண்மையில் ஆளும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன (SLPP) தேசியப் பட்டியலில் நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் நுழைந்த இலங்கை வர்த்தக அதிபர் தம்மிக்க பெரேரா, முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு அமைச்சராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "பெரேரா ஜூன் 24 வெள்ளிக்கிழமை மாலை ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ முன்னிலையில் பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்து கொண்டதாக ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "பெரேரா SLPP தேசிய பட்டியலில் முன்னாள் நிதி அமைச்சர் பசில் ராஜபக்ஷவிற்கு பதிலாக ஜூன் நடுப்பகுதியில் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு நுழைந்தார். (கொழும்பு/ஜூன்24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளிக்கிழமை ஜூன் 24 மாலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் நடுப்பகுதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூன்24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Sri Lanka’s Dhammika Perera sworn in as Minister of Investment Promotion",
  "body_lines": [
    "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lankan business tycoon Dhammika Perera, who recently entered parliament on the ruling Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) national list, has been appointed Minister of Investment Promotion.",
    "Perera was sworn in before President Gotabaya Rajapaksa Friday June 24 evening, the president’s office said.",
    "Perera entered parliament mid June replacing former Finance Minister Basil Rajapaksa on the SLPP national list. (Colombo/Jun24/2022)"
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s Dhammika Perera sworn in as Minister of Investment Promotion",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lankan business tycoon Dhammika Perera, who recently entered parliament on the ruling Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) national list, has been appointed Minister of Investment Promotion.",
        "Perera was sworn in before President Gotabaya Rajapaksa Friday June 24 evening, the president’s office said.",
        "Perera entered parliament mid June replacing former Finance Minister Basil Rajapaksa on the SLPP national list. (Colombo/Jun24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dhammika Perera",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday June 24 evening",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "mid June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jun24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ධම්මික පෙරේරා ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දෙයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආර්ථීකය - පාලක ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවෙන් මෑතකදී පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පිවිසි ශ්‍රී ලංකා ව්‍යාපාරික ධම්මික පෙරේරා ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස පත් කර ඇත.",
        "පෙරේරා ජූනි 24 සිකුරාදා සවස ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන් බව ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලය පවසයි.",
        "පෙරේරා ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවෙන් හිටපු මුදල් අමාත්‍ය බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ වෙනුවට ජූනි මස මැදදී පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පිවිසියේය. (කොළඹ/ජුනි24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 24 සිකුරාදා සවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි මැද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජුනි24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு அமைச்சராக இலங்கையின் தம்மிக்க பெரேரா பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - அண்மையில் ஆளும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன (SLPP) தேசியப் பட்டியலில் நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் நுழைந்த இலங்கை வர்த்தக அதிபர் தம்மிக்க பெரேரா, முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு அமைச்சராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "பெரேரா ஜூன் 24 வெள்ளிக்கிழமை மாலை ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ முன்னிலையில் பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்து கொண்டதாக ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "பெரேரா SLPP தேசிய பட்டியலில் முன்னாள் நிதி அமைச்சர் பசில் ராஜபக்ஷவிற்கு பதிலாக ஜூன் நடுப்பகுதியில் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு நுழைந்தார். (கொழும்பு/ஜூன்24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளிக்கிழமை ஜூன் 24 மாலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் நடுப்பகுதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூன்24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}