{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/business-news/Lankan-envoy-says-IMF-agreement-gives-much-needed-confidence-to-lure-investors/273-244247",
  "time_ut": 1662141960,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Lankan envoy says IMF agreement gives much-needed confidence to lure investors",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Lankan envoy says IMF agreement gives much-needed confidence to lure investors",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lankan High Commissioner to India Milinda Moragoda with Indian Finance and Corporate Affairs Minister Smt. Nirmala Sitharaman at a meeting in April 2022 in New Delhi",
        "Points out India is ‘only partner’, which stepped up to help SL, when it didn’t have any programme",
        "Sri Lankan High Commissioner to India Milinda Moragoda expressed gratitude to neighbouring giant India for its support in helping the crisis nation reach out to the International Monetary Fund (IMF) and said the firming up of the first step with the agency has given the much-needed confidence to lure investments.",
        "Moragoda shared that with the IMF agreement taking shape, Sri Lanka now expects more countries to offer assistance. He highlighted that India was the ‘only partner’ to have stepped up even without a framework in place.",
        "“The key fact here is that having the staff-level agreement gives us confidence. The money is not huge but it gives us confidence — one for investors to come in, maybe for our remittances, which have dropped by half to increase and also for other bilaterals like Japan to come,” said Moragoda while speaking at The Indian Express Idea Exchange on Thursday.",
        "“We are grateful to India, which encouraged us to go to the IMF. Finance Minister (Nirmala) Sitharaman and External Affairs Minister S. Jaishankar played a role in that. India was the only country, the only partner, which stepped up without us having any kind of programme,” he added.",
        "This week, the Sri Lankan authorities and IMF team reached a staff-level agreement to support the authorities’ economic adjustment and reform policies with a new 48-month Extended Fund Facility (EFF), with a requested access of US $ 2.9 billion.",
        "Earlier this year, Sri Lanka, battling the worst economic crisis in its history, had plunged into unprecedented turmoil, with an acute shortage of essentials such as fuel and medicine triggering massive protests, which forced Gotabaya Rajapaksa to flee the country and resign as the President, a post taken over by Ranil Wickremesinghe. Following the IMF package, Moragada identified power, oil and tourism as some of the areas where structural reforms, through cooperation with India, can help restore macroeconomic stability. India, he said, can explore developing the port city of Trincomalee as an energy hub."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Lankan",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Smt",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nirmala Sitharaman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "April 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "half",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moragoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Indian Express Idea Exchange",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nirmala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "This week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 2.9 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Earlier this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moragada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "IMF ගිවිසුම ආයෝජකයින් ආකර්ෂණය කර ගැනීමට අවශ්‍ය විශ්වාසය ලබා දෙන බව ලංකා නියෝජිතයා පවසයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දියාවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් මිලින්ද මොරගොඩ සහ ඉන්දීය මුදල් හා ආයතනික කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය ශ්‍රී. නිර්මලා සීතාරාමන් 2022 අප්‍රේල් මාසයේ නවදිල්ලියේ පැවති රැස්වීමකදී",
        "කිසිදු වැඩපිළිවෙලක් නොමැති විට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට උදව් කිරීමට පියවර ගත් ඉන්දියාව ‘එකම හවුල්කරු’ බව පෙන්වා දෙයි.",
        "ඉන්දියාවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් මිලින්ද මොරගොඩ, අර්බුදකාරී ජාතියට ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) වෙත ළඟා වීමට උපකාර කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අසල්වැසි දැවැන්ත ඉන්දියාවට කෘතඥතාව පළ කළ අතර, නියෝජිතායතනය සමඟ පළමු පියවර ස්ථිර කිරීම බොහෝ අවශ්‍යතා ලබා දී ඇති බව පැවසීය. ආයෝජන ආකර්ෂණය කර ගැනීමට විශ්වාසය.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ගිවිසුම හැඩගැසීමත් සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දැන් තවත් රටවල් ආධාර කරනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කරන බව මොරගොඩ මහතා පැවසීය. රාමුවක් නොමැතිව වුවද ඉදිරියට ගිය ‘එකම සහකරු’ ඉන්දියාව බව ඔහු අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "“මෙහි ඇති ප්‍රධාන කරුණ නම් කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමක් තිබීම අපට විශ්වාසයක් ඇති කරයි. මුදල් විශාල නොවේ, නමුත් එය අපට විශ්වාසයක් ලබා දෙයි - ආයෝජකයින්ට පැමිණීමට, සමහර විට අපගේ ප්‍රේෂණ, අඩකින් අඩු වී ඇති අතර, ජපානය වැනි අනෙකුත් ද්විපාර්ශ්වික පැමිණීම සඳහා, ”මොරගොඩ ද ඉන්දියන් එක්ස්ප්‍රස් අයිඩියා හි අදහස් දක්වමින් පැවසීය. බ්රහස්පතින්දා හුවමාරු කරන්න.",
        "“IMF වෙත යාමට අපව දිරිමත් කළ ඉන්දියාවට අපි කෘතඥ වෙනවා. මුදල් අමාත්‍ය (නිර්මලා) සීතාරාමන් සහ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය එස්. ජයශංකර් එහි කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කළහ. අපට කිසිදු ආකාරයක වැඩසටහනක් නොමැතිව ඉදිරියට ගිය එකම රට, එකම හවුල්කරුවා ඉන්දියාවයි, ”ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "මෙම සතියේ, ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලධාරීන් සහ IMF කණ්ඩායම, නව මාස 48ක විස්තීරණ අරමුදල් පහසුකම (EFF) සමඟ බලධාරීන්ගේ ආර්ථික ගැලපීම් සහ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ ප්‍රතිපත්තිවලට සහාය වීම සඳහා කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ එකඟතාවයකට එළැඹී ඇත.",
        "මේ වසර මුලදී, සිය ඉතිහාසයේ දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සමඟ පොරබදමින් සිටි ශ්‍රී ලංකාව, පෙර නොවූ විරූ කැළඹීමකට ඇද වැටුණු අතර, ඉන්ධන සහ ඖෂධ වැනි අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍යවල උග්‍ර හිඟයක් දැවැන්ත විරෝධතා ඇති කරමින්, ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂට රටින් පැන ගොස් ජනාධිපති ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට සිදුවිය. , රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් පවරා ගන්නා ලද තනතුරකි. ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ පැකේජය අනුගමනය කරමින්, මොරගඩා විසින් ඉන්දියාව සමඟ සහයෝගීතාවයෙන් ව්‍යුහාත්මක ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ මගින් සාර්ව ආර්ථික ස්ථාවරත්වය යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් කිරීමට උපකාරී වන ක්ෂේත්‍ර කිහිපයක් ලෙස විදුලිය, තෙල් සහ සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරය හඳුනාගෙන ඇත. ත්‍රිකුණාමලය වරාය නගරය බලශක්ති කේන්ද්‍රස්ථානයක් ලෙස සංවර්ධනය කිරීම පිළිබඳව ඉන්දියාවට ගවේෂණය කළ හැකි බව ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලාංකික",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Smt",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිර්මලා සීතාරාමන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඩක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොරගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු එක්ස්ප්‍රස් අදහස් හුවමාරුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිර්මලා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්. ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මීට පෙර මෙම වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොරගොඩ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "IMF உடன்படிக்கை முதலீட்டாளர்களை கவருவதற்கு தேவையான நம்பிக்கையை அளிக்கிறது என்று இலங்கை தூதுவர் கூறுகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்தியாவிற்கான இலங்கை உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் மிலிந்த மொரகொடவுடன் இந்திய நிதி மற்றும் பெருநிறுவன விவகார அமைச்சர் ஸ்ரீமதி. நிர்மலா சீதாராமன் ஏப்ரல் 2022 இல் புது டெல்லியில் ஒரு கூட்டத்தில்",
        "எந்தவொரு திட்டமும் இல்லாத நிலையில், இலங்கைக்கு உதவ முன்வந்த இந்தியா ‘ஒரே கூட்டாளி’ என்று சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "இந்தியாவுக்கான இலங்கை உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் மிலிந்த மொரகொட, நெருக்கடியான நாடு சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தை (IMF) அடைய உதவிய அண்டை நாடான இந்தியாவுக்கு நன்றி தெரிவித்ததுடன், நிறுவனத்துடனான முதல் படியை உறுதிப்படுத்துவது மிகவும் தேவையானதை அளித்துள்ளது என்றார். முதலீடுகளை ஈர்க்கும் நம்பிக்கை.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் உடன்படிக்கை வடிவமைத்துள்ள நிலையில், இலங்கை தற்போது மேலும் பல நாடுகள் உதவிகளை வழங்கும் என எதிர்பார்ப்பதாக மொரகொட பகிர்ந்து கொண்டார். ஒரு கட்டமைப்பு இல்லாமல் கூட முன்னேறிய ‘ஒரே கூட்டாளி’ இந்தியாதான் என்பதை அவர் எடுத்துரைத்தார்.",
        "\"இங்குள்ள முக்கிய உண்மை என்னவென்றால், ஊழியர்கள் அளவிலான ஒப்பந்தம் எங்களுக்கு நம்பிக்கை அளிக்கிறது. பணம் பெரியதாக இல்லை, ஆனால் அது எங்களுக்கு நம்பிக்கையை அளிக்கிறது - முதலீட்டாளர்கள் வருவதற்கு ஒன்று, ஒருவேளை நமது பணம் அனுப்புதல் பாதியாக குறைந்துள்ளது, மேலும் ஜப்பான் போன்ற மற்ற இருதரப்பு நாடுகளுக்கும் வரலாம், ”என்று மொரகோடா தி இந்தியன் எக்ஸ்பிரஸ் ஐடியாவில் பேசும்போது கூறினார். வியாழன் அன்று பரிமாற்றம்.",
        "IMF க்கு செல்ல எங்களை ஊக்கப்படுத்திய இந்தியாவுக்கு நாங்கள் நன்றியுள்ளவர்களாக இருக்கிறோம். அதில் நிதியமைச்சர் (நிர்மலா) சீதாராமன் மற்றும் வெளியுறவுத்துறை அமைச்சர் எஸ். ஜெய்சங்கர் ஆகியோர் பங்கு வகித்தனர். எங்களிடம் எந்த விதமான திட்டமும் இல்லாமல் முன்னேறிய ஒரே நாடு, ஒரே கூட்டாளியாக இந்தியா மட்டுமே இருந்தது,” என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "இந்த வாரம், இலங்கை அதிகாரிகளும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியக் குழுவும், 2.9 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்கள் கோரப்பட்ட அணுகலுடன், புதிய 48 மாத விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட நிதி வசதியுடன் (EFF) அதிகாரிகளின் பொருளாதார சரிசெய்தல் மற்றும் சீர்திருத்தக் கொள்கைகளை ஆதரிப்பதற்கான பணியாளர் அளவிலான உடன்பாட்டை எட்டியது.",
        "இந்த ஆண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில், தனது வரலாற்றில் மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொண்ட இலங்கை, வரலாறு காணாத கொந்தளிப்பில் மூழ்கியது, எரிபொருள் மற்றும் மருந்து போன்ற அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களின் கடுமையான தட்டுப்பாடு பாரிய எதிர்ப்புகளைத் தூண்டியது, இது கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவை நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறி ஜனாதிபதி பதவியை ராஜினாமா செய்ய வேண்டிய கட்டாயம் ஏற்பட்டது. , ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் பொறுப்பேற்ற ஒரு பதவி. IMF தொகுப்பைத் தொடர்ந்து, மொரகடா, இந்தியாவுடனான ஒத்துழைப்பு மூலம் கட்டமைப்பு சீர்திருத்தங்கள், மேக்ரோ பொருளாதார ஸ்திரத்தன்மையை மீட்டெடுக்க உதவும் சில பகுதிகளாக மின்சாரம், எண்ணெய் மற்றும் சுற்றுலாவை அடையாளம் கண்டுள்ளது. துறைமுக நகரமான திருகோணமலையை எரிசக்தி மையமாக மேம்படுத்துவது குறித்து இந்தியா ஆராய முடியும் என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீமதி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிர்மலா சீதாராமன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதி",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொரகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன் எக்ஸ்பிரஸ் ஐடியா எக்ஸ்சேஞ்ச்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிர்மலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ். ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 2.9 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொரகடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}