{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/stepped-up-share-buying-by-foreigners-as-cse-begins-politically-crucial-week-on-positive-note/",
  "time_ut": 1658249700,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Stepped-up share-buying by foreigners as CSE begins politically crucial week on positive note",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Stepped-up share-buying by foreigners as CSE begins politically crucial week on positive note",
      "author": "Sahan Weerasooriya",
      "body_lines": [
        "The CSE began the politically crucial week on a positive note as overall investor activity improved with foreigners stepping- up share-buying yesterday. Net foreign- buying notched a six-week high of Rs. 123 million with JKH accounting for Rs. 122 million. So far in July there has been a net inflow of Rs. 360 million, stock observers said.",
        "Over the last three weeks price appreciations were witnessed in plantation sector counters and at the tea auctions, all three elevations of low grown, mid grown and upper grown tea prices increased, which gave some impetus to the stock market, analysts said.",
        "The market ended on a positive note with the All- Share Price Index gaining 107.51 points (1.43 per cent) to end at 7644 and S and P SL20 rose by 51.03 points (2.11 per cent) to end the day at 2474.11. Turnover stood at Rs 1.12 billion with a single crossing. The crossing was reported in Melstacorp, which crossed 2.9 million shares to the tune of Rs 116 million, its shares traded at Rs 40.50.",
        "In the retail market top six companies that mainly contributed to the turnover were, Expolanka Holdings Rs 138 million (766,000 shares traded), Lanka IOC Rs 116 million (1.5 million shares traded), Browns Investments Rs 77.9 million (9.6 million shares traded), Hayleys Rs 52.2 million (742,000 shares traded), Kotagala Plantations Rs 46.9 million (9.1million shares traded) and Agalawatte Plantations Rs 35.6 million (960,000 shares traded). During the day 66.8 million share volumes changed hands in 15659 transactions,",
        "It is said high net worth and institutional investor participation was noted in JKH and Teejay Lanka. Mixed interest was observed in Hayleys, Lanka IOC and Expolanka Holdings, while retail interest was noted in Browns Investments, LOLC Finance and ACME Printing & Packaging (rights).",
        "Yesterday, the Central Bank- announced US dollar parity rate was Rs 358.94. ‘The Central Bank’s prudent monetary policies have stabilized the rupee against the dollar to a greater extent. Probably, the crude oil price surge in the global market will cushion the inflation pressure in the economy, some economists said.",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "six-week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "123 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "JKH",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "122 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "360 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the last three weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "All-",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "107.51",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.43 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "51.03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.11 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2474.11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs 1.12 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Melstacorp",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.9 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "116 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40.50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "138 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "766,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka IOC Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "116 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.5 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Browns Investments",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "77.9 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.6 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "52.2 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "742,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kotagala Plantations Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "46.9 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.1million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Agalawatte Plantations Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "35.6 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "960,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "66.8 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "15659",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Teejay Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hayleys",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "IOC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Expolanka Holdings",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Browns Investments",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ACME Printing & Packaging",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "358.94",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "CSE දේශපාලනික වශයෙන් තීරණාත්මක සතිය ධනාත්මක සටහනකින් ආරම්භ වීමත් සමඟ විදේශිකයන් විසින් කොටස් මිල දී ගැනීම ඉහළ යයි",
      "author": "සහන් වීරසූරිය",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඊයේ දිනයේ විදේශිකයන් විසින් කොටස් මිලදී ගැනීම් ඉහළ යාමත් සමඟ සමස්ත ආයෝජක ක්‍රියාකාරකම් වැඩිදියුණු වීමත් සමඟ CSE දේශපාලනික වශයෙන් තීරණාත්මක සතිය ධනාත්මක සටහනකින් ආරම්භ විය. ශුද්ධ විදේශ-මිලදී ගැනීම සති හයක ඉහළම අගය රු. මිලියන 123 ක් JKH ගිණුම සමඟ රු. මිලියන 122 කි. ජුලි මාසයේ මේ දක්වා ශුද්ධ ගලා ඒම රු. මිලියන 360 ක් බව කොටස් නිරීක්ෂකයෝ පවසති.",
        "පසුගිය සති තුනක කාලය තුළ වතුකරයේ කවුන්ටරවල මිල ඉහළ යාමක් දක්නට ලැබුණු අතර තේ වෙන්දේසියේදී අඩු වගා, මධ්‍යම හා ඉහළ තේ යන තේ මිල ඉහළ යෑම් තුනම ඉහළ ගිය අතර, එය කොටස් වෙළෙඳපොළට යම් ප්‍රබෝධයක් ලබා දුන් බව විශ්ලේෂකයෝ පවසති.",
        "සියලු කොටස් මිල දර්ශකය ඒකක 107.51කින් (සියයට 1.43කින්) ඉහළ ගොස් 7644 දක්වාත්, S සහ P SL20 ඒකක 51.03කින් (සියයට 2.11කින්) ඉහළ ගොස් 2474.11ක් වීමත් සමඟ වෙළෙඳ පොළ ධනාත්මක තත්ත්වයකින් අවසන් විය. එක් හරස් මාර්ගයකින් පිරිවැටුම රුපියල් බිලියන 1.12 ක් විය. මෙම හරස් කිරීම Melstacorp හි වාර්තා වූ අතර, එය රුපියල් මිලියන 2.9 ක කොටස් මිලියන 116 ක් ඉක්මවා ගිය අතර, එහි කොටස් රුපියල් 40.50 ට ගනුදෙනු විය.",
        "සිල්ලර වෙළඳපොලේ පිරිවැටුම සඳහා ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් දායක වූ ප්‍රමුඛ සමාගම් හය නම්, එක්ස්පෝලංකා හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් රුපියල් මිලියන 138 (කොටස් 766,000ක් ගනුදෙනු), ලංකා අයිඕසී රුපියල් මිලියන 116 (කොටස් මිලියන 1.5ක් ගනුදෙනු), බ්‍රවුන්ස් ඉන්වෙස්ට්මන්ට්ස් රුපියල් මිලියන 77.9 (කොටස් මිලියන 9.6ක් ගනුදෙනු), හේලීස් රුපියල් මිලියන 52.2ක් (කොටස් 742,000ක් ගනුදෙනු කර ඇත), කොටගල වැවිලි සමාගම රුපියල් මිලියන 46.9ක් (කොටස් මිලියන 9.1ක් ගනුදෙනු කර ඇත) සහ අගලවත්ත වැවිලි සමාගම රුපියල් මිලියන 35.6ක් (කොටස් 960,000ක් ගනුදෙනු කර ඇත). දවස තුළ ගනුදෙනු 15659 කදී කොටස් වෙළුම් මිලියන 66.8 ක් වෙනස් විය.",
        "JKH සහ Teejay Lanka හි ඉහළ ශුද්ධ වටිනාකමක් සහ ආයතනික ආයෝජකයින්ගේ සහභාගීත්වය සටහන් වූ බව පැවසේ. Hayleys, Lanka IOC සහ Expolanka Holdings හි මිශ්‍ර පොලී නිරීක්ෂණය වූ අතර Browns Investments, LOLC Finance සහ ACME මුද්‍රණ සහ ඇසුරුම් (අයිතිවාසිකම්) සඳහා සිල්ලර පොලී සටහන් විය.",
        "ඊයේ, මහ බැංකුව විසින් නිවේදනය කරන ලද එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලරයේ සමානාත්මතා අනුපාතය රුපියල් 358.94 කි. ‘මහ බැංකුවේ විචක්ෂණශීලී මූල්‍ය ප්‍රතිපත්ති නිසා ඩොලරයට සාපේක්ෂව රුපියල විශාල වශයෙන් ස්ථාවර වී තිබෙනවා. සමහර ආර්ථික විද්‍යාඥයින් පවසන්නේ ගෝලීය වෙළෙඳපොළේ බොරතෙල් මිල ඉහළ යාම ආර්ථිකයේ උද්ධමන පීඩනය අඩු කරනු ඇති බවයි.",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති හය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 123 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජේ.කේ.එච්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 122 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 360 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සති තුන",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියලුම-",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "107.51 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 1.43 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "51.03 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 2.11 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2474.11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල් බිලියන 1.12 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Melstacorp",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 2.9 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 116 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40.50 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 138 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "766,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා IOC රු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 116 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.5 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රවුන්ස් ආයෝජන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 77.9 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 9.6 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 52.2 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "742,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටගල වැවිලි රු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 46.9 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 9.1 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගලවත්ත වැවිලි රු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 35.6 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "960,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 66.8 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "15659",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ටීජේ ලංකා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හේලීස්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයි.ඕ.සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්පෝලංකා හෝල්ඩිංග්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රවුන්ස් ආයෝජන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC ෆිනෑන්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ACME මුද්‍රණ සහ ඇසුරුම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "358.94 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "CSE அரசியல் ரீதியாக முக்கியமான வாரத்தை நேர்மறையான குறிப்பில் தொடங்குவதால் வெளிநாட்டினரின் பங்குகளை வாங்குவது அதிகரித்துள்ளது.",
      "author": "சஹான் வீரசூரிய",
      "body_lines": [
        "சிஎஸ்இ அரசியல் ரீதியாக முக்கியமான வாரத்தை நேர்மறையான குறிப்பில் தொடங்கியது, ஒட்டுமொத்த முதலீட்டாளர் செயல்பாடுகள் நேற்று வெளிநாட்டவர்கள் பங்குகளை வாங்குவதை அதிகரித்தனர். நிகர வெளிநாட்டு கொள்முதல் ஆறு வாரங்களில் அதிகபட்சமாக ரூ. 123 மில்லியன் JKH கணக்கில் ரூ. 122 மில்லியன். ஜூலை மாதத்தில் இதுவரை நிகர வருமானம் ரூ. 360 மில்லியன் என்று பங்கு பார்வையாளர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "கடந்த மூன்று வாரங்களாக தோட்டத் துறை கவுன்டர்களில் விலை ஏற்றம் காணப்பட்டது மற்றும் தேயிலை ஏலத்தில் குறைந்த விளைச்சல், நடுத்தர மற்றும் மேல் விளைந்த தேயிலை விலைகள் ஆகிய மூன்று உயர்வும் அதிகரித்தது, இது பங்குச் சந்தைக்கு சில உத்வேகத்தை அளித்தது என்று ஆய்வாளர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "அனைத்துப் பங்கு விலைக் குறியீடு 107.51 புள்ளிகள் (1.43 சதவீதம்) அதிகரித்து 7644 ஆகவும், S மற்றும் P SL20 51.03 புள்ளிகள் (2.11 சதவீதம்) உயர்ந்து 2474.11 ஆகவும் முடிவுற்றது. விற்றுமுதல் ஒருமுறை கடக்க ரூ.1.12 பில்லியனாக இருந்தது. மெல்ஸ்டாகார்ப் நிறுவனத்தில் 2.9 மில்லியன் பங்குகளைத் தாண்டி ரூ. 116 மில்லியனுக்கும், அதன் பங்குகள் ரூ. 40.50க்கும் வர்த்தகமானது.",
        "சில்லறை விற்பனைச் சந்தையில், எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் ரூ. 138 மில்லியன் (766,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), லங்கா ஐஓசி ரூ. 116 மில்லியன் (1.5 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), பிரவுன்ஸ் இன்வெஸ்ட்மென்ட்ஸ் ரூ. 77.9 மில்லியன் (9.6 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), ஹேலிஸ் ரூ 52.2 மில்லியன் (742,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), கொட்டகலை பிளான்டேஷன்ஸ் ரூ 46.9 மில்லியன் (9.1 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்) மற்றும் அகலவத்தை பிளான்டேஷன்ஸ் ரூ 35.6 மில்லியன் (960,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்). நாளின் போது 15659 பரிவர்த்தனைகளில் 66.8 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் கைமாறின.",
        "JKH மற்றும் டீஜே லங்காவில் அதிக நிகர மதிப்பு மற்றும் நிறுவன முதலீட்டாளர் பங்கேற்பு குறிப்பிடப்பட்டதாக கூறப்படுகிறது. ஹேலிஸ், லங்கா ஐஓசி மற்றும் எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் ஆகியவற்றில் கலப்பு ஆர்வம் காணப்பட்டது, அதே சமயம் பிரவுன்ஸ் இன்வெஸ்ட்மென்ட்ஸ், எல்ஓஎல்சி ஃபினான்ஸ் மற்றும் ஏசிஎம்இ பிரிண்டிங் & பேக்கேஜிங் (உரிமைகள்) ஆகியவற்றில் சில்லறை வட்டி குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "நேற்று, மத்திய வங்கி-அறிவித்த அமெரிக்க டாலர் சமநிலை விகிதம் ரூ.358.94. ‘மத்திய வங்கியின் விவேகமான பணவியல் கொள்கைகள் டொலருக்கு எதிரான ரூபாவை அதிகளவிற்கு உறுதிப்படுத்தியுள்ளது. அநேகமாக, உலக சந்தையில் கச்சா எண்ணெய் விலை ஏற்றம் பொருளாதாரத்தில் பணவீக்க அழுத்தத்தைக் குறைக்கும் என்று சில பொருளாதார வல்லுநர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "123 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.கே.எச்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "122 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "360 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மூன்று வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனைத்தும்-",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "107.51",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.43 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "51.03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.11 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2474.11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ 1.12 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெல்ஸ்டாகார்ப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.9 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "116 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40.50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "138 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "766,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கா ஐஓசி ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "116 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரவுன்ஸ் முதலீடுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "77.9 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.6 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "52.2 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "742,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொட்டகலை தோட்டங்கள் ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "46.9 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.1 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அகலவத்தை தோட்டங்கள் ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "35.6 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "960,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "66.8 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "15659",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டீஜய் லங்கா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹேலிஸ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐஓசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரவுன்ஸ் முதலீடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ACME பிரிண்டிங் & பேக்கேஜிங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "358.94",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}