{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/හමුදා-සෙබලා-සහල්-කිලෝ-25ක්-උස්සා-මාට්ටු/11-395003",
  "time_ut": 1656651790,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "හමුදා සෙබලා සහල් කිලෝ 25ක් උස්සා මාට්ටු",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Troops seize 25 kilos of rice",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "An army soldier was arrested yesterday (30) by the Monaragala police in connection with the theft of 25 kilos of rice loaded in a three-wheeler in Monaragala town.",
        "A resident of Obbegoda, the owner of the three-wheeler, had complained to the police that someone had stolen 25 kilos of rice from a three-wheeler while it was stopped in the center of Monaragala on the 25th.",
        "The Monaragala police, who conducted an investigation into the incident through the nearby CCTV camera footage, arrested a thirty-three-year-old army sergeant working at Kurunegala Boyagane military camp, a resident of Moneragala Hulandawa South Gemunupura area.",
        "Monaragala Headquarters Police Inspector PS Charminda Sanjeeva is conducting investigations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "25 kilos",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monaragala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 kilos",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monaragala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Obbegoda",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 kilos",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monaragala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 25th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monaragala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CCTV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "thirty-three-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala Boyagane",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moneragala Hulandawa South Gemunupura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monaragala Headquarters Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PS Charminda Sanjeeva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හමුදා සෙබලා සහල් කිලෝ 25ක් උස්සා මාට්ටු",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මොනරාගල නගරයේදී ත්‍රීරෝද රථයක පටවා තිබූ සහල් කිලෝ 25 සොරකම්කිරීමේ සිද්ධියක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් යුද හමුදා සෙබලෙකු පෙරේදා (30) මොනරාගල පොලීසිය මඟින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "ත්‍රීරෝද රථයක ඉකුත් 25 වෙනි දින මොනරාගල නගරයේ මධ්‍යයේ නතරකර තිබියදී එහි තිබූ සහල් කිලෝ 25 කිසියම් අයෙකු සොරකම්කර ඇති බව ත්‍රීරෝද රථයේ හිමිකරු වන ඔබ්බේගොඩ ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිකරුවෙකු පොලීසියට පැමිණිලිකර තිබිණි.",
        "ඒ අසල වූ සීසීටීවී කැමරා දර්ශන ඔස්සේ සිද්ධිය පිළිබඳව පරීක්ෂණ පැවැත්වූ මොනරාගල පොලීසිය මොනරාගල හුලංදාව දකුණ ගැමුණුපුර ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි කුරුණෑගල බෝයගනේ යුදහමුදා කඳවුරේ සේවයකරන තිස්තුන් හැවිරිදි යුදහමුදා සැරයන්වරයෙකු අත්අඩංගුවටගෙන ඇත.",
        "මොනරාගල මූලස්ථාන පොලිස් පරීක්ෂක පී.එස් චාමින්ද සංජීව මහතා පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කිලෝ 25 යි",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොනරාගල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ 25 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොනරාගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඔබ්බේගොඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ 25 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොනරාගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මොනරාගල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීසීටීවී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිස්තුන් හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala Boyagane",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොණරාගල හුලංදාව දකුණු ගැමුණුපුර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මොනරාගල මූලස්ථාන පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PS චාමින්ද සංජීව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "25 கிலோ அரிசியை எடுத்துச் சென்ற இராணுவ வீரர்கள் பிடிபட்டனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மொனராகலை நகரில் முச்சக்கர வண்டியில் ஏற்றிச் செல்லப்பட்ட 25 கிலோ அரிசி திருடப்பட்ட சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் இராணுவ சிப்பாய் ஒருவர் மொனராகலை பொலிஸாரால் நேற்று (30) கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "கடந்த 25ஆம் திகதி மொனராகலை நகரின் மத்தியில் நிறுத்தி வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த முச்சக்கர வண்டியில் இருந்து 25 கிலோ அரிசியை யாரோ திருடிச் சென்றதாக முச்சக்கர வண்டி உரிமையாளரான ஒபேகொட பிரதேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்த ஒருவர் பொலிஸில் முறைப்பாடு செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் அருகாமையில் இருந்த சிசிடிவி கமெரா காட்சிகள் மூலம் விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்ட மொனராகலை பொலிஸார், மொனராகலை ஹுலந்தாவ தெற்கு கெமுனுபுர பிரதேசத்தை சேர்ந்த குருநாகல் போயகனே இராணுவ முகாமில் கடமையாற்றும் முப்பத்து மூன்று வயதுடைய இராணுவ சார்ஜன் ஒருவரை கைது செய்துள்ளனர்.",
        "மொனராகலை தலைமையக பொலிஸ் பரிசோதகர் பி.எஸ்.சர்மிந்த சஞ்சீவ விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகிறார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "25 கிலோ",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொனராகலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொனராகலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒபேகொட",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொனராகலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மொனராகலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மறைகாணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முப்பத்து மூன்று வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala Boyagane",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொனராகலை ஹுலந்தாவ தெற்கு கெமுனுபுர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மொனராகலை தலைமையக பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பி.எஸ்.சர்மிந்த சஞ்சீவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}