{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/woman-found-shot-dead-in-sri-lanka-main-opposition-party-office-in-kegalle-99341/",
  "time_ut": 1662019440,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Woman found shot dead in Sri Lanka main opposition party office in Kegalle",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Woman found shot dead in Sri Lanka main opposition party office in Kegalle",
      "author": "Neshella Perera",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – A woman was found dead in Sri Lanka’s main opposition Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB)’s Kegalle district office, police said.",
        "Sri Lanka’s Police Media Division said that the body was found inside a room at the SJB office in Kalugalla Mawatha, Kegalle, Thursday September 1 morning.",
        "Police has yet to determine whether the woman was murdered or whether she had taken her own life.",
        "The deceased was a 36-year-old employee working at the party office.",
        "Sri Lanka has seen an apparent spike in reportings of shootings in recent weeks, with cases reported almost daily in August.",
        "Police have attributed a majority of the shootings to underworld activity or drug trafficking. (Colombo/Sept1/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kegalle",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegalle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Police Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalugalla Mawatha",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegalle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "September",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "36-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "recent weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "almost daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කෑගල්ලේ පිහිටි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂයේ පක්ෂ කාර්යාලයේ වෙඩි තබා ඝාතනය කර තිබියදී කාන්තාවක් සොයා ගැනේ",
      "author": "නෙෂෙල්ලා පෙරේරා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂය වන සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ (SJB) කෑගල්ල දිස්ත්‍රික් කාර්යාලයේ කාන්තාවක් මියගොස් සිටි බව පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය කොට්ඨාශය පැවසුවේ කෑගල්ල, කළුගල්ල මාවතේ පිහිටි SJB කාර්යාලයේ කාමරයක් තුළ තිබී සැප්තැම්බර් 1 බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා උදෑසන මළ සිරුර සොයාගත් බවයි.",
        "මෙම කාන්තාව ඝාතනය කළේද එසේත් නැතිනම් ඇය සියදිවි නසා ගත්තාද යන්න පිළිබඳව පොලිසිය මෙතෙක් තීරණය කර නොමැත.",
        "මියගොස් ඇත්තේ 36 හැවිරිදි පක්ෂ කාර්යාලයේ සේවය කළ සේවකයෙකි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මෑත සතිවල වෙඩි තැබීම් වාර්තා කිරීම්වල කැපී පෙනෙන වැඩිවීමක් දැක ඇති අතර අගෝස්තු මාසයේදී දිනපතාම වාගේ සිද්ධීන් වාර්තා විය.",
        "වෙඩි තැබීම්වලින් වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් පාතාල ක්‍රියාකාරකම් හෝ මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය ජාවාරම්වලට හේතු වී ඇතැයි පොලිසිය පවසයි. (කොළඹ/සැප්තැම්බර් 1/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "කෑගල්ල",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය කොට්ඨාසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුගල්ල මාවත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "36 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෑත සති",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතාම පාහේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கேகாலையில் உள்ள இலங்கையின் பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சி அலுவலகத்தில் பெண் ஒருவர் சுட்டுக் கொல்லப்பட்ட நிலையில் கண்டெடுக்கப்பட்டார்",
      "author": "நெஷெல்லா பெரேரா",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையின் பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியான சமகி ஜன பலவேகயாவின் (SJB) கேகாலை மாவட்ட அலுவலகத்தில் பெண் ஒருவர் சடலமாக மீட்கப்பட்டதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "கேகாலை கலுகல்ல மாவத்தையில் உள்ள SJB அலுவலகத்தில் உள்ள அறையொன்றில் இருந்து செப்டெம்பர் 1 ஆம் திகதி வியாழக்கிழமை காலை சடலம் கண்டெடுக்கப்பட்டதாக இலங்கை பொலிஸ் ஊடகப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அந்த பெண் கொலை செய்யப்பட்டாரா அல்லது அவர் தற்கொலை செய்து கொண்டாரா என்பதை போலீசார் இன்னும் கண்டறியவில்லை.",
        "உயிரிழந்தவர் 36 வயதுடைய கட்சி அலுவலகத்தில் பணிபுரியும் ஊழியர் ஆவார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் சமீபத்திய வாரங்களில் துப்பாக்கிச்சூடு சம்பவங்கள் பற்றிய அறிக்கைகள் வெளிப்படையாக அதிகரித்துள்ளன, ஆகஸ்ட் மாதத்தில் வழக்குகள் கிட்டத்தட்ட தினசரி பதிவாகியுள்ளன.",
        "பெரும்பாலான துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டு சம்பவங்களுக்கு பாதாள உலக செயற்பாடுகள் அல்லது போதைப்பொருள் கடத்தல் காரணமாக இருக்கலாம் என பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர். (கொழும்பு/செப்டம்பர் 1/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கேகாலை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலிஸ் ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுகல்ல மாவத்தை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "36 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமீபத்திய வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}