{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/uncategorized/අනුරගේ-යාපන-සමළුවට-ටී-එන්-ඒ--නායකයොත්-එයි/1-394868",
  "time_ut": 1656310482,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අනුරගේ යාපන සමළුවට ටී.එන්.ඒ. නායකයොත් එයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "TNA presents Anura's Jaffna conference Leaders are coming too",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Leader of the National People's Force Anura Kumara Dissanayake said in Jaffna that the US case against Sri Lanka was similar to the atomic bomb dropped on Japan.",
        "Mr. Anura Kumara was addressing a gathering of participants at the National People's Force District Conference held at a private hotel in Jaffna on the 25th evening.",
        "Mavai Senathirajah, Leader of the Illangai Tamil Arusakachchi Party, Dharmalingam Siddharthan, Leader of the PLOTE, Suresh Premachandran, Leader of the EPRLF, CVK, Former Chairman of the Provincial Council were present on the occasion. Mr. Sivagnanam and many members of the Jaffna District National People's Force participated.",
        "Addressing the gathering, the Leader of the National People's Force Anura Kumara further said,",
        "‘People are suffering the most difficult setback in our country today. This is not a natural disaster. This is a situation created by bad governance. Today we are in danger of our children dying before our eyes. Oil imports have come to a complete standstill. The petrol and diesel ship that the Minister of Fuel had said was coming to Sri Lanka has now headed towards India.",
        "An American bank has filed a lawsuit against the Sri Lankan government. The government says the loans will not be repaid. Proponents of her case have been working to make the actual transcript of this statement available online. That it was similar to the atomic bomb dropped on Hiroshima and Nagasaki in Japan. As a result, the whole country and the economy have collapsed. ”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Anura",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Jaffna",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the National People's Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National People's Force District Conference",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dharmalingam Siddharthan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Leader of the PLOTE",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suresh Premachandran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Leader",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EPRLF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CVK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Provincial Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sivagnanam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "District National People's Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the National People's Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "American",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hiroshima",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nagasaki",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අනුරගේ යාපන සමළුවට ටී.එන්.ඒ. නායකයොත් එයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඇමරිකාව ශ්‍රීලංකාවට එරෙහිව දමා ඇති නඩුව ජපානයට එල්ලකල පරමානු බෝම්බය හා සමාන බවට ජාතික ජනබලවේගයේ නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක මහතා යාපනයේදී පැවසීය.",
        "අනුර කුමාර මහතා ඒ බව කියා සිටියේ යාපනයේ පෞද්ගලික හෝටලයක 25 දා සවස පැවති ජාතික ජනබලවේගයේ දිස්ත්‍රීක් සමලුවට සහභාගී වූ පිරිස් අමතමිනි.",
        "මෙම සමළුව වෙනුවෙන් දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානයේ ප්‍රධාන හවුල් කාර පක්ෂ වූ ඉලංගෙයි තමිල් අරුසකච්චි පක්ෂයේ නායක මාවෙයි සේනාධිරාජා මහතා, ප්ලොට් පක්ෂ නායක ධර්මලිංගම් සිද්ධාර්තන් මහතා, ඊ.පී.ආර්.එල්.එෆ් පක්ෂ නායක සුරෙස් ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍රන් මහතා, හිටපු පලාත්සභා සභාපති සී.වී.කේ.සිවඥානම් මහතා ඇතුලු යාපනය දිස්ත්‍රීක් ජාතික ජනබලවේගයේ සාමාජිකයින් රැසක් සහභාගී වූහ.",
        "එහිදී රැස්ව සිටි පිරිස් ඇමතු අජාතික ජනබලවේගයේ නායක අනුරකුමාර මහතා වැඩිදුරටත් පවසා සිටියේ,",
        "‘අද අපේ රටේ ඇතිවෙලා තියෙන අසීරුම අඩිය ජනතාව විඳමින් ඉන්නේ. මේක ස්වභාවික ව්‍යසනයක් නෙමෙයි. මේ නරක  පාලනය විසින් ඇති කරපු තත්වයක්. අද අපි අපේ දරුවන් ඇස් ඉදිරිපිට මිය යන අවධානමක අපි ඉන්නවා. තෙල් ආනයනය මුලුමනින්ම ඇණහිටල තියෙන්නේ. ඉන්ධන ඇමතිවරයා 23 මෙරටට එනව කියල කියපු පෙට්ට්‍රල් ඩීසල් නැව මේ වෙනකොට ඒ තෙල් නැව ඉන්දියාව දෙසට ගිහින් තියෙනවා.",
        "ඇමරිකාවේ බැංකුවක් ලංකාවේ ආණ්ඩුවට එරෙහිව ඇමරිකාවේ නඩුවක් දාලා තියනවා. ආණ්ඩුව කියනවා ණය ගෙවන්නැහැ කියල. නඩුව ගොනුකරල තියන අය සඳහන් කරල තියනවා රාජපක්ෂ පවුල මහජනතාවගේ ධනය විශාල ලෙසින් හොරකම් කර ඇති බවත් ඒවා බදු සහන දෙන රටවල සඟවා ඇති බවටත්, මේ නිසා මේ නඩුව ගැන සමහර ආර්ථික විශේෂඥයින් සඳහන් කරල තියෙන්නේ. ජපානයේ හිරෝෂිමා නාගසාකි වලට එල්ල වූ පරමානු බෝම්බය හා සමානයි කියලා. ඒ නිසා මුලු රටම, ආර්ථිකයම කඩාවැටිලා තියෙන්නේ.”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අනුර",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "යාපනය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලවේගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලවේගයේ දිස්ත්‍රික් සමුළුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධර්මලිංගම් සිද්ධාර්ථන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්ලොට් සංවිධානයේ නායකයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුරේෂ් ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍රන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊ.පී.ආර්.එල්.එෆ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සී.වී.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළාත් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිවඥානම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිස්ත්‍රික් ජාතික ජනතා බලවේගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලවේගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිරෝෂිමාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාගසාකි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அநுராவின் யாழ்ப்பாண மாநாட்டை தமிழ் தேசிய கூட்டமைப்பு முன்வைக்கிறது தலைவர்களும் வருகிறார்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கைக்கு எதிராக அமெரிக்கா தொடுத்துள்ள வழக்கு ஜப்பான் மீது வீசப்பட்ட அணுகுண்டு போன்றது என தேசிய மக்கள் படையின் தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க யாழ்ப்பாணத்தில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கடந்த 25ஆம் திகதி மாலை யாழ்ப்பாணத்தில் உள்ள தனியார் ஹோட்டலில் நடைபெற்ற தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி மாவட்ட மாநாட்டில் கலந்து கொண்டவர்கள் மத்தியில் உரையாற்றும் போதே அனுரகுமார இவ்வாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்நிகழ்வில் இலங்கைத் தமிழ் அறுசகச்சிக் கட்சியின் தலைவர் மாவை சேனாதிராஜா, புளொட் அமைப்பின் தலைவர் தர்மலிங்கம் சித்தார்த்தன், ஈ.பி.ஆர்.எல்.எப். தலைவர் சுரேஷ் பிரேமச்சந்திரன், மாகாண சபையின் முன்னாள் அவைத் தலைவர் சி.வி.கே., திரு.சிவஞானம் மற்றும் யாழ். மாவட்ட தேசிய மக்கள் படை கலந்துகொண்டது.",
        "இதில் கலந்து கொண்டு உரையாற்றிய தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தியின் தலைவர் அனுரகுமார மேலும் கூறியதாவது,",
        "‘இன்று எமது நாட்டில் மிகவும் கடினமான பின்னடைவை மக்கள் அனுபவித்து வருகின்றனர். இது இயற்கைப் பேரிடர் அல்ல. இது மோசமான ஆட்சியால் உருவாக்கப்பட்ட நிலை. இன்றைக்கு நம் குழந்தைகள் நம் கண் முன்னே இறக்கும் அபாயத்தில் இருக்கிறோம். எண்ணெய் இறக்குமதி முற்றிலும் ஸ்தம்பிதமடைந்துள்ளது. இலங்கைக்கு வருவதாக எரிபொருள் அமைச்சர் கூறிய பெட்ரோல், டீசல் கப்பல் தற்போது இந்தியாவை நோக்கி சென்றுள்ளது.",
        "அமெரிக்க வங்கியொன்று இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிராக வழக்குத் தாக்கல் செய்துள்ளது. கடனை திருப்பி செலுத்த முடியாது என அரசு கூறுகிறது. அவரது வழக்கின் ஆதரவாளர்கள் இந்த அறிக்கையின் உண்மையான டிரான்ஸ்கிரிப்டை ஆன்லைனில் கிடைக்கச் செய்ய முயற்சித்து வருகின்றனர். இது ஜப்பானின் ஹிரோஷிமா மற்றும் நாகசாகி மீது வீசப்பட்ட அணுகுண்டு போன்றது. இதன் விளைவாக, முழு நாடும் பொருளாதாரமும் வீழ்ச்சியடைந்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அனுர",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "யாழ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுர குமார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் படை மாவட்ட மாநாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தர்மலிங்கம் சித்தார்த்தன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புளொட்டின் தலைவர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுரேஷ் பிரேமச்சந்திரன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைவர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈ.பி.ஆர்.எல்.எப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.வி.கே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாகாண சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிவஞானம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாவட்ட தேசிய மக்கள் படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹிரோஷிமா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாகசாகி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}