{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Essential-service-order-before-P-ment-tomorrow/56-737065",
  "time_ut": 1656971760,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Essential service order before P’ment tomorrow",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Essential service order before P’ment tomorrow",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Essential Public Service order by President Gotabaya Rajapaksa relating to several sectors including power, electricity, fuel and medical sectors will be passed by Parliament without a debate on 6 June.",
        "The related gazette notification was issued by the President on Sunday.",
        "The Order will apply to all services connected to the supply of electricity, supply or distribution of petroleum products and fuel, all service, work or labour, of any description whatsoever, necessary or required to be done in connection with the maintenance, and the reception, care feeding and treatment, of patients in hospitals, nursing homes, dispensaries, and other similar institution"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "tomorrow",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Essential Public Service",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Order",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සේවා ඇණවුම හෙට P’ment ට පෙර",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "විදුලිය, විදුලිය, ඉන්ධන, වෛද්‍ය ඇතුළු ක්ෂේත්‍ර කිහිපයකට අදාළව ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා විසින් නිකුත් කරන ලද අත්‍යවශ්‍ය රාජ්‍ය සේවා නියෝගය ජුනි 6 වැනි දින විවාදයකින් තොරව පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී සම්මත වේ.",
        "ඊට අදාළ ගැසට් නිවේදනය ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් ඉරිදා නිකුත් කරනු ලැබුවා.",
        "විදුලිය සැපයීම, ඛනිජ තෙල් නිෂ්පාදන සහ ඉන්ධන සැපයීම හෝ බෙදා හැරීම සම්බන්ධ සියලුම සේවාවන්, සියලුම සේවා, වැඩ හෝ ශ්‍රමය, නඩත්තු කිරීම සහ පිළිගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අවශ්‍ය හෝ කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය ඕනෑම විස්තරයක් සඳහා මෙම නියෝගය අදාළ වේ. , රෝහල්, සාත්තු නිවාස, බෙහෙත් ශාලා සහ වෙනත් සමාන ආයතනවල සිටින රෝගීන්ගේ රැකවරණය පෝෂණය සහ ප්‍රතිකාර කිරීම"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හෙට",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අත්‍යවශ්‍ය රාජ්‍ය සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නියෝග",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாளை P’ment க்கு முன் அத்தியாவசிய சேவை ஆர்டர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மின்சாரம், மின்சாரம், எரிபொருள் மற்றும் மருத்துவ துறைகள் உட்பட பல துறைகள் தொடர்பான ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் அத்தியாவசிய பொது சேவை உத்தரவு ஜூன் 6 ஆம் தேதி விவாதம் இன்றி பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நிறைவேற்றப்படவுள்ளது.",
        "இது தொடர்பான வர்த்தமானி அறிவித்தல் ஜனாதிபதியினால் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை வெளியிடப்பட்டது.",
        "மின்சாரம் வழங்கல், பெட்ரோலியப் பொருட்கள் மற்றும் எரிபொருள் விநியோகம் அல்லது விநியோகம், அனைத்து சேவைகள், வேலைகள் அல்லது உழைப்பு, பராமரிப்பு மற்றும் வரவேற்பு தொடர்பாக தேவையான அல்லது செய்ய வேண்டிய விவரங்கள் அனைத்தும் இந்த உத்தரவு பொருந்தும். , மருத்துவமனைகள், முதியோர் இல்லங்கள், மருந்தகங்கள் மற்றும் பிற ஒத்த நிறுவனங்களில் உள்ள நோயாளிகளுக்கு பராமரிப்பு உணவு மற்றும் சிகிச்சை"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நாளை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அத்தியாவசிய பொது சேவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆர்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}