{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/seylan-bank-appoints-ramesh-jayasekara-as-dceo/",
  "time_ut": 1662311220,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Seylan Bank appoints Ramesh Jayasekara as DCEO",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Seylan Bank appoints Ramesh Jayasekara as DCEO",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "Seylan Bank announced the appointment of Ramesh Jayasekara as Deputy Chief Executive Officer of Seylan Bank PLC with effect from 1st September 2022. Jayasekara was the Chief Operating Officer prior to his latest appointment and is also a Non-Executive Director of Seylan Developments PLC since November 2012.",
        "Having joined Seylan Bank in 2011 as Chief Financial Officer, he took on the role of Chief Risk Officer in 2016 and moved on to be the Deputy General Manager – Corporate Banking from 2018 to 2019. In January 2020, he was promoted to the grade of Senior Deputy General Manager and then promoted to the position of Chief Operating Officer the following year.",
        "Prior to joining Seylan Bank PLC, Jayasekara was the Deputy Regional Financial Controller of the French Banking giant BNP Paribas, Middle East Region – (Bahrain, Saudi Arabia, Kuwait, Qatar, Dubai, Abu Dhabi & Cyprus) based in Bahrain. He has also worked at HSBC Sri Lanka as Resident Manager – Finance & Planning and at KPMG Sri Lanka as an Audit Manager. He has over 20 years of experience in Banking, Strategic Planning, Financial Management, Risk and Audit, both locally and internationally.",
        "Pakistan finance chief wants nation to live within its means",
        "BIMA Lanka processed Rs.2 bn worth of affordable Insurance claims, says Ajith Alexander Director and Country Manager",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Seylan Bank",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ramesh Jayasekara",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Seylan Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramesh Jayasekara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seylan Bank PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1st September 2022",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayasekara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Non-Executive",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seylan Developments PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "November 2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Seylan Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2011",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Financial Officer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "January 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the following year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Seylan Bank PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayasekara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "French",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "BNP Paribas",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Middle East Region",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bahrain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudi Arabia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kuwait",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abu Dhabi & Cyprus",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bahrain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "HSBC Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance & Planning",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "KPMG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Banking",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Financial Management",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BIMA Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs.2",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Alexander",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සෙලාන් බැංකුවේ DCEO ලෙස රමේෂ් ජයසේකර පත් කරයි",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "රමේෂ් ජයසේකර මහතා සෙලාන් බැංකුවේ නියෝජ්‍ය ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරීවරයා ලෙස 2022 සැප්තැම්බර් 1 වැනිදා සිට බලපැවැත්වෙන පරිදි පත් කරන බව සෙලාන් බැංකුව නිවේදනය කළේය. ජයසේකර ඔහුගේ නවතම පත්වීමට පෙර ප්‍රධාන මෙහෙයුම් නිලධාරියා වූ අතර 2012 නොවැම්බර් මාසයේ සිට සෙලාන් ඩිවලොප්මන්ට් පීඑල්සී හි විධායක නොවන අධ්‍යක්ෂවරයකු ද වේ. .",
        "2011 දී සෙලාන් බැංකුවේ ප්‍රධාන මූල්‍ය නිලධාරියා ලෙස සම්බන්ධ වූ ඔහු 2016 දී ප්‍රධාන අවදානම් නිලධාරියාගේ භූමිකාව භාරගත් අතර 2018 සිට 2019 දක්වා ආයතනික බැංකුකරණයේ නියෝජ්‍ය සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරීවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කළේය. 2020 ජනවාරි මාසයේදී ඔහු ශ්‍රේණියට උසස් කරන ලදී. ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නියෝජ්‍ය සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරීවරයා සහ ඊළඟ වසරේ ප්‍රධාන මෙහෙයුම් නිලධාරී තනතුරට උසස් කරන ලදී.",
        "Seylan Bank PLC හා සම්බන්ධ වීමට පෙර, ජයසේකර බහරේන් හි පිහිටි ප්‍රංශ බැංකු යෝධ BNP Paribas, මැද පෙරදිග කලාපයේ - (Bahrain, Saudi Arabia, Kuwait, Qatar, Dubai, Abu Dhabi & Cyprus) හි නියෝජ්‍ය ප්‍රාදේශීය මූල්‍ය පාලකවරයා විය. ඔහු HSBC ශ්‍රී ලංකා හි නේවාසික කළමණාකරු - මුල්‍ය සහ සැලසුම් සහ KPMG ශ්‍රී ලංකා හි විගණන කළමනාකරු ලෙස ද සේවය කර ඇත. ඔහුට දේශීය හා ජාත්‍යන්තර වශයෙන් බැංකුකරණය, උපාය මාර්ගික සැලසුම්කරණය, මූල්‍ය කළමනාකරණය, අවදානම් සහ විගණනය යන අංශවල වසර 20කට වැඩි පළපුරුද්දක් ඇත.",
        "පකිස්තාන මූල්‍ය ප්‍රධානියාට අවශ්‍ය වන්නේ ජාතිය තම හැකියාව තුළ ජීවත් වීමටයි",
        "BIMA Lanka විසින් රුපියල් බිලියන 2ක් වටිනා දැරිය හැකි රක්ෂණ හිමිකම් ක්‍රියාවට නංවා ඇති බව අධ්‍යක්ෂ සහ රට කළමණාකරු අජිත් ඇලෙක්සැන්ඩර් පවසයි.",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සෙලාන් බැංකුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "රමේෂ් ජයසේකර",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙලාන් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රමේෂ් ජයසේකර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙලාන් බැංකුව පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 සැප්තැම්බර් 1",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයසේකර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විධායක නොවන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙලාන් ඩිවලොප්මන්ට් පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012 නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙලාන් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2011",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය නිලධාරියා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020 ජනවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහත සඳහන් වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙලාන් බැංකුව පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයසේකර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රංශ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "BNP Paribas",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැද පෙරදිග කලාපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බහරේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවුදි අරාබිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුවේට්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබුඩාබි සහ සයිප්‍රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බහරේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "HSBC ශ්‍රී ලංකා",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුල්‍ය සහ සැලසුම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේ.පී.එම්.ජී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැංකු",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය කළමනාකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BIMA Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රු.2",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් ඇලෙක්සැන්ඩර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "செலான் வங்கி DCEOவாக ரமேஷ் ஜெயசேகரவை நியமித்தது",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "செலான் வங்கி ரமேஷ் ஜயசேகர செலான் வங்கி பிஎல்சியின் பிரதி பிரதம நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரியாக 2022 செப்டெம்பர் 1 ஆம் திகதி முதல் அமுலுக்கு வரும் வகையில் நியமனம் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக செலான் வங்கி அறிவித்தது. அவரது சமீபத்திய நியமனத்திற்கு முன்னர் ஜயசேகர பிரதம செயற்பாட்டு அதிகாரியாக இருந்தார் மேலும் நவம்பர் 2012 முதல் செலான் டெவலப்மெண்ட்ஸ் பிஎல்சியின் நிறைவேற்று அல்லாத இயக்குனராகவும் உள்ளார். .",
        "2011 ஆம் ஆண்டு செலான் வங்கியில் பிரதம நிதி அதிகாரியாக இணைந்து கொண்ட அவர், 2016 ஆம் ஆண்டு பிரதான இடர் அதிகாரியாகப் பொறுப்பேற்றார் மற்றும் 2018 ஆம் ஆண்டு முதல் 2019 ஆம் ஆண்டு வரை கூட்டுத்தாபன வங்கியின் பிரதிப் பொது முகாமையாளராக மாறினார். ஜனவரி 2020 இல், அவர் தரம் உயர்த்தப்பட்டார். மூத்த துணை பொது மேலாளர் மற்றும் அடுத்த ஆண்டு தலைமை இயக்க அதிகாரி பதவிக்கு உயர்த்தப்பட்டார்.",
        "செலான் பேங்க் பிஎல்சியில் இணைவதற்கு முன்னர், ஜயசேகர பஹ்ரைனை தளமாகக் கொண்ட பிரெஞ்சு வங்கியியல் நிறுவனமான BNP பரிபாஸ், மத்திய கிழக்கு பிராந்தியம் - (பஹ்ரைன், சவுதி அரேபியா, குவைத், கத்தார், துபாய், அபுதாபி & சைப்ரஸ்) துணைப் பிராந்திய நிதிக் கட்டுப்பாட்டாளராக இருந்தார். அவர் HSBC ஸ்ரீலங்காவில் வதிவிட முகாமையாளர் – நிதி மற்றும் திட்டமிடல் மற்றும் KPMG ஸ்ரீலங்காவில் கணக்காய்வு முகாமையாளராகவும் பணியாற்றியுள்ளார். உள்நாட்டிலும் சர்வதேச அளவிலும் வங்கியியல், மூலோபாய திட்டமிடல், நிதி மேலாண்மை, இடர் மற்றும் தணிக்கை ஆகியவற்றில் 20 ஆண்டுகளுக்கும் மேலான அனுபவம் உள்ளவர்.",
        "பாக்கிஸ்தான் நிதித் தலைவர் தேசம் அதன் எல்லைக்குள் வாழ வேண்டும் என்று விரும்புகிறார்",
        "BIMA லங்கா நிறுவனம் ரூ.2 பில்லியன் பெறுமதியான காப்புறுதி உரிமைகோரல்களை நடைமுறைப்படுத்தியுள்ளதாக பணிப்பாளர் மற்றும் நாட்டு முகாமையாளர் அஜித் அலெக்சாண்டர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "செலான் வங்கி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரமேஷ் ஜெயசேகர",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "செலான் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரமேஷ் ஜெயசேகர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செலான் வங்கி பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 1, 2022",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசேகர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிர்வாகமற்றவர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செலான் டெவலப்மெண்ட்ஸ் பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செலான் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2011",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அதிகாரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செலான் வங்கி பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசேகர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரெஞ்சு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிஎன்பி பரிபாஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு பிராந்தியம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பஹ்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவூதி அரேபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குவைத்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபுதாபி & சைப்ரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பஹ்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "HSBC இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி & திட்டமிடல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கே.பி.எம்.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 வருடங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வங்கியியல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி மேலாண்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிமா லங்கா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ.2",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் அலெக்சாண்டர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}