{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/politics/’’ණය-ගෙවීමට-කිසිම-ප්‍රශ්නයක්-නෑ’’/13-593884",
  "time_ut": 1625226571,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "’’ණය ගෙවීමට කිසිම ප්‍රශ්නයක් නෑ’’",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "\"There is no problem in paying the debt\"",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Ajith Nivard Kabral, Minister of State for Finance, Capital Market and Public Enterprise Reform, says that there is no problem in paying the loan money taken from abroad and their interest and the government has made all arrangements to pay that money at the end of this month.",
        "The Minister of State for Finance said that the opposition is sending a bad message to the international community that Sri Lanka is unable to pay its debts and said that what they are doing is very ugly.",
        "He also said that the opposition is telling that story to discourage investors who are hoping to come to Sri Lanka.",
        "Mr. Cabral said that what the opposition is saying is a false story and that the current government has paid all the debts on time.",
        "He said that the government has the ability to pay the debt no matter what anyone says and he also asked the opposition to refrain from making such treacherous statements against the country.",
        "However, he said that he admits that there is a problem in finding dollars and that the previous government handed over to the current government only a foreign reserve of seven billion US dollars.",
        "Mr. Ajith Nivard Kabral said that there is economic pressure in the face of the Covid epidemic and the government has somehow controlled the problem by facing the pressure.",
        "The Minister of State for Finance also stated that except for the import of vehicles, all other activities will be carried out as usual during a crisis.",
        "Mr. Cabral said that during the normal state of the country, more than 400 crores of rupees were received from the tourism industry and revealed that the income has now dropped to 50 crores of rupees."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ajith Nivard Kabral",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Capital Market and Public Enterprise Reform",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabral",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "seven billion US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ajith Nivard Kabral",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Covid",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabral",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 400",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "’’ණය ගෙවීමට කිසිම ප්‍රශ්නයක් නෑ’’",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "විදේශයන්ගෙන් ගත් ණය මුදල් හා ඒවායේ පොලිය ගෙවීමට කිසිදු ගැටළුවක් නැති බවත් මේ මාසය අවසානයේදී ඒ මුදල් ගෙවීමට රජය සියලු කටයුතු සූදානම් කර ඇති බවත් මුදල් ,ප්‍රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ හා රාජ්‍ය ව්‍යවසාය ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය අජිත් නිවාඩ් කබ්රාල් මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ණය ගෙවා ගත නොහැකිව ඇතැයි විපක්ෂය ජාත්‍යන්තරයට නරක පණිවිඩයක් යවමින් සිටින බව පැවසූ මුදල් රාජ්‍ය ඇමැතිවරයා ඔවුන් ඒ කරන්නේ ඉතාම කැත වැඩක් බවද ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "විපක්ෂය ඒ කතාව කියන්නේ මෙරටට ඒමට බලාපොරොත්තුවෙන් සිටින ආයෝජකයන් අධෛර්යමත් කිරීමට යැයිද ඔහු කීය.",
        "විපක්ෂය මේ ප්‍රකාශ කරන්නේ අසත්‍ය කතාවක් බවත් වත්මන් රජය හැම ණය මුදලක්ම කලට වේලාවට ගෙවා ඇති බවත් කබ්රාල් මහතා පැවසුවේය.",
        "කවුරු කුමක් පැවසුවත් ණය ගෙවීමට රජයට හැකියාව තිබෙන බව පැවසූ ඒ මහතා රටට එරෙහිව එවැනි ද්‍රෝහී ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් වළකින්නැයි තමා විපක්ෂයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින බවද සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් ඩොලර් සොයා ගැනීමට කිසියම් ගැටලුවක් තිබෙන බව පිළිගන්නේ යැයිද පසුගිය රජය වත්මන් රජයට බාර දුන්නේ ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන හතක විදේශ සංචිතයක් පමණකැයිද ඔහු කීවේය.",
        "කොවිඩ් වසංගතය හමුවේ ආර්ථිකමය වශයෙන් පීඩනයක් තිබෙන බවත් පීඩනයට මුහුණ දෙමින් රජය ඒ ගැටලුකාරී තත්වය කිසියම්වූ ආකාරයකට පාලනය කරගෙන ඇති බවත් අජිත් නිවාඩ් කබ්රාල් මහතා පැවසීය",
        "අර්බුදයක් පවතිද්දී වාහන ආනයනය හැරෙන්නට අනෙක් සියලු කටයුතු සාමාන්‍ය පරිදි සිදුවන බවද මුදල් රාජ්‍ය ඇමැති වරයා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "රට සාමාන්‍ය තත්වයේ පැවති කාලයේදී සංචාරක කර්මාන්තයෙන් රුපියල් කෝටි 400කට වැඩි මුදලක් ලැබුණු බව කී කබ්රාල් මහතා දැනට එම ආදායම රුපියල් කෝටි 50ක් දක්වා පහත බැස ඇතැයිද අනාවරණය කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අජිත් නිවාඩ් කබ්රාල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ සහ පොදු ව්යවසාය ප්රතිසංස්කරණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ මාසයේ අවසානය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කබ්රාල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන හතක්",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අජිත් නිවාඩ් කබ්රාල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොවිඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කබ්රාල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "400 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"கடனை அடைப்பதில் எந்த பிரச்சனையும் இல்லை\"",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வெளிநாட்டில் இருந்து பெற்ற கடன் தொகை மற்றும் வட்டியை செலுத்துவதில் எந்த பிரச்சனையும் இல்லை என்றும், இறுதியில் அந்த பணத்தை செலுத்த அரசு அனைத்து ஏற்பாடுகளையும் செய்துள்ளதாக நிதி, மூலதன சந்தை மற்றும் பொது நிறுவன சீர்திருத்த இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர் திரு.அஜித் நிவார்ட் கப்ரால் கூறுகிறார். இந்த மாதம்.",
        "இலங்கை கடனை செலுத்த முடியாத நிலையில் உள்ளதாக எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் சர்வதேச சமூகத்திற்கு மோசமான செய்தியை வெளியிடுவதாக தெரிவித்த நிதி இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர், அவர்கள் செய்வது மிகவும் அசிங்கமானது எனவும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கு வர எதிர்பார்த்துள்ள முதலீட்டாளர்களை ஊக்கப்படுத்த எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் அந்தக் கதையை கூறுவதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் கூறுவது பொய்யான கதை எனவும் தற்போதைய அரசாங்கம் அனைத்து கடன்களையும் உரிய காலத்தில் செலுத்திவிட்டதாகவும் கப்ரால் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "யார் என்ன சொன்னாலும் கடனை செலுத்தும் திறமை அரசாங்கத்திற்கு உள்ளது என்றும், நாட்டுக்கு எதிராக இதுபோன்ற துரோக கருத்துக்களை வெளியிடுவதை எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் தவிர்க்க வேண்டும் என்றும் அவர் கேட்டுக்கொண்டார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், டொலர்களை கண்டுபிடிப்பதில் சிக்கல் இருப்பதாகவும், ஏழு பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர் வெளிநாட்டு கையிருப்பையே தற்போதைய அரசாங்கத்திடம் கடந்த அரசாங்கம் கையளித்துள்ளதாகவும் அவர் ஒப்புக்கொண்டுள்ளார்.",
        "கோவிட் தொற்றுநோய்க்கு முகங்கொடுக்கும் வகையில் பொருளாதார அழுத்தம் இருப்பதாகவும், அழுத்தத்தை எதிர்கொண்டு அரசாங்கம் எப்படியோ பிரச்சினையை கட்டுப்படுத்தியுள்ளது என்றும் திரு.அஜித் நிவார்ட் கப்ரால் கூறினார்.",
        "நெருக்கடி நிலையின் போது வாகன இறக்குமதி தவிர்ந்த ஏனைய அனைத்து நடவடிக்கைகளும் வழமை போன்று மேற்கொள்ளப்படும் எனவும் நிதி இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர் மேலும் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "நாட்டின் இயல்பான நிலையில் சுற்றுலாத்துறை மூலம் 400 கோடி ரூபாய்க்கு மேல் வருமானம் கிடைத்ததாகவும், தற்போது அந்த வருமானம் 50 கோடி ரூபாயாக குறைந்துள்ளதாகவும் திரு.கப்ரால் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அஜித் நிவார்ட் கப்ரால்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூலதன சந்தை மற்றும் பொது நிறுவன சீர்திருத்தம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாத இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கப்ரால்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏழு பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அஜித் நிவார்ட் கப்ரால்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவிட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கப்ரால்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "400க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}