{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-central-banks-guidance-peg-strengthens-95-cents-dollar-shortage-remains-97296/",
  "time_ut": 1657657020,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka central bank’s guidance peg strengthens 95 cents; dollar shortage remains",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka central bank’s guidance peg strengthens 95 cents; dollar shortage remains",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – A guidance peg announced by Sri Lanka’s central bank for interbank transactions strengthened by 95 cents to 360.45 on July 12 from previous day’s 361.35, data showed on Monday.",
        "The commercial banks offered dollars for telegraphic transfers at rates between 368.35 and 370.00 for small transactions on July 12, commercial banks’ data showed.",
        "Banks offered to buy inward remittances at 358.50 -360.00 rupees.",
        "Sri Lanka secondary market rates went up with the Treasuries yields rose across maturities at Tuesday’s auction with the 3-month yield up 403 basis points to 32.11 percent data from the state debt office showed.",
        "The three months bill closed 32.75/33 percent. (Colombo/ July 12/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "95 cents",
          "label": "MONEY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "95 cents",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "360.45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "previous day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "361.35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "368.35",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "370.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "358.50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "-360.00",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasuries",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3-month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "403",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "32.11 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The three months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "32.75/33 percent",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 12/2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවේ මාර්ගෝපදේශක අගය ශත 95 කින් ශක්තිමත් කරයි; ඩොලර් හිඟය පවතී",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - අන්තර් බැංකු ගනුදෙනු සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව විසින් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද මාර්ගෝපදේශක සටහනක් පෙර දින 361.35 සිට ජූලි 12 වන දින 360.45 දක්වා ශත 95 කින් ශක්තිමත් වූ බව දත්ත සඳුදා පෙන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "වාණිජ බැංකු විසින් ජූලි 12 වන දින කුඩා ගනුදෙනු සඳහා 368.35 සහ 370.00 අතර මිලකට විදුලි පණිවුඩ හුවමාරු සඳහා ඩොලර් ලබා දුන් බව වාණිජ බැංකු දත්ත පෙන්වා දෙයි.",
        "බැංකු විසින් රුපියල් 358.50 - 360.00 ට අභ්‍යන්තර ප්‍රේෂණ මිලදී ගැනීමට ඉදිරිපත් විය.",
        "අඟහරුවාදා වෙන්දේසියේදී භාණ්ඩාගාර අස්වැන්න කල්පිරෙන කාලය පුරා ඉහළ යාමත් සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ද්විතීයික වෙළෙඳපොළ අනුපාත ඉහළ ගියේය. රාජ්‍ය ණය කාර්යාලයේ දත්ත පෙන්වා දෙන පරිදි මාස 3ක අස්වැන්න පදනම් ලකුණු 403කින් ඉහළ ගොස් සියයට 32.11ක් විය.",
        "මාස තුනේ බිල්පත සියයට 32.75/33 ක් අවසන් විය. (කොළඹ/ ජූලි 12/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශත 95යි",
          "label": "MONEY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශත 95යි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "360.45 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙර දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "361.35 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "368.35 කි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "370.00 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "358.50 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "-360.00",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3-මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "403",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 32.11 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාස තුනයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 32.75/33 කි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 12/2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கியின் வழிகாட்டல் பெக் 95 சென்ட்களை வலுப்படுத்துகிறது; டாலர் தட்டுப்பாடு உள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - வங்கிகளுக்கிடையிலான பரிவர்த்தனைகளுக்காக இலங்கையின் மத்திய வங்கியால் அறிவிக்கப்பட்ட வழிகாட்டல் பெக் முந்தைய நாளான 361.35 இலிருந்து ஜூலை 12 அன்று 360.45 ஆக 95 சென்ட்களால் வலுப்பெற்றது, தரவுகள் திங்களன்று காட்டப்பட்டது.",
        "வணிக வங்கிகள் ஜூலை 12 அன்று சிறிய பரிவர்த்தனைகளுக்கு 368.35 மற்றும் 370.00 க்கு இடையில் தந்தி பரிமாற்றங்களுக்கு டாலர்களை வழங்கியது, வணிக வங்கிகளின் தரவு காட்டுகிறது.",
        "வங்கிகள் 358.50 -360.00 ரூபாய்க்கு உள்நோக்கி அனுப்பும் பணத்தை வாங்க முன்வந்தன.",
        "இலங்கையின் இரண்டாம் நிலை சந்தை விகிதங்கள், செவ்வாய் கிழமை ஏலத்தில் முதிர்வுகள் முழுவதும் ட்ரெஷரீஸ் விளைச்சல்கள் அதிகரித்ததுடன், 3 மாத மகசூல் 403 அடிப்படை புள்ளிகள் அதிகரித்து 32.11 சதவீதமாக மாநில கடன் அலுவலகத்தின் தரவு காட்டியுள்ளது.",
        "மூன்று மாத பில் 32.75/33 சதவீதம் முடிந்தது. (கொழும்பு/ ஜூலை 12/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "95 சென்ட்",
          "label": "MONEY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "95 சென்ட்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "360.45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முன்தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "361.35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "368.35",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "370.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "358.50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "-360.00",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3-மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "403",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "32.11 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "32.75/33 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 12/2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}