{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/crisis-hit-sri-lanka-finally-starts-to-deal-with-bloated-public-sector-96277/",
  "time_ut": 1656064200,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Crisis-hit Sri Lanka finally starts to deal with bloated public sector",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Crisis-hit Sri Lanka finally starts to deal with bloated public sector",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka is looking at ways to trim the public sector by allowing state workers to go on leave for other jobs both locally and abroad as a worsening economic crisis compels the island nation to reduce government expenditure.",
        "The country is going through its worst ever forex crisis and the government is faced with the possibility of cutting down the number of employees in the state sector in order to manage a massive wage bill, even as talks begin with the International Monetary Fund (IMF) on a possible bailout.",
        "Sri Lanka has more than 1.5 million public sector employees at present, the size having doubled over the past 15 years, according to official data. Efficiency in the public service is lower compared to that of Sri Lanka’s peers in Asia, despite there being a public servant for every 14 citizens.",
        "Most state owned enterprises (SOEs) have become a dumping yard for politicians to recruit their supporters, resulting in more employees with very little do in spite of a monthly payments and pension scheme. Power and Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekera recently said there are 26,000 employees working in the state-owned Ceylon Electricity Board (CEB) alone, an institution that can be run with just 5,000 employees.",
        "In 2021, the government paid 86 cents as salaries and pension payment to public servants from every rupee it earned as tax revenue, leaving little for other public investments like health and education.",
        "Many multilateral finance organisations including the IMF, the World Bank, and the Asian Development Bank (ADB) have advised Sri Lanka to reform the public sector and to keep it tight and efficient bu political leaders have been stubborn in their reluctance to heed the advice fearing political repercussions including electoral defeats.",
        "However, the ongoing financial crisis has forced the government to look into alternatives, government sources said.",
        "“We may either have to go for a salary cut or reduce the number of  government servants by at least 30 percent as the first step,” a top government official told Economy Next.",
        "This week, the Ministry of Public Administration came up with two key proposals to reduce the size of the public sector: No-pay leave for state sector employees to go for foreign jobs or to work locally in the private sector.",
        "“It has been decided at the meeting of the Cabinet of Ministers held on 13.06.2022 to grant leave with no pay to be spent in/out of Sri Lanka to public officers under special provisions, deviating from the provisions existing in the Establishments Code regarding the granting of leave with no pay, until further notice,” M M P K Mayadunne, Secretary to the Ministry of Public Administration, Home Affairs, Provincial Councils and Local Government, said in a circular issued on Wednesday June 22.",
        "“Public officers are able to obtain leave with no pay to go out of Sri Lanka subject to a total period of five (05) years maximum, so as to be applicable to seniority and pension.”",
        "Public servants who are leaving the country for foreign jobs need to send remittances through formal channels, ranging from 100-500 US dollars monthly depending on their grades, the circular showed.",
        "It has also addressed the key issues of seniority and eligibility for pensions if they choose to leave the government service. According to the new circular, there won’t be any impact on both these both sensitive areas.",
        "In addition to this, a committee has been appointed to find out if five years of leave could be granted to government employees to work in the private sector. The committee is expected to submit its report to the cabinet within the two weeks, the government official said.",
        "“There is no way we can go ahead with the current public sector. The ideal size is 500,000. But it is an ambitious target and there could be a lot of socio-economic impact if we are going to implement that in the short term,” the official said.  (Colombo/Jun24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 1.5 million",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past 15 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "monthly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "just 5,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "86 cents",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Asian Development Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "at least 30 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Economy Next",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "This week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Public Administration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Cabinet of Ministers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "13.06.2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mayadunne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Public Administration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Home Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Provincial Councils and Local Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday June 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "05) years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100-500 US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "monthly",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "five years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the two weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "500,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jun24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අර්බුදකාරී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අවසානයේ පිම්බුණු රාජ්‍ය අංශය සමඟ කටයුතු කිරීමට පටන් ගනී",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - නරක අතට හැරෙන ආර්ථික අර්බුදයක් හේතුවෙන් රාජ්‍ය වියදම් අඩු කිරීමට දිවයිනට බල කෙරෙන බැවින් රාජ්‍ය සේවකයින්ට දේශීය හා විදේශීය වෙනත් රැකියා සඳහා නිවාඩු ලබා දීමෙන් රාජ්‍ය අංශය කප්පාදු කිරීමේ ක්‍රම පිළිබඳව ශ්‍රී ලංකාව බලා සිටී.",
        "රට මෙතෙක් පැවති දරුණුතම විදේශ විනිමය අර්බුදය හරහා ගමන් කරමින් සිටින අතර ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ සාකච්ඡා ආරම්භ වන විට පවා දැවැන්ත වැටුප් බිලක් කළමනාකරණය කිරීම සඳහා රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ සේවක සංඛ්‍යාව කපා හැරීමේ හැකියාවට රජය මුහුණ දී සිටී. හැකි ඇප මත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දැනට රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ සේවකයින් මිලියන 1.5 කට වඩා සිටින අතර, නිල දත්ත වලට අනුව පසුගිය වසර 15 තුළ එම ප්‍රමාණය දෙගුණයකින් වැඩි වී ඇත. සෑම පුරවැසියන් 14 දෙනෙකුටම රාජ්‍ය සේවකයෙකු සිටියද, ආසියාවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සම වයසේ මිතුරන්ට සාපේක්ෂව රාජ්‍ය සේවයේ කාර්යක්ෂමතාව අඩුය.",
        "බොහෝ රාජ්‍ය ව්‍යවසායන් (SOEs) දේශපාලකයන්ට තම ආධාරකරුවන් බඳවා ගැනීම සඳහා කසල අංගනයක් බවට පත් වී ඇති අතර, එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස මාසික ගෙවීම් සහ විශ්‍රාම වැටුප් ක්‍රමයක් තිබියදීත් ඉතා සුළු කාර්යයක් සහිත සේවක සංඛ්‍යාව වැඩි වේ. විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර පසුගියදා පැවසුවේ සේවකයන් 5000කින් පමණක් පවත්වාගෙන යා හැකි ආයතනයක් වන ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයේ (CEB) පමණක් සේවකයන් 26,000ක් සේවය කරන බවයි.",
        "2021 දී රජය බදු ආදායම ලෙස උපයන සෑම රුපියලකින්ම රජයේ සේවකයන්ට වැටුප් හා විශ්‍රාම වැටුප් ලෙස ශත 86ක් ගෙවා සෞඛ්‍ය හා අධ්‍යාපනය වැනි අනෙකුත් රාජ්‍ය ආයෝජන සඳහා ඉතිරි කළේ ඉතා අල්පයකි.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල, ලෝක බැංකුව සහ ආසියානු සංවර්ධන බැංකුව (ADB) ඇතුළු බහුපාර්ශ්වික මූල්‍ය සංවිධාන බොහොමයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට රාජ්‍ය අංශය ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණය කරන ලෙස උපදෙස් දී ඇති අතර එය තදින් හා කාර්යක්ෂමව තබා ගැනීමට දේශපාලන නායකයින් බියෙන් උපදෙස් පිළිපැදීමට අකමැත්තෙන් මුරණ්ඩු වී ඇත. මැතිවරණ පරාජයන් ඇතුළු දේශපාලන ප්‍රතිවිපාක.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, පවතින මූල්‍ය අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් විකල්ප සොයා බැලීමට රජයට සිදුව ඇති බව රජයේ ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "\"පළමු පියවර ලෙස අපට වැටුප් කප්පාදුවකට යාමට හෝ  රාජ්‍ය සේවකයන් සංඛ්‍යාව අවම වශයෙන් සියයට 30කින් අඩු කිරීමට සිදු විය හැක\" යනුවෙන් රජයේ ඉහළ නිලධාරියෙක් ඉකොනොමි නෙක්ස්ට් වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "මේ සතියේ රාජ්‍ය පරිපාලන අමාත්‍යාංශය විසින් රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ විශාලත්වය අඩු කිරීම සඳහා ප්‍රධාන යෝජනා දෙකක් ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇත: රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ සේවකයන්ට විදේශ රැකියා සඳහා යාමට හෝ දේශීයව පෞද්ගලික අංශයේ සේවය කිරීමට වැටුප් රහිත නිවාඩු.",
        "ආයතන සංග‍්‍රහයේ පවතින විධිවිධානවලින් බැහැරව විශේෂ විධිවිධාන යටතේ රාජ්‍ය නිලධාරීන්ට ශ‍්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ/පිටතට වියදම් නොකළ යුතු වැටුප් රහිත නිවාඩු ලබාදීමට 2022.06.13 දින පැවති අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩල රැස්වීමේදී තීරණය කර ඇත. නැවත දැනුම් දෙන තුරු වැටුප් රහිත නිවාඩු ලබා දීම” යනුවෙන් රාජ්‍ය පරිපාලන, ස්වදේශ කටයුතු, පළාත් සභා සහ පළාත් පාලන අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම් එම් එම් පී කේ මායාදුන්නේ ජුනි 22 බදාදා  නිකුත් කළ චක්‍රලේඛයක සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "\"රාජ්‍ය නිලධාරීන්ට ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨත්වයට සහ විශ්‍රාම වැටුපට අදාළ වන පරිදි උපරිම වසර පහක (05) සම්පූර්ණ කාලයකට යටත්ව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් පිටතට යාමට කිසිදු වැටුපක් නොමැතිව නිවාඩු ලබා ගත හැක.\"",
        "විදේශ රැකියා සඳහා රට හැර යන රාජ්‍ය සේවකයන්ට ඔවුන්ගේ ශ්‍රේණි අනුව මාසිකව ඩොලර් 100-500 අතර ප්‍රමාණයක විධිමත් මාර්ග ඔස්සේ ප්‍රේෂණ එවිය යුතු බව එම චක්‍රලේඛය පෙන්වා දෙයි.",
        "ඔවුන් රාජ්‍ය සේවයෙන් ඉවත් වීමට තෝරා ගන්නේ නම්, ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨත්වය සහ විශ්‍රාම වැටුප් සඳහා සුදුසුකම් පිළිබඳ ප්‍රධාන ගැටළු ද එය ආමන්ත්‍රණය කර ඇත. නව චක්‍රලේඛයට අනුව, මෙම සංවේදී ප්‍රදේශ දෙකටම කිසිදු බලපෑමක් සිදු නොවේ.",
        "මීට අමතරව පෞද්ගලික අංශයේ සේවය කිරීම සඳහා රජයේ සේවකයන්ට වසර පහක නිවාඩුවක් ලබාදිය හැකිද යන්න සොයා බැලීමට කමිටුවක් ද පත්කර තිබෙනවා. මෙම කමිටුව සති දෙක තුළ සිය වාර්තාව කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව රජයේ නිලධාරියා පැවසීය.",
        "“වර්තමාන රාජ්‍ය අංශය සමඟ අපට ඉදිරියට යා හැකි ක්‍රමයක් නැහැ. නියම ප්රමාණය 500,000 කි. නමුත් එය අභිලාෂකාමී ඉලක්කයක් වන අතර කෙටි කාලීනව එය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට ගියහොත් විශාල සමාජ-ආර්ථික බලපෑමක් ඇති විය හැකිය,” නිලධාරියා පැවසීය. (කොළඹ/ජුනි24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.5 කට වඩා වැඩිය",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසර 15 තුළ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාසිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,000 ක් පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශත 86 යි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු සංවර්ධන බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් සියයට 30 ක්",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්ථිකය ඊළඟ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය පරිපාලන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමාත්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022.06.13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මායාදුන්නේ ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය පරිපාලන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්වදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළාත් සභා සහ පළාත් පාලන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 22 බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "05) වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් 100-500",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු පහක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති දෙක",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "500,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජුනි24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நெருக்கடியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள இலங்கை இறுதியாக வீங்கிய பொதுத்துறையை சமாளிக்கத் தொடங்குகிறது",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி தீவு தேசத்தை அரசாங்க செலவினங்களைக் குறைக்க நிர்பந்திக்கப்படுவதால், அரச ஊழியர்கள் உள்நாட்டிலும் வெளிநாட்டிலும் பிற வேலைகளுக்கு விடுமுறையில் செல்ல அனுமதிப்பதன் மூலம் பொதுத்துறையை குறைப்பதற்கான வழிகளை இலங்கை கவனித்து வருகிறது.",
        "நாடு அதன் மோசமான அந்நிய செலாவணி நெருக்கடியை சந்தித்து வருகிறது, சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் (IMF) பேச்சுவார்த்தைகள் தொடங்கினாலும், ஒரு பாரிய ஊதிய மசோதாவை நிர்வகிப்பதற்கான அரச துறையில் ஊழியர்களின் எண்ணிக்கையை குறைக்கும் வாய்ப்பை அரசாங்கம் எதிர்கொள்கிறது. சாத்தியமான பிணை எடுப்பில்.",
        "உத்தியோகபூர்வ தரவுகளின்படி, இலங்கையில் தற்போது 1.5 மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான பொதுத்துறை ஊழியர்கள் உள்ளனர், இது கடந்த 15 ஆண்டுகளில் இரட்டிப்பாகியுள்ளது. ஒவ்வொரு 14 குடிமக்களுக்கும் ஒரு அரச ஊழியர் இருந்த போதிலும், ஆசியாவில் உள்ள இலங்கையின் சகாக்களுடன் ஒப்பிடுகையில் அரச சேவையில் செயல்திறன் குறைவாக உள்ளது.",
        "பெரும்பாலான அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான நிறுவனங்கள் (SOEs) அரசியல்வாதிகள் தங்கள் ஆதரவாளர்களை ஆட்சேர்ப்பு செய்வதற்கான ஒரு குப்பை கொட்டும் இடமாக மாறியுள்ளன, இதன் விளைவாக மாதாந்திர கொடுப்பனவுகள் மற்றும் ஓய்வூதியத் திட்டம் இருந்தபோதிலும் மிகக் குறைவான வேலைகளுடன் அதிகமான ஊழியர்கள் உள்ளனர். மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர அண்மையில் தெரிவித்ததாவது, அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான இலங்கை மின்சார சபையில் (CEB) மாத்திரம் 26,000 ஊழியர்கள் பணிபுரிவதாகவும், இது வெறும் 5,000 ஊழியர்களைக் கொண்டு இயங்கக்கூடிய ஒரு நிறுவனமாகும்.",
        "2021 ஆம் ஆண்டில், அரசாங்கம் வரி வருவாயாக ஈட்டிய ஒவ்வொரு ரூபாயிலிருந்தும் அரசு ஊழியர்களுக்கு சம்பளம் மற்றும் ஓய்வூதியத் தொகையாக 86 சென்ட்களை வழங்கியது, சுகாதாரம் மற்றும் கல்வி போன்ற பிற பொது முதலீடுகளுக்கு சிறிதளவு மட்டுமே உள்ளது.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம், உலக வங்கி மற்றும் ஆசிய அபிவிருத்தி வங்கி (ADB) உட்பட பல பலதரப்பு நிதி நிறுவனங்கள், பொதுத்துறையை சீர்திருத்துவதற்கும், அதை இறுக்கமாகவும் திறமையாகவும் வைத்திருக்குமாறு இலங்கைக்கு ஆலோசனை வழங்கியுள்ளன. தேர்தல் தோல்விகள் உட்பட அரசியல் விளைவுகள்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், தற்போது நிலவும் நிதி நெருக்கடியானது மாற்று வழிகளைக் காண அரசாங்கத்தை கட்டாயப்படுத்தியுள்ளது என்று அரசாங்க வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன.",
        "\"சம்பளக் குறைப்புக்கு நாங்கள் செல்ல வேண்டியிருக்கலாம் அல்லது முதல் கட்டமாக  அரசு ஊழியர்களின் எண்ணிக்கையை குறைந்தபட்சம் 30 சதவிகிதம் குறைக்க வேண்டும்\" என்று அரசாங்கத்தின் உயர் அதிகாரி ஒருவர் Economy Next இடம் கூறினார்.",
        "இந்த வாரம், பொது நிர்வாக அமைச்சகம் பொதுத் துறையின் அளவைக் குறைக்க இரண்டு முக்கிய திட்டங்களைக் கொண்டு வந்தது: அரசுத் துறை ஊழியர்கள் வெளிநாட்டு வேலைகளுக்குச் செல்ல அல்லது உள்நாட்டில் தனியார் துறையில் வேலை செய்ய ஊதியம் இல்லாத விடுப்பு.",
        "13.06.2022 அன்று நடைபெற்ற அமைச்சரவைக் கூட்டத்தில், ஸ்தாபனச் சட்டத்தில் உள்ள விதிகளிலிருந்து விலகி, சிறப்பு ஏற்பாடுகளின் கீழ் அரச உத்தியோகத்தர்களுக்கு இலங்கைக்குள்/வெளியே செலவழிக்கப்பட வேண்டிய சம்பளமில்லாத விடுமுறையை வழங்குவதற்கு தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. மறு அறிவித்தல் வரை சம்பளம் இன்றி விடுமுறை வழங்குதல்” என பொது நிர்வாகம், உள்நாட்டலுவல்கள், மாகாண சபைகள் மற்றும் உள்ளூராட்சி அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் எம்.எம்.பி.கே மாயாதுன்னே, ஜூன் 22 புதன்கிழமை வெளியிடப்பட்ட சுற்றறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"பொது அதிகாரிகள் அதிகபட்சமாக ஐந்து (05) வருடங்கள் வரை இலங்கைக்கு வெளியே செல்வதற்கு ஊதியம் ஏதுமின்றி விடுமுறையைப் பெற முடியும், இதனால் மூப்பு மற்றும் ஓய்வூதியத்திற்கு பொருந்தும்.\"",
        "வெளிநாட்டு வேலைகளுக்காக நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறும் அரசு ஊழியர்கள் தங்கள் தரத்தைப் பொறுத்து மாதந்தோறும் 100-500 அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் வரை முறையான வழிகளில் பணம் அனுப்ப வேண்டும் என்று சுற்றறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அவர்கள் அரசுப் பணியை விட்டு வெளியேறத் தேர்வுசெய்தால், மூத்தோர் மற்றும் ஓய்வூதியத்திற்கான தகுதி போன்ற முக்கியப் பிரச்சினைகளையும் அது எடுத்துரைத்துள்ளது. புதிய சுற்றறிக்கையின்படி, இந்த இரண்டு முக்கிய பகுதிகளிலும் எந்த பாதிப்பும் இருக்காது.",
        "இதுதவிர தனியார் துறையில் பணியாற்றும் அரசு ஊழியர்களுக்கு 5 ஆண்டுகள் விடுமுறை அளிக்க முடியுமா என்பதை கண்டறிய குழு ஒன்றும் நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. இந்தக் குழு தனது அறிக்கையை இரண்டு வாரங்களுக்குள் அமைச்சரவையில் சமர்ப்பிக்கும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது என்று அரசு அதிகாரி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“தற்போதைய பொதுத்துறையுடன் நாம் முன்னேற எந்த வழியும் இல்லை. உகந்த அளவு 500,000 ஆகும். ஆனால் இது ஒரு லட்சிய இலக்கு மற்றும் குறுகிய காலத்தில் அதை செயல்படுத்தப் போகிறோம் என்றால் நிறைய சமூக-பொருளாதார தாக்கம் இருக்கும்,” என்று அந்த அதிகாரி கூறினார். (கொழும்பு/ஜூன்24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.5 மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமாக",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த 15 ஆண்டுகளாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாதாந்திர",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெறும் 5,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "86 சென்ட்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய வளர்ச்சி வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 30 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொருளாதாரம் அடுத்தது",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது நிர்வாக அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரிசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "13.06.2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாயாதுன்னே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது நிர்வாக அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உள்நாட்டு விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாகாண சபைகள் மற்றும் உள்ளூராட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 22 புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "05) ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100-500 அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதாந்திர",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "500,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூன்24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Crisis-hit Sri Lanka finally starts to deal with bloated public sector",
  "body_lines": [
    "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka is looking at ways to trim the public sector by allowing state workers to go on leave for other jobs both locally and abroad as a worsening economic crisis compels the island nation to reduce government expenditure.",
    "The country is going through its worst ever forex crisis and the government is faced with the possibility of cutting down the number of employees in the state sector in order to manage a massive wage bill, even as talks begin with the International Monetary Fund (IMF) on a possible bailout.",
    "Sri Lanka has more than 1.5 million public sector employees at present, the size having doubled over the past 15 years, according to official data. Efficiency in the public service is lower compared to that of Sri Lanka’s peers in Asia, despite there being a public servant for every 14 citizens.",
    "Most state owned enterprises (SOEs) have become a dumping yard for politicians to recruit their supporters, resulting in more employees with very little do in spite of a monthly payments and pension scheme. Power and Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekera recently said there are 26,000 employees working in the state-owned Ceylon Electricity Board (CEB) alone, an institution that can be run with just 5,000 employees.",
    "In 2021, the government paid 86 cents as salaries and pension payment to public servants from every rupee it earned as tax revenue, leaving little for other public investments like health and education.",
    "Many multilateral finance organisations including the IMF, the World Bank, and the Asian Development Bank (ADB) have advised Sri Lanka to reform the public sector and to keep it tight and efficient bu political leaders have been stubborn in their reluctance to heed the advice fearing political repercussions including electoral defeats.",
    "However, the ongoing financial crisis has forced the government to look into alternatives, government sources said.",
    "“We may either have to go for a salary cut or reduce the number of  government servants by at least 30 percent as the first step,” a top government official told Economy Next.",
    "This week, the Ministry of Public Administration came up with two key proposals to reduce the size of the public sector: No-pay leave for state sector employees to go for foreign jobs or to work locally in the private sector.",
    "“It has been decided at the meeting of the Cabinet of Ministers held on 13.06.2022 to grant leave with no pay to be spent in/out of Sri Lanka to public officers under special provisions, deviating from the provisions existing in the Establishments Code regarding the granting of leave with no pay, until further notice,” M M P K Mayadunne, Secretary to the Ministry of Public Administration, Home Affairs, Provincial Councils and Local Government, said in a circular issued on Wednesday June 22.",
    "“Public officers are able to obtain leave with no pay to go out of Sri Lanka subject to a total period of five (05) years maximum, so as to be applicable to seniority and pension.”",
    "Public servants who are leaving the country for foreign jobs need to send remittances through formal channels, ranging from 100-500 US dollars monthly depending on their grades, the circular showed.",
    "It has also addressed the key issues of seniority and eligibility for pensions if they choose to leave the government service. According to the new circular, there won’t be any impact on both these both sensitive areas.",
    "In addition to this, a committee has been appointed to find out if five years of leave could be granted to government employees to work in the private sector. The committee is expected to submit its report to the cabinet within the two weeks, the government official said.",
    "“There is no way we can go ahead with the current public sector. The ideal size is 500,000. But it is an ambitious target and there could be a lot of socio-economic impact if we are going to implement that in the short term,” the official said.  (Colombo/Jun24/2022)"
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Crisis-hit Sri Lanka finally starts to deal with bloated public sector",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka is looking at ways to trim the public sector by allowing state workers to go on leave for other jobs both locally and abroad as a worsening economic crisis compels the island nation to reduce government expenditure.",
        "The country is going through its worst ever forex crisis and the government is faced with the possibility of cutting down the number of employees in the state sector in order to manage a massive wage bill, even as talks begin with the International Monetary Fund (IMF) on a possible bailout.",
        "Sri Lanka has more than 1.5 million public sector employees at present, the size having doubled over the past 15 years, according to official data. Efficiency in the public service is lower compared to that of Sri Lanka’s peers in Asia, despite there being a public servant for every 14 citizens.",
        "Most state owned enterprises (SOEs) have become a dumping yard for politicians to recruit their supporters, resulting in more employees with very little do in spite of a monthly payments and pension scheme. Power and Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekera recently said there are 26,000 employees working in the state-owned Ceylon Electricity Board (CEB) alone, an institution that can be run with just 5,000 employees.",
        "In 2021, the government paid 86 cents as salaries and pension payment to public servants from every rupee it earned as tax revenue, leaving little for other public investments like health and education.",
        "Many multilateral finance organisations including the IMF, the World Bank, and the Asian Development Bank (ADB) have advised Sri Lanka to reform the public sector and to keep it tight and efficient bu political leaders have been stubborn in their reluctance to heed the advice fearing political repercussions including electoral defeats.",
        "However, the ongoing financial crisis has forced the government to look into alternatives, government sources said.",
        "“We may either have to go for a salary cut or reduce the number of  government servants by at least 30 percent as the first step,” a top government official told Economy Next.",
        "This week, the Ministry of Public Administration came up with two key proposals to reduce the size of the public sector: No-pay leave for state sector employees to go for foreign jobs or to work locally in the private sector.",
        "“It has been decided at the meeting of the Cabinet of Ministers held on 13.06.2022 to grant leave with no pay to be spent in/out of Sri Lanka to public officers under special provisions, deviating from the provisions existing in the Establishments Code regarding the granting of leave with no pay, until further notice,” M M P K Mayadunne, Secretary to the Ministry of Public Administration, Home Affairs, Provincial Councils and Local Government, said in a circular issued on Wednesday June 22.",
        "“Public officers are able to obtain leave with no pay to go out of Sri Lanka subject to a total period of five (05) years maximum, so as to be applicable to seniority and pension.”",
        "Public servants who are leaving the country for foreign jobs need to send remittances through formal channels, ranging from 100-500 US dollars monthly depending on their grades, the circular showed.",
        "It has also addressed the key issues of seniority and eligibility for pensions if they choose to leave the government service. According to the new circular, there won’t be any impact on both these both sensitive areas.",
        "In addition to this, a committee has been appointed to find out if five years of leave could be granted to government employees to work in the private sector. The committee is expected to submit its report to the cabinet within the two weeks, the government official said.",
        "“There is no way we can go ahead with the current public sector. The ideal size is 500,000. But it is an ambitious target and there could be a lot of socio-economic impact if we are going to implement that in the short term,” the official said.  (Colombo/Jun24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 1.5 million",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past 15 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "monthly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "just 5,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "86 cents",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Asian Development Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "at least 30 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Economy Next",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "This week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Public Administration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Cabinet of Ministers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "13.06.2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mayadunne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Public Administration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Home Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Provincial Councils and Local Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday June 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "05) years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100-500 US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "monthly",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "five years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the two weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "500,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jun24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අර්බුදකාරී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අවසානයේ පිම්බුණු රාජ්‍ය අංශය සමඟ කටයුතු කිරීමට පටන් ගනී",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - නරක අතට හැරෙන ආර්ථික අර්බුදයක් හේතුවෙන් රාජ්‍ය වියදම් අඩු කිරීමට දිවයිනට බල කෙරෙන බැවින් රාජ්‍ය සේවකයින්ට දේශීය හා විදේශීය වෙනත් රැකියා සඳහා නිවාඩු ලබා දීමෙන් රාජ්‍ය අංශය කප්පාදු කිරීමේ ක්‍රම පිළිබඳව ශ්‍රී ලංකාව බලා සිටී.",
        "රට මෙතෙක් පැවති දරුණුතම විදේශ විනිමය අර්බුදය හරහා ගමන් කරමින් සිටින අතර ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ සාකච්ඡා ආරම්භ වන විට පවා දැවැන්ත වැටුප් බිලක් කළමනාකරණය කිරීම සඳහා රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ සේවක සංඛ්‍යාව කපා හැරීමේ හැකියාවට රජය මුහුණ දී සිටී. හැකි ඇප මත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දැනට රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ සේවකයින් මිලියන 1.5 කට වඩා සිටින අතර, නිල දත්ත වලට අනුව පසුගිය වසර 15 තුළ එම ප්‍රමාණය දෙගුණයකින් වැඩි වී ඇත. සෑම පුරවැසියන් 14 දෙනෙකුටම රාජ්‍ය සේවකයෙකු සිටියද, ආසියාවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සම වයසේ මිතුරන්ට සාපේක්ෂව රාජ්‍ය සේවයේ කාර්යක්ෂමතාව අඩුය.",
        "බොහෝ රාජ්‍ය ව්‍යවසායන් (SOEs) දේශපාලකයන්ට තම ආධාරකරුවන් බඳවා ගැනීම සඳහා කසල අංගනයක් බවට පත් වී ඇති අතර, එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස මාසික ගෙවීම් සහ විශ්‍රාම වැටුප් ක්‍රමයක් තිබියදීත් ඉතා සුළු කාර්යයක් සහිත සේවක සංඛ්‍යාව වැඩි වේ. විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර පසුගියදා පැවසුවේ සේවකයන් 5000කින් පමණක් පවත්වාගෙන යා හැකි ආයතනයක් වන ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයේ (CEB) පමණක් සේවකයන් 26,000ක් සේවය කරන බවයි.",
        "2021 දී රජය බදු ආදායම ලෙස උපයන සෑම රුපියලකින්ම රජයේ සේවකයන්ට වැටුප් හා විශ්‍රාම වැටුප් ලෙස ශත 86ක් ගෙවා සෞඛ්‍ය හා අධ්‍යාපනය වැනි අනෙකුත් රාජ්‍ය ආයෝජන සඳහා ඉතිරි කළේ ඉතා අල්පයකි.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල, ලෝක බැංකුව සහ ආසියානු සංවර්ධන බැංකුව (ADB) ඇතුළු බහුපාර්ශ්වික මූල්‍ය සංවිධාන බොහොමයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට රාජ්‍ය අංශය ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණය කරන ලෙස උපදෙස් දී ඇති අතර එය තදින් හා කාර්යක්ෂමව තබා ගැනීමට දේශපාලන නායකයින් බියෙන් උපදෙස් පිළිපැදීමට අකමැත්තෙන් මුරණ්ඩු වී ඇත. මැතිවරණ පරාජයන් ඇතුළු දේශපාලන ප්‍රතිවිපාක.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, පවතින මූල්‍ය අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් විකල්ප සොයා බැලීමට රජයට සිදුව ඇති බව රජයේ ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "\"පළමු පියවර ලෙස අපට වැටුප් කප්පාදුවකට යාමට හෝ  රාජ්‍ය සේවකයන් සංඛ්‍යාව අවම වශයෙන් සියයට 30කින් අඩු කිරීමට සිදු විය හැක\" යනුවෙන් රජයේ ඉහළ නිලධාරියෙක් ඉකොනොමි නෙක්ස්ට් වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "මේ සතියේ රාජ්‍ය පරිපාලන අමාත්‍යාංශය විසින් රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ විශාලත්වය අඩු කිරීම සඳහා ප්‍රධාන යෝජනා දෙකක් ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇත: රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ සේවකයන්ට විදේශ රැකියා සඳහා යාමට හෝ දේශීයව පෞද්ගලික අංශයේ සේවය කිරීමට වැටුප් රහිත නිවාඩු.",
        "ආයතන සංග‍්‍රහයේ පවතින විධිවිධානවලින් බැහැරව විශේෂ විධිවිධාන යටතේ රාජ්‍ය නිලධාරීන්ට ශ‍්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ/පිටතට වියදම් නොකළ යුතු වැටුප් රහිත නිවාඩු ලබාදීමට 2022.06.13 දින පැවති අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩල රැස්වීමේදී තීරණය කර ඇත. නැවත දැනුම් දෙන තුරු වැටුප් රහිත නිවාඩු ලබා දීම” යනුවෙන් රාජ්‍ය පරිපාලන, ස්වදේශ කටයුතු, පළාත් සභා සහ පළාත් පාලන අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම් එම් එම් පී කේ මායාදුන්නේ ජුනි 22 බදාදා  නිකුත් කළ චක්‍රලේඛයක සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "\"රාජ්‍ය නිලධාරීන්ට ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨත්වයට සහ විශ්‍රාම වැටුපට අදාළ වන පරිදි උපරිම වසර පහක (05) සම්පූර්ණ කාලයකට යටත්ව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් පිටතට යාමට කිසිදු වැටුපක් නොමැතිව නිවාඩු ලබා ගත හැක.\"",
        "විදේශ රැකියා සඳහා රට හැර යන රාජ්‍ය සේවකයන්ට ඔවුන්ගේ ශ්‍රේණි අනුව මාසිකව ඩොලර් 100-500 අතර ප්‍රමාණයක විධිමත් මාර්ග ඔස්සේ ප්‍රේෂණ එවිය යුතු බව එම චක්‍රලේඛය පෙන්වා දෙයි.",
        "ඔවුන් රාජ්‍ය සේවයෙන් ඉවත් වීමට තෝරා ගන්නේ නම්, ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨත්වය සහ විශ්‍රාම වැටුප් සඳහා සුදුසුකම් පිළිබඳ ප්‍රධාන ගැටළු ද එය ආමන්ත්‍රණය කර ඇත. නව චක්‍රලේඛයට අනුව, මෙම සංවේදී ප්‍රදේශ දෙකටම කිසිදු බලපෑමක් සිදු නොවේ.",
        "මීට අමතරව පෞද්ගලික අංශයේ සේවය කිරීම සඳහා රජයේ සේවකයන්ට වසර පහක නිවාඩුවක් ලබාදිය හැකිද යන්න සොයා බැලීමට කමිටුවක් ද පත්කර තිබෙනවා. මෙම කමිටුව සති දෙක තුළ සිය වාර්තාව කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව රජයේ නිලධාරියා පැවසීය.",
        "“වර්තමාන රාජ්‍ය අංශය සමඟ අපට ඉදිරියට යා හැකි ක්‍රමයක් නැහැ. නියම ප්රමාණය 500,000 කි. නමුත් එය අභිලාෂකාමී ඉලක්කයක් වන අතර කෙටි කාලීනව එය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට ගියහොත් විශාල සමාජ-ආර්ථික බලපෑමක් ඇති විය හැකිය,” නිලධාරියා පැවසීය. (කොළඹ/ජුනි24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.5 කට වඩා වැඩිය",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසර 15 තුළ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාසිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,000 ක් පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශත 86 යි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු සංවර්ධන බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් සියයට 30 ක්",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්ථිකය ඊළඟ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය පරිපාලන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමාත්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022.06.13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මායාදුන්නේ ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය පරිපාලන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්වදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළාත් සභා සහ පළාත් පාලන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 22 බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "05) වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් 100-500",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු පහක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති දෙක",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
