{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/සමහර-දේශපාලන-තීන්දු-ගැන-කනගාටුවනවා/11-394796",
  "time_ut": 1656066625,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "සමහර දේශපාලන තීන්දු ගැන කනගාටුවනවා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sorry about some of the political decisions",
      "body_lines": [
        "Ports, Shipping and Aviation Minister Nimal Siripala de Silva told Japanese Ambassador to Sri Lanka Misukoshi Hideki that he regretted some of the political decisions that led to the cancellation of valuable development projects that had been agreed with Japan.",
        "The Minister said this when he met the Japanese Ambassador to Sri Lanka at the Ministry today (24th).",
        "The Minister handed over a special report to the Ambassador on the delay in the construction of the second phase of the Katunayake Airport, which commenced construction with the assistance of a loan from the Government of Japan.",
        "Commenting on this, Japanese Ambassador Misukoshi Hideki said that he had received reports that the construction work had been delayed due to the corona menace and the current fuel crisis.",
        "Mr. Nimal Siripala Silva said that it was with great respect that he reminded the Japanese people of their support whenever Sri Lanka was in trouble."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ports",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Misukoshi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hideki",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Katunayake Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of Japan",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Misukoshi Hideki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සමහර දේශපාලන තීන්දු ගැන කනගාටුවනවා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජපානය සමග ගිවිසුම් ගත වූ වටිනා සංවර්ධන ව්‍යාපෘති අහෝසි කිරීමට බලපෑ  සමහර දේශපාලන තීන්දු ගැන  කනගාටුවන බව වරාය නාවික සහ ගුවන් සේවා අමාත්‍ය නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජපාන තානාපති මිසුකෝෂි හිදෙකි මහතාට පැවසීය.",
        "අමාත්‍යවරයා මෙසේ පැවසුවේ මෙරට ජපාන තානාපතිවරයා එම  අමාත්‍යාංශයේදී අද (24දා) හමුවූ අවස්ථාවේදිය.",
        "ජපන් රජයේ ණය ආධාර යටතේ ඉදිකිරීම් ඇරඹූ කටුනායක ගුවන්තොටුපොළ දෙවන අදියරේ  ඉදිකිරීම්වල  ප්‍රමාදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අවධානය යොමු කරමින් සකස් කෙරුණු විශේෂ වාර්තාවක් අමාත්‍යවරයා විසින් තානාපතිවරයාට මෙහිදී බාරදෙනු ලැබීය.",
        "ඒ සම්බන්ධව  අදහස් දක්වා ඇති ජපාන තානාපති මිසුකෝෂි හිදෙකි මහතා  පවසා ඇත්තේ   කොරෝනා උවදුර සහ වර්තමානයේ  පවතින ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් එම  ඉදිකිරීම් කටයුතු  ප්‍රමාදවී ඇති බව තමාට  වාර්තාවී ඇති බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අසීරුතාවට පත් වූ සෑම අවස්ථාවකදීම ජපාන ජනතාව සහයට ඉදිරිපත්වීම ඉතාම ගෞරවයෙන් සිහිපත් කරන  බව  නිමල් සිරිපාල සිල්වා මහතා මෙහිදී පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වරායන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Misukoshi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hideki",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපාන රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Misukoshi Hideki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சில அரசியல் முடிவுகளுக்கு மன்னிக்கவும்",
      "body_lines": [
        "துறைமுகங்கள், கப்பல் மற்றும் விமானப் போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சர் நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா இலங்கைக்கான ஜப்பானிய தூதுவர் மிசுகோஷி ஹிடேகியிடம், ஜப்பானுடன் ஒப்பந்தம் செய்யப்பட்ட பெறுமதிமிக்க அபிவிருத்தித் திட்டங்களை இரத்துச் செய்த சில அரசியல் தீர்மானங்களுக்கு வருந்துவதாக தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான ஜப்பானிய தூதுவரை இன்று (24) அமைச்சில் சந்தித்த போதே அமைச்சர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜப்பான் அரசாங்கத்தின் கடனுதவியுடன் நிர்மாணப் பணிகளை ஆரம்பித்த கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையத்தின் இரண்டாம் கட்ட நிர்மாணப் பணிகள் தாமதமாகி வருவது தொடர்பிலான விசேட அறிக்கையொன்றை அமைச்சர் தூதுவரிடம் கையளித்தார்.",
        "இது குறித்து கருத்து தெரிவித்த ஜப்பானிய தூதுவர் மிசுகோஷி ஹிடேகி, கொரோனா அச்சுறுத்தல் மற்றும் தற்போதைய எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடி காரணமாக கட்டுமான பணிகள் தாமதமாகி வருவதாக தமக்கு தகவல்கள் கிடைத்துள்ளதாக தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கு நெருக்கடிகள் ஏற்படும் போதெல்லாம் ஜப்பானிய மக்களின் ஆதரவை தாம் மிகுந்த மரியாதையுடன் நினைவுபடுத்துவதாக திரு.நிமல் சிறிபால சில்வா தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "துறைமுகங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Misukoshi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hideki",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான் அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Misukoshi Hideki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "සමහර දේශපාලන තීන්දු ගැන කනගාටුවනවා",
  "body_lines": [
    "ජපානය සමග ගිවිසුම් ගත වූ වටිනා සංවර්ධන ව්‍යාපෘති අහෝසි කිරීමට බලපෑ  සමහර දේශපාලන තීන්දු ගැන  කනගාටුවන බව වරාය නාවික සහ ගුවන් සේවා අමාත්‍ය නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජපාන තානාපති මිසුකෝෂි හිදෙකි මහතාට පැවසීය.",
    "අමාත්‍යවරයා මෙසේ පැවසුවේ මෙරට ජපාන තානාපතිවරයා එම  අමාත්‍යාංශයේදී අද (24දා) හමුවූ අවස්ථාවේදිය.",
    "ජපන් රජයේ ණය ආධාර යටතේ ඉදිකිරීම් ඇරඹූ කටුනායක ගුවන්තොටුපොළ දෙවන අදියරේ  ඉදිකිරීම්වල  ප්‍රමාදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අවධානය යොමු කරමින් සකස් කෙරුණු විශේෂ වාර්තාවක් අමාත්‍යවරයා විසින් තානාපතිවරයාට මෙහිදී බාරදෙනු ලැබීය.",
    "ඒ සම්බන්ධව  අදහස් දක්වා ඇති ජපාන තානාපති මිසුකෝෂි හිදෙකි මහතා  පවසා ඇත්තේ   කොරෝනා උවදුර සහ වර්තමානයේ  පවතින ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් එම  ඉදිකිරීම් කටයුතු  ප්‍රමාදවී ඇති බව තමාට  වාර්තාවී ඇති බවයි.",
    "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අසීරුතාවට පත් වූ සෑම අවස්ථාවකදීම ජපාන ජනතාව සහයට ඉදිරිපත්වීම ඉතාම ගෞරවයෙන් සිහිපත් කරන  බව  නිමල් සිරිපාල සිල්වා මහතා මෙහිදී පැවසීය."
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sorry about some of the political decisions",
      "body_lines": [
        "Ports, Shipping and Aviation Minister Nimal Siripala de Silva told Japanese Ambassador to Sri Lanka Misukoshi Hideki that he regretted some of the political decisions that led to the cancellation of valuable development projects that had been agreed with Japan.",
        "The Minister said this when he met the Japanese Ambassador to Sri Lanka at the Ministry today (24th).",
        "The Minister handed over a special report to the Ambassador on the delay in the construction of the second phase of the Katunayake Airport, which commenced construction with the assistance of a loan from the Government of Japan.",
        "Commenting on this, Japanese Ambassador Misukoshi Hideki said that he had received reports that the construction work had been delayed due to the corona menace and the current fuel crisis.",
        "Mr. Nimal Siripala Silva said that it was with great respect that he reminded the Japanese people of their support whenever Sri Lanka was in trouble."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ports",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Misukoshi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hideki",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Katunayake Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of Japan",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Misukoshi Hideki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සමහර දේශපාලන තීන්දු ගැන කනගාටුවනවා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජපානය සමග ගිවිසුම් ගත වූ වටිනා සංවර්ධන ව්‍යාපෘති අහෝසි කිරීමට බලපෑ  සමහර දේශපාලන තීන්දු ගැන  කනගාටුවන බව වරාය නාවික සහ ගුවන් සේවා අමාත්‍ය නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජපාන තානාපති මිසුකෝෂි හිදෙකි මහතාට පැවසීය.",
        "අමාත්‍යවරයා මෙසේ පැවසුවේ මෙරට ජපාන තානාපතිවරයා එම  අමාත්‍යාංශයේදී අද (24දා) හමුවූ අවස්ථාවේදිය.",
        "ජපන් රජයේ ණය ආධාර යටතේ ඉදිකිරීම් ඇරඹූ කටුනායක ගුවන්තොටුපොළ දෙවන අදියරේ  ඉදිකිරීම්වල  ප්‍රමාදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අවධානය යොමු කරමින් සකස් කෙරුණු විශේෂ වාර්තාවක් අමාත්‍යවරයා විසින් තානාපතිවරයාට මෙහිදී බාරදෙනු ලැබීය.",
        "ඒ සම්බන්ධව  අදහස් දක්වා ඇති ජපාන තානාපති මිසුකෝෂි හිදෙකි මහතා  පවසා ඇත්තේ   කොරෝනා උවදුර සහ වර්තමානයේ  පවතින ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් එම  ඉදිකිරීම් කටයුතු  ප්‍රමාදවී ඇති බව තමාට  වාර්තාවී ඇති බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අසීරුතාවට පත් වූ සෑම අවස්ථාවකදීම ජපාන ජනතාව සහයට ඉදිරිපත්වීම ඉතාම ගෞරවයෙන් සිහිපත් කරන  බව  නිමල් සිරිපාල සිල්වා මහතා මෙහිදී පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වරායන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Misukoshi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hideki",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපාන රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Misukoshi Hideki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சில அரசியல் முடிவுகளுக்கு மன்னிக்கவும்",
      "body_lines": [
        "துறைமுகங்கள், கப்பல் மற்றும் விமானப் போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சர் நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா இலங்கைக்கான ஜப்பானிய தூதுவர் மிசுகோஷி ஹிடேகியிடம், ஜப்பானுடன் ஒப்பந்தம் செய்யப்பட்ட பெறுமதிமிக்க அபிவிருத்தித் திட்டங்களை இரத்துச் செய்த சில அரசியல் தீர்மானங்களுக்கு வருந்துவதாக தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான ஜப்பானிய தூதுவரை இன்று (24) அமைச்சில் சந்தித்த போதே அமைச்சர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜப்பான் அரசாங்கத்தின் கடனுதவியுடன் நிர்மாணப் பணிகளை ஆரம்பித்த கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையத்தின் இரண்டாம் கட்ட நிர்மாணப் பணிகள் தாமதமாகி வருவது தொடர்பிலான விசேட அறிக்கையொன்றை அமைச்சர் தூதுவரிடம் கையளித்தார்.",
        "இது குறித்து கருத்து தெரிவித்த ஜப்பானிய தூதுவர் மிசுகோஷி ஹிடேகி, கொரோனா அச்சுறுத்தல் மற்றும் தற்போதைய எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடி காரணமாக கட்டுமான பணிகள் தாமதமாகி வருவதாக தமக்கு தகவல்கள் கிடைத்துள்ளதாக தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கு நெருக்கடிகள் ஏற்படும் போதெல்லாம் ஜப்பானிய மக்களின் ஆதரவை தாம் மிகுந்த மரியாதையுடன் நினைவுபடுத்துவதாக திரு.நிமல் சிறிபால சில்வா தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "துறைமுகங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Misukoshi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hideki",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான் அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Misukoshi Hideki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}