{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84751/heavy-rains-above-100mm-expected-in-several-areas",
  "time_ut": 1662344340,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Heavy rains above 100mm expected in several areas",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Heavy rains above 100mm expected in several areas",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Department of Meteorology says showers will occur at times in the Western, Sabaragamuwa and North-Western provinces and in Kandy, Nuwara-Eliya, Galle and Matara districts.",
        "Heavy showers above 100mm may occur at some places in Western and Sabaragamuwa provinces and in Kandy, Nuwara-Eliya, Galle and Matara districts.",
        "Several spells of shower will occur in the Northern Province.",
        "Showers or thundershowers will occur at several places elsewhere in the evening or night.",
        "Strong winds about 50 kmph can be expected at times over the western slopes of the Central hills.",
        "General public is kindly requested to take adequate precautions to minimize damages caused by temporary localized strong winds and lightning during thundershowers.",
        "On the apparent southward relative motion of the sun, it is going to be directly over the latitudes of Sri Lanka during 28th of August to 07th of September in this year. The nearest towns of Sri Lanka over which the sun is overhead today (05) are Polgasovita, Palabaddala, Randeniya about 12.09 noon.",
        "Showers or thundershowers will occur at times in the sea area off the cost extending from Puttalam to Galle via Colombo. Showers or thundershowers may occur at several places in the other sea areas.",
        "Winds will be south-westerly and wind speed will be 30-40 kmph. Wind speed may increase up to 50-60 kmph at times in the sea area off the coast extending from Colombo to Pottuvil via Galle and Hambantota and, up to 45-50 kmph at times in the sea areas off the coast extending from Trincomalee to Colombo via Kankasanturai, Mannar and Puttalam.",
        "The sea areas off the coast extending from Colombo to Pottuvil via Galle and Hambantota will be very rough at times. The sea areas off the coast extending from Trincomalee to Colombo via Kankasanturai, Mannar and Puttalam will be rough at times. The other sea areas around the island may be moderate.",
        "There is a possibility to increase swell waves (about 2.0 – 2.5 m) in the sea areas off the coast extending fromColombo to Pottuvil via Galle and Hambantota.",
        "The naval and fishing communities are requested to be vigilant in this regard."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "100mm",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "North-Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100mm",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Northern Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 50 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28th of August to 07th of September",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polgasovita",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Palabaddala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 12.09 noon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30-40 kmph",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "50-60 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "45-50 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kankasanturai, Mannar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kankasanturai, Mannar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ප්‍රදේශ රැසකට මිලිමීටර් 100 ඉක්මවූ තද වැසි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "බස්නාහිර, සබරගමුව සහ වයඹ පළාත්වලත් මහනුවර, නුවරඑළිය, ගාල්ල සහ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් විටින් විට වැසි ඇති වන බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "බස්නාහිර සහ සබරගමුව පළාත්වලත් මහනුවර, නුවරඑළිය, ගාල්ල සහ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලිමීටර් 100 ට වැඩි තද වැසි ඇති විය හැක.",
        "උතුරු පළාතේ වැසි වාර කිහිපයක් ඇතිවේ.",
        "සෙසු ප්‍රදේශවල සවස් කාලයේ හෝ රාත්‍රී කාලයේ වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇති වේ.",
        "මධ්‍යම කඳුකරයේ බටහිර බෑවුම් ප්‍රදේශවල විටින් විට පැයට කිලෝමීටර් 50 ක පමණ තද සුළං බලාපොරොත්තු විය හැක.",
        "ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇති වන විට එම ප්‍රදේශවල තාවකාලික තද සුළං සහ අකුණු මඟින් සිදුවන අනතුරු අවම කර ගැනීමට ප්‍රමාණවත් පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස සාමාන්‍ය ජනතාවගෙන් කාරුණිකව ඉල්ලා සිටියි.",
        "සූර්යයාගේ දකුණට සාපේක්ෂ චලිතය මත, එය මේ වසරේ අගෝස්තු 28 සිට සැප්තැම්බර් 07 දක්වා කාලය තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අක්ෂාංශවලට සෘජුවම ඉහළින් පවතී. අද (05) දහවල් 12.09 ට පමණ පොල්ගස්ඕවිට, පලාබද්දල, රන්දෙණිය යන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආසන්නතම නගර වේ.",
        "පුත්තලම සිට කොළඹ හරහා ගාල්ල දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල විටින් විට වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇති වේ. සෙසු මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල තැනින් තැන වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇති විය හැක.",
        "සුළං නිරිත දෙසින් හමන අතර සුළගේ වේගය පැ.කි.මී.30-40 පමණ වේ. කොළඹ සිට ගාල්ල සහ හම්බන්තොට හරහා පොතුවිල් දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල සුළගේ වේගය විටින් විට පැ.කි.මී. කන්කසන්තුරේ, මන්නාරම සහ පුත්තලම හරහා.",
        "කොළඹ සිට ගාල්ල සහ හම්බන්තොට හරහා පොතුවිල් දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ විටින් විට ඉතා රළු වේ. ත්‍රිකුණාමලය සිට කන්කසන්තුරය, මන්නාරම සහ පුත්තලම හරහා කොළඹ දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ විටින් විට රළු වේ. දිවයින වටා වන අනෙකුත් මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ මධ්‍යස්ථ විය හැක.",
        "කොළඹ සිට ගාල්ල සහ හම්බන්තොට හරහා පොතුවිල් දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල රළ (මීටර් 2.0 - 2.5 පමණ) වැඩිවීමේ හැකියාවක් පවතී.",
        "ධීවර සහ නාවික ප්‍රජාව මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමසිලිමත් වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටියි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "100 මි.මී",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100 මි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උතුරු පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 kmph පමණ වේ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 28 සිට සැප්තැම්බර් 07 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොල්ගසෝවිට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පලාබද්දල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල් 12.09ට පමණ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30-40 kmph",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "50-60 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "45-50 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කන්කසන්තුරේ, මන්නාරම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කන්කසන්තුරේ, මන්නාරම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பல பிரதேசங்களில் 100 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான கனமழை எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மேல், சப்ரகமுவ மற்றும் வடமேல் மாகாணங்களிலும் கண்டி, நுவரெலியா, காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறை மாவட்டங்களிலும் அவ்வப்போது மழை பெய்யும் என வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மேல் மற்றும் சப்ரகமுவ மாகாணங்களிலும் கண்டி, நுவரெலியா, காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறை மாவட்டங்களிலும் சில இடங்களில் 100 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான பலத்த மழை பெய்யக்கூடும்.",
        "வட மாகாணத்தில் பல தடவைகள் மழை பெய்யும்.",
        "ஏனைய இடங்களில் மாலை அல்லது இரவில் மழை அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை பெய்யும்.",
        "மத்திய மலைநாட்டின் மேற்கு சரிவுகளில் அவ்வப்போது மணிக்கு 50 கிமீ வேகத்தில் பலத்த காற்று வீசக்கூடும்.",
        "இடியுடன் கூடிய மழையின் போது தற்காலிகமாக பலத்த காற்று மற்றும் மின்னல் தாக்கங்களினால் ஏற்படக்கூடிய பாதிப்புகளை குறைத்துக்கொள்ள போதுமான முன்னெச்சரிக்கை நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுக்குமாறு பொதுமக்கள் கேட்டுக் கொள்ளப்படுகிறார்கள்.",
        "சூரியனின் தெற்கு நோக்கிய ஒப்பீட்டு இயக்கத்தில், இந்த ஆண்டு ஆகஸ்ட் 28 முதல் செப்டம்பர் 07 வரை இலங்கையின் அட்சரேகைகளுக்கு நேரடியாக மேலே செல்லப் போகிறது. இன்று (05) மதியம் 12.09 மணியளவில் பொல்கசோவிட, பாலபத்தல, ரந்தெனிய ஆகிய நகரங்களில் சூரியன் தலைக்கு மேல் இருக்கும் இலங்கையின் அருகிலுள்ள நகரங்கள்.",
        "புத்தளத்திலிருந்து கொழும்பு ஊடாக காலி வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளில் அவ்வப்போது மழை அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை பெய்யும். ஏனைய கடற்பரப்புகளில் பல இடங்களில் மழை அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை பெய்யக்கூடும்.",
        "காற்று தென்மேற்கு திசையில் வீசும், காற்றின் வேகம் மணிக்கு 30-40 கி.மீ. கொழும்பில் இருந்து காலி மற்றும் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை ஊடாக பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளில் காற்றின் வேகமானது அவ்வப்போது மணித்தியாலத்துக்கு 50-60 கிலோ மீற்றர் வரை அதிகரிக்கக்கூடும் எனவும், திருகோணமலையிலிருந்து கொழும்பு வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளில் காற்றின் வேகமானது அவ்வப்போது மணித்தியாலத்துக்கு 45-50 கிலோ மீற்றர் வரை அதிகரித்து வீசக்கூடும். காங்கேசன்துறை, மன்னார் மற்றும் புத்தளம் ஊடாக.",
        "கொழும்பில் இருந்து காலி மற்றும் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை ஊடாக பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்கரைக்கு அப்பாற்பட்ட கடற்பரப்புகள் அவ்வப்போது மிகவும் கொந்தளிப்பாக காணப்படும். திருகோணமலையிலிருந்து காங்கேசன்துறை, மன்னார் மற்றும் புத்தளம் ஊடாக கொழும்பு வரையான கடற்பரப்புகள் அவ்வப்போது கொந்தளிப்பாக காணப்படும். நாட்டைச் சூழவுள்ள ஏனைய கடற்பரப்புக்கள் மிதமானதாக இருக்கலாம்.",
        "கொழும்பிலிருந்து காலி மற்றும் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை ஊடாக பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளுக்கு அப்பாற்பட்ட கடற்பரப்புகளில் அலைகள் (சுமார் 2.0 – 2.5 மீ) அதிகரிக்கும் சாத்தியம் காணப்படுகின்றது.",
        "இது தொடர்பில் கடற்படை மற்றும் மீனவ சமூகங்கள் அவதானமாக இருக்குமாறு கோரப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "100மிமீ",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடமேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100மிமீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 50 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 28 முதல் செப்டம்பர் 07 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "போல்கசோவிதா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பலபத்தலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 12.09 மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 30-40 கி.மீ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 50-60 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 45-50 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "காங்கேசன்துறை, மன்னார்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "காங்கேசன்துறை, மன்னார்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}