{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/සර්ව-පාක්ෂික-ආණ්ඩුවකට-අපට-ආරාධනා-නෑ/101-617020",
  "time_ut": 1658751880,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවකට අපට ආරාධනා නෑ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "We are not invited to an all-party government",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Leaders of Tamil and Muslim political parties said that they have not yet received an official invitation to form an all-party government.",
        "In this regard, when we asked the leader of the All Ceylon People's Congress, Mr. Rishad Badurdeen, he said that such an invitation has not been received yet.",
        "He also mentioned that he saw that such a government would be formed only from the media.",
        "In this regard, in a query made to TNA Media Spokesperson, Member of Parliament MA Sumandhiran, he said that there is no invitation to an all-party government.",
        "He said that he will consider joining such a government after receiving the invitation.",
        "When asked about the formation of an all-party government, the leader of the Tamil Progressive Alliance, MP Mano Ganesan, said that there is no such invitation yet.",
        "He also mentioned that when the leaders of the parliamentary parties met after the swearing in of the President, they informed that such a government would be formed.",
        "In a query made to the leader of the National Labor Front, Member of Parliament Mr. Palani Digambaram regarding the all-party government, he stated that his party has not received such an invitation so far.",
        "He also mentioned that after receiving an invitation, the party will discuss it and take a decision."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Muslim",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rishad Badurdeen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "TNA Media Spokesperson",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament MA Sumandhiran",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Tamil Progressive Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the National Labor Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Palani Digambaram",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවකට අපට ආරාධනා නෑ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම සඳහා තවමත් තමන්ට නිල වශයෙන් ආරාධනා ලැබී නැතැයි දෙමළ සහ මුස්ලිම් දේශපාලන පක්ෂවල නායකයෝ පැවසූහ.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් අප  සමස්ත ලංකා මහජන කොංග්‍රසයේ නායක පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රිෂාඩ්  බදුර්දීන්  මහතාගෙන් කළ විමසුමකදී ඔහු පැවසුවේ එවැනි ආරාධනයක්  තවමත් ලැබී නැති බවයි.",
        "එවැනි ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවන බව මාධ්‍යවලින්  පමණක්  තමා දුටුවේ යැයිද  හෙතෙම සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මේ  සම්බන්ධයෙන් දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානයේ මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී එම්.ඒ සුමන්දිරන්  මහතාගෙන් කළ විමසුමකදී ඔහු පැවසූවේ සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවකට ආරාධනයක් නැති බවයි.",
        "එවැනි ආණ්ඩුවකට සම්බන්ධ වන්නේ දැයි  ආරාධනය ලැබුණු පසු සලකා බලන බවද  ඔහු කීවේය.",
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අප දමිළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානයේ නායක පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රි මනෝ ගනේෂන් මහතාගෙන් කළ විමසුමකදී ඔහු පැවසුවේ  තවමත් එවැනි ආරාධනයක් නැති බවයි.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා දිවුරුම් දුන්  අවස්ථාවෙන් පසු පාර්ලිමේන්තු පක්ෂ නායකයන් හමු වූ අවස්ථාවේදී එවැනි ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවන බව දැනුම් දුන්නේ යැයිද  ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුව සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජාතික කම්කරු පෙරමුණේ නායක පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී පලනි දිගම්බරම් මහතාගෙන් කළ විමසුමකදී ඔහු සඳහන් කළේ මෙතෙක් තම පක්ෂයට එවැනි ආරාධනයක් ලැබී නැති බවයි.",
        "ආරාධනයක් ලැබුණු පසු පක්ෂය ඒ ගැන   සාකච්ඡා පවත්වා තීරණයක් ගන්නා බවද ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මුස්ලිම්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොංග්රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිෂාඩ් බදුර්දීන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "TNA මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව එම් ඒ සුමන්දිරන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික කම්කරු පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පලනි දිගම්බරම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அனைத்துக் கட்சி ஆட்சிக்கு எங்களை அழைக்கவில்லை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பதற்கான உத்தியோகபூர்வ அழைப்பு இதுவரை தமக்கு கிடைக்கவில்லை என தமிழ் மற்றும் முஸ்லிம் அரசியல் கட்சிகளின் தலைவர்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இது தொடர்பில் அகில இலங்கை மக்கள் காங்கிரஸின் தலைவர் திரு.றிஷாத் பதுர்தீனிடம் நாம் கேட்ட போது, ​​அவ்வாறான அழைப்பு இதுவரை கிடைக்கப்பெறவில்லை என தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஊடகங்களில் இருந்து தான் இவ்வாறானதொரு அரசாங்கம் அமையும் என்பதை தான் பார்த்ததாகவும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இது தொடர்பில் தமிழ்த் தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பின் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளரும், நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருமான எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரனிடம் வினவிய போது, ​​சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்திற்கு அழைப்பு விடுக்கப்படவில்லை எனத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அழைப்பிதழ் கிடைத்தவுடன் அத்தகைய அரசில் இணைவது குறித்து பரிசீலிப்பேன் என்றார்.",
        "சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் அமைப்பது தொடர்பில் தமிழ் முற்போக்குக் கூட்டணியின் தலைவர் எம்.பி மனோ கணேசனிடம் வினவியபோது, ​​அவ்வாறான அழைப்பு இதுவரை வரவில்லை எனத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்து கொண்டதன் பின்னர் பாராளுமன்றக் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் சந்தித்த போது அவ்வாறான அரசாங்கம் அமைக்கப்படும் என தெரிவித்ததாகவும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் தொடர்பில் தேசிய தொழிலாளர் முன்னணியின் தலைவர், நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் திரு.பழனி திகாம்பரத்திடம் வினவிய போது, ​​தமது கட்சிக்கு இதுவரையில் அவ்வாறான அழைப்பு வரவில்லை எனத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அழைப்பிதழ் கிடைத்தவுடன் கட்சியில் கலந்துரையாடி முடிவெடுக்கப்படும் என்றும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "முஸ்லிம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிஷாத் பதுர்தீன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பின் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய தொழிலாளர் முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பழனி திகாம்பரம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}