{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/World-s-No-1-TV-manufacturer-Samsung-introduces-Samsung-Sahana/34-737258",
  "time_ut": 1657307952,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "World’s No. 1 TV manufacturer Samsung introduces ‘Samsung Sahana’",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "World’s No. 1 TV manufacturer Samsung introduces ‘Samsung Sahana’",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Offering discounts of up to Rs. 900,000 as relief to grief-stricken locals",
        "Samsung, Sri Lanka’s leading electronics brand, unveiled “Samsung Sahana” in order to provide relief to its consumers during these turbulent times where the whole country is facing its worst economic crisis yet. Samsung has taken measures to provide relief by offering massive discounts up to Rs. 900,000 on its TV range for consumers who wish to bring home some happiness with the purchase of an entertainment system (TV).",
        "Under Samsung Sahana, customers are eligible for discounts on Samsung TVs amounting to up to Rs. 900,000 to allow consumers to purchase Samsung TVs at a time when prices are at a peak due to economic inflation. Starting from 5 July, Samsung Sahana allows consumers to purchase premium Samsung TVs at an affordable price.",
        "The Samsung 43” FHD Smart TV for a reduced price of Rs. 204,999 with a discount of Rs. 8,000. The 43” UHD TV is now available for a price of Rs. 249,999 with a Rs. 20,000 discount. Further, the Samsung 50” UHD TV is available at a discounted price of Rs. 319,999 while the 55” UHD TV is available for a price of Rs. 399,999 at a discount of Rs. 50,000. The 65” UHD TV is now available for a price of Rs. 569,999 with a discount of Rs. 60,000 while the 75” UHD TV is available for a price of Rs. 799,999 with a discount of Rs. 100,000.",
        "In the QLED range, Samsung offers a discount of Rs. 65,000 for the 55” QLED TV, Rs. 160,000 for the 65” QLED TV and Rs. 300,000 for the 75” Neo QLED 8K TV. The highest discount is offered to the 85” Neo QLED 8K TV, with a discount of Rs. 900,000 which is now available for the price of Rs. 4,399,999 only.",
        "“We have always been conscious of our consumers’ needs and wants. We want all of them to be able to afford our products and enjoy the innovations we bring. This is the reason for Samsung Sahana, which will allow Samsung consumers to purchase premium-level TVs at an affordable price even in these trying times,” said Samsung Sri Lanka Managing Director Kevin SungSu YOU.",
        "Samsung Electronics has been leading the TV industry for more than a decade with the latest technologies available on consumer TVs. In 2022, Samsung has yet again secured the number one spot in terms of market share for 16 consecutive years.",
        "At the heart of Samsung screens is customer-centric innovation, which powers Samsung screens, including Neo QLED 8K, to deliver immaculate, true-to-life picture quality. Samsung Neo QLED 8K is the TV for the modern day, with next-level picture quality and one-of-a-kind features powered by artificial intelligence(AI). With TVs at the centre of the smart home ecosystem, users can easily control all their devices using their TV, thus putting them to the best use.",
        "Samsung also unveiled Smart Hub, its new user interface, powered by Tizen. The all-new Samsung Smart Hub brings every aspect of the smart experience into one easy-to-navigate home screen. The new tab classifies features, settings and content into three categories for a seamless user experience: Media, Gaming Hub and Ambient.",
        "At the core of the innovation behind Samsung’s Neo QLED 8K lies its Neural Quantum Processor 8K. 20 independent neural AI networks analyse each scene and adjust picture quality to deliver the best viewing experiences regardless of content’s original picture quality.",
        "The Samsung TV range is available at authorised partners Softlogic, Singer, Singhagiri, Damro and Samsung e-Store for purchase."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Samsung",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Samsung Sahana",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "900,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samsung",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung Sahana",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "900,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samsung Sahana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "900,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung Sahana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FHD Smart TV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "204,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "43",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UHD TV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "249,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UHD TV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "319,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "55",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UHD TV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "399,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "65",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UHD TV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "569,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UHD TV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "799,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samsung",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "65,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "55",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "160,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 65",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "300,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "K TV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "85",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "K TV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "900,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,399,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samsung Sahana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kevin SungSu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samsung Electronics",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than a decade",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "16 consecutive years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samsung",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Neo QLED",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8K",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung Neo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8K",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the modern day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samsung",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Smart Hub",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung Smart Hub",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gaming Hub and Ambient",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samsung",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Neo QLED",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8K",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Neural Quantum Processor",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "AI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samsung TV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Softlogic",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singer",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singhagiri",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Damro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung e-Store",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලොව අංක 1 රූපවාහිනී නිෂ්පාදක සැම්සුන් විසින් ‘Samsung Sahana’ හඳුන්වා දෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දක්වා වට්ටම් පිරිනමයි. ශෝකයට පත් ප්‍රදේශවාසීන්ට සහන වශයෙන් රුපියල් 900,000",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රමුඛතම ඉලෙක්ට්‍රොනික නිෂ්පාදන සන්නාමය වන Samsung, මුළු රටම තවමත් දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකට මුහුණ දී සිටින මෙම කැලඹිලි සහිත කාලවලදී තම පාරිභෝගිකයින්ට සහන සැලසීම සඳහා \"Samsung Sahana\" එළිදක්වන ලදී. සැම්සුන් සමාගම රු. විනෝදාස්වාද පද්ධතියක් (රූපවාහිනී) මිලදී ගැනීමෙන් නිවසට යම් සතුටක් ගෙන ඒමට කැමති පාරිභෝගිකයින් සඳහා එහි රූපවාහිනී පරාසයේ 900,000.",
        "Samsung Sahana යටතේ, පාරිභෝගිකයන් Samsung TV සඳහා රු. ආර්ථික උද්ධමනය හේතුවෙන් මිල ඉහළ මට්ටමක පවතින අවස්ථාවක පාරිභෝගිකයින්ට Samsung TV මිලදී ගැනීමට ඉඩ දීම සඳහා 900,000. ජූලි 5 වැනිදා සිට Samsung Sahana පාරිභෝගිකයින්ට දැරිය හැකි මිලකට වාරික Samsung TV මිලදී ගැනීමට ඉඩ සලසයි.",
        "Samsung 43” FHD Smart TV අඩු මිලකට රු. 204,999 ක වට්ටමක් සහිතව. 8,000 කි. 43” UHD TV දැන් රු. 249,999 සමඟ රු. 20,000 ක වට්ටමක්. තවද, Samsung 50” UHD TV වට්ටම් සහිත මිලකට රු. 319,999 ක් වන අතර 55” UHD රූපවාහිනිය රු. 399,999 ක වට්ටමක් සහිතව. 50,000 කි. 65” UHD TV දැන් රු. 569,999 ක වට්ටමක් සහිතව. 60,000ක් වන අතර 75” UHD රූපවාහිනිය රු. 799,999 ක වට්ටමක් සහිතව. 100,000 කි.",
        "QLED පරාසය තුළ Samsung විසින් රු. 55” QLED TV සඳහා 65,000, රු. 65\" QLED TV සඳහා 160,000 සහ රු. 75” Neo QLED 8K TV සඳහා 300,000. 85” Neo QLED 8K TV සඳහා ඉහළම වට්ටමක් පිරිනමනු ලබන අතර, රු. 900,000 දැන් ලබා ගත හැකි මිල රු. 4,399,999 ක් පමණි.",
        "“අපි සැමවිටම අපගේ පාරිභෝගික අවශ්‍යතා සහ අවශ්‍යතා පිළිබඳව දැනුවත්ව සිටිමු. ඔවුන් සියලු දෙනාටම අපගේ නිෂ්පාදන මිල දී ගැනීමටත් අප ගෙන එන නවෝත්පාදනයන් භුක්ති විඳීමටත් අපට අවශ්‍යය. සැම්සුන් සහන සඳහා හේතුව මෙයයි, මෙම දුෂ්කර කාලවලදී පවා සැම්සුන් පාරිභෝගිකයින්ට දැරිය හැකි මිලකට වාරික මට්ටමේ රූපවාහිනී මිලදී ගැනීමට ඉඩ සලසයි, ”සැම්සුන්ග් ශ්‍රී ලංකා කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ Kevin SungSu YOU පැවසීය.",
        "සැම්සුන් ඉලෙක්ට්‍රොනික්ස් දශකයකට වැඩි කාලයක් පුරා රූපවාහිනී කර්මාන්තයේ ප්‍රමුඛයා වී ඇත්තේ පාරිභෝගික රූපවාහිනීවල පවතින නවීනතම තාක්ෂණයන් සමඟිනි. 2022 දී, Samsung අඛණ්ඩව වසර 16 ක් සඳහා වෙළඳපල කොටස අනුව අංක එකේ ස්ථානය නැවත ලබා ගෙන ඇත.",
        "Samsung තිරවල හදවත වන්නේ පාරිභෝගික කේන්ද්‍රීය නවෝත්පාදනයන් වන අතර, එය Neo QLED 8K ඇතුළු Samsung තිරවලට නිර්මල, සත්‍ය-ජීවිත පින්තූරයේ ගුණාත්මක භාවය ලබා දීමට බල කරයි. Samsung Neo QLED 8K යනු කෘත්‍රිම බුද්ධිය (AI) මගින් බල ගැන්වෙන මීළඟ මට්ටමේ පින්තූර ගුණාත්මක භාවය සහ එක්-ආකාරයේ විශේෂාංග සහිත නවීන දින සඳහා රූපවාහිනියයි. ස්මාර්ට් නිවාස පරිසර පද්ධතියේ මධ්‍යයේ රූපවාහිනී සමඟින්, පරිශීලකයින්ට ඔවුන්ගේ රූපවාහිනිය භාවිතයෙන් ඔවුන්ගේ සියලුම උපාංග පහසුවෙන් පාලනය කළ හැකි අතර එමඟින් ඒවා හොඳම භාවිතයට ගත හැකිය.",
        "සැම්සුන් විසින් සිය නව පරිශීලක අතුරුමුහුණත වන ටයිසන් මගින් බල ගැන්වෙන Smart Hub ද එළිදක්වන ලදී. නවතම Samsung Smart Hub ස්මාර්ට් අත්දැකීමේ සෑම අංගයක්ම පහසුවෙන් සැරිසැරීමට හැකි මුල් තිරයකට ගෙන එයි. නව ටැබය බාධාවකින් තොර පරිශීලක අත්දැකීමක් සඳහා විශේෂාංග, සැකසීම් සහ අන්තර්ගතය වර්ග තුනකට වර්ග කරයි: මාධ්‍ය, ක්‍රීඩා මධ්‍යස්ථානය සහ අවට.",
        "Samsung හි Neo QLED 8K පිටුපස ඇති නවෝත්පාදනයේ හරය වන්නේ එහි Neural Quantum Processor 8K ය. ස්වාධීන ස්නායුක AI ජාල 20 ක් එක් එක් දර්ශනය විශ්ලේෂණය කර අන්තර්ගතයේ මුල් පින්තූරයේ ගුණාත්මක භාවය නොසලකා හොඳම නැරඹුම් අත්දැකීම් ලබා දීමට පින්තූරයේ ගුණාත්මකභාවය සකස් කරයි.",
        "Samsung TV පරාසය බලයලත් හවුල්කරුවන් වන Softlogic, Singer, Singhagiri, Damro සහ Samsung e-Store වෙතින් මිලදී ගැනීමට තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "සැම්සුන්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Samsung Sahana",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "900,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සැම්සුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung Sahana",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැම්සුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "900,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samsung Sahana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැම්සුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "900,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැම්සුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung Sahana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැම්සුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FHD ස්මාර්ට් රූපවාහිනිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "204,999 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "43",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UHD රූපවාහිනිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "249,999 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UHD රූපවාහිනිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "319,999 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "55",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UHD රූපවාහිනිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "399,999 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "65",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UHD රූපවාහිනිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "569,999 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UHD රූපවාහිනිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "799,999 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සැම්සුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "65,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "55",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "160,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "65",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "300,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේ ටීවී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "85",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේ ටීවී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "900,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,399,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samsung Sahana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැම්සුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙවින් සුංසු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samsung ඉලෙක්ට්‍රොනික්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දශකයකට වැඩි කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැම්සුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඛණ්ඩව වසර 16 ක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සැම්සුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැම්සුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Neo QLED",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8K",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung Neo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8K",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "නූතන දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සැම්සුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්මාර්ට් හබ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung Smart Hub",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්‍රීඩා මධ්‍යස්ථානය සහ අවට",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සැම්සුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Neo QLED",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8K",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්නායු ක්වොන්ටම් ප්‍රොසෙසරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "AI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samsung TV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Softlogic",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගායකයා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහගිරි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දම්රෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung e-Store",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "உலகின் நம்பர் 1 தொலைக்காட்சி தயாரிப்பு நிறுவனமான சாம்சங் நிறுவனம் ‘சாம்சங் சஹானா’வை அறிமுகப்படுத்துகிறது.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ரூ. வரை தள்ளுபடி வழங்குகிறது. துக்கத்தால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட உள்ளூர் மக்களுக்கு 900,000 நிவாரணம்",
        "இலங்கையின் முன்னணி இலத்திரனியல் வர்த்தக நாமமான Samsung, முழு நாடும் இன்னும் மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை எதிர்நோக்கி வரும் இந்த கொந்தளிப்பான காலங்களில் தனது நுகர்வோருக்கு நிவாரணம் வழங்குவதற்காக \"Samsung Sahana\" ஐ வெளியிட்டது. சாம்சங் நிறுவனம் நிவாரணம் வழங்க நடவடிக்கை எடுத்துள்ளது, இதன் மூலம் ரூ. ஒரு பொழுதுபோக்கு அமைப்பை (டிவி) வாங்குவதன் மூலம் வீட்டிற்குச் சிறிது மகிழ்ச்சியைக் கொண்டுவர விரும்பும் நுகர்வோருக்கு அதன் டிவி வரம்பில் 900,000.",
        "சாம்சங் சஹானாவின் கீழ், வாடிக்கையாளர்கள் சாம்சங் டிவிகளில் ரூ. வரை தள்ளுபடி பெறத் தகுதியுடையவர்கள். பொருளாதார பணவீக்கம் காரணமாக விலைகள் உச்சத்தில் இருக்கும் நேரத்தில் சாம்சங் டிவிகளை வாங்க நுகர்வோரை அனுமதிக்க 900,000. ஜூலை 5 முதல், சாம்சங் சஹானா வாடிக்கையாளர்களுக்கு பிரீமியம் சாம்சங் டிவிகளை மலிவு விலையில் வாங்க அனுமதிக்கிறது.",
        "சாம்சங் 43” FHD ஸ்மார்ட் டிவி குறைந்த விலை ரூ. 204,999 தள்ளுபடியுடன் ரூ. 8,000. 43” UHD TV இப்போது ரூ. விலையில் கிடைக்கிறது. 249,999 உடன் ரூ. 20,000 தள்ளுபடி. மேலும், Samsung 50” UHD TV தள்ளுபடி விலையில் ரூ. 319,999 மற்றும் 55” UHD TV ரூ. விலையில் கிடைக்கிறது. 399,999 தள்ளுபடியில் ரூ. 50,000. 65” UHD TV இப்போது ரூ. விலையில் கிடைக்கிறது. 569,999 தள்ளுபடியுடன் ரூ. 60,000 மற்றும் 75” UHD TV ரூ. விலையில் கிடைக்கிறது. 799,999 தள்ளுபடியுடன் ரூ. 100,000.",
        "QLED வரம்பில், சாம்சங் ரூ. தள்ளுபடி வழங்குகிறது. 55” QLED டிவிக்கு 65,000, ரூ. 65” QLED டிவிக்கு 160,000 மற்றும் ரூ. 75” நியோ QLED 8K டிவிக்கு 300,000. 85” நியோ கியூஎல்இடி 8கே டிவிக்கு அதிகபட்ச தள்ளுபடி வழங்கப்படுகிறது, ரூ. 900,000 இப்போது ரூ. விலையில் கிடைக்கிறது. 4,399,999 மட்டுமே.",
        "\"எங்கள் நுகர்வோரின் தேவைகள் மற்றும் விருப்பங்களை நாங்கள் எப்போதும் உணர்ந்துள்ளோம். அவர்கள் அனைவரும் எங்கள் தயாரிப்புகளை வாங்கவும், நாங்கள் கொண்டு வரும் புதுமைகளை அனுபவிக்கவும் நாங்கள் விரும்புகிறோம். இதுவே சாம்சங் சஹானாவின் காரணமாகும், இது சாம்சங் நுகர்வோர் இக்கட்டான காலத்திலும் மலிவு விலையில் பிரீமியம் நிலை தொலைக்காட்சிகளை கொள்வனவு செய்ய அனுமதிக்கும்” என Samsung இலங்கையின் முகாமைத்துவப் பணிப்பாளர் Kevin SungSu YOU தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சாம்சங் எலக்ட்ரானிக்ஸ் ஒரு தசாப்தத்திற்கும் மேலாக நுகர்வோர் டிவிகளில் கிடைக்கும் சமீபத்திய தொழில்நுட்பங்களுடன் தொலைக்காட்சி துறையில் முன்னணியில் உள்ளது. 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டில், சாம்சங் தொடர்ந்து 16 ஆண்டுகளாக சந்தைப் பங்கின் அடிப்படையில் மீண்டும் முதலிடத்தைப் பிடித்துள்ளது.",
        "சாம்சங் திரைகளின் மையத்தில் வாடிக்கையாளர்களை மையமாகக் கொண்ட கண்டுபிடிப்பு உள்ளது, இது நியோ கியூஎல்இடி 8கே உள்ளிட்ட சாம்சங் திரைகளை மாசற்ற, உண்மையான வாழ்க்கைப் படத் தரத்தை வழங்க உதவுகிறது. சாம்சங் நியோ கியூஎல்இடி 8கே என்பது நவீன காலத்துக்கான டிவியாகும், அடுத்த நிலை படத் தரம் மற்றும் செயற்கை நுண்ணறிவு (AI) மூலம் இயங்கும் ஒரு வகையான அம்சங்களுடன். ஸ்மார்ட் ஹோம் சுற்றுச்சூழலின் மையத்தில் டிவிகள் இருப்பதால், பயனர்கள் தங்கள் டிவியைப் பயன்படுத்தி தங்கள் எல்லா சாதனங்களையும் எளிதாகக் கட்டுப்படுத்தலாம், இதனால் அவற்றைச் சிறந்த முறையில் பயன்படுத்த முடியும்.",
        "சாம்சங் ஸ்மார்ட் ஹப்பை வெளியிட்டது, அதன் புதிய பயனர் இடைமுகம், டைசன் மூலம் இயக்கப்படுகிறது. புதிய சாம்சங் ஸ்மார்ட் ஹப் ஸ்மார்ட் அனுபவத்தின் ஒவ்வொரு அம்சத்தையும் ஒரு சுலபமான முகப்புத் திரையில் கொண்டு வருகிறது. புதிய தாவல் அம்சங்கள், அமைப்புகள் மற்றும் உள்ளடக்கத்தை தடையற்ற பயனர் அனுபவத்திற்காக மூன்று வகைகளாக வகைப்படுத்துகிறது: மீடியா, கேமிங் ஹப் மற்றும் சுற்றுப்புறம்.",
        "சாம்சங்கின் நியோ க்யூஎல்இடி 8கேயின் புதிய கண்டுபிடிப்பின் மையத்தில் அதன் நியூரல் குவாண்டம் செயலி 8கே உள்ளது. 20 சுயாதீன நரம்பியல் AI நெட்வொர்க்குகள் ஒவ்வொரு காட்சியையும் பகுப்பாய்வு செய்து, உள்ளடக்கத்தின் அசல் படத் தரத்தைப் பொருட்படுத்தாமல் சிறந்த பார்வை அனுபவங்களை வழங்க படத்தின் தரத்தை சரிசெய்கிறது.",
        "சாம்சங் டிவி வரம்பு அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்ட கூட்டாளர்களான Softlogic, Singer, Singhagiri, Damro மற்றும் Samsung e-Store இல் வாங்குவதற்கு கிடைக்கிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "சாம்சங்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சாம்சங் சஹானா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "900,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங் சஹானா",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "900,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங் சஹானா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "900,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங் சஹானா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FHD ஸ்மார்ட் டிவி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "204,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "43",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UHD டிவி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "249,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UHD டிவி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "319,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "55",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UHD டிவி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "399,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "65",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UHD டிவி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "569,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UHD டிவி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "799,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "65,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "55",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "160,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "65",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "300,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கே டி.வி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "85",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கே டி.வி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "900,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,399,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங் சஹானா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங் இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெவின் சுங்சு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங் எலக்ட்ரானிக்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு தசாப்தத்திற்கும் மேலாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொடர்ந்து 16 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நியோ கியூஎல்இடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8K",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங் நியோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8K",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவீன நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்மார்ட் ஹப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங் ஸ்மார்ட் ஹப்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேமிங் ஹப் மற்றும் சுற்றுப்புறம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நியோ கியூஎல்இடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8K",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "நியூரல் குவாண்டம் செயலி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "AI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங் டிவி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாஃப்ட்லாஜிக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாடகர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்ககிரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டம்ரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங் இ-ஸ்டோர்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}