{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ශ්‍රී--ලංකාවට-අත-දෙන්න-ජපානයෙන්-සමූළුවක්/11-396622",
  "time_ut": 1661493224,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ශ්‍රී  ලංකාවට අත දෙන්න ජපානයෙන් සමූළුවක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A group from Japan to lend a hand to Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Japan hopes to organize a meeting of Sri Lanka's creditors, which it hopes will help resolve Sri Lanka's debt crisis.",
        "In order to rescue Sri Lanka from the worst debt crisis, Tokyo is open to hold talks between all the creditor countries.",
        "But it is not clear whether China, which owns nearly 20 percent of Sri Lanka's total debt, will join it.",
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe told Reuters last week that Sri Lanka would ask Japan to invite major creditor nations to talks on bilateral debt restructuring."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tokyo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly 20 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී  ලංකාවට අත දෙන්න ජපානයෙන් සමූළුවක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ණය හිමියන්ගේ සමුළුවක් සංවිධානය කිරීමට ජපානය  බලාපොරොත්තු වන අතර එය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය අර්බුදය විසඳීමට උපකාරී වනු ඇතැයි ජපානයය අපේක්ෂා කරයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුහුණ දෙනන දරුණුතම ණය අර්බුදයෙන් මුදාගැනීමේ අරමුණින් ටෝකියෝ  අගනුුවරදී සියලු ණයහිමි රටවල් අතර සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වීමට මේ හරහා විවෘතව පවති.",
        "නමුත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සමස්ත ණයෙන් සියයට 20කට ආසන්න සංඛ්‍යාවකට හිමිකම් කියන චීනය එයට සම්බන්ධ වන්නේද යන්න පැහැදිලි නොමැත.",
        "ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡා සඳහා ප්‍රධාන ණය දෙන ජාතීන්ට ආරාධනා කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජපානයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ පසුගිය සතියේ රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවයට පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටෝකියෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 20කට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கைக்கு கைகொடுக்க ஜப்பானில் இருந்து ஒரு குழு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் கடன் நெருக்கடியைத் தீர்க்க உதவும் என்று நம்பும் ஜப்பான் இலங்கையின் கடன் வழங்குநர்களின் கூட்டத்தை ஏற்பாடு செய்ய நம்புகிறது.",
        "மிக மோசமான கடன் நெருக்கடியில் இருந்து இலங்கையை மீட்பதற்காக, அனைத்து கடன் வழங்கும் நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையே பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்த டோக்கியோ தயாராக உள்ளது.",
        "ஆனால் இலங்கையின் மொத்தக் கடனில் கிட்டத்தட்ட 20 வீதத்தை வைத்திருக்கும் சீனா அதனுடன் இணையுமா என்பது தெளிவாகத் தெரியவில்லை.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க கடந்த வாரம் ரொய்ட்டர்ஸிடம், இருதரப்பு கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு தொடர்பான பேச்சுவார்த்தைக்கு பெரிய கடன் வழங்கும் நாடுகளை அழைக்குமாறு ஜப்பானை இலங்கை கேட்டுக் கொள்ளும் என்று கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோக்கியோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 20 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}