{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Sri-Lanka-seeks-greater-cooperation-in-food-processing-and-dairy-sectors-with-India/56-737014",
  "time_ut": 1656880372,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka seeks greater cooperation in food processing and dairy sectors with India",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka seeks greater cooperation in food processing and dairy sectors with India",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka and India agreed to explore further avenues towards greater cooperation in the food processing and dairy sectors, when Sri Lanka’s High Commissioner to India Milinda Moragoda recently met with India’s Minister of Food Processing Industries Shri Pashupati Kumar Paras in New Delhi.",
        "At the outset, Minister Paras accorded a warm welcome to High Commissioner Moragoda and said that he and his government led by Prime Minister Shri Narendra Modi are always ready to help Sri Lanka in these difficult times.",
        "While thanking the Minister, High Commissioner Moragoda stressed the importance of establishing close linkages between India and Sri Lanka in various sectors under the Minister’s purview, in particular the dairy industry. The High Commissioner observed that import of milk powder from India including through the existing credit line would contribute to increase nutrition levels among children in Sri Lanka.",
        "The Minister and the High Commissioner agreed that cooperation could commence with the dairy sector, and it could later be expanded into other sectors falling under the supervision of the Ministry of Food Processing Industries. High Commissioner Moragoda said that the ultimate objective of these efforts would be greater economic integration of the two countries.",
        "With a view to looking into the way forward for cooperation in these sectors, it was decided to form a study group that would comprise officials from the Ministry of Food Processing Industries and the High Commission of Sri Lanka as well as other relevant stakeholders both in India and Sri Lanka. It was also decided to have the first meeting of the study group soon.",
        "Minister Paras who hails from the State of Bihar is the incumbent President of the Rashtriya Lok Janshakti Party, which is part of the ruling National Democratic Alliance led by Prime Minister Narendra Modi. He has been a member of the Bihar Legislative Assembly seven times since 1977 and had served thrice as a Minister in the State.",
        "Secretary to the Ministry of Food Processing Industries Smt. Anita Praveen, senior officials of the Ministry as well as senior diplomatic officers of the High Commission of Sri Lanka in New Delhi also attended the meeting."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paras",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Paras",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moragoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shri Narendra Modi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Moragoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Food Processing Industries",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moragoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Food Processing Industries",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Paras",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the State of Bihar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rashtriya Lok Janshakti Party",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Democratic Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Narendra Modi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bihar Legislative Assembly",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Food Processing Industries Smt",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anita Praveen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the High Commission of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඉන්දියාව සමඟ ආහාර සැකසුම් සහ කිරි නිෂ්පාදන ක්ෂේත්‍රවල වැඩි සහයෝගීතාවයක් අපේක්ෂා කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දියාවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් මිලින්ද මොරගොඩ පසුගියදා නවදිල්ලි නුවරදී ඉන්දියාවේ ආහාර සැකසුම් කර්මාන්ත අමාත්‍ය ශ්‍රී පශුපති කුමාර් පරස් මහතා හමුවූ අවස්ථාවේදී ආහාර සැකසීම සහ කිරි නිෂ්පාදන ක්ෂේත්‍රවල වැඩි සහයෝගීතාවක් සඳහා වැඩිදුර මාර්ග ගවේෂණය කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ ඉන්දියාව එකඟ වූහ.",
        "ආරම්භයේදීම අමාත්‍ය පරාස් මහතා මහ කොමසාරිස් මොරගොඩ මහතාව උණුසුම් ලෙස පිළිගත් අතර තමා සහ අගමැති ශ්‍රී නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි ප්‍රමුඛ තම රජය මෙම දුෂ්කර කාලවලදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට උපකාර කිරීමට සැමවිටම සූදානම් බව පැවසීය.",
        "අමාත්‍යවරයාට ස්තූතිය පළ කළ මහ කොමසාරිස් මොරගොඩ මහතා, අමාත්‍යවරයාගේ විෂය පථය යටතේ විවිධ ක්ෂේත්‍රවල, විශේෂයෙන් කිරි කර්මාන්තය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉන්දියාව සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර සමීප සබඳතා ඇති කර ගැනීමේ වැදගත්කම අවධාරණය කළේය. දැනට පවතින ණය මාර්ගය ඇතුළුව ඉන්දියාවෙන් කිරිපිටි ආනයනය කිරීම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දරුවන්ගේ පෝෂණ මට්ටම ඉහළ නැංවීමට දායක වන බව මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයා නිරීක්ෂණය කළේය.",
        "කිරි නිෂ්පාදන අංශය සමඟ සහයෝගීතාව ආරම්භ කළ හැකි බවට අමාත්‍යවරයා සහ මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයා එකඟ වූ අතර, පසුව එය ආහාර සැකසුම් කර්මාන්ත අමාත්‍යාංශයේ අධීක්‍ෂණයට යටත්ව අනෙකුත් අංශ වෙත ද ව්‍යාප්ත කළ හැකිය. මහ කොමසාරිස් මොරගොඩ කියා සිටියේ මෙම ප්‍රයත්නවල අවසාන අරමුණ දෙරටේ විශාල ආර්ථික ඒකාබද්ධතාවයක් වනු ඇති බවයි.",
        "මෙම ක්ෂේත්‍රවල සහයෝගීතාවයේ ඉදිරි මාවත සොයා බැලීමේ අරමුණින්, ආහාර සැකසුම් කර්මාන්ත අමාත්‍යාංශයේ සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලයේ නිලධාරීන් මෙන්ම ඉන්දියාවේ අනෙකුත් අදාළ පාර්ශවකරුවන්ගෙන් සමන්විත අධ්‍යයන කණ්ඩායමක් පිහිටුවීමට තීරණය විය. සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව. අධ්‍යයන කණ්ඩායමේ පළමු රැස්වීම ළඟදීම පැවැත්වීමට ද තීරණය විය.",
        "බිහාර් ප්‍රාන්තයෙන් පැමිණි අමාත්‍ය පරාස්, අගමැති නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදිගේ නායකත්වයෙන් යුත් පාලක ජාතික ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී සන්ධානයේ කොටසක් වන Rashtriya Lok Janashakti පක්ෂයේ වත්මන් සභාපතිවරයා වේ. ඔහු 1977 සිට හත් වතාවක් බිහාර් ව්‍යවස්ථාදායක සභාවේ සාමාජිකයෙකු වී ඇති අතර ප්‍රාන්තයේ අමාත්‍යවරයෙකු ලෙස තුන් වතාවක් සේවය කර ඇත.",
        "ආහාර සැකසුම් කර්මාන්ත අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම් ශ්‍රී. අනීටා ප්‍රවීන්, අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරීන් මෙන්ම නවදිල්ලි නුවර ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික නිලධාරීන් ද මෙම රැස්වීමට සහභාගි වූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පරස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පරස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොරගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මොරගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආහාර සැකසුම් කර්මාන්ත අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොරගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආහාර සැකසුම් කර්මාන්ත අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ කොමසාරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පරස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිහාර් ප්‍රාන්තය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාෂ්ට්‍රිය ලෝක් ජනශක්ති පක්ෂය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිහාර් ව්‍යවස්ථාදායක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආහාර සැකසුම් කර්මාන්ත අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනීටා ප්‍රවීන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்தியாவுடன் உணவு பதப்படுத்துதல் மற்றும் பால் உற்பத்தி துறைகளில் இலங்கை அதிக ஒத்துழைப்பை நாடுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்தியாவிற்கான இலங்கை உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் மிலிந்த மொரகொட அண்மையில் இந்தியாவின் உணவு பதப்படுத்துதல் கைத்தொழில் அமைச்சர் ஸ்ரீ பசுபதி குமார் பராஸை புதுடில்லியில் சந்தித்த போது, ​​உணவு பதப்படுத்துதல் மற்றும் பால் உற்பத்தித் துறைகளில் அதிக ஒத்துழைப்பை மேற்கொள்வதற்கான மேலதிக வழிகளை ஆராய இலங்கையும் இந்தியாவும் ஒப்புக்கொண்டன.",
        "ஆரம்பத்தில், உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் மொரகொடவிற்கு அன்பான வரவேற்பை வழங்கிய அமைச்சர் பராஸ், இந்த இக்கட்டான காலங்களில் இலங்கைக்கு உதவ தானும் பிரதமர் திரு நரேந்திர மோடி தலைமையிலான தனது அரசாங்கமும் எப்போதும் தயாராக இருப்பதாக கூறினார்.",
        "அமைச்சருக்கு நன்றி தெரிவித்த உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் மொரகொட, அமைச்சரின் பணிப்புரையின் கீழ் பல்வேறு துறைகளில் குறிப்பாக பால் கைத்தொழில் துறைகளில் இந்தியாவிற்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையில் நெருங்கிய தொடர்பை ஏற்படுத்துவதன் முக்கியத்துவத்தை வலியுறுத்தினார். இந்தியாவில் இருந்து பால் மாவை இறக்குமதி செய்வது, தற்போதுள்ள கடன் வரி உட்பட இலங்கையில் உள்ள குழந்தைகளிடையே ஊட்டச்சத்து அளவை அதிகரிக்க பங்களிப்பதாக உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் அவதானித்தார்.",
        "அமைச்சர் மற்றும் உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் ஆகியோர் பால் உற்பத்தித் துறையுடன் ஒத்துழைப்பைத் தொடங்கலாம் என்று ஒப்புக்கொண்டனர், பின்னர் அது உணவு பதப்படுத்தும் தொழில்துறை அமைச்சகத்தின் மேற்பார்வையின் கீழ் வரும் மற்ற துறைகளுக்கும் விரிவுபடுத்தப்படலாம். உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் மொரகொட, இந்த முயற்சிகளின் இறுதி நோக்கம் இரு நாடுகளின் பொருளாதார ஒருங்கிணைப்பு ஆகும்.",
        "இந்தத் துறைகளில் ஒத்துழைப்பதற்கான முன்னோக்கி வழியைக் கண்டறியும் நோக்கில், உணவுப் பதப்படுத்தும் கைத்தொழில் அமைச்சு மற்றும் இலங்கை உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயத்தின் அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் இந்தியாவில் உள்ள பிற தொடர்புடைய பங்குதாரர்களை உள்ளடக்கிய ஒரு ஆய்வுக் குழுவை உருவாக்க முடிவு செய்யப்பட்டது. மற்றும் இலங்கை. ஆய்வுக்குழுவின் முதல் கூட்டத்தை விரைவில் நடத்தவும் முடிவு செய்யப்பட்டது.",
        "பீகார் மாநிலத்தைச் சேர்ந்த அமைச்சர் பராஸ், பிரதமர் நரேந்திர மோடி தலைமையிலான ஆளும் தேசிய ஜனநாயகக் கூட்டணியில் அங்கம் வகிக்கும் ராஷ்டிரிய லோக் ஜனசக்தி கட்சியின் தற்போதைய தலைவராக உள்ளார். 1977 முதல் ஏழு முறை பீகார் சட்டமன்ற உறுப்பினராக இருந்த அவர், மாநிலத்தில் அமைச்சராக மூன்று முறை பணியாற்றியுள்ளார்.",
        "உணவு பதப்படுத்தும் தொழில் அமைச்சகத்தின் செயலாளர் ஸ்ரீமதி. அனிதா பிரவீன், அமைச்சின் சிரேஷ்ட அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் புதுடெல்லியில் உள்ள இலங்கை உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயத்தின் சிரேஷ்ட இராஜதந்திர அதிகாரிகள் ஆகியோர் இந்த சந்திப்பில் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பராஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பராஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொரகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ நரேந்திர மோடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மொரகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உணவு பதப்படுத்தும் தொழில் அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொரகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உணவு பதப்படுத்தும் தொழில் அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உயர் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பராஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீகார் மாநிலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஷ்ட்ரிய லோக் ஜனசக்தி கட்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய ஜனநாயகக் கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நரேந்திர மோடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீகார் சட்டமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உணவு பதப்படுத்தும் தொழில்துறை அமைச்சகம் ஸ்ரீமதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனிதா பிரவீன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}