{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130654",
  "time_ut": 1656777334,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "அமெரிக்க இராஜாங்க செயலர் இலங்கை வருகிறார்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "US Secretary of State arrives in Sri Lanka",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka, which is facing a major economic crisis, is seeking additional cooperation from friendly countries.",
        "In this case, US President Joe Biden has announced that he will provide 20 million dollars for the food security of the country in order to reflect that the US is paying more attention to the crisis in Sri Lanka.",
        "President Biden made the announcement while attending the G-20 summit.",
        "Similarly, Sri Lankan Ambassador Mahinda Samarasinghe in Washington along with President Biden and Secretary of State Anthony Blinken also met.",
        "Ambassador Mahinda Samarasinghe mentioned that Sri Lanka's demands and expectations have been positively responded to during those meetings.",
        "At the same time, a high-level delegation including US Treasury Deputy Assistant Secretary for Asia Robert Kaproth and Deputy Assistant Secretary for South and Central Asian Affairs Kelly Geideling visited Sri Lanka last week and participated in various meetings.",
        "During this, they discussed a wide range of issues including Sri Lanka-US joint projects to recover from the economic crisis and expansion of cooperation.",
        "An important official of the government mentioned that important announcements may be made regarding US cooperation for Sri Lanka as the team has now returned to Washington.",
        "At the same time, he also mentioned that the date of State Secretary Anthony Blinken's visit to Sri Lanka may be announced as soon as possible."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "State",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 million dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "G-20",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Samarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Washington",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anthony Blinken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Samarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Robert Kaproth",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "South",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelly Geideling",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka-",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Washington",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anthony Blinken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඇමෙරිකානු රාජ්‍ය ලේකම් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "විශාල ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකට මුහුණ දී සිටින ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මිත්‍ර රටවලින් අමතර සහයෝගයක් අපේක්ෂා කරයි.",
        "මෙහිදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අර්බුදකාරී තත්ත්වය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අමෙරිකාව වැඩි අවධානයක් යොමු කර ඇති බව පිළිබිඹු කිරීම සඳහා රටේ ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතාව වෙනුවෙන් ඩොලර් මිලියන 20ක මුදලක් ලබාදෙන බව ඇමෙරිකානු ජනාධිපති ජෝ බයිඩන් ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබේ.",
        "G-20 සමුළුවට සහභාගී වෙමින් ජනාධිපති Biden මේ බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "එසේම, වොෂින්ටනයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති මහින්ද සමරසිංහ, ජනාධිපති බිඩෙන් සහ රාජ්‍ය ලේකම් ඇන්තනි බ්ලින්කන් ද හමු විය.",
        "එම රැස්වීම්වලදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉල්ලීම් සහ අපේක්ෂාවන් සඳහා ධනාත්මක ප්‍රතිචාර ලැබී ඇති බව තානාපති මහින්ද සමරසිංහ සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ඒ සමගම, ඇමෙරිකානු භාණ්ඩාගාර ආසියානු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ නියෝජ්‍ය සහකාර ලේකම් රොබට් කප්‍රොත් සහ දකුණු හා මධ්‍යම ආසියානු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ නියෝජ්‍ය සහකාර ලේකම් කෙලී ගයිඩලින් ඇතුළු ඉහළ පෙළේ නියෝජිත පිරිසක් පසුගිය සතියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණ විවිධ රැස්වීම්වලට සහභාගි වූහ.",
        "ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩ ඒම සහ සහයෝගීතාව පුළුල් කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා - අමෙරිකා ඒකාබද්ධ ව්‍යාපෘති ඇතුළු පුළුල් පරාසයක කරුණු පිළිබඳව මෙහිදී සාකච්ඡා කළහ.",
        "කණ්ඩායම මේ වන විට වොෂින්ටනයට පැමිණ ඇති බැවින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා අමෙරිකානු සහයෝගීතාව පිළිබඳ වැදගත් නිවේදන නිකුත් කිරීමට ඉඩ ඇති බව රජයේ වැදගත් නිලධාරියෙක් සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ඒ අතරම, රාජ්‍ය ලේකම් ඇන්තනි බ්ලින්කන් මහතාගේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරයේ දිනය හැකි ඉක්මනින් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කළ හැකි බවද ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "රජයේ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 20 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බයිඩෙන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "G-20",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද සමරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වොෂින්ටනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බයිඩෙන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇන්තනි බ්ලින්කන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද සමරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද භාණ්ඩාගාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොබට් කප්රොත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙලී ගෙයිඩලිං",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව-",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වොෂින්ටනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇන්තනි බ්ලින්කන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அமெரிக்க இராஜாங்க செயலர் இலங்கை வருகிறார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பெரும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை எதிர்க்கொண்டுள்ள இலங்கை நட்பு நாடுகளிடம் கூடுதல் ஒத்துழைப்புகளை கோரிவருகின்றது.",
        "இந்நிலையில் இலங்கையின் நெருக்கடி குறித்து அமெரிக்கா கூடுதல் அவதானம் கொண்டுள்ளமையை பிரதிப்பளிக்கும் வகையில் நாட்டின் உணவு பாதுகாப்பிற்காக  20 மில்லியன் டொலர்களை வழங்குவதாக அமெரிக்க ஜனாதிபதி ஜோ பைடன் அறிவித்திருந்தார்.",
        "ஜி -20 உச்சி மாநாட்டில் கலந்துக்கொண்டிருந்த சந்தர்ப்பத்திலேயே ஜனாதிபதி பைடன் இந்த அறிவிப்பை விடுத்திருந்தார்.",
        "அதே போன்று வொஷிங்டனில் உள்ள இலங்கை தூதுவர் மஹிந்த சமரசிங்கவை ஜனாதிபதி பைடன் உட்பட இராஜாங்க செயலர் அண்டனி பிளிங்கன் ஆகியோரும் சந்தித்திருந்தனர்.",
        "அந்த சந்திப்புகளின் போது இலங்கையின் கோரிக்கைகள் மற்றும் எதிர்பார்ப்புகளுக்கு சாதகமான பதிலளிப்பே கிடைத்துள்ளதாக தூதுவர் மஹிந்த சமரசிங்க குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இதேவேளை அமெரிக்க திறைசேரியின் ஆசியப்பிராந்தியத்துக்கான பிரதி உதவிச்செயலர் ரொபேர்ட் கப்ரொத் மற்றும் தெற்கு மற்றும் மத்திய ஆசிய விவகாரங்களுக்கான பிரதி உதவிச்செயலாளர் கெலி கெய்டெலிங் உட்பட உயர் மட்ட குழுவினர் கடந்த வாரத்தில்  இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் மேற்கொண்டு பலதரப்பட்ட சந்திப்புகளில் கலந்துக்கொண்டிருந்தனர்.",
        "இதன் போது பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து மீள்வதற்கான இலங்கை - அமெரிக்கக் கூட்டுத்திட்டங்கள் மற்றும் ஒத்துழைப்புள் விஸ்தரிப்பு உள்ளிட்ட பரந்துபட்ட பல விடயங்கள் குறித்து கலந்துரைளாடியிருந்தனர்.",
        "இந்த குழுவினர் தற்போது வோஷpங்டன் திரும்பியுள்ள நிலையில் இலங்கைக்கான அமெரிக்க ஒத்துழைப்புகள் குறித்து முக்கிய அறிவிப்புகள் வெளியிடப்படலாம் என அரசாங்கத்தின் முக்கியஸ்தர் ஒருவர் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "இதேவேளை இராஜாங்க செயலர் அண்டனி பிளிங்கனின் இலங்கை விஜயம் தொடர்பான திகதி விபரங்களும் கூடிய விரைவில் அறிவிக்கப்படலாம் எனவும் அவர் மேலும் குறிப்பிட்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "நிலை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 மில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிடன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி-20",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த சமரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாஷிங்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிடன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்தோனி பிளிங்கன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த சமரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராபர்ட் கப்ரோத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெல்லி கீடிலிங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை-",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாஷிங்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்தோனி பிளிங்கன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}