{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84481/hal-sameera-arrested-by-stf-with-guns-and-ammo",
  "time_ut": 1661239380,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "‘Hal Sameera’ arrested by STF with guns and ammo",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "‘Hal Sameera’ arrested by STF with guns and ammo",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Police Special Task Force (STF) has arrested a wanted criminal by the name of Warnakulasooriya Kristembuge Sameera Sampath Fernando alias “Hal Sameera”, along with several firearms and ammunition.",
        "The officers have conducted a raid at a house in the Minuwangoda area yesterday (22), according to a tip-off received by the special operations unit of the Police STF.",
        "During the raid, officers arrested the 36-year-old suspect who allegedly collected rice on a large scale from rice producers across the island, issued bounced cheques for them and engaged in rice racket in a fraudulent manner.",
        "The arrestee had been convicted and imprisoned on several occasions for illegal activities and it is also reported that he had threatened and intimidated several people in the Kochchikade and Katana areas by illegally collecting money.",
        "Moreover, two revolvers made in Italy with no serial numbers, one shotgun made in China, an illegal sword, ten 09mm type bullets, two 0.38mm type bullets and eleven 12 bore type bullets have been seized during the search carried out at the residence of the suspect."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "STF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Warnakulasooriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sameera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hal Sameera",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Minuwangoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Police STF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "36-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kochchikade",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katana",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Italy",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "eleven 12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තුවක්කු සහ උණ්ඩ සමඟ ‘හල් සමීර’ STF අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "වර්ණකුලසූරිය ක්‍රිස්ටෙඹුගේ සමීර සම්පත් ප්‍රනාන්දු හෙවත් “හාල් සමීර” නමැති අපරාධකරු ගිනි අවි සහ පතොරම් කිහිපයක් සමඟ පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකාය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකායේ විශේෂ මෙහෙයුම් ඒකකයට ලද තොරතුරකට අනුව එම නිලධාරීන් ඊයේ (22) මිනුවන්ගොඩ ප්‍රදේශයේ නිවසක වැටලීමක් සිදුකර තිබේ.",
        "වැටලීමේදී දිවයින පුරා සහල් නිෂ්පාදකයින්ගෙන් මහා පරිමාණයෙන් සහල් එකතු කර ඔවුන්ට බවුන්ස් චෙක්පත් නිකුත් කර වංචනික ලෙස සහල් ජාවාරමේ නිරත වූ බව කියන 36 හැවිරිදි සැකකරු අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට නිලධාරීන් සමත් විය.",
        "මෙම අත්අඩංගුවේ පසුවන පුද්ගලයා නීතිවිරෝධී ක්‍රියා සම්බන්ධයෙන් අවස්ථා කිහිපයකදී වැරදිකරු වී සිරගත කර ඇති අතර ඔහු කොච්චිකඩේ සහ කටාන ප්‍රදේශවල පුද්ගලයින් කිහිප දෙනෙකුට තර්ජනය කර බිය ගන්වා නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස මුදල් එකතු කර ඇති බවද වාර්තා වේ.",
        "මීට අමතරව, ඉතාලියේ නිෂ්පාදිත අනුක්‍රමික අංක රහිත රිවෝල්වර දෙකක්, චීනයේ නිෂ්පාදිත තුවක්කුවක්, නීති විරෝධී කඩුවක්, මිලිමීටර් 09 වර්ගයේ උණ්ඩ දහයක්, මිලිමීටර් 0.38 වර්ගයේ උණ්ඩ දෙකක්, බෝර 12 වර්ගයේ උණ්ඩ 11ක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත. සැකකරු."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ටී.එෆ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වර්ණකුලසූරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හාල් සමීර",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිනුවන්ගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "36 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොච්චිකඩේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාන",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉතාලිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එකොළොස් 12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "துப்பாக்கிகள் மற்றும் வெடிமருந்துகளுடன் ‘ஹல் சமீரா’ STF யால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பல துப்பாக்கிகள் மற்றும் தோட்டாக்களுடன் வர்ணகுலசூரிய கிறிஸ்டெம்புகே சமீர சம்பத் பெர்னாண்டோ என்றழைக்கப்படும் “ஹால் சமீர” என்ற தேடப்படும் குற்றவாளியை பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப்படையினர் (STF) கைது செய்துள்ளனர்.",
        "பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப்படையின் விசேட அதிரடிப் பிரிவினருக்குக் கிடைத்த இரகசியத் தகவலின் பிரகாரம், மினுவாங்கொட பிரதேசத்தில் உள்ள வீடொன்றில் நேற்று (22) அதிகாரிகள் சோதனை மேற்கொண்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "சோதனையின் போது, ​​தீவு முழுவதும் உள்ள அரிசி உற்பத்தியாளர்களிடம் இருந்து அரிசியை பெருமளவில் சேகரித்து, அவர்களுக்கு காசோலைகளை வழங்கியதாகக் கூறப்படும் 36 வயதுடைய சந்தேகநபரை அதிகாரிகள் கைது செய்தனர் மற்றும் மோசடியான முறையில் அரிசி மோசடியில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "கைதுசெய்யப்பட்டவர் சட்டவிரோத நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக பல சந்தர்ப்பங்களில் தண்டனை பெற்று சிறையில் அடைக்கப்பட்டவர் என்பதுடன் கொச்சிக்கடை மற்றும் கட்டான பிரதேசத்தில் பலரை அச்சுறுத்தி மிரட்டி சட்டவிரோதமாக பணம் வசூலித்துள்ளதாகவும் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "மேலும், இத்தாலியில் தயாரிக்கப்பட்ட வரிசை எண்கள் இல்லாத இரண்டு ரிவால்வர்கள், சீனாவில் தயாரிக்கப்பட்ட துப்பாக்கி ஒன்று, சட்டவிரோத வாள், பத்து 09 மிமீ ரக தோட்டாக்கள், இரண்டு 0.38 மிமீ ரக தோட்டாக்கள், பதினொரு 12 போர் ரக தோட்டாக்கள் ஆகியவை கைப்பற்றப்பட்டுள்ளன. சந்தேகத்துக்குரியவர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.டி.எஃப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வர்ணகுலசூரிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமீரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹல் சமீரா",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மினுவாங்கொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "போலீஸ் எஸ்.டி.எஃப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "36 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொச்சிக்கடை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டானா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இத்தாலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதினொரு 12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}