{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/14/two-soldiers-rendered-unconscious-in-brutal-attack-in-battaramulla-protest-army/",
  "time_ut": 1657786680,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Two soldiers rendered unconscious in brutal attack in Battaramulla protest – Army",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Two soldiers rendered unconscious in brutal attack in Battaramulla protest – Army",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Army Spokesman Brigadier Nilantha Premarathna in a special televised statement said that two Sri Lanka Army soldiers were brutally and inhumanely assaulted when they stepped forward to control a protest on Wednesday (13) evening in Battaramulla.",
        "The Army Spokesperson said the soldiers were beaten with steel poles and clubs until they were rendered unconscious, and thereafter two T-56 Assault Rifles along with the magazines were stolen from them.",
        "He said the two soldiers are being treated in hospital due to the serious nature of their injuries.",
        "The Army Spokesperson said the stolen weapons may be used for acts of violence and urged the public to exercise vigilance.",
        "Two soldiers rendered unconscious in brutal attack in Battaramulla protest – Army"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Battaramulla",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nilantha Premarathna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Army",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Battaramulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Army Spokesperson",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "T-56 Assault Rifles",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Army Spokesperson",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Battaramulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බත්තරමුල්ල විරෝධතාවයේ දී ම්ලේච්ඡ ප්‍රහාරයකින් හමුදා සෙබළුන් දෙදෙනෙක් සිහිසුන් වෙති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); බදාදා (13) සවස බත්තරමුල්ලේ පැවති විරෝධතාවයක් පාලනය කිරීමට පැමිණි ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුද හමුදා සෙබළුන් දෙදෙනකුට අමානුෂික සහ අමානුෂික ලෙස පහර දුන් බව යුද හමුදා මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක බ්‍රිගේඩියර් නිලන්ත ප්‍රේමරත්න මහතා විශේෂ රූපවාහිනී ප්‍රකාශයක් කරමින් පැවසීය.",
        "හමුදා ප්‍රකාශකවරයා පැවසුවේ සෙබළුන් සිහිසුන් වන තුරු වානේ පොලුවලින් සහ පොලුවලින් පහර දී ඇති අතර ඉන් අනතුරුව ඔවුන් සතුව තිබී ටී 56 ප්‍රහාරක රයිෆල් දෙකක් සහ මැගසින් සොරාගෙන ඇති බව ය.",
        "හමුදා සෙබළුන් දෙදෙනාගේ බරපතල තුවාල හේතුවෙන් රෝහල්ගතව ප්‍රතිකාර ලබන බවද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "සොරකම් කරන ලද අවි ප්‍රචණ්ඩ ක්‍රියා සඳහා භාවිත කළ හැකි බව පැවසූ යුද හමුදා මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශකවරයා මහජනතාවගෙන් විමසිලිමත් වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "බත්තරමුල්ල විරෝධතාවයේ දී ම්ලේච්ඡ ප්‍රහාරයකින් හමුදා සෙබළුන් දෙදෙනෙක් සිහිසුන් වෙති"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "බත්තරමුල්ල",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිලන්ත ප්‍රේමරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුද හමුදාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බත්තරමුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුද හමුදා මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "T-56 ප්රහාරක රයිෆල්",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුද හමුදා මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බත්තරමුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பத்தரமுல்ல ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் இடம்பெற்ற கொடூர தாக்குதலில் இராணுவத்தினர் இருவர் மயக்கமடைந்துள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பத்தரமுல்லையில் புதன்கிழமை (13) மாலை இடம்பெற்ற ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தை கட்டுப்படுத்த முன்வந்த இரண்டு சிறிலங்கா இராணுவ வீரர்கள் கொடூரமான மற்றும் மனிதாபிமானமற்ற முறையில் தாக்கப்பட்டதாக இராணுவப் பேச்சாளர் பிரிகேடியர் நிலந்த பிரேமரத்ன விசேட தொலைக்காட்சி அறிக்கையொன்றில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இராணுவத்தினர் மயங்கும் வரை இரும்புக் கம்பங்கள் மற்றும் தடிகளால் தாக்கப்பட்டதாகவும், அதன் பின்னர் இரண்டு T-56 தாக்குதல் துப்பாக்கிகள் மற்றும் பத்திரிகைகள் அவர்களிடமிருந்து திருடப்பட்டதாகவும் இராணுவப் பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இரண்டு ராணுவ வீரர்களும் படுகாயம் அடைந்து மருத்துவமனையில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வருகின்றனர் என்றார்.",
        "திருடப்பட்ட ஆயுதங்கள் வன்முறைச் செயல்களுக்குப் பயன்படுத்தப்படலாம் எனத் தெரிவித்த இராணுவப் பேச்சாளர், பொதுமக்கள் அவதானமாக இருக்குமாறு கேட்டுக்கொண்டுள்ளார்.",
        "பத்தரமுல்ல ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் இடம்பெற்ற கொடூர தாக்குதலில் இராணுவத்தினர் இருவர் மயக்கமடைந்துள்ளனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "பத்தரமுல்ல",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலந்த பிரேமரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை இராணுவம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தரமுல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராணுவ செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "T-56 தாக்குதல் துப்பாக்கிகள்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராணுவ செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தரமுல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}