{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ත්‍රිරෝද-300ක්-විද්‍යුත්-කරණයට/101-618767",
  "time_ut": 1661478120,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ත්‍රිරෝද 300ක් විද්‍යුත් කරණයට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "300 tricycles to be electrified",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to Motor Transport Commissioner General Nishantha Weerasinghe, a pilot project to electrify 300 three-wheelers has been started with the support of the United Nations Development Program as a solution to the petroleum crisis that Sri Lanka is facing.",
        "The Commissioner General of Motor Transport added that a special conference to receive proposals for preparing the legal background related to this project will be held on the 30th of the month at the Bandaranaike International Conference Hall in Colombo and the technical and regulations of this project will be discussed there."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "300 tricycles",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Motor Transport",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nishantha Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations Development Program",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "General of Motor Transport",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 30th of the month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bandaranaike International Conference Hall in Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ත්‍රිරෝද 300ක් විද්‍යුත් කරණයට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුහුණදී සිටින ඛනිජ තෙල් අර්බුදයට විසඳුමක් ලෙස එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවර්ධන වැඩසටහනේ සහයෝගය ඇතිව ත්‍රීරෝද රථ 300ක් විද්‍යුත්කරණය කිරීමේ නියමු ව්‍යාපෘතියක ආරම්භ කර ඇතැයි මෝටර් රථ ප්‍රවාහන කොමසාරිස් ජෙනරාල් නිශාන්ත වීරසිංහ මහතා පවසයි.",
        "මෙම ව්‍යාපෘතියට අදාළ නීතිමය පසුබිම සකස් කිරීම සඳහා වන යෝජනා ලබා ගැනීමේ විශේෂ සම්මන්ත්‍රණයක්මේ මස 30 වෙනිදා කොළඹ බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර සම්මන්ත්‍රණ ශාලාවේදී පැවැත්වෙන බවත් මෙම ව්‍යාපෘතියේ තාක්ෂණික සහ රෙගුලාසි පිළිබඳව එහිදී සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට නියමිත බවත් මෝටර් රථ ප්‍රවාහන කොමසාරිස් ජනරාල්වරයා වැඩිදුරටත් කීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ත්‍රිරෝද රථ 300ක්",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මෝටර් රථ ප්රවාහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිශාන්ත වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවර්ධන වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෝටර් රථ ප්රවාහන ජෙනරාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසයේ 30 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ කොළඹ බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර සම්මන්ත්‍රණ ශාලාවේදීයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "300 முச்சக்கரவண்டிகள் மின்மயமாக்கப்படும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை எதிர்நோக்கும் பெற்றோலிய நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வாக ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் அபிவிருத்தி திட்டத்தின் அனுசரணையுடன் 300 முச்சக்கர வண்டிகளை மின்மயமாக்கும் முன்னோடித் திட்டம் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக மோட்டார் போக்குவரத்து ஆணையாளர் நாயகம் நிஷாந்த வீரசிங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இத்திட்டம் தொடர்பான சட்டப் பின்னணியை தயாரிப்பதற்கான முன்மொழிவுகளை பெற்றுக்கொள்ளும் விசேட மாநாடு எதிர்வரும் 30ஆம் திகதி கொழும்பு பண்டாரநாயக்க சர்வதேச மாநாட்டு மண்டபத்தில் நடைபெறவுள்ளதாகவும், இத்திட்டத்தின் தொழில்நுட்ப மற்றும் ஒழுங்குமுறைகள் தொடர்பில் மோட்டார் போக்குவரத்து ஆணையாளர் நாயகம் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார். அங்கு விவாதிக்கப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "300 முச்சக்கர வண்டிகள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மோட்டார் போக்குவரத்து",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிஷாந்த வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் வளர்ச்சித் திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மோட்டார் போக்குவரத்து ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதத்தின் 30 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு பண்டாரநாயக்க சர்வதேச மாநாட்டு மண்டபத்தில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}