{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/22-අනිද්දා-මැති-සබයට/101-616954",
  "time_ut": 1658663390,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "22 අනිද්දා මැති සබයට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "22 to the audience the next day",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Minister of Justice Dr. Wijayadasa Rajapaksa said that the twenty-second constitutional amendment bill, which was prepared by repealing the twentieth constitutional amendment and incorporating the positive clauses of the nineteenth constitutional amendment, will be submitted to the parliament tomorrow (27th Wednesday).",
        "Thus, according to parliamentary standing orders, the bill can be debated one week after the first reading (if not challenged before the Supreme Court).",
        "The twenty-second constitutional amendment bill was approved by the cabinet recently. After that, the bill was gazetted on 24th June last.",
        "It is special that the ability of a person holding dual citizenship to be involved in governance activities has been blocked by this constitutional amendment bill.",
        "The amendment also states that a Sri Lankan citizen who is a citizen of another country should not be elected to the Parliament by popular vote.",
        "It also states that if the Prime Minister resigns by sending a letter to the President with his own signature or if he is no longer a Member of Parliament, he is not eligible to hold his office.",
        "The twenty-second constitutional amendment states that the Prime Minister will hold his position as long as the Cabinet remains active.",
        "It also states that if the President is of the opinion that Parliament has lost confidence in the Prime Minister during the period starting from the effective date of this Act and when the Parliament is to be dissolved, the Prime Minister can be removed from office.",
        "It is also stated that the President should not make any appointment or assign or change subjects and tasks without consulting the Prime Minister.",
        "It is stated that a minister can be removed by a letter sent under the signature of the President on the advice of the Prime Minister and any minister can resign from office by a letter with his signature sent to the President.",
        "The constitutional amendment further states that if he or she is not a member of parliament, he or she will lose the post of non-cabinet minister or deputy minister.",
        "In this regard, in a query made to the chief organizer of our ruling party, Minister Prasanna Ranatunga, he said that President Ranil Wickramasinghe has instructed to present the twenty-second constitutional amendment to Parliament.",
        "Accordingly, he mentioned that the bill is being included in the parliamentary agenda."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "the next day",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijayadasa Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "twentieth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "nineteenth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27th Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "24th June last",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "22 අනිද්දා මැති සබයට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "විසි වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය අහෝසි කරමින් සහ දහ නව වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනයේ සාධනීය වගන්ති ඇතුළත් කරමින් සැකසුණු විසිදෙවැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධන පනත් කෙටුම්පත පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට අනිද්දා( 27) බදාදා ඉදිරිපත් කරන බව අධිකරණ අමාත්‍ය ආචාර්ය විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "මේ අනුව එම පනත් කෙටුම්පත පළමු වර කියවීමෙන් සතියකට පසු ( ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය හමුවේ අභියෝගයට ලක් නොවුණ හොත්) විවාදයට ගැනීමට පාර්ලිමේන්තු ස්ථාවර නියෝග අනුව හැකියාව පවතින්නේය.",
        "විසිදෙවෙනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධන පනත් කෙටුම්පතට කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයේ අනුමැතියද පසුගියදා හිමිවිය. ඉන් අනතුරුව පනත් කෙටුම්පත ගැසට් පත්‍රයක් මඟින් පසුගිය ජුනි මස 24 වෙනිදා ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කෙරිණ.",
        "ද්විත්ව පුරවැසිභාවය හිමි අයෙකුට පාලන කටයුතු සඳහා සම්බන්ධවීමට ඇති හැකියාව මෙම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධන පනත් කෙටුම්පත මගින් අවහිර කරනු ලැබ තිබීම විශේෂත්වයකි.",
        "එසේම වෙනත් රටක පුරවැසියකු වන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පුරවැසියකු මහජන ඡන්දයෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට තේරී පත්වීම සිදු නොවිය යුත්තක් බවද එම සංශෝධනයේ දැක්වේ.",
        "ස්වකීය අත්සන මගින් ජනාධිපතිවරයාට ලිපියක් යවා ඉල්ලා අස්වුවහොත් හෝ තවදුරටත් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයකු නොවුණහොත් අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා සිය ධුරය දැරීමට නුසුදුසු බවද එහි දැක්වෙයි.",
        "යම්තාක් කල් අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය සක්‍රියව පවතින්නේද එතෙක් අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා සිය ධුරය දරන බවද විසි දෙවෙනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනයේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "මෙම පනත ක්‍රියාත්මක වන දිනයෙන් ආරම්භ වන සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසුරුවා හැරීමට නියමිත කාල පරිච්ඡේදයේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා කෙරෙහි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ විශ්වාසය අහිමි වී ඇති බවට ජනාධිපතිවරයා ගේ මතය වන්නේ නම් අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ධූරයෙන් ඉවත් කළ හැකි බවද එහි දැක්වේ.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගෙන් නොවිමසා යම් පත් කිරීමක් හෝ විෂය සහ කාර්ය පැවරීමක් හෝ වෙනස් කිරීමක් නොකළ යුතු බවද සඳහන් වේ.",
        "අමාත්‍යවරයකු අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ උපදෙස් අනුව ජනාධිපතිවරයා ගේ අත්සන යටතේ යවනු ලබන ලිපියක් මඟින් ඉවත් කළ හැකි බවත් ඕනෑම අමාත්‍යවරයකුට ජනාධිපතිවරයාට යවන සිය අත්සන සහිත ලිපියක් මගින් ධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස් විය හැකි බවත් සඳහන් වේ.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයකු නොවන්නේ නම් ඔහුට හෝ ඇයට කැබිනට් කැබිනට් නොවන හෝ නියෝජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය ධූරය අහිමි වන බව ද ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනයේ වැඩිදුරටත් දැක්වේ.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් අප ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක අමාත්‍ය ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග මහතාගෙන් කළ විමසුමකදී ඔහු පැවසුවේ විසිදෙවෙනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා උපදෙස් දී ඇති බවයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව එම පනත් කෙටුම්පත පාර්ලිමේන්තු න්‍යාය පත්‍රයට ඇතුළත් කිරීමට කටයුතු කරගෙන යන බවද ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඊළඟ දිනය",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "යුක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විසිවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහනවවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සතියක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය ජුනි 24 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அடுத்த நாள் பார்வையாளர்களுக்கு 22",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இருபதாவது அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தத்தை நீக்கி, பத்தொன்பதாவது அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தத்தின் சாதகமான சரத்துக்களை உள்ளடக்கி தயாரிக்கப்பட்ட இருபத்தி இரண்டாவது அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தச் சட்டமூலம் நாளை (27ம் திகதி புதன்கிழமை) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படவுள்ளதாக நீதி அமைச்சர் கலாநிதி விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எனவே, நாடாளுமன்ற நிலையியற் கட்டளைகளின்படி, முதல் வாசிப்புக்கு ஒரு வாரத்திற்குப் பிறகு (உச்சநீதிமன்றத்தில் சவால் விடப்படாவிட்டால்) மசோதாவை விவாதிக்க முடியும்.",
        "இருபத்தி இரண்டாவது அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தச் சட்டமூலத்திற்கு அண்மையில் அமைச்சரவை அங்கீகாரம் வழங்கியுள்ளது. அதன்பிறகு, கடந்த ஜூன் 24ஆம் தேதி மசோதா அரசிதழில் வெளியிடப்பட்டது.",
        "இரட்டைக் குடியுரிமையைக் கொண்ட ஒருவரின் ஆளுகை நடவடிக்கைகளில் ஈடுபடும் திறன் இந்த அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தச் சட்டமூலத்தினால் முடக்கப்பட்டுள்ளமை விசேட அம்சமாகும்.",
        "மற்றைய நாட்டின் பிரஜையாக இருக்கும் இலங்கை பிரஜை மக்கள் வாக்கு மூலம் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு தெரிவு செய்யப்படக் கூடாது எனவும் திருத்தம் கூறுகிறது.",
        "பிரதமர் தனது சொந்த கையொப்பத்துடன் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு கடிதம் அனுப்பி ராஜினாமா செய்தாலோ அல்லது அவர் இனி நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக இல்லாவிட்டால், அவர் தனது பதவியை வகிக்க தகுதியற்றவர் என்றும் அதில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அமைச்சரவை செயலில் இருக்கும் வரை பிரதமர் தனது பதவியை வகிப்பார் என்று இருபத்தி இரண்டாவது அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தம் கூறுகிறது.",
        "இந்தச் சட்டம் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட்டு பாராளுமன்றம் கலைக்கப்படும் காலப்பகுதியில் பிரதமர் மீது பாராளுமன்றம் நம்பிக்கை இழந்துள்ளதாக ஜனாதிபதி கருதினால் பிரதமரை பதவியில் இருந்து நீக்க முடியும் எனவும் அதில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பிரதமருடன் கலந்தாலோசிக்காமல் ஜனாதிபதி எந்த ஒரு நியமனம் செய்யவோ அல்லது பாடங்கள் மற்றும் பணிகளை மாற்றவோ அல்லது மாற்றவோ கூடாது என்றும் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பிரதமரின் ஆலோசனையின் பேரில் ஜனாதிபதியின் கையொப்பத்துடன் அனுப்பப்படும் கடிதத்தின் மூலம் அமைச்சர் ஒருவரை பதவி நீக்கம் செய்ய முடியும் எனவும், ஜனாதிபதிக்கு அனுப்பப்படும் கையொப்பத்துடன் கூடிய கடிதம் மூலம் எந்தவொரு அமைச்சரும் பதவி விலக முடியும் எனவும் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அவர் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக இல்லாவிட்டால் அமைச்சரவை அல்லாத அமைச்சர் அல்லது பிரதியமைச்சர் பதவியை இழக்க நேரிடும் என அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தம் மேலும் கூறுகிறது.",
        "இது தொடர்பில் எமது ஆளும் கட்சியின் பிரதம அமைப்பாளர் அமைச்சர் பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்கவிடம் வினவிய போது, ​​இருபத்தி இரண்டாவது அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தத்தை பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்குமாறு ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பணிப்புரை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "அதன் பிரகாரம் குறித்த சட்டமூலம் பாராளுமன்ற நிகழ்ச்சி நிரலில் உள்ளடக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "அடுத்த நாள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நீதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இருபதாம்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தொன்பதாம்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஜூன் 24ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}