{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/SL-looks-to-Indian-visitors-to-restore-battered-tourism-sector/108-240497",
  "time_ut": 1657142362,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SL looks to Indian visitors to restore battered tourism sector",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SL looks to Indian visitors to restore battered tourism sector",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "REUTERS: Sri Lanka will hold road shows in five key Indian cities to attract more visitors from its populous northern neighbour in a bid to bring more foreign currency into the crisis-hit island, Tourism Minister said yesterday.",
        "Known for its rolling hills, pristine beaches and laidback seaside towns, Sri Lanka is grappling with its worst financial crisis in seven decades, partly triggered by economic mismanagement and the COVID-19 pandemic, which wiped out its lucrative tourism industry.",
        "The country of 22 million people is now without enough foreign currency to import even essentials, leading to shortages of medicine, food and fuel.",
        "Despite the turmoil, Sri Lanka has seen a steady trickle of 61,951 Indian tourists - the most from any foreign country - in the first five months of this year and the government is keen to bring in more Indians.",
        "“Sri Lanka must have tourism revenue if it is to emerge from this crisis. That is essential,” Tourism Minister Harin Fernando told reporters.",
        "Sri Lanka’s Tourism Ministry will hold road shows in five major Indian cities, seeking to draw business and leisure travellers, besides destination weddings, Fernando said.",
        "Fernando said he hoped the country would end the year with around one million tourists, compared to less than 200,000 arrivals last year, even though some countries, including Britain, have issued advisories asking citizens to only undertake essential travel to Sri Lanka.",
        "“We are confident the winter season will be good,” Fernando said.",
        "Running out of fuel, Sri Lanka has extended a countrywide school shutdown and asked public employees to work from home.",
        "The country will present its debt restructuring plan to the International Monetary Fund (IMF) in August, a crucial step for securing a possible US $ 3 billion programme to put the economy back on track."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SL",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "61,951",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first five months of this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indians",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Harin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tourism Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fernando",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "around one million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "less than 200,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Britain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the winter season",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 3 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බැට කෑ සංචාරක ක්ෂේත්‍රය යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඉන්දියානු අමුත්තන් දෙස බලයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රොයිටර්ස්: අර්බුදකාරී දිවයිනට වැඩි විදේශ මුදල් ප්‍රමාණයක් ගෙන ඒමේ අරමුණින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය ජනාකීර්ණ උතුරු අසල්වැසි ප්‍රදේශයෙන් වැඩි නරඹන්නන් ආකර්ෂණය කර ගැනීම සඳහා ප්‍රධාන ඉන්දීය නගර පහක මාර්ග සංදර්ශන පවත්වන බව සංචාරක අමාත්‍යවරයා ඊයේ පැවසීය.",
        "කඳුකරය, පෞරාණික වෙරළ තීරයන් සහ මුහුදුබඩ නගර සඳහා ප්‍රසිද්ධියක් උසුලන ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දශක හතක් තුළ එහි දරුණුතම මූල්‍ය අර්බුදය සමඟ පොරබදමින් සිටින අතර, අර්ධ වශයෙන් ආර්ථික අවභාවිතය සහ COVID-19 වසංගතය හේතුවෙන් එහි ලාභදායී සංචාරක කර්මාන්තය අතුගා දැමීය.",
        "මිලියන 22 ක ජනතාවක් වෙසෙන රට දැන් අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය පවා ආනයනය කිරීමට ප්‍රමාණවත් විදේශ මුදල් නොමැතිව ඖෂධ, ආහාර සහ ඉන්ධන හිඟයකට තුඩු දී තිබේ.",
        "කැලඹීම නොතකා, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මේ වසරේ මුල් මාස පහ තුළ ඉන්දියානු සංචාරකයින් 61,951 ක් - ඕනෑම විදේශීය රටකින් වැඩිම සංඛ්‍යාවක් පැමිණ ඇති අතර, තවත් ඉන්දියානුවන් ගෙන්වා ගැනීමට රජය උනන්දු වෙයි.",
        "“මෙම අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩ ඒමට නම් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සංචාරක ආදායමක් තිබිය යුතුයි. ඒක අත්‍යාවශ්‍යයි,” සංචාරක අමාත්‍ය හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු මාධ්‍යවේදීන් හමුවේ පැවසීය.",
        "ගමනාන්ත මංගල උත්සවවලට අමතරව ව්‍යාපාරික සහ විවේකී සංචාරකයින් ආකර්ෂණය කර ගැනීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංචාරක අමාත්‍යාංශය ඉන්දියාවේ ප්‍රධාන නගර පහක මාර්ග සංදර්ශන පවත්වන බව ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "බ්‍රිතාන්‍යය ඇතුළු ඇතැම් රටවල් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සංචාර පමණක් සිදු කරන ලෙස පුරවැසියන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියද, පසුගිය වසරේ පැමිණි ලක්ෂ දෙකකට අඩු සංචාරකයින් සංඛ්‍යාවක් සමඟ සසඳන විට වසර මිලියනයකින් පමණ සංචාරකයින් වසර අවසන් වනු ඇතැයි තමා බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව ප්‍රනාන්දු පැවසීය.",
        "\"ශීත සමය යහපත් වනු ඇතැයි අපට විශ්වාසයි,\" ප්‍රනාන්දු පැවසීය.",
        "ඉන්ධන අවසන් වීම හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව රටපුරා පාසල් වසා දැමීම දීර්ඝ කර ඇති අතර රජයේ සේවකයන්ට නිවසේ සිට වැඩ කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා තිබේ.",
        "ආර්ථිකය යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් කිරීම සඳහා එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලර් බිලියන 3 ක වැඩසටහනක් සුරක්ෂිත කිරීමේ තීරණාත්මක පියවරක් වන අගෝස්තු මාසයේදී රට සිය ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ සැලැස්ම ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලට (IMF) ඉදිරිපත් කරනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එස්.එල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දශක හතක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 22 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "61,951 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ මුල් මාස පහ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංචාරක අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියනයක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "200,000 ට අඩු",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය අවුරුද්දේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශීත සමය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 3 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள சுற்றுலாத் துறையை மீட்டெடுக்க இந்திய பார்வையாளர்களை SL எதிர்பார்க்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்: நெருக்கடியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட தீவிற்கு அதிக வெளிநாட்டு நாணயத்தை கொண்டு வரும் முயற்சியில், அதன் மக்கள்தொகை கொண்ட வடக்கு அண்டை நாடுகளில் இருந்து அதிகமான பார்வையாளர்களை ஈர்க்கும் வகையில், இலங்கை ஐந்து முக்கிய இந்திய நகரங்களில் சாலை நிகழ்ச்சிகளை நடத்தும் என்று சுற்றுலாத்துறை அமைச்சர் நேற்று தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மலைகள், அழகிய கடற்கரைகள் மற்றும் ஒதுங்கிய கடலோர நகரங்களுக்கு பெயர் பெற்ற இலங்கை, ஏழு தசாப்தங்களில் மிக மோசமான நிதி நெருக்கடியில் சிக்கித் தவிக்கிறது, பொருளாதார முறைகேடு மற்றும் COVID-19 தொற்றுநோயால் ஓரளவு தூண்டப்பட்டு, அதன் இலாபகரமான சுற்றுலாத் துறையை அழித்துவிட்டது.",
        "22 மில்லியன் மக்கள் வசிக்கும் நாட்டில் அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களைக் கூட இறக்குமதி செய்ய போதுமான வெளிநாட்டு நாணயம் இல்லாமல், மருந்து, உணவு மற்றும் எரிபொருள் தட்டுப்பாடு ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "கொந்தளிப்பு இருந்தபோதிலும், இந்த ஆண்டின் முதல் ஐந்து மாதங்களில் 61,951 இந்திய சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் வருகையை இலங்கை கண்டுள்ளது - எந்த ஒரு வெளிநாட்டில் இருந்தும் அதிகம் - இந்த ஆண்டின் முதல் ஐந்து மாதங்களில் மேலும் இந்தியர்களை அழைத்து வருவதில் அரசாங்கம் ஆர்வமாக உள்ளது.",
        "“இந்த நெருக்கடியில் இருந்து வெளிவர வேண்டுமானால் இலங்கைக்கு சுற்றுலா வருமானம் இருக்க வேண்டும். அது இன்றியமையாதது” என சுற்றுலாத்துறை அமைச்சர் ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ செய்தியாளர்களிடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் சுற்றுலா அமைச்சு, இலக்கு திருமணங்களைத் தவிர, வணிக மற்றும் ஓய்வுப் பயணிகளை ஈர்க்கும் வகையில் ஐந்து முக்கிய இந்திய நகரங்களில் சாலைக் காட்சிகளை நடத்தும் என்று பெர்னாண்டோ கூறினார்.",
        "பிரித்தானியா உட்பட சில நாடுகள் இலங்கைக்கு அத்தியாவசியப் பயணங்களை மாத்திரம் மேற்கொள்ளுமாறு பிரஜைகளைக் கேட்டுக்கொண்ட போதிலும், கடந்த ஆண்டு 200,000க்கும் குறைவான சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளே வருகை தந்திருந்த நிலையில், நாடு ஒரு மில்லியன் சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளுடன் ஆண்டை முடிக்கும் என நம்புவதாக பெர்னாண்டோ கூறினார்.",
        "\"குளிர்காலம் நன்றாக இருக்கும் என்று நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம்\" என்று பெர்னாண்டோ கூறினார்.",
        "எரிபொருள் தீர்ந்துவிட்டதால், நாடு தழுவிய அளவில் பள்ளி பணிநிறுத்தத்தை நீட்டித்து, பொது ஊழியர்களை வீட்டிலிருந்து வேலை செய்யும்படி இலங்கை கேட்டுக் கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "நாடு தனது கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு திட்டத்தை ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்திடம் (IMF) முன்வைக்கும், இது பொருளாதாரத்தை மீண்டும் பாதையில் கொண்டு வர 3 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர் திட்டத்தைப் பாதுகாப்பதற்கான ஒரு முக்கியமான படியாகும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.எல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு தசாப்தங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "61,951",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டின் முதல் ஐந்து மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுற்றுலா அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் ஒரு மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "200,000 க்கும் குறைவாக",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குளிர்காலம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 3 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}