{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/තව-පොහොර-නැවක්-දෙසතියකින්-එයි/1-616672",
  "time_ut": 1658212198,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "තව පොහොර නැවක් දෙසතියකින් එයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Another fertilizer ship will arrive in a fortnight",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to the Ministry of Agriculture, another ship with 21,000 metric tons of urea is scheduled to arrive in Sri Lanka within the next fortnight.",
        "The stock of fertilizer is planned to be given to the farmers at the beginning of the cultivation activities in the high season.",
        "Also, the Ministry of Agriculture says that the World Bank has already agreed to provide 110 million dollars to purchase 1,50,000 metric tons of urea fertilizer for the 2022/2023 season.",
        "Out of the 65,000 metric tons of urea fertilizer given to Sri Lanka under the Indian loan scheme, 44,000 metric tons, which is the first batch, has been packed and distributed in the warehouses of the government-owned Lanka Fertilizer Company and Commercial Fertilizer Company.",
        "According to the Ministry of Agriculture, 3000 metric tons of urea fertilizer has been distributed to agricultural service centers all over the island within a period of three days.",
        "The second batch of Indian fertilizers is scheduled to arrive in Sri Lanka in another fortnight."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the high season",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "110 million dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,50,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 2022/2023 season",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 65,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "44,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka Fertilizer Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "a period of three days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තව පොහොර නැවක් දෙසතියකින් එයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "යූරියා මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 21,000ක් සහිත තවත් නැවක් ඉදිරි දෙසතිය ඇතුළත මෙරටට පැමිණීමට නියමිත බව කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි.",
        "එම පොහොර තොගය මහ කන්නයේ වගා කටයුතු ආරම්භයේදීම ගොවීන්ට ලබාදීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇත.",
        "එමෙන්ම 2022/2023 මහ කන්නය‍ට අවශ්‍ය යූරියා පොහොර මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 1,50,000ක් මිලදී ගැනීමට ලෝක බැංකුව ඩොලර් මිලියන 110ක් ලබා දීමට දැනටමත් එකඟතාවය පළ තිබෙන බව කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි.",
        "ඉන්දීය ණය යෝජනා ක්‍රමය යටතේ මෙරටට ලබාදුන් යූරියා පොහොර මෙට්‍රික් ටොන්  65,000න් පළමු තොගය වන මෙට්‍රික් ටොන්  44,000ක් රජයට අයත් ලංකා පො‍හොර සමාගම සහ කොමර්ෂල් පොහොර සමාගමේ ගබඩාවල අසුරා බෙදාහැරීම් කටයුතු අරඹා තිබේ.",
        "දින තුනක කාලයක් තුළ දිවයින පුරා පිහිටි ගොවිජන සේවා මධ්‍යස්ථානවලට යූරියා පොහොර මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 3000ක් බෙදාහැර ඇතැයි කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි.",
        "තව දෙසතියකින් ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට නියමිතව ඇත්තේ එම ඉන්දීය පොහොර වලින් දෙවන තොගයයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 21,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉහළ සමය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 110 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 1,50,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022/2023 සමය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 65,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 44,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා පොහොර සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 3000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින තුනක කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இன்னும் பதினைந்து நாட்களில் இன்னொரு உரக் கப்பல் வரும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அடுத்த பதினைந்து நாட்களுக்குள் 21,000 மெற்றிக் தொன் யூரியாவுடன் மற்றுமொரு கப்பல் இலங்கைக்கு வரவுள்ளதாக விவசாய அமைச்சு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அதிக பருவத்தில் சாகுபடி நடவடிக்கைகளின் தொடக்கத்தில் விவசாயிகளுக்கு உர இருப்பு வழங்க திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மேலும், 2022/2023 பருவத்திற்கு 1,50,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் யூரியா உரத்தை கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்கு உலக வங்கி ஏற்கனவே 110 மில்லியன் டொலர்களை வழங்குவதற்கு இணக்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளதாக விவசாய அமைச்சு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்திய கடன் திட்டத்தின் கீழ் இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கப்பட்ட 65,000 மெற்றிக் தொன் யூரியா உரத்தில் முதல் தொகுதியான 44,000 மெட்ரிக் தொன், அரசாங்கத்திற்கு சொந்தமான லங்கா உர நிறுவனம் மற்றும் கொமர்ஷல் உர நிறுவனம் ஆகியவற்றின் களஞ்சியசாலைகளில் பொதி செய்யப்பட்டு விநியோகிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மூன்று நாட்களுக்குள் நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் உள்ள விவசாய சேவை நிலையங்களுக்கு 3000 மெற்றிக் தொன் யூரியா உரம் விநியோகிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக விவசாய அமைச்சு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்திய உரங்களின் இரண்டாவது தொகுதி இன்னும் பதினைந்து நாட்களில் இலங்கைக்கு வர உள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உயர் பருவம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "110 மில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,50,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022/2023 சீசன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "65,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "44,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கா உர நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று நாட்கள் ஒரு காலம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}