{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Karnataka-HC-issues-notices-to-Centre-Karnataka-Govt-over-detention-of-SL-citizens-in-prison/108-242257",
  "time_ut": 1659425154,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Karnataka HC issues notices to Centre, Karnataka Govt over ’detention’ of SL citizens in prison",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Karnataka HC issues notices to Centre, Karnataka Govt over ’detention’ of SL citizens in prison",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Karnataka High Court has issued notices to the union and state government over the alleged detention of Sri Lankan citizens in the central prison at Parappana Agrahara in Bangalore, India.",
        "A Public interest litigation (PIL) on behalf of 25 persons was filed by the Karnataka State Legal Services Authority (KSLSA), which was heard by the division bench headed by the Acting Chief Justice Alok Aradhe on Monday.",
        "The bench directed issuance of notices to the Union home Ministry, National Investigation Agency, Karnataka Home Ministry, Mangaluru South Police and Bengaluru Urban Deputy Commissioner.",
        "During a visit to the Central Prison, the member secretary of the KSLSA found that 38 Sri Lankan nationals including the 25 named in the PIL were allegedly illegally detained there, according to the PIL.",
        "The PIL claims that this detention is ’illegal’ and a violation of human rights, and sought that these people be transferred to detention centres.",
        "The Mangaluru police had, based on information that these 25 Sri Lankan nationals were illegally staying in the Seaport Guest House without proper documents and passports, filed cases against them under various sections of the IPC, it was alleged. (PTI)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Karnataka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Centre",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Karnataka Govt",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Karnataka High Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parappana Agrahara",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangalore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PIL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Karnataka State Legal Services Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alok Aradhe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "National Investigation Agency",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karnataka Home Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mangaluru South Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bengaluru Urban",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Central Prison",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "KSLSA",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "PIL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PIL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PIL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mangaluru",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Seaport Guest House",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "IPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පුරවැසියන් බන්ධනාගාරයේ රඳවා තබා ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් කර්නාටක මහාධිකරණය මධ්‍යස්ථානය, කර්නාටක රජයට නොතීසි නිකුත් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දියාවේ බැංගලෝර් හි පරප්පන අග්‍රහාර මධ්‍යම බන්ධනාගාරයේ ශ්‍රී ලාංකික පුරවැසියන් රඳවා තබා ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් කර්නාටක මහාධිකරණය සංගමයට සහ ප්‍රාන්ත රජයට නොතීසි නිකුත් කර තිබේ.",
        "කර්නාටක ප්‍රාන්ත නීති සේවා අධිකාරිය (KSLSA) විසින් පුද්ගලයින් 25 දෙනෙකු වෙනුවෙන් මහජන අවශ්‍යතා පෙත්සමක් (PIL) ගොනු කරන ලද අතර එය සඳුදා වැඩබලන අගවිනිසුරු ආලෝක් ආරාදේ ප්‍රමුඛ කොට්ඨාශ විනිසුරු මඩුල්ල විසින් විභාග කරන ලදී.",
        "විනිසුරු මඩුල්ල මධ්‍යම ස්වදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය, ජාතික විමර්ශන ඒජන්සිය, කර්නාටක ස්වදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය, Mangaluru South පොලිසිය සහ බංගලාරු නාගරික නියෝජ්‍ය කොමසාරිස් වෙත නොතීසි නිකුත් කරන ලෙස නියෝග කළේය.",
        "මධ්‍යම බන්ධනාගාරයේ සංචාරයක නිරත වූ KSLSA හි සාමාජික ලේකම්වරයා විසින් PIL හි සඳහන් කර ඇති 25 දෙනා ඇතුළුව ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින් 38 දෙනෙකු නීති විරෝධී ලෙස එහි රඳවාගෙන සිටින බව PIL හි සඳහන් කර ඇත.",
        "මෙම රඳවා තබා ගැනීම 'නීති විරෝධී' සහ මානව හිමිකම් උල්ලංඝනය කිරීමක් බව PIL කියා සිටින අතර, මෙම පුද්ගලයින් රැඳවුම් මධ්‍යස්ථාන වෙත මාරු කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "මෙම ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින් 25 දෙනා නිසි ලියකියවිලි සහ විදේශ ගමන් බලපත්‍ර නොමැතිව සීපෝට් ගෙස්ට් හවුස් හි නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස රැඳී සිටින බවට ලද තොරතුරක් මත මංගලුරු පොලිසිය ඔවුන්ට එරෙහිව IPC හි විවිධ වගන්ති යටතේ නඩු පවරා ඇති බවට චෝදනා එල්ල විය. (PTI)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කර්නාටක",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "මධ්යස්ථානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "කර්නාටක රජය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කර්නාටක මහාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පරප්පන අග්‍රහාර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැංගලෝර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PIL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කර්නාටක ප්‍රාන්ත නීති සේවා අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආලෝක් ආදරේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික විමර්ශන ඒජන්සිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කර්නාටක ස්වදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු මන්ගලූරු පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැංගලෝර් නාගරික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම බන්ධනාගාරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "KSLSA",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "PIL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PIL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PIL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mangaluru",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීපෝට් ගෙස්ට් හවුස්",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "IPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පී.ටී.අයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை குடிமக்கள் சிறையில் அடைக்கப்பட்டிருப்பது தொடர்பாக கர்நாடகா உயர்நீதிமன்றம் மத்திய, கர்நாடக அரசுக்கு நோட்டீஸ் அனுப்பியுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்தியாவின் பெங்களூரில் உள்ள பரப்பன அக்ரஹாராவில் உள்ள மத்திய சிறைச்சாலையில் இலங்கை பிரஜைகள் தடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்டதாகக் கூறப்படும் விவகாரம் தொடர்பாக மத்திய மற்றும் மாநில அரசுக்கு கர்நாடக உயர்நீதிமன்றம் நோட்டீஸ் அனுப்பியுள்ளது.",
        "கர்நாடக மாநில சட்ட சேவைகள் ஆணையத்தால் (கேஎஸ்எல்எஸ்ஏ) 25 பேர் சார்பில் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட பொதுநல வழக்கு, திங்களன்று தற்காலிக தலைமை நீதிபதி அலோக் ஆராதே தலைமையிலான டிவிஷன் பெஞ்சில் விசாரணைக்கு வந்தது.",
        "மத்திய உள்துறை அமைச்சகம், தேசிய புலனாய்வு முகமை, கர்நாடக உள்துறை அமைச்சகம், மங்களூரு தெற்கு போலீஸ் மற்றும் பெங்களூரு நகர்ப்புற துணை கமிஷனர் ஆகியோருக்கு நோட்டீஸ் அனுப்ப பெஞ்ச் உத்தரவிட்டது.",
        "மத்திய சிறைச்சாலைக்கு விஜயம் செய்த KSLSA இன் உறுப்பினர் செயலாளர், PIL இல் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ள 25 பேர் உட்பட 38 இலங்கைப் பிரஜைகள் சட்டவிரோதமாக அங்கு தடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்டிருப்பதாகக் கூறப்பட்டதைக் கண்டறிந்தார்.",
        "இந்த தடுப்புக் காவல் 'சட்டவிரோதமானது' மற்றும் மனித உரிமை மீறல் என்று கூறி, இந்த மக்களை தடுப்பு மையங்களுக்கு மாற்ற வேண்டும் என்று கோரியது.",
        "இந்த 25 இலங்கை பிரஜைகள் முறையான ஆவணங்கள் மற்றும் கடவுச்சீட்டுகள் இன்றி சட்டவிரோதமாக சீபோர்ட் விருந்தினர் மாளிகையில் தங்கியிருப்பதாக கிடைத்த தகவலின் அடிப்படையில் மங்களூரு பொலிஸார் அவர்கள் மீது ஐபிசியின் பல்வேறு பிரிவுகளின் கீழ் வழக்குப்பதிவு செய்துள்ளனர். (பிடிஐ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கர்நாடகா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "மையம்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கர்நாடக அரசு",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கர்நாடக உயர் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பரப்பன அக்ரஹாரா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெங்களூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PIL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கர்நாடக மாநில சட்ட சேவைகள் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலோக் ஆராதே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய புலனாய்வு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கர்நாடக உள்துறை அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மங்களூரு தெற்கு போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெங்களூரு நகர்ப்புறம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய சிறை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "KSLSA",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "PIL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PIL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PIL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மங்களூரு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறைமுக விருந்தினர் மாளிகை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.பி.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}