{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/අඹේවෙල-ජලාශයේ-මියගොස්-සිටින-ගෝනුන්-ඉවත්-කිරිමට-පියවර/11-396580",
  "time_ut": 1661333988,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අඹේවෙල ජලාශයේ මියගොස් සිටින ගෝනුන් ඉවත් කිරිමට පියවර",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Steps to remove dead elk from Ambewela Reservoir",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Samantha Jayasundara, Assistant Superintendent of Police of Nuwara Eliya Police Division, said that necessary measures will be taken to remove the bodies of a large number of dead elk in Ambewela Reservoir, Nuwara Eliya.",
        "A group of officers of the Nuwara Eliya Police, including the Assistant Superintendent of Police, conducted an investigation at the reservoir today (24th) following a notification by the Station Commander of the Ambewela Police Station that a large number of elks had died in the reservoir.",
        "After the inquiry, the Assistant Superintendent of Police said that elk hunters roaming in the Horton plains ecological zone and Ambewela reserve are caught in the traps set and the elk coming to Ambewela reserve in search of food and water in the reserve are bitten by the roaming hunting dogs and the elk are chased into the reservoir.",
        "After being bitten by the hunting dogs, the elk's scars are not visible, and after that the elk that jump to save their lives in the reservoir drown in the reservoir and die.",
        "The Dhiwaras who are engaged in the Dhiwara industry in that reservoir also claim that Ambewela Reservoir has a special place among the cleanest reservoirs in the Nuwara Eliya district.",
        "It is said that some people in the reservoir which is 996 acres are engaged in the dhiwara industry, and due to the death of a large number of elks in the reservoir in a short period of two months, a situation has arisen where it is impossible to engage in the dhiwara industry.",
        "Dhivareen claims that there are about 30 stray hunting dogs roaming in the Ambewela reserve, and those dogs live by hunting animals like elk, deer, rabbits, and anyone who enters the reserve can see the dogs.",
        "Although the wildlife officers were informed about this, they came to the place and conducted an investigation, but there has been no response so far. A group of public health inspectors came and cut off the head of a dead elephant to find out if the dead elephant was infected with hydrops. Dhivarin said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ambewela Reservoir",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Samantha Jayasundara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambewela Reservoir",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwara Eliya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Nuwara Eliya Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Assistant Superintendent of Police",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ambewela Police Station",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "elk",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Horton",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambewela",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambewela",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhiwara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambewela Reservoir",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwara Eliya",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "996 acres",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "two months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhivareen",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambewela",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhivarin",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අඹේවෙල ජලාශයේ මියගොස් සිටින ගෝනුන් ඉවත් කිරිමට පියවර",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "නුවරඑලිය අඹේවෙල ජලාශයේ මියගොස් සිටින ගෝනුන් විශාල පිරිසකගේ සිරුරු කඩිනමින් ඉවත් කිරිමට අවශ්‍ය පියවර ගන්නා බව නුවරඑලිය පොලිස් කොට්ඨාශයේ සහකාර පොලිස් අධිකාරි සමන්ත ජයසුන්දර මහතා පැවසිය.",
        "එම ජලාශයේ ගෝනුන් විශාල පිරිසක් මියගොස් සිටින බවට අඹේවෙල පොලිස් ස්ථානයේ ස්ථානාධිපතිවරයා විසින් කල දැනුම් දිමක් මත සහකාර පොලිස් අධිකාරිවරයා ඇතුළු නුවරඑලිය පොලිසියේ නිලධාරින් පිරිසක් එම ජලාශයේ ධිවර කටයුතු වල නියැලි සිටින ධිවරයන් සමග අද (24දා)  ජලාශයේ විමර්ෂණයක නිරත විය.",
        "එම විමර්ෂණයෙන් අනතුරුව අප කල විමසුමකට සහකාර පොලිස් අධිකාරිවරයා කියා සිටියේ හෝර්ටන් තැන්න පාරිසරික කලාපයේ සහ අඹේවෙල රක්ෂිතයේ සැරිසරන ගෝනුන් දඩයම්කරුවන් අටවන උගුල් වලට හසු වි සහ එම රක්ෂිතයේ ආහාර සහ ජලය සොයා අඹේවෙල රක්ෂිතයට පැමිණෙන ගෝනුන් අයාලයේ සැරිසරන දඩයම් සුනඛයින් විසින් සපා කා ගෝනුන්ව ජලාශයට පන්නා දමන බවයි.",
        "දඩයම් සුනඛයින් විසින් ගෝනුන් සපා කැමෙන් අනතුරුව ගෝනුන්ගේ දැස් නොපෙනෙන බවත්, ඉන් අනතුරුව ජලාශයේ දිවි බේරා ගැනිම සදහා පිනා යන ගෝනුන් ජලාශයේම ගිලි මෙසේ ජිවිතක්ෂයට පත් වන බවයි.",
        "එම ජලාශයේ ධිවර කර්මාන්තයේ නියැලි සිටින ධිවරයින්ද කියා සිටින්නේ නුවරඑලිය දිස්ත්‍රික්කය තුල පිහිටි පිරිසිදුම ජලාශ අතරින් අඹේවෙල ජලාශයට සුවිශේෂි තැනක් හිමිවන බවයි.",
        "අක්කර 996කින් සමන්විත එම ජලාශයේ කිහිප දෙනෙකු නිතියානුකුලව ධිවර කර්මාන්තයේ නියැලෙන බවත්,මාස දෙකක් වැනි කෙටි කාලයක් තුල මෙසේ ගෝනුන් විශාල පිරිසක් ජලාශය තුල මියයාම නිසා මේ වන විට ජලාශය තුල විශාල පරිසර හානියක් සිදු වි ඇති නිසා ධිවර කර්මාන්තයේද නියැලිමට නොහැකි තත්ත්වයක් උද්ගත වි ඇති බවයි.",
        "අඹේවෙල රක්ෂිතය තුල අයාලේ යන දඩයම් සුනඛයන් 30 දෙනෙකු පමණ සැරිසරන බවත්, එම සුනඛයින් ගෝනුන් , මුවන් , හාවුන් වැනි සතුන් දඩයම් කර ජිවත් වන බවත්, එම රක්ෂිතය තුලට පිවිසෙන ඕනැම කෙනෙකුට සුනඛයන් දැක ගැනිමට හැකි වන බවයි ධිවරයින් කියා සිටින්නේ.",
        "වනජිවි නිලධාරින්ට මේ පිලිබදව දැනුම් දුන්නද ඔහුන් එම ස්ථානයට පැමිණ විමර්ෂණයක් සිදු කලද ඉන් අනතුරුව මෙතෙක් කිසිදු ප්‍රතිචාරයක් නොමැති බවත්,මහජන සෞඛ්‍ය පරික්ෂකවරුන් පිරිසක් පැමිණ මියගිය ගෝනුන්ට ජලභිතිකා රෝගය වැලදි ඇත්ද යන්න පිලිබදව සොයා බැලිමට මිය ගිය ගෝනෙකුගේ හිසක් කපාගෙන ගිය බව අඹේවෙල ජලාශයේ ධිවර කටයුතු වල නියැලි සිටින ධිවරයින් කියා සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අඹේවෙල ජලාශය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමන්ත ජයසුන්දර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඹේවෙල ජලාශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුවරඑළිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නුවරඑළිය පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සහකාර පොලිස් අධිකාරි",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඹේවෙල පොලිස් ස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එල්ක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෝටන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඹේවෙල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඹේවෙල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිවාර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඹේවෙල ජලාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුවරඑළිය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අක්කර 996 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිවාරීන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඹේවෙල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිවාරින්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அம்பேவெல நீர்த்தேக்கத்திலிருந்து இறந்த எலிகளை அகற்றுவதற்கான நடவடிக்கைகள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நுவரெலியா, அம்பேவெல நீர்த்தேக்கத்தில் உயிரிழந்த பெருந்தொகையான எலிகளின் சடலங்களை அகற்றுவதற்கு தேவையான நடவடிக்கைகள் எடுக்கப்படும் என நுவரெலியா பொலிஸ் பிரிவின் உதவி பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் திரு.சமந்த ஜயசுந்தர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நுவரெலியா பொலிஸ் நிலையத்தின் உதவி பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் உட்பட அதிகாரிகள் குழு இன்று (24) நீர்த்தேக்கத்தில் அதிகளவான எலிகள் உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக அம்பேவெல பொலிஸ் நிலைய கட்டளைத் தளபதி அறிவித்ததையடுத்து அங்கு விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டுள்ளனர். .",
        "விசாரணையின் பின்னர், ஹோர்டன் சமவெளி சுற்றுச்சூழல் வலயம் மற்றும் அம்பேவெல காப்புக்காடு ஆகியவற்றில் சுற்றித் திரியும் எலிகள் வேட்டையாடுபவர்கள் வலையில் சிக்குவதாகவும், உணவு மற்றும் தண்ணீரைத் தேடி அம்பேவெல காப்புக்காட்டுக்கு வரும் எலிகள் அலைந்து திரிவதால் கடிக்கப்படுவதாகவும் கூறினார். வேட்டை நாய்கள் மற்றும் எல்க் ஆகியவை நீர்த்தேக்கத்திற்குள் துரத்தப்படுகின்றன.",
        "வேட்டை நாய்கள் கடித்த பிறகு, எலிகளின் தழும்புகள் தெரியவில்லை, அதன் பிறகு நீர்த்தேக்கத்தில் உயிரைக் காப்பாற்றிக் கொள்ள குதிக்கும் எலிகள் நீர்த்தேக்கத்தில் மூழ்கி இறக்கின்றன.",
        "நுவரெலியா மாவட்டத்தில் உள்ள தூய்மையான நீர்த்தேக்கங்களில் அம்பேவெல நீர்த்தேக்கத்திற்கு தனி இடம் உண்டு என அந்த நீர்த்தேக்கத்தில் திவாரத் தொழிலில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள திவாரக்களும் கூறுகின்றனர்.",
        "996 ஏக்கர் பரப்பளவுள்ள நீர்த்தேக்கத்தில் சிலர் திவாரத் தொழிலில் ஈடுபட்டு வருவதாகவும், இரண்டு மாதங்களாகிய குறுகிய காலத்தில் நீர்த்தேக்கத்தில் அதிகளவான எலிகள் உயிரிழந்துள்ளதால் அது முடியாத நிலை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது. திவார தொழிலில் ஈடுபட வேண்டும்.",
        "அம்பேவெல காப்புக்காட்டில் சுமார் 30 வேட்டை நாய்கள் சுற்றித் திரிவதாகவும், அந்த நாய்கள் எலி, மான், முயல் போன்ற விலங்குகளை வேட்டையாடி வாழ்வதாகவும், காப்பகத்திற்குள் நுழையும் எவரும் நாய்களைப் பார்க்க முடியும் என்றும் திவாரீன் கூறுகிறார்.",
        "இது குறித்து வனவிலங்கு அதிகாரிகளுக்கு தகவல் தெரிவித்தும், அவர்கள் சம்பவ இடத்திற்கு வந்து விசாரணை நடத்திய போதும் இதுவரை எந்த பதிலும் வராததால், பொது சுகாதார பரிசோதகர்கள் குழு வந்து இறந்த யானையின் தலையை வெட்டி இறந்ததா என கண்டறிய யானை ஹைட்ரோப்ஸால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அம்பேவெல நீர்த்தேக்கம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சமந்தா ஜெயசுந்தர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பேவெல நீர்த்தேக்கம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுவரெலியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நுவரெலியா பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உதவி காவல் கண்காணிப்பாளர்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பேவெல பொலிஸ் நிலையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எல்க்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹார்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பேவெல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பேவெல",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "திவார",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பேவெல நீர்த்தேக்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுவரெலியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "996 ஏக்கர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திவரேன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பேவெல",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திவரின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}