{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/30/suspect-remanded-for-stealing-liquor-bottle-from-rws-private-home/",
  "time_ut": 1661864160,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Suspect remanded for stealing liquor bottle from RWs private home",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Suspect remanded for stealing liquor bottle from RWs private home",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); A man who was arrested for entering the private residence of President Ranil Wickremesinghe and stealing a foreign liquor bottle was remanded to the 7th of September by Fort Magistrate Thilina Gamage on Tuesday.",
        "The Criminal Investigations Department told the court that the suspect was arrested during the investigations on the torching of President Ranil Wickremesinghe's private residence, and looting.",
        "The Magistrate ordered for the suspect to be remanded and to be produced in an identification parade on the 7th of September.",
        "Another Suspect was arrested in Kottawa on Monday night on charges of setting fire to President Ranil Wickramasinghe's private house, damaging property, and committing theft.",
        "The Police Media Division stated that the 33-year-old suspect is a carpenter from Aranayake.",
        "Suspect remanded for stealing liquor bottle from RWs private home",
        "Bangladesh will never face a situation like Sri Lanka: PM Sheikh Hasina"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "RWs private home",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "7th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "September",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fort Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Criminal Investigations Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "7th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "September",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kottawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Police Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "33-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aranayake",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "RWs private home",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PM Sheikh",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hasina",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "RWs පෞද්ගලික නිවසකින් මත්පැන් බෝතලයක් සොරකම් කළ සැකකරු රිමාන්ඩ්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ඇතුළු වී විදේශීය මත්පැන් බෝතලයක් සොරකම් කිරීමේ සිද්ධියක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් පුද්ගලයෙකු සැප්තැම්බර් 7 වැනිදා දක්වා රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කිරීමට කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් තිළිණ ගමගේ මහතා අඟහරුවාදා නියෝග කළේය.",
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ගිනි තැබීම සහ කොල්ලකෑම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් සිදුකළ විමර්ශනවලදී සැකකරු අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව අධිකරණයට ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "සැකකරු රක්‍ෂිත බන්ධනාගාරගත කර සැප්තැම්බර් 07 වැනිදා හඳුනාගැනීමේ පෙරට්ටුවකට ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලෙස මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා නියෝග කළේය.",
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ගිනි තැබීම, දේපළවලට හානි කිරීම සහ සොරකම් කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් තවත් සැකකරුවෙකු සඳුදා රාත්‍රියේ කොට්ටාව ප්‍රදේශයේදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගනු ලැබුවා.",
        "පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය කොට්ඨාශය සඳහන් කළේ 33 හැවිරිදි සැකකරු අරණායක ප්‍රදේශයේ වඩු කාර්මිකයෙකු බවයි.",
        "RWs පෞද්ගලික නිවසකින් මත්පැන් බෝතලයක් සොරකම් කළ සැකකරු රිමාන්ඩ්",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වැනි තත්ත්වයකට බංග්ලාදේශයට කිසිදා මුහුණ නොදෙන බව අගමැතිනි ෂෙයික් හසීනා පවසයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "RWs පෞද්ගලික නිවස",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "7 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "7 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kottawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය කොට්ඨාසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "33 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරණායක",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "RWs පෞද්ගලික නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගමැති ෂීක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හසීනා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "RWs தனியார் வீட்டில் மதுபாட்டில்களை திருடிய சந்தேகநபர் விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்திற்குள் நுழைந்து வெளிநாட்டு மதுபான போத்தல்களை திருடிய குற்றச்சாட்டில் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட நபரை எதிர்வரும் செப்டெம்பர் மாதம் 7 ஆம் திகதி வரை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்க கோட்டை நீதவான் திலின கமகே உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்திற்கு தீ வைத்து கொள்ளையடித்தமை தொடர்பான விசாரணைகளின் போது சந்தேகநபர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக குற்றப் புலனாய்வு திணைக்களம் நீதிமன்றில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "சந்தேக நபரை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்குமாறும், எதிர்வரும் செப்டெம்பர் மாதம் 7ஆம் திகதி அடையாள அணிவகுப்பில் ஆஜர்படுத்துமாறும் நீதவான் உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட வீட்டிற்கு தீ வைத்தமை, சொத்துக்களை சேதப்படுத்தியமை மற்றும் திருடுதல் போன்ற குற்றச்சாட்டின் பேரில் மற்றுமொரு சந்தேகநபர் திங்கட்கிழமை இரவு கொட்டாவ பிரதேசத்தில் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "33 வயதான சந்தேக நபர் அரநாயக்க பிரதேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்த தச்சர் என பொலிஸ் ஊடகப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "RWs தனியார் வீட்டில் மதுபாட்டில்களை திருடிய சந்தேகநபர் விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்",
        "இலங்கையைப் போன்ற ஒரு சூழ்நிலையை வங்கதேசம் சந்திக்காது: பிரதமர் ஷேக் ஹசீனா"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "RWs தனியார் வீடு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "7வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "7வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kottawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கள் இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொலிஸ் ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "33 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரநாயக்க",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "RWs தனியார் வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PM ஷேக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹசீனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}