{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/சான்றிதழைக்-கோரும்-ஐ-எம்-எப்/175-302657",
  "time_ut": 1660964563,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "சான்றிதழைக் கோரும் ஐ.எம்.எப்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "IMF seeking certification",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The International Monetary Fund (IMF) said it expected adequate guarantees from the creditors during the visit of an IMF delegation to Sri Lanka.",
        "The International Monetary Fund has announced a visit to Sri Lanka to broker a staff-level agreement to introduce an aid package to tackle the economic crisis Sri Lanka is facing.",
        "Reuters news service reported that IMF staff will visit Sri Lanka from August 24 to 31.",
        "It has been reported that a certificate obtained from the creditor regarding Sri Lanka's debt restructuring is necessary to provide the facilities of the International Monetary Fund. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 24 to 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "IMF සහතිකය අපේක්ෂා කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නියෝජිත පිරිසකගේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරයේදී ණය හිමියන්ගෙන් ප්‍රමාණවත් ඇපකරයක් අපේක්ෂා කරන බව ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුහුණ දී සිටින ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට මුහුණ දීම සඳහා ආධාර පැකේජයක් හඳුන්වා දීම සඳහා කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමක් තැරැව් කිරීම සඳහා ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංචාරයක් නිවේදනය කර තිබේ.",
        "රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවය වාර්තා කළේ IMF කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය අගෝස්තු 24 සිට 31 දක්වා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංචාරය කරන බවයි.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ පහසුකම් ලබාදීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ණයහිමියාගෙන් ලබාගත් සහතිකයක් අවශ්‍ය බව වාර්තා වේ. (ඒ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 24 සිට 31 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சான்றிதழைக் கோரும் ஐ.எம்.எப்",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகள் குழுவொன்றின் இலங்கைக்கான விஜயத்தின் போது கடனாளிகளிடமிருந்து போதிய உத்தரவாதத்தை எதிர்பார்ப்பதாக சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை முகங்கொடுக்கும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியைச் சமாளிக்க உதவிப் பொதியை அறிமுகப்படுத்துவதற்கான பணியாளர் மட்ட ஒப்பந்தத்தை ஏற்படுத்துவதற்காக இலங்கைக்கான விஜயத்தை மேற்கொள்ளவுளதாக சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பணியாளர்கள் ஒகஸ்ட் மாதம் 24 முதல் 31 வரை இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்வார்கள் என ரொய்டர்ஸ் செய்தித் சேவை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் வசதிகளை வழங்குவதற்கு, இலங்கையின் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு தொடர்பில் கடன் வழங்குநரிடமிருந்து பெறப்பட்ட சான்றிதழ் அவசியமாகும் என தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 24 முதல் 31 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}