{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Japanese-Ambassador-makes-first-visit-to-Northern-Province/56-736937",
  "time_ut": 1656700961,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Japanese Ambassador makes first visit to Northern Province",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Japanese Ambassador makes first visit to Northern Province",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Japanese Ambassador to Sri Lanka Mizukoshi Hideaki visited Jaffna from 27 to 30 June. This was his first trip to the Northern Province as Ambassador.",
        "In his visit to Jaffna, the Ambassador had discussions with Fisheries Minister Douglas Devananda, Jaffna Mayor V. Manivannan, the Commander of Security Forces Headquarters Jaffna Major General W.M.G.C.S.B. Wijayasundara and several political figures including a Member of Parliament, as well as the representatives of the Chamber of Commerce and journalists in Jaffna. Through the meetings, the Ambassador deepened his understanding and enriched knowledge on the Northern Province.",
        "In a meeting with Minister Devananda, Ambassador Mizukoshi recalled the past assistance which contributed to the fishing area, such as Ocean University of Sri Lanka Regional Centre Jaffna, and aquafarming facility, and explored possibilities of future cooperation for further development of the northern region. During the meeting with dignitaries, the Ambassador highlighted Japan’s previous and ongoing development project to support infrastructural development such as irrigation system and water management, as well as the agricultural sector through the construction of the Agricultural Faculty of University of Jaffna and productivity improvement by supporting small-scale farmers.",
        "As a newly implemented project, the Ambassador was delighted to introduce the provision of agricultural plant quarantine equipment at the Jaffna International Airport, which is expected to contribute to increased export of agricultural products from Sri Lanka.",
        "While in Jaffna, Ambassador Mizukoshi started his visit by signing a grant contract for the financial assistance to the demining project, with the Delvon Assistance for Social Harmony (DASH) which produces safe land for local communities. Furthermore, he visited the several sites that Japan has supported through different grant assistance, such as Jaffna Teaching Hospital, Vembodukrny c.c.t.m. School for resettled children in Kilinochchi, and Tech Ceylon, a coconut oil production facility in Mullaitivu. The Ambassador also went through two bridges in the national road A9, which were part of the Major Bridges Construction Project that constructed eight bridges in the Northern Province. In addition, he visited MAS Kreeda Vaanavil, which is one of the well-known apparel companies in Kilinochchi related to JASTECA (Japan Sri Lanka Technical and Cultural Association).",
        "Japan, a longstanding partner in Sri Lanka’s socio-economic development, has been supporting Sri Lanka’s peace building, reconstruction and development of the conflict affected area for many years. Japan believes that the past and current projects have been contributing to not only prosperity and welfare of all people of Sri Lanka, but also enhancing the friendship between the people of Sri Lanka and Japan. Japan will continue to do its part in combining its efforts with the people and Government of Sri Lanka."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Japanese",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "first",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Northern Province",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Mizukoshi Hideaki",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 to 30 June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Northern Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Douglas Devananda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "V. Manivannan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Commander of Security Forces Headquarters Jaffna Major",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "W.M.G.C.S.B. Wijayasundara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Chamber of Commerce",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Northern Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Devananda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mizukoshi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ocean University of Sri Lanka Regional Centre Jaffna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Agricultural Faculty of University of Jaffna",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Jaffna International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mizukoshi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Delvon Assistance for Social Harmony",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna Teaching Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vembodukrny c.c.t.m.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kilinochchi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tech Ceylon",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mullaitivu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Major Bridges Construction Project",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "eight",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Northern Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kreeda Vaanavil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kilinochchi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "many years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජපාන තානාපති උතුරු පළාතේ පළමු සංචාරය කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජපාන තානාපති Mizukoshi Hideaki ජුනි 27 සිට 30 දක්වා යාපනයේ සංචාරයක නිරත විය. තානාපතිවරයා වශයෙන් ඔහු උතුරු පළාතට ගිය පළමු සංචාරය මෙය විය.",
        "යාපනයේ සංචාරයක නිරත වූ තානාපතිවරයා ධීවර අමාත්‍ය ඩග්ලස් දේවානන්ද, යාපනය නගරාධිපති වී. මනිවන්නන්, යාපනය ආරක්ෂක සේනා මූලස්ථාන ආඥාපති මේජර් ජෙනරාල් ඩබ්ලිව්.එම්.ජී.සී.එස්.බී. විජයසුන්දර සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ඇතුළු දේශපාලන ප්‍රධානීන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු මෙන්ම වාණිජ මණ්ඩලයේ නියෝජිතයින් සහ යාපනයේ මාධ්‍යවේදීන් ද එක්ව සිටියහ. රැස්වීම් තුළින් තානාපතිවරයා උතුරු පළාත පිළිබඳ සිය අවබෝධය ගැඹුරු කර ගත් අතර දැනුම පොහොසත් කළේය.",
        "අමාත්‍ය දේවානන්ද මහතා සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවකදී තානාපති මිසුකෝෂි මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකා සාගර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය යාපනය ප්‍රාදේශීය මධ්‍යස්ථානය, ජල ගොවිතැන් පහසුකම් වැනි ධීවර ප්‍රදේශයට දායක වූ අතීත ආධාර සිහිපත් කළ අතර උතුරු කලාපයේ තවදුරටත් සංවර්ධනය සඳහා අනාගත සහයෝගීතාවයේ හැකියාවන් ගවේෂණය කළේය. සම්භාවනීය අමුත්තන් සමඟ පැවති හමුවේදී තානාපතිවරයා යාපනය විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ කෘෂිකාර්මික පීඨය ඉදි කිරීම තුළින් කෘෂිකාර්මික අංශයට මෙන්ම වාරිමාර්ග පද්ධතිය සහ ජල කළමනාකරණය වැනි යටිතල පහසුකම් සංවර්ධනයට සහය වීම සඳහා ජපානයේ පෙර සහ දැනට ක්‍රියාත්මක සංවර්ධන ව්‍යාපෘතිය පිළිබඳව අවධානය යොමු කළේය. - පරිමාණ ගොවීන්.",
        "අලුතින් ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන ලද ව්‍යාපෘතියක් ලෙස, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් කෘෂිකාර්මික නිෂ්පාදන අපනයනය වැඩි කිරීමට දායක වනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කරන යාපනය ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළේ කෘෂිකාර්මික ශාක නිරෝධායන උපකරණ ලබා දීම පිළිබඳව තානාපතිවරයා සතුටට පත් විය.",
        "යාපනයේ සිටියදී, තානාපති මිසුකෝෂි සිය සංචාරය ආරම්භ කළේ බිම්බෝම්බ ඉවත් කිරීමේ ව්‍යාපෘතිය සඳහා මූල්‍ය ආධාර සඳහා ප්‍රදානය කිරීමේ කොන්ත්‍රාත්තුවක් අත්සන් කරමින්, ප්‍රාදේශීය ප්‍රජාවන්ට ආරක්ෂිත ඉඩම් නිපදවන සමාජ සහජීවනය සඳහා වන ඩෙල්වෝන් සහාය (DASH) සමඟිනි. තවද, යාපනය ශික්ෂණ රෝහල, වෙම්බොඩුක්‍රිනි c.c.t.m වැනි විවිධ ප්‍රදාන ආධාර හරහා ජපානය සහාය දුන් ස්ථාන කිහිපයකම ඔහු සංචාරය කළේය. කිලිනොච්චියේ නැවත පදිංචි වූ ළමුන් සඳහා පාසල සහ මුලතිව්හි පොල්තෙල් නිෂ්පාදන මධ්‍යස්ථානයක් වන ටෙක් සිලෝන්. උතුරු පළාතේ පාලම් අටක් ඉදිකරන ලද ප්‍රධාන පාලම් ඉදිකිරීම් ව්‍යාපෘතියේ කොටසක් වූ A9 ජාතික මාර්ගයේ පාලම් දෙකක් හරහා ද තානාපතිවරයා ගමන් කළේය. මීට අමතරව, ඔහු JASTECA (ජපානය ශ්‍රී ලංකා තාක්ෂණික හා සංස්කෘතික සංගමය) සම්බන්ධ කිලිනොච්චියේ සුප්‍රසිද්ධ ඇඟලුම් සමාගමක් වන MAS ක්‍රීඩා වානවිල් වෙත ගියේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සමාජ-ආර්ථික සංවර්ධනයේ දිගුකාලීන හවුල්කරුවෙකු වන ජපානය වසර ගණනාවක් පුරා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සාමය ගොඩනැගීම, ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණය සහ සංවර්ධනය සඳහා සහය දක්වයි. ජපානය විශ්වාස කරන්නේ අතීත සහ වර්තමාන ව්‍යාපෘති ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සියලුම ජනතාවගේ සමෘද්ධිය සහ සුබසාධනය සඳහා පමණක් නොව, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සහ ජපානයේ ජනතාව අතර මිත්‍රත්වය වැඩි දියුණු කිරීමට ද දායක වී ඇති බවයි. ජපානය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාව සහ රජය සමඟ තම ප්‍රයත්නයන් ඒකාබද්ධ කිරීමෙහිලා සිය කාර්යභාරය අඛණ්ඩව ඉටු කරනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජපන්",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "පළමුවන",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "උතුරු පළාත",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Mizukoshi Hideaki",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි 27 සිට 30 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩග්ලස් දේවානන්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වී මනිවන්නන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය ආරක්ෂක සේනා මූලස්ථානයේ ආඥාපති මේජර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩබ්ලිව්.එම්.ජී.සී.එස්.බී. විජයසුන්දර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාණිජ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දේවානන්දයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mizukoshi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සාගර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය ප්‍රාදේශීය මධ්‍යස්ථානය යාපනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ කෘෂිකර්ම පීඨය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යාපනය ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mizukoshi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාජ සංහිඳියාව සඳහා Delvon සහාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය ශික්ෂණ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vembodukrny c.c.t.m.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලිනොච්චි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටෙක් සිලෝන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුලතිව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රධාන පාලම් ඉදිකිරීම් ව්යාපෘතිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අට",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්‍රීඩා වානවිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලිනොච්චි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වර්ෂ බොහෝ ගණනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜப்பானிய தூதுவர் வட மாகாணத்திற்கு முதல் விஜயம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கைக்கான ஜப்பானிய தூதுவர் Mizukoshi Hideaki ஜூன் 27 முதல் 30 வரை யாழ்ப்பாணத்திற்கு விஜயம் செய்தார். தூதுவராக அவர் வடமாகாணத்திற்கான முதல் பயணம் இதுவாகும்.",
        "யாழ்ப்பாணத்திற்கு விஜயம் செய்த தூதுவர், கடற்றொழில் அமைச்சர் டக்ளஸ் தேவானந்தா, யாழ் மேயர் வி.மணிவண்ணன், பாதுகாப்பு படைத் தலைமையகத்தின் யாழ்.மாவட்டத் தளபதி மேஜர் ஜெனரல் டபிள்யூ.எம்.ஜி.சி.எஸ்.பி. விஜயசுந்தர மற்றும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் உட்பட பல அரசியல் பிரமுகர்கள், வர்த்தக சபையின் பிரதிநிதிகள் மற்றும் ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் யாழ். சந்திப்புகள் மூலம், தூதுவர் வடக்கு மாகாணம் பற்றிய தனது புரிதலை ஆழப்படுத்தி, அறிவை வளப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "அமைச்சர் தேவானந்தாவுடனான சந்திப்பில், தூதுவர் மிசுகோஷி, இலங்கைப் பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் யாழ்ப்பாணப் பிராந்திய மையம், மீன்வளர்ப்பு வசதி போன்ற மீன்பிடிப் பகுதிக்கு கடந்தகால உதவிகளை நினைவுகூர்ந்தார், மேலும் வடக்கு பிராந்தியத்தின் மேலும் அபிவிருத்திக்கான எதிர்கால ஒத்துழைப்புக்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகளை ஆராய்ந்தார். பிரமுகர்களுடனான சந்திப்பின் போது, ​​யாழ்ப்பாணப் பல்கலைக்கழக விவசாய பீடத்தை நிர்மாணிப்பதன் மூலம் விவசாயத் துறை மற்றும் விவசாயத் துறையின் உட்கட்டமைப்பு மேம்பாடுகளான நீர்ப்பாசனம் மற்றும் நீர் முகாமைத்துவம் மற்றும் சிறிய ஆதரவின் மூலம் உற்பத்தித்திறனை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கு ஜப்பானின் முந்தைய மற்றும் தற்போதைய அபிவிருத்தித் திட்டத்தை தூதுவர் எடுத்துரைத்தார். - அளவிலான விவசாயிகள்.",
        "புதிதாக நடைமுறைப்படுத்தப்பட்ட திட்டமாக, யாழ்ப்பாண சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தில் விவசாய ஆலை தனிமைப்படுத்தப்பட்ட உபகரணங்களை அறிமுகப்படுத்தியதில் தூதுவர் மகிழ்ச்சியடைகிறார், இது இலங்கையில் இருந்து விவசாய உற்பத்திகளின் ஏற்றுமதியை அதிகரிக்க பங்களிக்கும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "யாழ்ப்பாணத்தில் இருந்தபோது, ​​தூதுவர் மிசுகோஷி, கண்ணிவெடி அகற்றும் திட்டத்திற்கான நிதி உதவிக்கான மானிய ஒப்பந்தத்தில் கையெழுத்திட்டு, உள்ளூர் சமூகங்களுக்கு பாதுகாப்பான நிலத்தை உருவாக்கும் சமூக நல்லிணக்கத்திற்கான Delvon Assistance (DASH) உடன் தனது பயணத்தைத் தொடங்கினார். மேலும், யாழ்ப்பாணம் போதனா வைத்தியசாலை, வெம்படுகிருனி c.c.t.m போன்ற பல்வேறு மானிய உதவிகள் மூலம் ஜப்பான் ஆதரவளித்த பல தளங்களை அவர் பார்வையிட்டார். கிளிநொச்சியில் மீள்குடியேற்றப்பட்ட குழந்தைகளுக்கான பாடசாலை மற்றும் முல்லைத்தீவில் தேங்காய் எண்ணெய் உற்பத்தி நிலையமான டெக் சிலோன். வடக்கு மாகாணத்தில் எட்டு பாலங்களை நிர்மாணித்த பிரதான பாலங்கள் நிர்மாணத் திட்டத்தின் ஒரு அங்கமான தேசிய வீதி A9 இல் உள்ள இரண்டு பாலங்களின் ஊடாகவும் தூதுவர் சென்றுள்ளார். மேலும், JASTECA (ஜப்பான் இலங்கை தொழில்நுட்ப மற்றும் கலாச்சார சங்கம்) தொடர்பான கிளிநொச்சியில் உள்ள பிரபல ஆடை நிறுவனங்களில் ஒன்றான MAS Kreeda Vaanavil ஐ அவர் பார்வையிட்டார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் சமூக-பொருளாதார அபிவிருத்தியில் நீண்டகால பங்காளியாக இருக்கும் ஜப்பான், இலங்கையின் சமாதானத்தை கட்டியெழுப்புதல், புனரமைப்பு மற்றும் மோதலில் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட பிரதேசத்தின் அபிவிருத்திக்கு பல வருடங்களாக ஆதரவளித்து வருகின்றது. கடந்த கால மற்றும் தற்போதைய திட்டங்கள் இலங்கையின் அனைத்து மக்களின் செழிப்பு மற்றும் நலனுக்காக மட்டுமல்லாமல், இலங்கை மற்றும் ஜப்பான் மக்களுக்கும் இடையிலான நட்புறவை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கும் பங்களிப்பதாக ஜப்பான் நம்புகிறது. இலங்கை மக்கள் மற்றும் அரசாங்கத்துடன் தனது முயற்சிகளை இணைப்பதில் ஜப்பான் தனது பங்களிப்பை தொடர்ந்து செய்யும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "முதலில்",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "வட மாகாணம்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Mizukoshi Hideaki",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 27 முதல் 30 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டக்ளஸ் தேவானந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வி.மணிவண்ணன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாணம் பாதுகாப்பு படைத் தலைமையகத்தின் தளபதி மேஜர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டபிள்யூ.எம்.ஜி.சி.எஸ்.பி. விஜயசுந்தர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வர்த்தக சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேவானந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mizukoshi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கைப் பெருங்கடல் பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் பிராந்திய மையம் யாழ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாணப் பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் விவசாயப் பீடம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாண சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mizukoshi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமூக நல்லிணக்கத்திற்கான டெல்வோன் உதவி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாணம் போதனா வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெம்போடுக்ரினி சி.சி.டி.எம்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிளிநொச்சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெக் சிலோன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முல்லைத்தீவு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரிய பாலங்கள் கட்டுமான திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிரீடா வானவில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிளிநொச்சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}