{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131831",
  "time_ut": 1658244754,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவு வெளிப்படைத்தன்மையுடன் இடம்பெறும் - பன்னாட்டு இராஜதந்திரிகளிடம் சபாநாயகர் உறுதி",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Speaker assures international diplomats that presidential election will be held transparently",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "Speaker Mahinda Yappa Abeywardhana told the ambassadors and high commissioners that all arrangements have been made to carry out the process of electing a new president transparently as the oldest country in Asia.",
        "US Ambassador to Sri Lanka Julie Sung, EU Ambassador Denis Saipi, New Zealand High Commissioner Michelle Apelton, British High Commissioner Sarah Halton, Australian High Commissioner David Holley and Canadian High Commissioner David McGinnon attended the meeting held at the Parliament building.",
        "As the oldest country in Asia with a secure parliamentary democracy, Speaker Mahinda Yappa Abeywardena informed the delegates and ambassadors that all arrangements have been made to carry out the process of electing a new president in a transparent manner.",
        "The Secretary General of the Parliament explained to the Ambassadors and High Commissioners the process of electing the new President through the Parliament. The Ambassadors and High Commissioners appreciated the steps taken to ensure democracy in the country."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yappa Abeywardhana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Sung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Denis Saipi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Zealand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Michelle Apelton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sarah Halton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "David Holley",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canadian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "David McGinnon",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yappa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපතිවරණය විනිවිදභාවයෙන් පවත්වන බවට කථානායක ජාත්‍යන්තර තානාපතිවරුන්ට සහතික වෙයි",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආසියාවේ පැරණිතම රට ලෙස නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනීමේ කටයුතු විනිවිදභාවයෙන් යුතුව සිදුකිරීමට සියලු කටයුතු සූදානම් කර ඇති බව කථානායක මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන මහතා තානාපතිවරුන්ට සහ මහ කොමසාරිස්වරුන්ට ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඇමෙරිකානු තානාපතිනි Julie Sung, EU තානාපති Denis Saipi, නවසීලන්ත මහ කොමසාරිස් Michelle Apelton, බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය මහ කොමසාරිස් Sarah Halton, Australian මහ කොමසාරිස් David Holley, Canadian High Commissioner David McGinnon යන මහත්ම මහත්මීහු පාර්ලිමේන්තු ගොඩනැගිල්ලේ පැවති මෙම හමුවට එක්ව සිටියහ.",
        "සුරක්ෂිත පාර්ලිමේන්තු ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදයක් සහිත ආසියාවේ පැරණිතම රට ලෙස නව ජනාධිපතිවරයකු තෝරා ගැනීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය විනිවිදභාවයෙන් යුතුව සිදුකිරීමට සියලු කටයුතු සූදානම් කර ඇති බව කථානායක මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන මහතා නියෝජිතයන්ට සහ තානාපතිවරුන්ට දැනුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව හරහා නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය පිළිබඳව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම්වරයා තානාපතිවරුන්ට සහ මහ කොමසාරිස්වරුන්ට පැහැදිලි කළේය.රටේ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය තහවුරු කිරීමට ගෙන ඇති පියවර තානාපතිවරුන් සහ මහ කොමසාරිස්වරුන්ගේ ඇගයීමට ලක් විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි සන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩෙනිස් සයිපි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවසීලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිෂෙල් ඇපල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාරා හැල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේවිඩ් හොලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනේඩියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේවිඩ් මැක්ගිනන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவு வெளிப்படைத்தன்மையுடன் இடம்பெறும் - பன்னாட்டு இராஜதந்திரிகளிடம் சபாநாயகர் உறுதி",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஆசியாவின் பழமையான நாடு என்ற வகையில் புதிய ஜனாதிபதியைத் தெரிவு செய்யும் செயற்பாடுகள் வெளிப்படைத் தன்மையுடன் முன்னெடுக்க சகல ஏற்பாடுகளும் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டிருப்பதாக சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன  தூதுவர்களிடமும், உயர்ஸ்தானிகர்களிடமும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற கட்டடத்தொகுதியில் இடம்பெற்ற இச்சந்திப்பில் இலங்கைக்கான அமெரிக்க தூதுவர் ஜூலி சங்,ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியத்தின் தூதுவர் டெனிஸ் சைபி,நியூசிலாந்து உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் மிஷேல் அபல்டன்,பிரித்தானிய உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் சாரா ஹல்டன், அவுஸ்ரேலியாவுக்கான உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் டேவிட் ஹொலி,கனேடிய உயரஸ்தானிகர் டேவிட் மெகினன் ஆகியோர் கலந்துக்கொண்டனர்.",
        "பாதுகாப்பான பாராளுமன்ற ஜனநாயகத்தை கொண்ட ஆசியாவின் பழமையான நாடு என்ற வகையில் புதிய ஜனாதிபதியைத் தெரிவு செய்யும் செயற்பாடுகள் வெளிப்படைத் தன்மையுடன் முன்னெடுக்க சகல ஏற்பாடுகளும் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டிருப்பதாக சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன  தூதுவர்களிடமும்,உயர்ஸ்தானிகர்களிடமும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தின் ஊடாக புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்யும் நடைமுறையை பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் தூதுவர்களுக்கும்,உயர்ஸ்தானிகர்களுக்கும் தெளிவுப்படுத்தினார்.நாட்டில் ஜனநாயகத்தை உறுதிப்படுத்த முன்னெடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள நடவடிக்கைகளை தூதுவர்களும்,உயர்ஸ்தானிகர்களும் பாராட்டினர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெனிஸ் சைபி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நியூசிலாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைக்கேல் அபெல்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாரா ஹால்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "டேவிட் ஹோலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "டேவிட் மெக்கின்னன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}