{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83481/two-representatives-from-russian-oil-company-arrive-in-sri-lanka",
  "time_ut": 1657180260,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Two representatives from Russian oil company arrive in Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Two representatives from Russian oil company arrive in Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Two representatives from a Russian oil company have reportedly arrived in the island today (07).",
        "Ada Derana reporter said the two officials had touched down at the Bandaranaike International Airport (BIA) in Katunayake this morning.",
        "During this visit, discussions are scheduled to be held between the relevant oil company representatives and Sri Lankan authorities regarding the import of fuel.",
        "Due to the suspension of direct flights between Moscow and Katunayake, the relevant representatives have had to come to Sri Lanka via Bahrain.",
        "National Freedom Front (NFF) leader MP Wimal Weerawansa and others were present to welcome the representatives.",
        "Meanwhile President Gotabaya Rajapaksa had yesterday sought an offer of credit support from Russian President Vladimir Putin to import fuel to Sri Lanka to ride out the current economic challenges.",
        "Taking to his official Twitter account, the President said he had a very productive telephone conversation with his Russian counterpart.",
        "The two leaders had unanimously agreed that strengthening bilateral relations in sectors such as tourism, trade and culture is paramount in reinforcing the friendship between the two nations.",
        "During their conversation, President Rajapaksa has appealed to President Putin to resume Russian airline Aeroflot’s flight operations to Sri Lanka."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Russian",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ada Derana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bandaranaike International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bahrain",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "National Freedom Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රුසියානු තෙල් සමාගමේ නියෝජිතයන් දෙදෙනෙක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රුසියානු තෙල් සමාගමක නියෝජිතයින් දෙදෙනෙකු අද (07) දිවයිනට පැමිණ ඇති බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "අද උදෑසන මෙම නිලධාරීන් දෙදෙනා කටුනායක බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළට පැමිණ ඇති බව අද දෙරණ වාර්තාකරු පැවසීය.",
        "මෙම සංචාරයේදී ඉන්ධන ආනයනය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අදාළ තෙල් සමාගම් නියෝජිතයින් සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලධාරීන් අතර සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "මොස්කව් සහ කටුනායක අතර සෘජු ගුවන් ගමන් අත්හිටුවීම හේතුවෙන් අදාළ නියෝජිතයින්ට බහරේනය හරහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට සිදුව තිබේ.",
        "එම නියෝජිතයන් පිළිගැනීමට ජාතික නිදහස් පෙරමුණේ නායක පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී විමල් වීරවංශ මහතා ඇතුළු පිරිසක් පැමිණ සිටියහ.",
        "මේ අතර, වත්මන් ආර්ථික අභියෝගවලින් මිදීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඉන්ධන ආනයනය කිරීම සඳහා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ ඊයේ රුසියානු ජනාධිපති ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්ගෙන් ණය ආධාර ඉල්ලා තිබේ.",
        "සිය නිල ට්විටර් ගිණුමට සටහනක් තබමින් ජනාධිපතිවරයා කියා සිටියේ තමන් රුසියානු සහචරයා සමඟ ඉතා ඵලදායී දුරකථන සංවාදයක නිරත වූ බවයි.",
        "දෙරට අතර මිත්‍රත්වය ශක්තිමත් කිරීමේදී සංචාරක, වෙළෙඳ සහ සංස්කෘතික වැනි ක්ෂේත්‍රවල ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතා ශක්තිමත් කර ගැනීම ප්‍රමුඛ වන බවට නායක දෙපළ ඒකමතිකව එකඟ වී ඇත.",
        "ඔවුන්ගේ සංවාදය අතරතුර, රුසියානු ගුවන් සමාගමක් වන Aeroflot හි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ගුවන් ගමන් නැවත ආරම්භ කරන ලෙස ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ ජනාධිපති පුටින්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "රුසියානු",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද දෙරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බහරේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික නිදහස් පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரஷ்ய எண்ணெய் நிறுவனத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகள் இருவர் இலங்கை வந்துள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ரஷ்ய எண்ணெய் நிறுவனமொன்றின் பிரதிநிதிகள் இருவர் இன்று (07) நாட்டிற்கு வந்துள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இரு அதிகாரிகளும் இன்று காலை கட்டுநாயக்க பண்டாரநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தில் (BIA) தரையிறங்கியதாக அத தெரண செய்தியாளர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த விஜயத்தின் போது எரிபொருள் இறக்குமதி தொடர்பில் சம்பந்தப்பட்ட எண்ணெய் நிறுவன பிரதிநிதிகள் மற்றும் இலங்கை அதிகாரிகளுக்கு இடையில் கலந்துரையாடல் இடம்பெறவுள்ளது.",
        "மொஸ்கோவிற்கும் கட்டுநாயக்கவிற்கும் இடையிலான நேரடி விமான சேவைகள் இடைநிறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதால், சம்பந்தப்பட்ட பிரதிநிதிகள் பஹ்ரைன் ஊடாக இலங்கைக்கு வரவேண்டிய நிலை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "தேசிய சுதந்திர முன்னணியின் (NFF) தலைவர் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் விமல் வீரவங்ச உள்ளிட்டோர் பிரதிநிதிகளை வரவேற்க பிரசன்னமாகியிருந்தனர்.",
        "இதேவேளை, தற்போதைய பொருளாதார சவால்களை சமாளிக்க இலங்கைக்கு எரிபொருளை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்கு ரஷ்ய ஜனாதிபதி விளாடிமிர் புட்டினிடம் கடனுதவி வழங்குமாறு ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ நேற்று கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "தனது உத்தியோகபூர்வ ட்விட்டர் கணக்கில் எடுத்துக்கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதி, தனது ரஷ்ய பிரதிநிதியுடன் மிகவும் பயனுள்ள தொலைபேசி உரையாடலை நடத்தியதாகக் கூறினார்.",
        "சுற்றுலா, வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் கலாச்சாரம் போன்ற துறைகளில் இருதரப்பு உறவுகளை வலுப்படுத்துவது இரு நாடுகளுக்கு இடையேயான நட்புறவை வலுப்படுத்துவதில் மிக முக்கியமானது என்று இரு தலைவர்களும் ஒருமனதாக ஒப்புக்கொண்டனர்.",
        "அவர்களின் உரையாடலின் போது, ​​ரஷ்ய விமான நிறுவனமான ஏரோஃப்ளோட்டின் இலங்கைக்கான விமான நடவடிக்கைகளை மீண்டும் தொடங்குமாறு ஜனாதிபதி புட்டினிடம் ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ வேண்டுகோள் விடுத்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அட தெரண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்கா சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பஹ்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய சுதந்திர முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளாடிமிர் புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}