{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Dullas-Sajith-agree-to-fulfill-TNA-demands-in-return-for-support/342-241394",
  "time_ut": 1658255076,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Dullas, Sajith agree to fulfill TNA demands in return for support",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dullas, Sajith agree to fulfill TNA demands in return for support",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Presidential candidate Dullas Allahapperuma and his prime ministerial candidate Sajith Premadasa have agreed to fulfill demands put forward by the TNA in a meeting held today evening which included the release of all political prisoners and the release of all private lands, including those occupied by the army and archeological sites in the North and East.",
        "A senior TNA source who attended the meeting said that some of the other demands put forward included the Office of Missing Persons (OMP) restarting inquiries into missing persons, the Sri Lankan government must cooperate with the UN Human Rights resolution and a process must start to resolve the Tamil national issue.",
        "Both Dullas and Sajith had agreed to the demands laid down by the TNA and only after this was accepted that the TNA said they would support Dullas in the presidential race tomorrow.",
        "SLPP MP G.L. Peiris also attended the meeting. (Jamila Husain)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dullas",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sajith",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "TNA",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dullas Allahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "North and East",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Office of Missing Persons",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "OMP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "UN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dullas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "G.L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jamila Husain",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඩලස්, සජිත් සහයෝගය වෙනුවෙන් TNA ඉල්ලීම් ඉටු කිරීමට එකඟ වෙති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සියලු දේශපාලන සිරකරුවන් නිදහස් කිරීම සහ හමුදාව විසින් අත්පත් කරගෙන සිටින ඉඩම් ඇතුළු පෞද්ගලික ඉඩම් නිදහස් කිරීම ඇතුළු දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානය අද සවස පැවති සාකච්ඡාවකදී ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂක ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම සහ ඔහුගේ අගමැති අපේක්ෂක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ඉදිරිපත් කළ ඉල්ලීම් ඉටු කිරීමට එකඟ වී තිබේ. උතුරු නැගෙනහිර පුරාවිද්‍යා ස්ථාන.",
        "මෙම රැස්වීමට සහභාගී වූ TNA ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ මූලාශ්‍රයක් ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති අනෙකුත් ඉල්ලීම් අතර අතුරුදහන් වූවන් පිළිබඳ විමර්ශන නැවත ආරම්භ කිරීම, ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් යෝජනාවට සහය විය යුතු අතර ඒ සඳහා ක්‍රියාවලියක් ආරම්භ කළ යුතු බව අතුරුදහන් වූවන්ගේ කාර්යාලය (OMP) ඇතුළත් වේ. දෙමළ ජාතික ප්‍රශ්නය විසඳන්න.",
        "දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානය ඉදිරිපත් කළ ඉල්ලීම්වලට ඩලස් සහ සජිත් දෙදෙනාම එකඟ වී ඇති අතර එය පිළිගත් පසුවයි දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානය ප්‍රකාශ කළේ හෙට පැවැත්වෙන ජනාධිපතිවරණයේදී ඩලස්ට සහය දෙන බවයි.",
        "මෙම රැස්වීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ජී එල් පීරිස් ද සහභාගී විය. (ජමිලා හුසේන්)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩලස්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "සජිත්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ටීඑන්ඒ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටීඑන්ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු නැගෙනහිර",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ටීඑන්ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අතුරුදහන් වූවන් පිළිබඳ කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "OMP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "එ.ජා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටීඑන්ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටීඑන්ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජමිලා හුසේන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டலஸ், சஜித் ஆதரவுக்கு பதில் TNA கோரிக்கைகளை நிறைவேற்ற சம்மதம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி வேட்பாளர் டலஸ் அலகப்பெருமவும் அவரது பிரதமர் வேட்பாளர் சஜித் பிரேமதாசவும் இன்று மாலை நடைபெற்ற தமிழ் தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பினால் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட அனைத்து அரசியல் கைதிகளையும் விடுவித்தல், இராணுவம் மற்றும் இராணுவத்தால் ஆக்கிரமிக்கப்பட்ட காணிகள் உட்பட அனைத்து தனியார் காணிகளையும் விடுவித்தல் உள்ளிட்ட கோரிக்கைகளை நிறைவேற்ற இணங்கியுள்ளனர். வடக்கு மற்றும் கிழக்கில் உள்ள தொல்பொருள் இடங்கள்.",
        "காணாமல் போனோர் தொடர்பான விசாரணைகளை மீள ஆரம்பிக்க வேண்டும், ஐ.நா மனித உரிமைகள் தீர்மானத்திற்கு இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் ஒத்துழைக்க வேண்டும் என்பன உள்ளிட்ட ஏனைய சில கோரிக்கைகள் முன்வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக கூட்டத்தில் கலந்து கொண்ட தமிழ் தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பின் சிரேஷ்ட வட்டாரம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. தமிழ் தேசிய பிரச்சினையை தீர்க்க வேண்டும்.",
        "தமிழ்த் தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பு முன்வைத்த கோரிக்கைகளுக்கு டளஸ் மற்றும் சஜித் இருவரும் இணக்கம் தெரிவித்திருந்தனர், இது ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்பட்ட பின்னரே நாளை ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் டளஸுக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதாக தமிழ்த் தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பு தெரிவித்தது.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸும் இந்த சந்திப்பில் கலந்துகொண்டார். (ஜமிலா ஹுசைன்)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "சஜித்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "TNA",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அலகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாயங்காலம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு மற்றும் கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காணாமல் போனோர் அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "OMP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜமீலா ஹுசைன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}