{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83807/kamal-gunaratne-re-appointed-defence-secretary",
  "time_ut": 1658474700,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Kamal Gunaratne re-appointed Defence Secretary",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Kamal Gunaratne re-appointed Defence Secretary",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "General (Retd.) Kamal Gunaratne has been re-appointed as the Secretary to the Ministry of Defence by President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Gunaratne, a decorated veteran of the Sri Lanka Army, was first appointed to the post by former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa in November 2019.",
        "He is the former Commander Security Forces Headquarters - Wanni, General Officer Commanding (GOC) 53 Division, Colonel of the Regiment, Mechanized Infantry Regiment (MIR) and Master General Ordnance (MGO) of the Army Headquarters.",
        "He has also served as a Deputy Ambassador of Sri Lanka to Brazil.",
        "Following his retirement from the army in September 2016, Gunaratne authored a book ‘Road to Nandikadal’ on the war against the LTTE."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kamal Gunaratne",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Defence",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kamal Gunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gunaratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "November 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Officer Commanding",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "53",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MIR",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Brazil",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "September 2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunaratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LTTE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කමල් ගුණරත්න යළි ආරක්ෂක ලේකම් ධූරයට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජෙනරාල් (විශ්‍රාමික) කමල් ගුණරත්න මහතා ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම්වරයා ලෙස ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් යළි පත් කර තිබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුද හමුදාවේ කීර්තිමත් ප්‍රවීණයෙකු වන ගුණරත්න, හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ විසින් 2019 නොවැම්බර් මාසයේදී එම තනතුරට ප්‍රථම වරට පත් කරන ලදී.",
        "ඔහු වන්නි ආරක්ෂක සේනා මූලස්ථානයේ හිටපු ආඥාපති, 53 වන සේනාංකයේ (ජීඕසී) සේනාංකාධිපති, රෙජිමේන්තුවේ කර්නල්, යාන්ත්‍රික පාබල රෙජිමේන්තුව (MIR) සහ යුධ හමුදා මූලස්ථානයේ මාස්ටර් ජෙනරල් යුධෝපකරණ (MGO) වේ.",
        "ඔහු බ්‍රසීලයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නියෝජ්‍ය තානාපතිවරයකු ලෙස ද කටයුතු කර ඇත.",
        "2016 සැප්තැම්බරයේ හමුදාවෙන් විශ්‍රාම ගැනීමෙන් පසු ගුණරත්න එල්ටීටීඊයට එරෙහි යුද්ධය පිළිබඳව ‘රෝඩ් ටු නන්දිකඩාල්’ කෘතියක් රචනා කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කමල් ගුණරත්න",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කමල් ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුණරත්න ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුද හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019 නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අණදෙන නිලධාරී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "53",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MIR",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රසීලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2016 සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුණරත්න ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්ටීටීඊය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கமல் குணரத்ன மீண்டும் பாதுகாப்பு செயலாளராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சின் செயலாளராக ஜெனரல் (ஓய்வு) கமல் குணரத்ன மீண்டும் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை இராணுவத்தின் அலங்கரிக்கப்பட்ட வீரரான குணரத்ன, 2019 நவம்பரில் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவினால் முதன்முதலில் பதவிக்கு நியமிக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "இவர் வன்னி பாதுகாப்புப் படைத் தலைமையகத்தின் முன்னாள் தளபதி, 53 ஆவது படைப்பிரிவின் பொது அதிகாரி கட்டளைத் தளபதி, படைப்பிரிவின் கர்னல், இயந்திரமயமாக்கப்பட்ட காலாட்படை படைப்பிரிவு (எம்ஐஆர்) மற்றும் இராணுவத் தலைமையகத்தின் மாஸ்டர் ஜெனரல் ஆர்ட்னன்ஸ் (எம்ஜிஓ) ஆவார்.",
        "பிரேசிலுக்கான இலங்கையின் துணைத் தூதுவராகவும் பணியாற்றியுள்ளார்.",
        "2016 செப்டம்பரில் இராணுவத்தில் இருந்து ஓய்வு பெற்ற குணரத்ன, விடுதலைப் புலிகளுக்கு எதிரான போர் குறித்து ‘ரோட் டு நந்திக்கடல்’ என்ற புத்தகத்தை எழுதியுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கமல் குணரத்ன",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கமல் குணரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குணரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அதிகாரி கட்டளை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "53",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.ஐ.ஆர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேசில்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குணரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விடுதலைப் புலிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}