{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132243",
  "time_ut": 1658748091,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "புதிய ஜனாதிபதியின் தலைமையில் அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மையை விரைவாக ஏற்படுத்துவோம் - விஜேதாச உறுதி",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Let us speedily establish political stability under the leadership of a new President - Vijetasa Assimilation",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "Minister of Justice Wijetasa Rajapaksh has told the Sri Lankan Ambassador to Thailand that we will quickly establish political stability and submit the 22nd amendment of the Constitution to the Parliament for approval.",
        "Thai Ambassador to Sri Lanka Bhoj Hanbol met and discussed with the Minister of Justice, Prisons and Constitutional Reform Wijetasa Rajapaksa today at the Ministry of Justice.",
        "During this, attention was paid to further increase the long standing economic, political and cultural cooperation between the two countries.",
        "Under the leadership of the new president, steps will be taken to bring political stability and normalization of the economy to Sri Lanka.",
        "Also, the minister told the ambassador that we are taking steps to submit the 22nd amendment of the constitution to the parliament and approve it.",
        "Also, the minister recalled that in 2016, he had the opportunity to deliver the keynote speech at the United Nations International Vesak Festival held in Thailand and in 2017, when the festival was held in Sri Lanka, Thailand provided massive cooperation for it.",
        "The Minister also reminded the cooperation that Thailand is receiving for the reconstruction of Buddhism and for economic and religious cultural development in Sri Lanka by taking steps to restore the Buddhist upasampada to this country.",
        "We hope that the current problematic situation in Sri Lanka will be over and economic stability will be achieved.",
        "According to a statement issued by the Ministry of Justice, the Ambassador to Thailand said that we are ready to provide diplomatic assistance."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Justice Wijetasa Rajapaksh",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thai",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijetasa Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations International Vesak Festival",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකුගේ නායකත්වය යටතේ කඩිනමින් දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වය ඇතිකර ගනිමු - විජේතාස සමීකරණය",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "අපි කඩිනමින් දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වයක් ඇති කර 22 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ අනුමැතිය සඳහා ඉදිරිපත් කරන බව අධිකරණ අමාත්‍ය විජේතාස රාජපක්ෂ මහතා තායිලන්තයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපතිවරයාට පවසා තිබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තායිලන්ත තානාපති Bhoj Hanbol මහතා අධිකරණ, බන්ධනාගාර සහ ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ අමාත්‍ය විජේතාසා රාජපක්ෂ මහතා අද අධිකරණ අමාත්‍යාංශයේදී හමුවී සාකච්ඡා කළේය.",
        "දෙරට අතර දීර්ඝ කාලීන ආර්ථික, දේශපාලන සහ සංස්කෘතික සහයෝගීතාව තවදුරටත් ඉහළ නැංවීම කෙරෙහි මෙහිදී අවධානය යොමු විය.",
        "නව ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ නායකත්වය යටතේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වය සහ ආර්ථිකය සාමාන්‍යකරණය කිරීමට පියවර ගැනේ.",
        "එමෙන්ම 22 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කර එය අනුමත කිරීමට අප කටයුතු කරමින් සිටින බවද අමාත්‍යවරයා තානාපතිවරයාට පැවසීය.",
        "එමෙන්ම 2016 වසරේ තායිලන්තයේ පැවති එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ජාත්‍යන්තර වෙසක් උළෙලේ ප්‍රධාන දේශනය කිරීමට තමාට අවස්ථාව ලැබුණු බවත් 2017 වසරේ එම උත්සවය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පැවැත්වෙන විට තායිලන්තය ඒ සඳහා විශාල සහයෝගයක් ලබාදුන් බවත් අමාත්‍යවරයා සිහිපත් කළේය.",
        "එමෙන්ම බෞද්ධ උපසම්පදාව මෙරටට ප්‍රතිෂ්ඨාපනය කිරීමට පියවර ගනිමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බුද්ධාගම ප්‍රතිනිර්මාණය කිරීම සහ ආර්ථික හා ආගමික සංස්කෘතික සංවර්ධනය සඳහා තායිලන්තයට ලැබෙන සහයෝගීතාවය ද අමාත්‍යවරයා සිහිපත් කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දැනට පවතින ගැටලුකාරී තත්ත්වය අවසන් වී ආර්ථික ස්ථාවරත්වයක් ඇති වේ යැයි අපි බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා.",
        "අධිකරණ අමාත්‍යාංශය නිකුත් කළ නිවේදනයකට අනුව තායිලන්තයේ තානාපතිවරයා කියා සිටියේ රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික සහාය ලබාදීමට අප සූදානම් බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "විනිසුරු විජේතාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තායි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජේතාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණ අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ජාත්‍යන්තර වෙසක් උත්සවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණ අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புதிய ஜனாதிபதியின் தலைமையில் அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மையை விரைவாக ஏற்படுத்துவோம் - விஜேதாச உறுதி",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மையை விரைவாக ஏற்படுத்துவதுடன் அரசியலமைப்பின் 22ஆம் திருத்தத்தை பாராளுமன்றத்துக்கு சமர்ப்பித்து அனுமதித்துக்கொள்வோம் என நீதி அமைச்சர் விஜேதாச ராஜபக்ஷ் தாய்லாந்துக்கான இலங்கை தூதுவரிடம் எடுத்துக்கூடியுள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான தாய்லாந்து தூதுவர் போஜ் ஹான்போல் நீதி, சிறைச்சாலைகள் மற்று்ம் அரசியலமைப்பு மறுசீரமைப்பு அமைச்சர் விஜேதாச ராஜபக்ஷ்வை  இன்று நீதி அமைச்சில் சந்தித்து கலந்துரையாடினார்.",
        "இதன்போது இரண்டு நாடுகளுக்கிடையில் நீண்டகாலமாக இடம்பெற்றுவரும் பொருளாதாரம், அரசியல் மற்றும் கலாசார ஒத்துழைப்புகளை மேலும் அதிகரிப்பது தொடர்பாக கவனம் செலுத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதியின் தலைமையில் இலங்கையில் அரசியல் ஸ்திரதத்தன்மையை ஏற்படுத்துதல் மற்றும் பொருளாதாரத்தை இயல்புநிலைக்கு கொணடுவருவரும் நடவடிக்கை விரைவாக மேற்கொள்ளப்படும்.",
        "அத்துடன் அரசியலமைப்பின் 22ஆம் திருத்தத்தை பாராளுமன்றத்துக்கு சமர்ப்பித்து அனுமதித்துக்கொள்ள நடவடிக்கை எடுத்து வருகின்றோம் என அமைச்சர் தூதுவருக்கு எடுத்துக்கூறினார்.",
        "அத்துடன் 2016ஆம் ஆண்டும் தாய்லாந்தில் இடம்பெற்ற ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் சர்வதேச வெசாக் விழாவின் பிரதான உரையை ஆற்றுவதற்கு தனக்கு சந்தர்ப்பம் கடைத்தது என்றும் 2017இல் அந்த விழா இலங்கையில் இடம்பெற்றபோது, தாய்லாந்து அதற்காக பாரியளவில் ஒத்துழைப்பை வழங்கியதாவும் அமைச்சர் இதன்போது ஞாபகப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "மேலும் பௌத்த உபசம்பதத்தை மீண்டும் இந்த நாட்டுக்கு பெற்றுக்கொடுப்பதற்கு நடவடிக்கை எடுப்பதன் மூலம் பௌத்த மதத்தை மீண்டும் கட்டியெழுப்புவதற்காகவும் தற்காலத்தில் இலங்கையில் பொருளாதாரம் மற்றும் மத கலாசார அபிவிருத்திக்காகவும் தாய்லாந்து பெற்றுத்தரும் ஒத்துழைப்பையும் அமைச்சர் நினைவுபடுத்தினார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் தற்போது ஏற்பட்டிருக்கும் பிரச்சினைக்குரிய நிலைமைகள் நிறைவடைந்து பொருளாதார ஸ்திரத்தன்மை ஏற்படும் என எதிர்பார்க்கின்றோம்.",
        "அதற்காக ராஜதந்திர ரீதியில் முடியுமான உதவிகளை பெற்றுத்தர தயாராக இருக்கின்றோம் என இதன்போது தாய்லாந்துக்கான தூதுவர் குறிப்பிட்டதாக நீதி அமைச்சு விடுத்துள்ள அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நீதியரசர் விஜேதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தாய்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜேதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் சர்வதேச வெசாக் விழா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நீதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}