{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/28/information-on-mps-erased-from-pment-site/",
  "time_ut": 1656430740,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Information on MPs erased from P’ment site?",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Information on MPs erased from P’ment site?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The addresses of all Members of Parliament currently representing the Parliament have been removed from the official website of the Parliament of Sri Lanka.",
        "After an inquiry was made by News 1st, a Spokesman for Parliament stated that these steps were taken to protect the Members of Parliament in view of the current situation in the country.",
        "The official website of the Parliament had previously included the landline and mobile phone numbers of all 225 Members who currently represented the Parliament, as well as the addresses of their residences in Colombo and its suburbs.",
        "Russia, UAE & India to assist; Minister explains way out of fuel crisis"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliament of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Spokesman for Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Members of Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UAE & India",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "P’ment අඩවියෙන් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ තොරතුරු මකාද?",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); දැනට පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන සියලුම පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ ලිපින ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ නිල වෙබ් අඩවියෙන් ඉවත් කර තිබේ.",
        "News 1st කළ විමසීමකදී පාර්ලිමේන්තු ප්‍රකාශකයෙකු සඳහන් කළේ රටේ පවතින තත්ත්වය හමුවේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ ආරක්ෂාව වෙනුවෙන් මෙම පියවර ගත් බවයි.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ නිල වෙබ් අඩවියේ දැනට පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 225 දෙනාගේම ස්ථාවර දුරකථන සහ ජංගම දුරකථන අංක මෙන්ම කොළඹ සහ තදාසන්න ප්‍රදේශවල පිහිටි ඔවුන්ගේ නිවෙස්වල ලිපිනයන් ද මීට පෙර ඇතුළත් කර තිබුණි.",
        "රුසියාව, එක්සත් අරාබි එමීර් රාජ්‍යය සහ ඉන්දියාව සහය වීමට; ඉන්ධන අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩ ඒමේ මග ගැන ඇමති කියයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රකාශක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UAE සහ ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "P’ment தளத்தில் இருந்து எம்.பி.க்கள் பற்றிய தகவல்கள் அழிக்கப்பட்டதா?",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றத்தின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இணையத்தளத்தில் இருந்து தற்போது பாராளுமன்றத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் அனைத்து பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் முகவரிகளும் நீக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "நியூஸ் 1ஸ்டிடம் வினவியபோது, ​​நாட்டின் தற்போதைய நிலைமையை கருத்திற்கொண்டு நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களைப் பாதுகாக்கும் நோக்கில் இந்த நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டதாக நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் பேச்சாளர் ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இணையத்தளத்தில் தற்போது பாராளுமன்றத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் 225 உறுப்பினர்களின் தரைவழி மற்றும் கைபேசி இலக்கங்கள் மற்றும் கொழும்பு மற்றும் அதன் புறநகர் பகுதிகளில் உள்ள அவர்களது வசிப்பிடங்களின் முகவரிகள் ஏற்கனவே உள்ளடக்கப்பட்டிருந்தன.",
        "ரஷ்யா, ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸ் & இந்தியா உதவ; எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடியில் இருந்து மீள்வதற்கான வழிகளை அமைச்சர் விளக்கினார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றத்தின் செய்தி தொடர்பாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UAE & இந்தியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}