{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/16/police-arrest-gang-responsible-for-theft/",
  "time_ut": 1660639500,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Police arrest gang responsible for theft",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Police arrest gang responsible for theft",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka Police arrested five people connected to a series of thefts in the country.",
        "The Weliweriya Police said that two suspects were arrested for the possession of heroin.",
        "Investigations revealed that the suspects were linked to the theft of vehicles, motorcycles, and bicycles across the island.",
        "Based on the information extracted from the suspects, another three men were arrested.",
        "Investigations revealed they are linked to burglaries in Ja-Ela, Boyagama, Kadawatha, Kelaniya, Yakkala, Mahabage, Fort, Peliyagoda, Meegahawatte, Ragama, and Weliweriya.",
        "Three-Wheelers, Ten motorcycles, and 11 bicycles were discovered by Sri Lanka Police.",
        "Sri Lanka Court rejects Scottish tourist request not to deport her"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Weliweriya Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ja-Ela",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kadawatha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelaniya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yakkala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahabage",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fort",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peliyagoda",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Meegahawatte",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ragama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weliweriya",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ten",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Scottish",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සොරකම් කළ කල්ලියක් පොලිසිය අත්අඩංගුවට ගනී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); මෙරට සිදුවූ සොරකම් රැසකට සම්බන්ධ පුද්ගලයින් පස් දෙනෙකු ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "හෙරොයින් ළඟ තබාගෙන සිටි සැකකරුවන් දෙදෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව වැලිවේරිය පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "සැකකරුවන් දිවයින පුරා වාහන, යතුරුපැදි සහ පාපැදි සොරකම් කිරීමට සම්බන්ධ අය බව විමර්ශනවලදී අනාවරණය විය.",
        "සැකකරුවන්ගෙන් ලබාගත් තොරතුරු මත තවත් තිදෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "ජා-ඇල, බෝයගම, කඩවත, කැලණිය, යක්කල, මහබාගේ, කොටුව, පෑලියගොඩ, මීගහවත්ත, රාගම සහ වැලිවේරිය යන ප්‍රදේශවල සිදු වූ සොරකම්වලට මොවුන් සම්බන්ධ බවට විමර්ශනවලදී අනාවරණය වී තිබේ.",
        "ත්‍රිරෝද රථ, යතුරුපැදි දහයක් සහ පාපැදි 11ක් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය විසින් සොයා ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "ඇය පිටුවහල් නොකරන ලෙසට කරන ලද ස්කොට්ලන්ත සංචාරක ඉල්ලීම ශ්‍රී ලංකා අධිකරණය ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වැලිවේරිය පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජා-ඇල",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කඩවත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelaniya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යක්කල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහබාගේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලකොටුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෑලියගොඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීගහවත්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිවේරිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දහය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්කොට්ලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "திருட்டு கும்பலை போலீசார் கைது செய்தனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கையில் இடம்பெற்ற தொடர் திருட்டு சம்பவங்களுடன் தொடர்புடைய 5 பேரை இலங்கை பொலிஸார் கைது செய்துள்ளனர்.",
        "ஹெரோயின் போதைப் பொருளை வைத்திருந்த இரண்டு சந்தேகநபர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக வெலிவேரிய பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "சந்தேக நபர்கள் நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் வாகனங்கள், மோட்டார் சைக்கிள்கள் மற்றும் துவிச்சக்கர வண்டிகள் திருடப்பட்ட சம்பவங்களுடன் தொடர்புடையவர்கள் என விசாரணைகளில் தெரியவந்துள்ளது.",
        "சந்தேக நபர்களிடமிருந்து பெறப்பட்ட தகவலின் அடிப்படையில், மேலும் மூன்று பேர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டனர்.",
        "ஜா-எல, போயாகம, கடவத்தை, களனி, யக்கல, மஹாபாகே, கோட்டை, பேலியகொட, மீகஹவத்தை, ராகம மற்றும் வெலிவேரிய ஆகிய இடங்களில் இடம்பெற்ற திருட்டுச் சம்பவங்களுடன் இவர்கள் தொடர்புபட்டுள்ளதாக விசாரணைகளில் தெரியவந்துள்ளது.",
        "முச்சக்கர வண்டிகள், பத்து மோட்டார் சைக்கிள்கள் மற்றும் 11 துவிச்சக்கர வண்டிகள் இலங்கை பொலிஸாரால் கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "அவரை நாடு கடத்த வேண்டாம் என்ற ஸ்கொட்லாந்து சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் கோரிக்கையை இலங்கை நீதிமன்றம் நிராகரித்துள்ளது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெலிவேரிய பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜா-எல",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடவத்த",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelaniya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யக்கலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹாபாகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேலியகொட",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மீகஹவத்த",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராகம",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிவேரிய",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பத்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்காட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}