{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131048",
  "time_ut": 1657264828,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "டி ராஜேந்தர்,  உருத்திரகுமாரன்  சந்திப்பு !",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "D Rajendar, Uruthirakumaran meet!",
      "author": "Rajeeban",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Prime Minister of the Transnational Government of Tamil Eelam V. Uruthirakumaran met Mr. T. Rajendar, a multi-talented film director and supporter of Tamil Eelam, who was visiting America for medical treatment. He was admitted to the hospital for the past few days and is now recovering and resting.",
        "In addition to expressing his friendship and support for the struggle for justice and political sovereignty of the Elamites, he has led many protests in Tamil Nadu. Prime Minister V. Uruthirakumaran, who is resting after completing advanced treatment, thanked him for his support to the struggle of Elamites. He wished him a long life and return home.",
        "Mr. Lokes, Mr. Karuna, Mr. Kamal, Mr. Kalaiyarasi, members of the Subcommittee of the Transnational Tamil Eelam Government in New York, and Mr. Bala Swaminathan, President of the Council of North American Tamil Associations also participated in this meeting.",
        "D. Rajender, who emotionally expressed his feelings on the Eelam independence struggle, said that he was happy to meet Eelam relations in New York. Mr. Bala Swaminathan, who has taken over as the new president of the North American Council of Tamil Associations, also conveyed his congratulations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Rajendar",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Uruthirakumaran",
          "label": "EVENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Transnational Government of Tamil Eelam V. Uruthirakumaran",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "T. Rajendar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Eelam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "America",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past few days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "V. Uruthirakumaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lokes",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kamal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalaiyarasi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Subcommittee of the Transnational Tamil Eelam Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "New York",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bala Swaminathan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Council of North American Tamil Associations",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "D. Rajender",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eelam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "New York",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bala Swaminathan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the North American Council of Tamil Associations",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඩී රාජේන්දර්, උරුතිරකුමාරන් හමුවෙයි!",
      "author": "රජීබන්",
      "body_lines": [
        "වෛද්‍ය ප්‍රතිකාර සඳහා ඇමරිකාවට ගොස් සිටි දෙමළ ඊළාම් පාර්ශ්වයේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය වී.උරුතිරකුමාරන් දෙමළ ඊළාම් ආධාරකරු බහු දක්ෂ චිත්‍රපට අධ්‍යක්ෂක සහ ඊළාම් ආධාරකරුවෙකු වන ටී.රාජේන්දර් මහතා හමුවිය.",
        "එලමයිට්වරුන්ගේ යුක්තිය සහ දේශපාලන ස්වෛරීභාවය සඳහා වන අරගලයට තම මිත්‍රත්වය සහ සහයෝගය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට අමතරව, ඔහු තමිල්නාඩුවේ විරෝධතා රැසකට නායකත්වය දී ඇත.උසස් ප්‍රතිකාර අවසන් කර විවේක ගනිමින් සිටින අගමැති වී. Elamites අරගලය.ඔහු ඔහුට දීර්ඝායුෂ ප්‍රාර්ථනා කර නැවත නිවසට පැමිණේවා.",
        "ලෝකේස් මහතා, කරුණා මහතා, කමල් මහතා, නිව්යෝර්ක් නුවර පිහිටි අන්තර්ජාතික දෙමළ ඊළාම් රජයේ අනුකමිටු සාමාජිකයින් වන කලයිරසි මහතා සහ උතුරු ඇමෙරිකානු දෙමළ සංගම් කවුන්සිලයේ සභාපති බාල ස්වාමිනාදන් මහතා ද මෙම රැස්වීමට සහභාගී විය. .",
        "ඊළාම් නිදහස් අරගලය පිළිබඳව හැඟීම්බරව තම හැඟීම් ප්‍රකාශ කළ ඩී.රාජේන්දර් නිව්යෝර්ක්හිදී ඊළාම් සබඳතා හමුවීමට ලැබීම සතුටට කරුණක් බව පැවසීය. උතුරු ඇමරිකානු දෙමළ සංගම් කවුන්සිලයේ නව සභාපතිවරයා ලෙස වැඩ භාරගත් බාල ස්වාමිනාදන් මහතා ද සිය සුබපැතුම් පළ කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රාජේන්ද්‍ර",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "උරුතිරකුමාරන්",
          "label": "EVENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ඊළාම් පාර්ශ්ව රජය V. උරුතිරකුමාරන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටී. රාජේන්දර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ඊළම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය දින කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වී උරුතිරකුමාරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝකේස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කරුණා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කලෛයරසි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අන්තර් ජාතික දෙමළ ඊළාම් රජයේ අනුකමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිව්යෝක්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බාල ස්වාමිනාදන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු ඇමරිකානු දෙමළ සංගම් කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩී.රාජේන්දර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළාම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිව්යෝක්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බාල ස්වාමිනාදන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු ඇමරිකානු දෙමළ සංගම් කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டி ராஜேந்தர்,  உருத்திரகுமாரன்  சந்திப்பு !",
      "author": "Rajeeban",
      "body_lines": [
        "மருத்துவ சிகிச்சைக்காக அமெரிக்காவுக்கு வருகை தந்திருந்த தமிழக பன்முக கலைஞரான திரைப்பட இயக்குனர், ஈழத்தமிழர் ஆதரவாளர் திரு.டி.ராஜேந்தர் அவர்களை நாடுகடந்த தமிழீழ அரசாங்கத்தின் பிரதமர் வி.உருத்திரகுமாரன் அவர்கள் சந்தித்து நலம் விசாரித்திருந்தார்.கடந்த சில நாட்களாக மருத்துவமனையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டு சிகிச்சை பெற்றிருந்த நிலையில், தற்போது குணமடைந்து ஒய்வெடுத்து வருகின்றார்.",
        "ஈழத்தமிழர்களின் நீதிக்கும் அரசியல் இறைமைக்குமான போராட்டத்துக்கு தனது தோழமையினையும் உறுதுணையினையும் வெளிப்படுத்தும் வகையில் தொடர்ச்சியாக குரல் கொடுத்து வருவதோடு, பல போராட்டங்களையும் தமிழ்நாட்டில் முன்னெடுத்துள்ளார்.உயர் சிகிச்சை நிறைவுற்று ஓய்வில் இருக்கும் திரு.டி.ராஜேந்தர்களை அவர்களை நலன்விசாரித்த பிரதமர் வி.உருத்திரகுமாரன் அவர்கள், ஈழத்தமிழர் போராட்டத்துக்கான அவரது உறுதுணைக்கு நன்றி தெரிவித்திருந்ததோடு, பூரண குணமடைந்து நிறைந்த ஆரோக்கியத்தோடும், நீண்ட ஆயுளோடும் ஊர் திரும்புவதற்கு வாழ்த்துரைத்தார்.",
        "இச்சந்திப்பில் நியூ யோர்க் வாழ் நாடுகடந்த தமிழீழ அரசாங்கத்தின் உறுதுணைக்குழு உறுப்பினர்கள் திரு.லோகேஸ், திரு.கருணா, திரு.கமல், திரு.கலையரசி ஆகியோர் பங்கெடுத்திருந்ததோடு, வட அமெரிக்க தமிழ்சங்கங்களின் பேரவைத் தலைவர் திரு.பாலா சுவாமிநாதன் அவர்களும் பங்கெடுத்திருந்தார்.",
        "ஈழவிடுதலைப் போராட்டத்தின் மீதான தனது மன உணர்வுகளை உணர்ச்சிபூர்வமாக வெளிப்படுத்திய டி.ராஜேந்தர் அவர்கள், நியூ யோர் மண்ணில் ஈழத்தமிழ் உறவுகளை சந்தித்ததில் மகிழ்ச்சி என தெரிவித்திருந்தார். வட அமெரிக்க தமிழ்சங்கங்களின் பேரவைக்கு புதிதாக தலைவராக பொறுப்பேற்றிருக்கும் திரு.பாலா சுவாமிநாதன் அவர்களுக்கும் தனது வாழ்த்துக்களை தெரிவித்திருந்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ராஜேந்தர்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "உருத்திரகுமாரன்",
          "label": "EVENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நாடுகடந்த தமிழீழ அரசாங்கம் வி. உருத்திரகுமாரன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.ராஜேந்தர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் ஈழம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த சில நாட்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வி.உருத்திரகுமாரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லோக்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருணா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கமல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கலையரசி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாடுகடந்த தமிழீழ அரசாங்கத்தின் உபகுழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நியூயார்க்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாலா சுவாமிநாதன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட அமெரிக்க தமிழ் சங்கங்களின் கவுன்சில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டி.ராஜேந்தர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈழம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நியூயார்க்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாலா சுவாமிநாதன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் சங்கங்களின் வட அமெரிக்க கவுன்சில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}