{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/28/rambukkana-shooting-four-suspects-further-arrested/",
  "time_ut": 1659021360,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Rambukkana shooting: Four suspects further arrested",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Rambukkana shooting: Four suspects further arrested",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The former SSP of Kegalle Police, K.B. Keerthirathne, and three Police officers who were involved in the Rambukkana shooting were further remanded until 10th August.",
        "The case was taken up before the Kegalle Magistrate Wasana Navaratne today (28).",
        "Keerthiratne and the other three police officers who are remanded were not presented to the court today as the court informed that the officials of the Dumbara prison could not bring along the suspects due to lack of fuel, however, they were presented before the Magistrate via video technology.",
        "The Criminal Investigation Department stated that the reports of the equipment sent to the government analyst regarding the incident have not yet been received, however, they have obtained evidence from 125 Police personnel and 120 civilians.",
        "Parliament prorogued with effect from today (28); Next session on 3rd August",
        "NO split in the SLPP, but there is a conspiracy: Kariyawasam"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Rambukkana",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Four",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegalle Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "K.B. Keerthirathne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rambukkana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10th August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wasana Navaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Keerthiratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dumbara",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "125 Police",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "120",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Next",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3rd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රඹුක්කන වෙඩි තැබීම: සැකකරුවන් 4ක් තවදුරටත් අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); කෑගල්ල පොලිසියේ හිටපු ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී කේ.බී. කීර්තිරත්න සහ රඹුක්කන වෙඩි තැබීමේ සිද්ධියට සම්බන්ධ පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් තිදෙනෙකු අගෝස්තු මස 10 වනදා දක්වා යළි රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කෙරුණා.",
        "මෙම නඩුව අද (28) කෑගල්ල මහේස්ත්‍රාත් වාසනා නවරත්න හමුවේ කැදවනු ලැබුවා.",
        "දුම්බර බන්ධනාගාරයේ නිලධාරීන්ට ඉන්ධන නොමැතිකම හේතුවෙන් සැකකරුවන් රැගෙන ඒමට නොහැකි බව අධිකරණය දැනුම් දීම නිසා කීර්තිරත්න ඇතුළු රක්‍ෂිත බන්ධනාගාරගතව සිටින අනෙකුත් පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් තිදෙනා අද අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් නොකළ නමුත් වීඩියෝ මාර්ගයෙන් ඔවුන් මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා හමුවට ඉදිරිපත් කළා. තාක්ෂණය.",
        "සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් රජයේ රස පරීක්ෂකවරයා වෙත යවා ඇති උපකරණවල වාර්තා මෙතෙක් ලැබී නොමැති නමුත් පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් 125 දෙනෙකුගෙන් සහ සිවිල් වැසියන් 120 දෙනෙකුගෙන් සාක්ෂි ලබාගෙන ඇති බවයි අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සඳහන් කළේ.",
        "අද (28) සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කල්දමයි; මීළඟ සැසිය අගෝස්තු 3 වැනිදා",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ බෙදීමක් නැහැ, නමුත් කුමන්ත්‍රණයක් තියෙනවා: කාරියවසම්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රඹුක්කන",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "හතර",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේ.බී. කීර්තිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රඹුක්කන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වාසනා නවරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කීර්තිරත්න ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුම්බර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "125 පොලිසිය",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "120",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரம்புக்கன துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு: நான்கு சந்தேகநபர்கள் மேலும் கைது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); கேகாலை காவல்துறையின் முன்னாள் எஸ்.எஸ்.பி கே.பி. ரம்புக்கனை துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டுச் சம்பவத்துடன் தொடர்புடைய கீர்த்திரத்ன மற்றும் மூன்று பொலிஸ் உத்தியோகத்தர்களும் ஆகஸ்ட் 10 ஆம் திகதி வரை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்த வழக்கு இன்று (28) கேகாலை நீதவான் வாசன நவரத்ன முன்னிலையில் விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக்கொள்ளப்பட்டது.",
        "தும்பரை சிறைச்சாலையில் எரிபொருள் பற்றாக்குறை காரணமாக சந்தேக நபர்களை அழைத்து வர முடியாது என நீதிமன்றம் தெரிவித்ததையடுத்து கீர்த்திரத்ன மற்றும் ஏனைய மூன்று பொலிஸ் உத்தியோகத்தர்கள் இன்று நீதிமன்றில் முன்னிலைப்படுத்தப்படவில்லை எனினும் காணொலி காட்சி மூலம் நீதவான் முன்னிலையில் ஆஜர்படுத்தப்பட்டனர். தொழில்நுட்பம்.",
        "சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் அரசாங்க பகுப்பாய்வாளருக்கு அனுப்பப்பட்ட உபகரணங்களின் அறிக்கைகள் இதுவரை கிடைக்கப்பெறவில்லை எனவும் எனினும் 125 பொலிஸார் மற்றும் 120 சிவிலியன்களிடம் சாட்சியங்களைப் பெற்றுள்ளதாகவும் குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "பாராளுமன்றம் இன்று (28) முதல் அமுலுக்கு வரும் வகையில் ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்டது; அடுத்த அமர்வு ஆகஸ்ட் 3ஆம் தேதி",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவில் பிளவு இல்லை, ஆனால் சதி உள்ளது: காரியவசம்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரம்புக்கன",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "நான்கு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கே.பி. கீர்த்திரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரம்புக்கன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாசன நவரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கீர்த்திரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தும்பரா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "125 போலீஸ்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "120",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்தது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}