{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131112",
  "time_ut": 1657301085,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "சர்வாதிகாரத்தை முறியடித்து  ஜனநாயகத்தை வெற்றி பெறச் செய்யுங்கள் - சஜித்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Defeat Dictatorship and Make Democracy Win - Sajid",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "Take to the streets tomorrow. Leader of Opposition Sajith Premadasa has called upon the people of the country to defeat dictatorship and make democracy win.",
        "A police curfew has been imposed as people prepare for a massive protest against the government tomorrow.",
        "Police have been enforced in Colombo North, Colombo South, Colombo Madhi, Nukegoda, Kelani, Negombo Police Divisions from 9pm tonight until further notice.",
        "In this case, the police curfew is a fraud. It is illegal. Take to the streets tomorrow. Defeat dictatorship and make democracy triumph. Leader of Opposition Sajith Premadasa has called the people that we can do it."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Defeat Dictatorship and Make Democracy Win - Sajid",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo North, Colombo South, Colombo Madhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "tonight",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඒකාධිපතිවාදය පරාජය කර ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය දිනවන්න - සජිඩ්",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "හෙට පාරට බහින්න. ඒකාධිපතිවාදය පරාජය කර ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය දිනවන්නැයි විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා රටේ ජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී.",
        "රජයට එරෙහිව හෙට දිනයේ දැවැන්ත විරෝධතාවයකට ජනතාව සූදානම් වීමත් සමඟ පොලිස් ඇඳිරි නීතිය පනවා තිබේ.",
        "කොළඹ උතුර, කොළඹ දකුණ, කොළඹ මඩි, නුකේගොඩ, කැලණි, මීගමුව යන පොලිස් බල ප්‍රදේශවලට අද රාත්‍රී 9 සිට නැවත දැනුම් දෙන තුරු පොලිසිය ක්‍රියාත්මක කර ඇත.",
        "මෙහිදී පොලිස් ඇඳිරි නීතිය වංචාවකි. එය නීති විරෝධී ය. හෙට පාරට බහින්න. ඒකාධිපතිවාදය පරාජය කර ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය ජයග්‍රහණය කරන්න. විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ජනතාව කැඳවා ඇත්තේ අපට එය කළ හැකි බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඒකාධිපතිවාදය පරාජය කර ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය දිනවන්න - සජිඩ්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂයේ සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ උතුර, කොළඹ දකුණ, කොළඹ මදි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප.ව.9",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂයේ සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சர்வாதிகாரத்தை முறியடித்து  ஜனநாயகத்தை வெற்றி பெறச் செய்யுங்கள் - சஜித்",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாளை வீதிக்கு இறங்குங்கள். சர்வாதிகாரத்தை முறியடித்து  ஜனநாயகத்தை வெற்றி பெறச் செய்யுங்கள் என நாட்டு மக்களுக்கு எதிர்க்கட்சி தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "நாளையதினம் அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிராக மக்கள் பெரும் போராட்டத்திற்கு தயாராகிக்கொண்டிருக்கும் வேளையில் பொலிஸ் ஊரடங்கு அமுல்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "கொழும்பு வடக்கு, கொழும்பு தெற்கு , கொழும்பு மத்தி , நுகேகொட, களனி, நீர்கொழும்பு ஆகிய பொலிஸ் பிரிவுகளில் பொலிஸ் இன்று இரவு 9 மணி முதல் மறு அறிவித்தல் வரை அமுல் படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்நிலையிலேயே பொலிஸ் ஊரடங்குச் சட்டம் ஒரு மோசடி.  இது சட்டவிரோதமானது.  நாளை வீதிக்கு இறங்குங்கள். சர்வாதிகாரத்தை முறியடித்து  ஜனநாயகத்தை வெற்றி பெறச் செய்யுங்கள்.  அது நம்மால் முடியும் என எதிர்க்கட்சி தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச மக்களுக்கு அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சர்வாதிகாரத்தை தோற்கடித்து ஜனநாயகத்தை வெற்றி பெறச் செய்யுங்கள் - சஜித்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்க்கட்சியான சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு வடக்கு, கொழும்பு தெற்கு, கொழும்பு மத்தி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு 9 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்றிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்க்கட்சியான சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}