{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/මැදිරිගිරියට-දින-16කට-පසුව-ලැබුණු-ඉන්ධන-සෞඛ්‍යට-පමණයි/101-616533",
  "time_ut": 1657982434,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මැදිරිගිරියට දින 16කට පසුව ලැබුණු ඉන්ධන සෞඛ්‍යට පමණයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Madrigiri received fuel after 16 days only for health",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "After 16 days, Madrigiriya cooperative fuel station was given only to the employees of the health department.",
        "This situation arose when the filling station workers did not give fuel to any person who had been waiting in the queue for many days.",
        "This gas station finally received fuel on the 30th of June and with the receipt of 6600 liters of fuel today, the health department, with the approval of the district secretary, distributed about 2000 liters of this fuel stock to Madirigiri Base Hospital staff and 500 liters of fuel for essential services and the remaining 4100 liters of fuel in Attanakada. The filling station manager Mr. Saman Kumara told Lankadeepa that it was mentioned in the letter that Alahera, Bakamoona etc. hospitals should be segregated.",
        "According to that, a fuel stock of 2500 rupees was issued for an employee who reports to work by motorcycle and tricycle and for a person who comes by car, fuel was issued in the amount of 7000 rupees.",
        "The people who were staying in Polim said that although it is mandatory to issue fuel to the health staff to come to the hospital for work, if there is no fuel to bring a patient to the hospital, he will even have to die at home.",
        "Due to that, they insisted to provide fuel to all the people.",
        "Polonnaruwa District Health Services Director W.K. Although he tried to negotiate with Mr. WS Kumaramwansa, all those opportunities failed."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Madrigiri",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "16 days",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "16 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Madrigiriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "many days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 30th of June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 2000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Madirigiri Base Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4100",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Attanakada",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Kumara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lankadeepa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alahera",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bakamoona",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Polonnaruwa District Health Services",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "W.K.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "WS Kumaramwansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මැදිරිගිරියට දින 16කට පසුව ලැබුණු ඉන්ධන සෞඛ්‍යට පමණයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මැදිරිගිරිය සමූපකාර ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හලට දින 16 පසු පැමිණි ඉන්ධන තොගය සෞඛය අංශයේ සේවකයන්ට පමණක් ලබා දීමට කටයුතු කිරීමත් සමග දැඩි උණුසුම්කාරී තත්ත්වයක් ඇති විය.",
        "දින ගණනාවක් පෝලිම්හි රැදී සිටි කිසිදු පුද්ගලයකුට  ඉන්ධන ලබා නොදීමට පිරවුම්හල් සේවකයන් කටයුතු කිරීමත් සමග මෙම තත්ත්වය ඇති විය.",
        "මෙම ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හලට පසුගිය ජූනි මස 30වන දින  අවසාන වශයෙන් ඉන්ධන ලැබී අතර අද ඉන්ධන ලීටර 6600 ලැබීමත් සමග සෞඛ්‍ය අංශය විසින් දිස්ත්‍රික් ලේකම්වයාගේ අනුමැතියෙන් මෙම ඉන්ධන තොගයෙන් ලීටර 2000 පමණ ප්‍රමාණයක් මැදිරිගිරිය මූලික රෝහල් කාර්යය මණ්ඩලයටද අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සේවා සදහා ඉන්ධන ලීටර 500 ද ඉතිරි ඉන්ධන 4100 ප්‍රමාණය  අත්තනකඩවල, ඇලහැර, බකමූණ ආදී රෝහල් අදහා වෙන් කරන ලෙසට ඒම ලිපියේ සදහන් කර තිබූ බව ඉන්ධ පිරවුම්හල් කළමණාකරු සමන් කුමාර මහතා ලංකාදීපයට කීය.",
        "ඒ් අනුව මැදිරිගිරිය මූලික රෝහලේ කාර්යය මණ්ඩලයේ යතුරුපැදියෙන් සහ ත්‍රීරෝදරථයෙන් සේවයට වාර්ථා කරන සේවකයකු සදහා රුපියල් 2500 ඉන්ධන තොගයක්ද මෝටර් රථයකින් පැමිණෙන අයකු සදහා රුපියල් 7000 වශයෙන් ඉන්ධන  නිකුත් කරනු ලැබීය.",
        "පොලිම්හි රැදී සිටි පිරිස කියා සිටියේ රෝහලේ වැඩ කටයුතු සදහා පැමිණීමට සෞඛ්‍ය කාර්යය මණ්ඩලයට ඉන්ධන නිකුත් කිරීම අනිවාර්යය වුවද රෝගියකු රෝහල වෙත රැගෙන ඒ්මට ඉන්ධන නොමැති වුවහොත් ඔහු නිවසේදීම මිය යාමට පවා සිදු වන බවයි.",
        "ඒ් හේතුවෙන් සියළු පුද්ගලයන්ට ඉන්ධන ලබා දීම සිදු කරන ලෙස ඔවුන් බලකර සිටියහ.",
        "අප මේ පිළීබදව විමසීමට පොලොන්නරුව දිස්ත්‍රීක් සෞඛ්‍ය සේවා අධ්‍යක්ෂ ඩබ්ලිව්.කේ. ඩබ්ලිව්.ඒස් කුමාරවංශ මහතා සම්න්ධ කර ගැනීමට උත්සහ දැරුවද ඒ් සියළු අවස්ථාවන් අසාර්ථක විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මද්රිගිරිය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "දින 16 යි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දින 16 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මද්රිගිරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බොහෝ දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජුනි 30 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2000 පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැදිරිගිරි මූලික රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4100",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අත්තනකඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් කුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකාදීප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලහැර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බකමූන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොළොන්නරුව දිස්ත්‍රික් සෞඛ්‍ය සේවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩබ්ලිව්.කේ.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩබ්ලිව් එස් කුමාරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மத்ரிகிரி 16 நாட்களுக்கு பிறகு உடல் நலத்திற்காக மட்டுமே எரிபொருள் கிடைத்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "16 நாட்களுக்குப் பிறகு, மத்ரிகிரிய கூட்டுறவு எரிபொருள் நிலையம் சுகாதாரத் திணைக்கள ஊழியர்களுக்கு மட்டுமே வழங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "பல நாட்களாக வரிசையில் காத்திருந்த யாருக்கும் எரிபொருள் நிரப்பும் நிலைய பணியாளர்கள் எரிபொருள் கொடுக்காததால் இந்த நிலை ஏற்பட்டது.",
        "இந்த எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையத்திற்கு கடந்த ஜூன் மாதம் 30ஆம் திகதி எரிபொருள் கிடைக்கப்பெற்றதுடன், இன்று 6600 லீற்றர் எரிபொருள் கிடைக்கப்பெற்றதையடுத்து, சுகாதாரத் திணைக்களம், மாவட்டச் செயலாளரின் ஒப்புதலுடன், சுமார் 2000 லீற்றர் இந்த எரிபொருளை, மாதிரிகிரி ஆதார வைத்தியசாலை ஊழியர்களுக்கும், 500 லீற்றர்களுக்கும் விநியோகித்துள்ளது. அத்தியாவசிய சேவைகளுக்கான எரிபொருள் மற்றும் எஞ்சிய 4100 லீற்றர் எரிபொருள் அத்தனகடவில் உள்ளது.அலஹெர, பகமூன போன்ற வைத்தியசாலைகளை தனிமைப்படுத்துமாறு கடிதத்தில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளதாக எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலைய முகாமையாளர் திரு.சமன் குமார லங்காதீபவிடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அதன்படி மோட்டார் சைக்கிள் மற்றும் முச்சக்கரவண்டியில் பணிக்கு வரும் ஊழியருக்கு 2500 ரூபா எரிபொருள் கையிருப்பு வழங்கப்பட்டதுடன் காரில் வரும் ஒருவருக்கு 7000 ரூபா எரிபொருள் வழங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "பணி நிமித்தமாக வைத்தியசாலைக்கு வருவதற்கு சுகாதார ஊழியர்களுக்கு எரிபொருள் வழங்குவது கட்டாயமாக்கப்பட்டுள்ள போதிலும், நோயாளியை வைத்தியசாலைக்கு கொண்டு வருவதற்கு எரிபொருள் இல்லாவிட்டால் வீட்டிலேயே இறக்க நேரிடும் என பொலிமில் தங்கியிருந்த மக்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "அதன் காரணமாக அனைத்து மக்களுக்கும் எரிபொருள் வழங்க வலியுறுத்தினர்.",
        "பொலன்னறுவை மாவட்ட சுகாதார சேவைகள் பணிப்பாளர் டபிள்யூ.கே. அவர் திரு.டபிள்யூ.எஸ்.குமாரமவன்சவுடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்த முயற்சித்த போதிலும், அந்த வாய்ப்புகள் அனைத்தும் தோல்வியடைந்தன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மாத்ரிகிரி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "16 நாட்கள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "16 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்ரிகிரியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பல நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 30 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 2000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதிரிகிரி அடிப்படை மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4100",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அத்தனகட",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் குமார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்காதீப",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலஹெரா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பகமூனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொலன்னறுவை மாவட்ட சுகாதார சேவைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டபிள்யூ.கே.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டபிள்யூ.எஸ்.குமாரம்வன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}