{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ජැක්සන්ගේ-වාහනයේ-ගැටුණු-අලියා-සොයා-මෙහෙයුමක්/1-615838",
  "time_ut": 1656916342,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ජැක්සන්ගේ වාහනයේ ගැටුණු අලියා සොයා මෙහෙයුමක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "An operation to find the elephant that crashed into Jackson's vehicle",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A senior officer of the Anuradhapura Assistant Director's Office of the Department of Wildlife Conservation said that two teams have been deployed to search for the wild elephant that collided with the cab in which veteran actor Jackson Anthony was traveling.",
        "He also said that it is believed that the wild elephant may have been seriously injured as the wild elephant landed twice on the bonnet of the vehicle when it collided with the cab in which three people including Mr. Jackson Anthony were traveling on the night of the 2nd at around 10.30 p.m. near the Seventh Post in Talawa Moragoda.",
        "Accordingly, two teams consisting of officers working in Anuradhapura and Talawa offices are engaged in a search operation to search for this wild elephant in Ulukkulam and Wiraveva areas of Moragoda area.",
        "The senior officer of the Anuradhapura Assistant Director's Office of the Wildlife Conservation Department added that no information has been received so far regarding the elephant that collided with the vehicle."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Jackson",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Office of the Department of Wildlife Conservation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jackson Anthony",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jackson Anthony",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the night of the 2nd",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "around 10.30 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Seventh Post",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Talawa Moragoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Talawa",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ulukkulam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wiraveva",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Office of the Wildlife Conservation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජැක්සන්ගේ වාහනයේ ගැටුණු අලියා සොයා මෙහෙයුමක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ප්‍රවීන රංගන ශිල්පි ජැක්සන් ඇන්තනි මහතා  ගමන්ගත් කැබ් රථයේ ගැටුන වල් අලියා සෙවිම සදහා කණ්ඩායම් දෙකක් යොදවා ඇතැයි වනජීවි සංරක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ අනුරාධපුර සහකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂක කාර්යාලයේ උසස් නිලධාරියෙකු පැවසිය.",
        "තලාව මොරගොඩ හතේ කණුව ආසන්නයේදි පසුගිය 02 වැනි දින රාත්‍රි 10.30 ට පමණ ජැක්සන් ඇන්තනි මහතා ඇතුළු තිදෙනකු ගමන් ගනිමින් සිටි කැබ් රථයේ ගැටිමෙන් මෙම වල් අලියා වාහනයේ බොනට්ටුව මත දෙවරක්ම පතිතවිම නිසා වන අලියාද බරපතල තුවාල ලබන්නට ඇතැයි විශ්වාශ කරන බවද හෙතෙම පැවසිය.",
        "ඒ අනුව මෙම වන අලියා මොරගොඩ ප්‍රදේශයේ උලුක්කුලම,විරවැව ප්‍රදේශයේ සොයා බැලිම සදහා අනුරාධපුර හා තලාව කාර්යාලවල සේවයේ නිරත නිලධාරින් ගෙන් සමන්විත කණ්ඩායම් දෙකක් සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමක නිරතව සිටිති.",
        "වාහනයේ ගැටුන අලියා සම්බන්ධයෙන් මෙතෙක් තොරතුරක් ලැබි නොමැති බවද වනජීවි සංරක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ අනුරාධපුර සහකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂක කාර්යාලයේ එම උසස් නිලධාරියා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසිය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජැක්සන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වනජීවී සංරක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැක්සන් ඇන්තනි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැක්සන් ඇන්තනි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 වැනිදා රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.30 ට පමණ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "හත්වන තනතුර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලාව මොරගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලාව",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "උළුක්කුලම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විරවේවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වනජීවී සංරක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜாக்சனின் வாகனத்தில் மோதிய யானையைக் கண்டுபிடிக்கும் ஆபரேஷன்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மூத்த நடிகர் ஜாக்சன் அந்தோணி பயணித்த கெப் வண்டியில் மோதிய காட்டு யானையை தேடும் பணியில் இரு குழுக்கள் ஈடுபடுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாக வனஜீவராசிகள் பாதுகாப்பு திணைக்களத்தின் அனுராதபுரம் உதவி பணிப்பாளர் அலுவலக சிரேஷ்ட அதிகாரி ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அன்றைய தினம் இரவு திரு.ஜாக்சன் அந்தோணி உட்பட மூவர் பயணித்த கெப் வண்டியின் மீது காட்டு யானை மோதியதில் இரண்டு தடவைகள் வாகனத்தின் பானட்டில் இறங்கியதால் காட்டு யானைக்கு பலத்த காயம் ஏற்பட்டிருக்கலாம் என நம்பப்படுவதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார். 2ஆம் திகதி இரவு 10.30 மணியளவில் தலாவ மொரகொட ஏழாவது தபால் நிலையத்திற்கு அருகில்.",
        "அதன்படி, மொரகொட பிரதேசத்தின் உளுக்குளம் மற்றும் வைரவெவ பிரதேசங்களில் இந்த காட்டு யானையை தேடும் பணியில் அனுராதபுரம் மற்றும் தலாவ அலுவலகங்களில் கடமையாற்றும் அதிகாரிகள் அடங்கிய இரண்டு குழுக்கள் தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "வாகனத்துடன் மோதிய யானை தொடர்பில் இதுவரை எவ்வித தகவல்களும் கிடைக்கப்பெறவில்லை என வனஜீவராசிகள் பாதுகாப்பு திணைக்களத்தின் அனுராதபுரம் உதவிப் பணிப்பாளர் அலுவலக சிரேஷ்ட அதிகாரி மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜாக்சன்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வனவிலங்கு பாதுகாப்பு துறை அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்சன் ஆண்டனி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்சன் ஆண்டனி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2ம் தேதி இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 10.30 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழாவது இடுகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலவா மொரகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைவா",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "உளுக்குளம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வைரவேவா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வனவிலங்கு பாதுகாப்பு துறை அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}