{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130567",
  "time_ut": 1656671343,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "நெருக்கடிக்கு முகங்கொடுத்திருக்கும் இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு உதவுவோம் - அமெரிக்க இராஜாங்க செயலாளர்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Let's help the people of Sri Lanka in crisis - US Secretary of State",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "A meeting between the Sri Lankan Ambassador to the US, Mahinda Samarasinghe, and Secretary of the US Department of State, Anne J. Blinken, took place two weeks ago, during which Anne Blinken reaffirmed her commitment to help the people of Sri Lanka, who are facing a massive crisis.",
        "Now that the country is facing a massive economic crisis, the United States has been providing aid to India in recent times, and high-level meetings with the United States have also taken place.",
        "In particular, the Sri Lankan ambassador to the United States, Mahinda Samarasinghe, had met the American President Joe Biden a few weeks ago and briefed him on the current situation in the country.",
        "In conjunction with that, a meeting with the US Secretary of State, Henry J.",
        "Meanwhile, a group consisting of high-level representatives of the US Department of State and the US Treasury visited Sri Lanka last week and held discussions with various parties regarding the country's economic situation and the assistance needed to recover from this crisis.",
        "In this case, it is noteworthy that Sri Lankan Ambassador Mahinda Samarasinghe, who met US Secretary of State Anne J. Blinken and his partner and White House Cabinet Secretary Evan Ryan two weeks ago, briefed them on the country's situation."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "State",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Samarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the US Department of State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anne J. Blinken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two weeks ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anne Blinken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "American",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "a few weeks ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Henry J.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the US Department of State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the US Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Samarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anne J. Blinken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "White House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Evan Ryan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two weeks ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අර්බුදකාරී ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය ජනතාවට පිහිට වෙමු - ඇමෙරිකානු රාජ්‍ය ලේකම්",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඇමෙරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති මහින්ද සමරසිංහ මහතා සහ ඇමෙරිකානු රාජ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ලේකම් ඈන් ජේ බ්ලින්කන් මහත්මිය අතර හමුවක් සති දෙකකට පෙර සිදු වූ අතර, එහිදී ඈන් බ්ලින්කන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවට උපකාර කිරීමට ඇති කැපවීම යළිත් තහවුරු කළාය. දැවැන්ත අර්බුදයකට මුහුණ දී සිටිති.",
        "මේ වන විට රට දැවැන්ත ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකට මුහුණ දී සිටින බැවින් මෑත කාලයේ ඇමරිකාව ඉන්දියාවට ආධාර ලබා දෙමින් සිටින අතර ඇමෙරිකාව සමඟ ඉහළ පෙළේ සාකච්ඡා ද පැවැත්විණි.",
        "විශේෂයෙන්ම අමෙරිකාවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති මහින්ද සමරසිංහ මහතා මීට සති කිහිපයකට පෙර ඇමරිකානු ජනාධිපති ජෝ බයිඩන් හමුවී රටේ වත්මන් තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව දැනුවත් කර තිබේ.",
        "ඊට සමගාමීව ඇමෙරිකානු රාජ්‍ය ලේකම් හෙන්රි ජේ.",
        "මේ අතර ඇමෙරිකානු රාජ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ සහ ඇමෙරිකානු භාණ්ඩාගාරයේ ඉහළ පෙළේ නියෝජිතයන්ගෙන් සමන්විත කණ්ඩායමක් පසුගිය සතියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණ රටේ ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය සහ මෙම අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩ ඒමට අවශ්‍ය සහය පිළිබඳව විවිධ පාර්ශ්ව සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කළහ.",
        "මෙම නඩුවේදී, සති දෙකකට පෙර ඇමෙරිකානු රාජ්‍ය ලේකම් ඈන් ජේ බ්ලින්කන් සහ ඔහුගේ සහකාරිය සහ ධවල මන්දිර කැබිනට් ලේකම් ඉවන් රයන් හමුවූ ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති මහින්ද සමරසිංහ රටේ තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව ඔවුන් දැනුවත් කිරීම විශේෂත්වයකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "රජයේ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද සමරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඈන් ජේ බ්ලින්කන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති දෙකකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඈන් බ්ලින්කන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති කිහිපයකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙන්රි ජේ.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද භාණ්ඩාගාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද සමරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඈන් ජේ බ්ලින්කන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධවල මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉවාන් රයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති දෙකකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நெருக்கடிக்கு முகங்கொடுத்திருக்கும் இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு உதவுவோம் - அமெரிக்க இராஜாங்க செயலாளர்",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "அமெரிக்காவிற்கான இலங்கைத்தூதுவர் மஹிந்த சமரசிங்க மற்றும் அமெரிக்க இராஜாங்கத்திணைக்களத்தின் செயலாளர் அன்ரனி ஜே பிளின்கென் ஆகியோருக்கு இடையிலான சந்திப்பொன்று இருவாரங்களுக்கு முன்னர் இடம்பெற்றிருப்பதுடன், இதன்போது பாரிய நெருக்கடிக்கு முகங்கொடுத்திருக்கும் இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு உதவுவதற்கான தமது கடப்பாட்டை அன்ரனி பிளின்கென் மீளுறுதிப்படுத்தியுள்ளார்.",
        "தற்போது நாடு பாரிய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு முகங்கொடுத்திருக்கும் நிலையில் அண்மையகாலங்களில் இந்தியாவிற்கு அடுத்ததாக அமெரிக்கா உதவிகளை வழங்கிவருவதுடன், அமெரிக்காவுடனான உயர்மட்ட சந்திப்புக்களும் இடம்பெற்றிருக்கின்றன.",
        "குறிப்பாக அமெரிக்காவிற்கான இலங்கைத்தூதுவர் மஹிந்த சமரசிங்க சில வாரங்களுக்கு முன்னர் அமெரிக்க ஜனாதிபதி ஜோ பைடனைச் சந்தித்திருந்ததுடன் நாட்டின் தற்போதைய நிலைவரம் குறித்து அவரிடம் விளக்கமளித்திருந்தார்.",
        "அதனோடு இணைந்ததாகவே அமெரிக்க இராஜாங்க செயலாளர் அன்ரனி ஜே பிளிங்கனுடனான சந்திப்பும் இடம்பெற்றிருக்கின்றது.",
        "அதேவேளை அமெரிக்க இராஜாங்கத்திணைக்களம் மற்றும் அமெரிக்கத்திறைசேரி ஆகியவற்றின் உயர்மட்டப்பிரதிநிதிகள் அடங்கிய குழு கடந்த வாரம் இலங்கைக்கு வருகைதந்திருந்ததுடன், நாட்டின் பொருளாதார நிலைவரம் மற்றும் இந்நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து மீட்சியடைவதற்கு அவசியமான உதவிகள் என்பன தொடர்பில் பல்வேறு தரப்பினருடனும் கலந்துரையாடல்களை முன்னெடுத்தனர்.",
        "இந்நிலையில் அமெரிக்க இராஜாங்க செயலாளர் அன்ரனி ஜே பிளின்கென் மற்றும் அவரது பாரியாரும் வெள்ளை மாளிகை அமைச்சரவை செயலாளருமான எவான் ரயன் ஆகியோரை இருவாரங்களுக்கு முன்னர் சந்தித்த இலங்கைத்தூதுவர் மஹிந்த சமரசிங்க அவர்களிடம் நாட்டின் நிலைவரம் தொடர்பில் விளக்கமளித்துள்ளமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "நிலை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த சமரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க வெளியுறவுத்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அன்னே ஜே. பிளிங்கன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு வாரங்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அன்னே பிளிங்கன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சில வாரங்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹென்றி ஜே.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க வெளியுறவுத்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த சமரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அன்னே ஜே. பிளிங்கன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளை மாளிகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இவான் ரியான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு வாரங்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}