{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132347",
  "time_ut": 1658913447,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "சமந்தா பவர் இந்தியாவில் - இலங்கை நிலவரம் குறித்தும் பேச்சுவார்த்தை",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Samantha Power also discussed the India-Sri Lanka situation",
      "author": "Rajeeban",
      "body_lines": [
        "USAID Chief Executive Samantha Power, who is on a visit to India, has also held discussions on the situation in Sri Lanka.",
        "Samantha Power visited India from 25th to 27th.",
        "International issues such as Sri Lanka's crisis and food crisis, climate change, are reported to have featured prominently in Samantha Power's talks in India.",
        "On the 26th, Samantha Power held talks with representatives of civil society organizations on several issues including freedom of expression and protection of the rights of minority groups.",
        "He expressed America's commitment to continue working with civil society to advance human rights and fundamental rights.",
        "Samantha Pawar also met the Indian External Affairs Minister and External Affairs Secretary and held talks.",
        "Saying that the purpose of this meeting is to reaffirm that India and the United States are strategic partners and collaborators in many development issues, USAIT's response speaker Sejal Pulivartiri said that they discussed the region, India's leadership, and America's assistance at a time when Sri Lanka is facing an economic crisis."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Samantha Power",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "the India-Sri Lanka",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "USAID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samantha Power",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samantha Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25th to 27th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samantha Power's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samantha Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "America",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samantha Pawar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "External Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USAIT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sejal Pulivartiri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "America",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සමන්තා පවර් ඉන්දීය ශ්‍රී ලංකා තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව ද සාකච්ඡා කළාය",
      "author": "රජීබන්",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දියාවේ සංචාරයක නිරත USAID ප්‍රධාන විධායක සමන්තා පවර් මහත්මිය ද ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කර තිබේ.",
        "සමන්තා පවර් 25 සිට 27 දක්වා ඉන්දියාවේ සංචාරය කළා.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අර්බුද සහ ආහාර අර්බුදය, දේශගුණික විපර්යාස වැනි ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රශ්න සමන්තා පවර්ගේ ඉන්දියාවේ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවලදී ප්‍රමුඛස්ථානයක් ගත් බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "අදහස් ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමේ නිදහස සහ සුළු ජන කණ්ඩායම්වල අයිතිවාසිකම් සුරැකීම ඇතුළු කරුණු කිහිපයක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් සමන්තා පවර් මහත්මිය සිවිල් සංවිධාන නියෝජිතයන් සමඟ පසුගිය 26 වැනිදා සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වූවාය.",
        "මානව හිමිකම් සහ මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාම සඳහා සිවිල් සමාජය සමඟ අඛණ්ඩව කටයුතු කිරීමට ඇමරිකාවේ කැපවීම ඔහු ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "සමන්ත පවාර් ඉන්දීය විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරයා සහ විදේශ කටයුතු ලේකම්වරයා ද හමුවී සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වීය.",
        "ඉන්දියාව සහ එක්සත් ජනපදය සංවර්ධන ගැටළු රැසක උපායමාර්ගික හවුල්කරුවන් සහ සහයෝගිතාකරුවන් බව යළිත් තහවුරු කිරීම මෙම හමුවෙහි අරමුණ බව පවසන USAIT හි ප්‍රතිචාර කථිකාචාර්ය සේජල් පුලිවර්තිරි පැවසුවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පවතින අවස්ථාවක කලාපය, ඉන්දියාවේ නායකත්වය සහ ඇමරිකාවේ සහාය පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කළ බවයි. ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකට මුහුණ දී සිටී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සමන්තා පවර්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව-ශ්‍රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "USAID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන්තා පවර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමන්තා පවර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 සිට 27 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන්තා පවර්ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන්තා පවර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමන්ත පවර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USAIT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සේජල් පුලිවර්තිරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சமந்தா பவர் இந்தியாவில் - இலங்கை நிலவரம் குறித்தும் பேச்சுவார்த்தை",
      "author": "Rajeeban",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்தியாவிற்கு விஜயம் மேற்கொண்டுள்ள யுஎஸ்எயிட்டின் தலைமை நிர்வாகி சமந்தா பவர் இலங்கை நிலவரம் குறித்தும் பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை மேற்கொண்டுள்ளார்.",
        "சமந்தா பவர் 25 முதல்  27 ம் திகதி வரை இந்தியாவிற்கு விஜயம் மேற்கொண்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் நெருக்கடி மற்றும் உணவு நெருக்கடி காலநிலை மாற்றம் போன்ற சர்வதேச விவகாரங்கள் இந்தியாவில் சமந்தா பவர் மேற்கொண்ட பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளில் முக்கியமாக இடம்பெற்றிருந்தன என தகவல்கள் வெளியாகியுள்ளன.",
        "26ம் திகதி சமந்தா பவர் சிவில் சமூக அமைப்புகளின் பிரதிநிதிகளுடன் கருத்துசுதந்திரம் சிறுபான்மை குழுக்களின் உரிமைகளை பாதுகாப்பது உட்பட பல விடயங்கள்குறித்து பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை மேற்கொண்டுள்ளார்.",
        "மனித உரிமைகள் மற்றும் அடிப்படை உரிமைகளை முன்னேற்றுவதற்காக சிவில் சமூகத்துடன் தொடர்ந்தும் இணைந்து பணியாற்றுவது குறித்த அமெரிக்காவின் அர்ப்பணிப்பை அவர் வெளியிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இந்திய வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் மற்றும் வெளிவிவகார செயலாளரையும் சமந்தா பவர் சந்தித்து பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை மேற்கொண்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இந்தியாவும் அமெரிக்காவும் மூலோபாய சகாக்கள் மற்றும் பல அபிவிருத்தி விவகாரங்களில் ஒத்துழைப்பாளர்கள் என்பதை மீள உறுதி செய்வதே இந்த  சந்திப்பின் நோக்கம்  என தெரிவித்துள்ள யுஎஸ்எயிட்டின் பதில் பேச்சாளர் செஜால் புலிவர்ட்டிரி அவர்கள் பிராந்தியம் குறித்தும் இந்தியாவின் தலைமைத்துவம் குறித்தும் இலங்கை பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி யை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ள தருணத்தில் அமெரிக்காவின் உதவி குறித்தும் ஆராய்ந்தனர் என குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சமந்தா பவர்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா-இலங்கை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "USAID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமந்தா பவர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமந்தா பவர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 முதல் 27 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமந்தா பவர் தான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமந்தா பவர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமந்தா பவார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு விவகாரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USAIT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சேஜல் புலிவர்திரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}