{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/25/amber-alert-issued-for-strong-winds-rough-seas-3/",
  "time_ut": 1656143940,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Amber alert issued for strong winds & rough seas",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Amber alert issued for strong winds & rough seas",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Meteorology Department has issued an amber alert for strong winds and rough seas, citing that wind speed can increase up to (55-60) kmph in the sea areas off the coast extending from Kankasanturai to Puttalam and Matara to Pottuvil via Hambantota.",
        "Accordingly, Wind speed can increase up to 50 kmph in the sea areas off the coast extending from Puttalam to Galle via Colombo, while swell waves (about 2.0 – 2.5) may increase in the above-mentioned sea areas and these sea areas will be rough.",
        "Naval and fishing communities have been requested to remain vigilant in this regard, and to remain attentive to future forecasts issued by the Department of Meteorology in this regard.",
        "Prof. Rangita De Silva De Alwis elected as SL representative for CEDAW",
        "Six people get addicted to heroin daily: National Authority on Tobacco and Alcohol"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Meteorology Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "55-60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kankasanturai",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 2.0",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rangita De Silva De Alwis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEDAW",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Authority on Tobacco and Alcohol",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තද සුළං සහ රළු මුහුද සඳහා ඇම්බර් අනතුරු ඇඟවීම් නිකුත් කර ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); කන්කසන්තුරේ සිට පුත්තලම දක්වා සහ මාතර සිට හම්බන්තොට හරහා පොතුවිල් දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල සුළගේ වේගය පැයට කිලෝමීටර් (55-60) දක්වා ඉහළ යා හැකි බව සඳහන් කරමින් කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව තද සුළං සහ රළු මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ පිළිබඳ ඇම්බර් අනතුරු ඇඟවීමක් නිකුත් කර ඇත.",
        "ඒ අනුව, පුත්තලම සිට කොළඹ හරහා ගාල්ල දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල සුළගේ වේගය පැයට කිලෝමීටර 50 දක්වා වැඩි විය හැකි අතර, ඉහත සඳහන් කළ මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල රළ (2.0 - 2.5 පමණ) වැඩි විය හැකි අතර එම මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ රළු වනු ඇත. .",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමසිලිමත්ව සිටින ලෙසත්, කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් නිකුත් කරන අනාගත අනාවැකි පිළිබඳව අවධානයෙන් සිටින ලෙසත් නාවික සහ ධීවර ප්‍රජාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා ඇත.",
        "CEDAW හි ශ්‍රී ලංකා නියෝජිතයා ලෙස මහාචාර්ය රංගිත ද සිල්වා ද අල්විස් තේරී පත් විය",
        "දිනකට හය දෙනෙක් හෙරොයින් වලට ඇබ්බැහි වෙති: දුම්කොළ සහ මධ්‍යසාර පිළිබඳ ජාතික අධිකාරිය"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "55-60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කන්කසන්තුරේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.0 පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රංගිත ද සිල්වා ද අල්විස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.එල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEDAW",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුම්කොළ සහ මධ්‍යසාර පිළිබඳ ජාතික අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பலத்த காற்று மற்றும் கொந்தளிப்பான கடல்களுக்கு ஆம்பர் எச்சரிக்கை விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் காங்கேசன்துறையிலிருந்து புத்தளம் மற்றும் மாத்தறை முதல் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை ஊடாக பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளில் காற்றின் வேகமானது மணிக்கு (55-60) கிலோமீற்றர் வரை அதிகரித்து வீசக்கூடும் என சுட்டிக்காட்டி, பலத்த காற்று மற்றும் கொந்தளிப்பான கடல்களுக்கான அம்பர் எச்சரிக்கையை விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "அதன்படி, புத்தளத்திலிருந்து கொழும்பு ஊடாக காலி வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளில் காற்றின் வேகம் மணிக்கு 50 கிலோமீற்றர் வரை அதிகரிக்கலாம். அதேவேளை மேற்கூறிய கடற்பரப்புகளில் அலைகள் (சுமார் 2.0 – 2.5) அதிகரிக்கலாம் மேலும் இந்த கடல் பகுதிகள் கொந்தளிப்பாக இருக்கும். .",
        "கடற்படை மற்றும் மீனவ சமூகங்கள் இவ்விடயத்தில் விழிப்புடன் இருக்குமாறும், இது தொடர்பாக வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் வெளியிடும் எதிர்கால முன்னறிவிப்புகளை கவனித்துக்கொள்ளும்படியும்  கேட்டுக்கொள்ளப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "CEDAW இன் இலங்கைப் பிரதிநிதியாக பேராசிரியர் ரங்கிதா டி சில்வா டி அல்விஸ் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார்",
        "தினமும் ஆறு பேர் ஹெராயினுக்கு அடிமையாகிறார்கள்: புகையிலை மற்றும் மதுபானம் மீதான தேசிய ஆணையம்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "55-60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காங்கசந்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 50 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 2.0",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வானிலை ஆய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரங்கிதா டி சில்வா டி அல்விஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEDAW",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புகையிலை மற்றும் மதுபானம் மீதான தேசிய ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}