{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/බදියුදීන්ගේ-පෙත්සම-ජනවාරියට-කල්-යයි/1-619345",
  "time_ut": 1662380106,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "බදියුදීන්ගේ පෙත්සම ජනවාරියට කල් යයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Badiuddin's petition is adjourned to January",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Supreme Court has fixed today (05) to consider the appeal filed by Mr. Rishad Badiuddin from the Court of Appeal to revoke the order given by the Court of Appeal to re-cultivate the illegally cleared forests of Wilpattu at his own expense.",
        "This appeal was considered before a Supreme Court bench consisting of Mr. Gamini Amarasekara, Achala Vengappuli and Mr. Arjuna Obeysekera.",
        "Mr. Arjuna Obeysekera, who is a member of this three-member Supreme Court bench, has also participated in the appeal court hearing of this case, so it is proper to refer this appeal petition to another Supreme Court bench for consideration.",
        "The Environmental Justice Center had filed a writ petition against the former minister Mr. Rishad Badiuddin in the Court of Appeal, alleging that he illegally cleared the forests and built villages in the vicinity of Wilpattu forest. Dissatisfied with that order, the former minister filed an appeal petition before the Supreme Court requesting that the relevant order be annulled."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Badiuddin",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "January",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rishad Badiuddin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Court of Appeal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Court of Appeal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wilpattu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gamini Amarasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Achala Vengappuli",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arjuna Obeysekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Arjuna Obeysekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "another Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Environmental Justice Center",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rishad Badiuddin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Court of Appeal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wilpattu",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බදියුදීන්ගේ පෙත්සම ජනවාරියට කල් යයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "නිතීවිරෝධී අන්දමින් එළි පෙහෙළි කළ විල්පත්තු ආශ්‍රිත කැලෑ යළි තම පෞද්ගලික වියදමින් වගාකිරීමට හිටපු අමාත්‍ය රිෂාඩ් බදියුදීන් මහතාට අභියාචනාධිකරණයෙන් ලබාදී තිබූ තින්දුව බලරහිත කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා ඒ මහතා විසින් ගොනුකරනු ලැබ තිබූ අභියාචනය ලබන ජනවාරි මස 19 වැනිදා සළකා බැලිමට ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය අද (05) දින නියම කළේය.",
        "ගාමිණී අමරසේකර, අචල වෙන්ගප්පුලි සහ අර්ජුන ඔබේසේකර යන මහත්වරුන්ගෙන් සමන්විත ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ විනිසුරු මඩුල්ලක් හමුවේ මෙම අභියාචනය සලකා බැලිණී.",
        "මෙම ත්‍රිපුද්ගල ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ විනිසුරු මඩුල්ලේ සාමාජික විනිසුරුවරයෙකු වන අර්ජුන ඔබේසේකර මහතා මෙම සිද්ධියේ අභියාචනාධිකරණ නඩු විභාගය සදහා ද සහභාගී වී ඇති බැවින් මෙම අභියාචනා පෙත්සම සලකා බැලීම සදහා වෙනත් ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ විනිසුරු මඩුල්ලක් වෙත යොමු කිරිමට ද නියම විණී.",
        "විල්පත්තු වනය ආශ්‍රිතව නිති විරෝධී අන්දමින් කැළෑ එළිපෙහෙළි කර ගම්මාන ඉදිකරන ලදැයි චෝදනා කරමින් හිටපු අමාත්‍ය රිෂාඩ් බදියුදීන් මහතාට එරෙහිව පාරිසරික යුක්ති කේන්ද්‍රය අභියාචනාධිකරණයට රිට් පෙත්සමක් ගොනු කර තිබූ අතර, එහි දී නියෝග නිකුත් වූයේ හිටපු අමාත්‍යවරයාට සිය පෞද්ගලික වියදමින් අදාළ කැළෑ යළි වගා කරන ලෙසටය. එම නියෝගයෙන් අතෘප්තියට පත් හිටපු අමාත්‍යවරයා අදාළ නියෝගය බල රහිත කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය හමුවේ අභියචනා පෙත්සමක් ගොනු කරනු ලැබීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බදියුදීන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජනවාරි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිෂාඩ් බදියුදීන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අභියාචනාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අභියාචනාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විල්පත්තුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාමිණී අමරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අචල වෙංගප්පුලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අර්ජුන ඔබේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අර්ජුන ඔබේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තවත් ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාරිසරික යුක්ති මධ්යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිෂාඩ් බදියුදීන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අභියාචනාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විල්පත්තුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பதியுதீனின் மனு ஜனவரிக்கு ஒத்திவைக்கப்படுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வில்பத்துவில் சட்டவிரோதமான முறையில் அழிக்கப்பட்ட காடுகளை தனது சொந்த செலவில் மீள வளர்ப்பதற்கு மேன்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றம் வழங்கிய உத்தரவை ரத்து செய்யுமாறு மேன்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றத்தினால் ரிஷாட் பதியுதீன் தாக்கல் செய்த மேன்முறையீட்டு மனுவை இன்று (05) பரிசீலிக்க உயர் நீதிமன்றம் தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "திரு.காமினி அமரசேகர, அச்சல வெங்கப்புலி மற்றும் திரு.அர்ஜுன ஒபேசேகர ஆகியோர் அடங்கிய உச்ச நீதிமன்ற அமர்வு முன் இந்த மேன்முறையீடு பரிசீலிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இந்த மூவரடங்கிய உச்ச நீதிமன்ற பெஞ்சில் அங்கம் வகிக்கும் திரு.அர்ஜுன ஒபேசேகரவும் இந்த வழக்கின் மேன்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்ற விசாரணையில் பங்குபற்றியிருப்பதால் இந்த மேல்முறையீட்டு மனுவை வேறு உச்ச நீதிமன்ற பெஞ்ச் பரிசீலனைக்கு அனுப்புவது முறையானது.",
        "வில்பத்து வனப்பகுதியை அண்மித்த பகுதியில் சட்டவிரோதமான முறையில் காடுகளை அப்புறப்படுத்தி கிராமங்களை நிர்மாணித்ததாக முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் ரிஷாட் பதியுதீனுக்கு எதிராக சுற்றாடல் நீதி மையம் மேன்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றில் ரிட் மனுவொன்றை தாக்கல் செய்திருந்தது. அந்த உத்தரவால் அதிருப்தி அடைந்த முன்னாள் அமைச்சர், உரிய உத்தரவை ரத்து செய்யக் கோரி உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தில் மேல்முறையீட்டு மனு தாக்கல் செய்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பதியுதீன்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜனவரி",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிஷாத் பதியுதீன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வில்பத்து",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமினி அமரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அச்சலா வெங்கப்புலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அர்ஜுன ஒபேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அர்ஜுன ஒபேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மற்றொரு உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுற்றுச்சூழல் நீதி மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிஷாத் பதியுதீன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வில்பத்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}