{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84705/sjb-and-dissident-slpp-mps-to-boycott-interim-budget-vote",
  "time_ut": 1662099780,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SJB and dissident SLPP MPs to boycott interim budget vote",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SJB and dissident SLPP MPs to boycott interim budget vote",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The main opposition Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) says its parliamentarians will refrain from voting in the Appropriation (Amendment) Bill vote this evening.",
        "SJB MP Thushara Indunil stated this speaking to the media this morning. Meanwhile, the party’s general secretary MP Ranjith Madduma Bandara also confirmed the decision to boycott the vote.",
        "Meanwhile, Prof. G.L. Peiris stated that the group of 13 MPs from Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP), who recently decided to sit in the opposition, has also decided to boycott the interim budget vote.",
        "The National People’s Power (NPP) is planning to announce its decision at a media briefing, scheduled to be convened this afternoon."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SJB",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bill",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thushara Indunil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Madduma Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "G.L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The National People’s Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SJB සහ විරුද්ධ මත දරන ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරු අතුරු අයවැය ඡන්ද විමසීම වර්ජනය කරති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අද සවස පැවැත්වෙන විසර්ජන (සංශෝධන) පනත් කෙටුම්පතේ ඡන්ද විමසීමේදී සිය පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් වැළකී සිටින බව ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂය වන සමගි ජන බලවේගය (SJB) පවසයි.",
        "අද පෙරවරුවේ මාධ්‍ය වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී තුෂාර ඉඳුනිල් මේ බව කියා සිටියා. මේ අතර, එම පක්ෂයේ මහලේකම් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රංජිත් මද්දුම බණ්ඩාර ද ඡන්දය වර්ජනය කිරීමේ තීරණය තහවුරු කළා.",
        "මේ අතර පසුගියදා විපක්ෂයේ අසුන් ගැනීමට තීරණය කළ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 13 දෙනාගේ කණ්ඩායමද අතුරු අයවැය ඡන්ද විමසීම වර්ජනය කිරීමට තීරණය කර ඇති බව මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්.පීරිස් ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "ජාතික ජන බලවේගය (NPP) අද පස්වරුවේ කැඳවීමට නියමිත මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී සිය තීරණය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කිරීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිල්පත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුෂාර ඉඳුනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් මද්දුම බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්පීපී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SJB மற்றும் அதிருப்தி SLPP பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட வாக்கெடுப்பை புறக்கணிக்க உள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முக்கிய எதிர்க்கட்சியான சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) இன்று மாலை நிதி ஒதுக்கீட்டு (திருத்த) சட்டமூல வாக்கெடுப்பில் தமது பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் வாக்களிப்பதைத் தவிர்ப்பார்கள் என தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் துஷார இந்துனில் இன்று காலை ஊடகங்களுக்கு கருத்து தெரிவிக்கும் போதே இதனை தெரிவித்துள்ளார். இதேவேளை, கட்சியின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சித் மத்தும பண்டாரவும் வாக்கெடுப்பை புறக்கணிக்கும் தீர்மானத்தை உறுதிப்படுத்தியுள்ளார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, அண்மையில் எதிர்க்கட்சியில் அமரத் தீர்மானித்த ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் (SLPP) 13 பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் குழுவும் இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட வாக்கெடுப்பை புறக்கணிக்க தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக பேராசிரியர் ஜீ.எல்.பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி (NPP) இன்று பிற்பகல் கூட்டப்படவுள்ள ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் தனது முடிவை அறிவிக்க திட்டமிட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ர சி து",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துஷாரா இந்துனில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சித் மத்தும பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}