{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84603/school-girl-drowns-while-bathing-in-medagama-lake",
  "time_ut": 1661749740,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "School girl drowns while bathing in Medagama Lake",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "School girl drowns while bathing in Medagama Lake",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A school girl has drowned while bathing in the Medagama Lake in the Galgamuwa police area.",
        "Police stated that an investigation was initiated in accordance with a message received that the girl was in a serious condition after drowning, and had died after she was admitted to Thambuttegama Hospital.",
        "The 18-year-old victim is identified as a resident of the Leekolawewa area of Mahagalkadawara.",
        "The body has been placed in the mortuary of Thambuttegama Hospital."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Medagama Lake",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Medagama Lake",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galgamuwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thambuttegama Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "18-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Leekolawewa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahagalkadawara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මැදගම වැවේ දිය නෑමට ගිය පාසල් සිසුවියක් දියේ ගිලී මරුට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ගල්ගමුව පොලිස් බල ප්‍රදේශයට අයත් මැදගම වැවේ දිය නෑමට ගිය පාසල් සිසුවියක් දියේ ගිලී මියගොස් තිබේ.",
        "දියේ ගිලීමෙන් දැරිය බරපතළ තත්ත්වයෙන් පසුවන බවට ලැබුණු පණිවිඩයකට අනුව පරීක්ෂණයක් ආරම්භ කළ බවත්, ඇය තඹුත්තේගම රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කිරීමෙන් පසු මියගොස් ඇති බවත් පොලිසිය සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ඝාතනයට ලක්ව ඇත්තේ 18 හැවිරිදි මහගල්කඩවර, ලීකොළවැව ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිකරුවෙකි.",
        "මෘත ශරීරය තඹුත්තේගම රෝහලේ මෘත ශරීරාගාරයේ තැන්පත් කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මැදගම වැව",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මැදගම වැව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්ගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තඹුත්තේගම රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "18 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලීකොළවැව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහගල්කඩවර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மெதகம ஏரியில் குளித்த பாடசாலை மாணவி நீரில் மூழ்கி உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கல்கமுவ பொலிஸ் பிரிவிற்குட்பட்ட மெதகம ஏரியில் குளித்த பாடசாலை மாணவி ஒருவர் நீரில் மூழ்கி உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "சிறுமி நீரில் மூழ்கி ஆபத்தான நிலையில் இருந்ததாகவும், தம்புத்தேகம வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்ட பின்னர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாகவும் கிடைத்த செய்திக்கு அமைய விசாரணைகள் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "உயிரிழந்த 18 வயதுடைய நபர் மஹகல்கடவர லீகொலவெவ பிரதேசத்தில் வசிப்பவர் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "சடலம் தம்புத்தேகம வைத்தியசாலையின் பிரேத அறையில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மெதகம ஏரி",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மெதகம ஏரி",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்கமுவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தம்புத்தேகம வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "18 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லீகொலவெவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகாகல்கடவர",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}