{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/79336",
  "time_ut": 1662144480,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Former Sri Lankan President Gotabaya Rajapaksa arrives in Colombo’s Bandaranaike International airport under cover of darkness and is  whisked away in a heavily guarded convoy of vehicles after  Sri Lankan Ministers  garland  and welcome him back,",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Former Sri Lankan President Gotabaya Rajapaksa arrives in Colombo’s Bandaranaike International airport under cover of darkness and is  whisked away in a heavily guarded convoy of vehicles after  Sri Lankan Ministers  garland  and welcome him back,",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former Sri Lankan President Gotabaya Rajapaksa arrived in Colombo’s Bandaranaike International airport exactly the same way he left the country seven weeks ago—under cover of darkness and shrouded in secrecy—aided by Sinhalese politicians who closed ranks.",
        "Just past midnight on September 3, a Singapore Airlines flight brought the former President back to his country. He was whisked away in a heavily guarded convoy of vehicles while media persons scrambled to confirm if indeed Gotabaya had arrived.",
        "Sri Lankan media reported that he was met at the airport by Sri Lankan Ministers. They garlanded him and welcomed him back, an act which was unthinkable just a few weeks ago.",
        "The same Ministers had distanced themselves from him as a restive crowd demanded the resignation of the government and forced the resignation of key Ministers and bureaucrats.",
        "The state crackdown on activists who worked on the “Gota go gama” (Gota go home) campaign since mid-July this year, which resulted in the sudden disappearance of some of these activists, was a clear indication that the state machinery was carrying out all the orders of the political bosses.",
        "In effect, the spontaneous people’s revolution that engulfed the country just a few months ago has been put down with a heavy hand, despite the fact that it managed to unseat a President and others. It will perhaps go down as history’s shortest revolution that came undone.",
        "Gotabaya’s party, the SLPP, essentially a family-run enterprise, began a stock-taking exercise recently to consolidate the gains made by Sinhalese politicians in the last month. In an indication that the party is already looking forward to returning to status quo, former Minister and Gotabaya’s brother, Basil Rajapaksa, who was turned away from the airport when he tried to flee in July, chaired the meeting.",
        "Gotabaya had fled on July 9 after crowds of angry protestors broke into the Presidential palace and occupied it. He first landed in the Maldives and later left for Singapore. Although the Sri Lankan Intelligence Services chief was seen in Dubai about a week before Gotabaya fled, the former President decided not to travel to the UAE and instead moved to Thailand, where he waited for the Sri Lankan political situation to stabilise."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Colombo",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Bandaranaike International",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandaranaike International",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven weeks ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhalese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Just past midnight",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 3",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Ministers",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "just a few weeks ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gota",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gota",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "mid-July this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "just a few months ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhalese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Intelligence Services",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about a week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UAE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා අඳුර මවාගෙන කොළඹ බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළට පැමිණ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඇමැතිවරුන් මල්මාලා පළඳවා ආපසු පිළිගැනීමෙන් පසු දැඩි ආරක්‍ෂාවක් සහිත වාහන පෙළකින් ඉවතට ගෙන යනු ලැබීය.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ සති හතකට පෙර රටින් පිටව ගිය ආකාරයටම කොළඹ බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළට පැමිණියේ අඳුරට මුවා වී රහසිගතව - නිලයන් වසා දැමූ සිංහල දේශපාලකයන්ගේ සහායෙනි.",
        "සැප්තැම්බර් 3 වෙනිදා මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රිය පහුවෙනකොටම සිංගප්පූරු ගුවන් සේවයට අයත් යානයකින් හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා නැවත සිය රටට ගෙන්වා ගත්තා. දැඩි ආරක්‍ෂාවක් සහිත වාහන පෙළකින් ඔහුව ගසාගෙන යන අතර, ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම ගෝඨාභය පැමිණියේ දැයි තහවුරු කිරීමට මාධ්‍යවේදීන් පොරකමින් සිටියහ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අමාත්‍යවරුන් විසින් ගුවන් තොටුපළේදී ඔහු හමුවූ බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කළේය. ඔවුන් ඔහුට මල්මාලා දමා නැවත පිළිගත්තා, සති කිහිපයකට පෙර සිතාගත නොහැකි ක්‍රියාවක්.",
        "නොසන්සුන් වූ පිරිසක් ආණ්ඩුවෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු යැයි බල කර ප්‍රධාන අමාත්‍යවරුන්ට සහ නිලධාරීන්ට ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට බල කිරීම නිසා එම අමාත්‍යවරුම ඔහුගෙන් ඈත් වී සිටියහ.",
        "මෙම ක්‍රියාකාරීන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු හදිසියේ අතුරුදහන් කිරීමට හේතු වූ “ගෝඨා ගෝ ගම” (ගෝඨා ගෙදර යන්න) ව්‍යාපාරයේ ක්‍රියාකාරීන්ට එරෙහිව මේ වසරේ ජූලි මැද සිට රාජ්‍ය මර්දනය රාජ්‍ය යාන්ත්‍රණය ක්‍රියාත්මක වන බවට පැහැදිලි ඇඟවීමකි. දේශපාලන ලොක්කන්ගේ සියලුම නියෝග.",
        "ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම, මීට මාස කිහිපයකට පෙර රටම ගිලගත් ස්වයංසිද්ධ ජනතා විප්ලවය ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු සහ අනෙකුත් අය බලයෙන් පහ කිරීමට සමත් වුවද, එය දැඩි අතකින් යටපත් කර ඇත. එය සමහර විට ඉතිහාසයේ අවලංගු වූ කෙටිම විප්ලවය ලෙස පහත වැටෙනු ඇත.",
        "ගෝඨාභයගේ පක්ෂය, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ, අත්‍යවශ්‍යයෙන්ම පවුල විසින් පවත්වාගෙන යනු ලබන ව්‍යාපාරයක්, පසුගිය මාසයේ සිංහල දේශපාලඥයින් විසින් ලබා ගත් ජයග්‍රහණ තහවුරු කර ගැනීම සඳහා කොටස් ගැනීමේ අභ්‍යාසයක් මෑතකදී ආරම්භ කරන ලදී. පක්ෂය දැනටමත් යථා තත්ත්වයට පැමිණීමට අපේක්ෂාවෙන් සිටින බවට ඉඟියක් ලෙස, හිටපු අමාත්‍ය සහ ගෝඨාභයගේ සහෝදරයා වන බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ ජූලි මාසයේදී පලා යාමට උත්සාහ කළ විට ගුවන් තොටුපළෙන් හරවා යැවූ අතර රැස්වීමේ මුලසුන දැරීය.",
        "කෝපයට පත් විරෝධතාකරුවන් පිරිසක් ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට කඩා වැදී එය අත්පත් කර ගැනීමෙන් පසු ගෝඨාභය පලා ගොස් තිබුණේ ජූලි 9 වැනිදාය. ඔහු මුලින්ම මාලදිවයිනට ගොඩබසින අතර පසුව සිංගප්පූරුව බලා පිටත්ව ගියේය. ගෝඨාභය පලා යාමට සතියකට පමණ පෙර ශ්‍රී ලංකා බුද්ධි සේවා ප්‍රධානියා ඩුබායිහිදී දැකගත හැකි වුවද, හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා එක්සත් අරාබි එමීර් රාජ්‍යයට නොයෑමට තීරණය කර ඒ වෙනුවට තායිලන්තයට ගොස් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දේශපාලන තත්ත්වය ස්ථාවර වන තෙක් බලා සිටියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "කොළඹ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තරය",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තරය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති හතකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රිය පසු වූවා පමණි",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 3",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරු ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඇමතිවරු",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති කිහිපයකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨා",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨා",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම වසරේ ජූලි මැද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාස කිහිපයකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඔත්තු සේවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතියක් පමණ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UAE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச, இருளில் மூழ்கிய நிலையில் கொழும்பு பண்டாரநாயக்கா சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தை வந்தடைந்ததுடன், இலங்கை அமைச்சர்கள் மாலை அணிவித்து வரவேற்ற பின்னர், பலத்த பாதுகாப்புடன் கூடிய வாகனத் தொடரணியில் அழைத்துச் செல்லப்பட்டார்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச, ஏழு வாரங்களுக்கு முன்னர் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறிய அதே வழியில் கொழும்பு பண்டாரநாயக்கா சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தை வந்தடைந்தார் - இருளில் மறைத்து, இரகசியமாக மூடிய சிங்கள அரசியல்வாதிகளின் உதவியால்.",
        "செப்டம்பர் 3 ஆம் தேதி நள்ளிரவைத் தாண்டி, சிங்கப்பூர் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் விமானம் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியை அவரது நாட்டுக்கு அழைத்து வந்தது. கோட்டாபய உண்மையில் வந்தாரா என்பதை உறுதிப்படுத்த ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் முண்டியடித்த வேளையில், பலத்த பாதுகாப்புடன் கூடிய வாகனத் தொடரணியில் அவர் தூக்கிச் செல்லப்பட்டார்.",
        "அவரை இலங்கை அமைச்சர்கள் விமான நிலையத்தில் சந்தித்ததாக இலங்கை ஊடகங்கள் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளன. அவர்கள் அவருக்கு மாலை அணிவித்து வரவேற்றனர், இது சில வாரங்களுக்கு முன்பு நினைத்துப் பார்க்க முடியாத செயல்.",
        "அரசாங்கத்தை ராஜினாமா செய்யக் கோரி அமைதியான கூட்டம் முக்கிய அமைச்சர்கள் மற்றும் அதிகாரிகளை ராஜினாமா செய்ய கட்டாயப்படுத்தியதால் அதே அமைச்சர்கள் அவரிடமிருந்து விலகினர்.",
        "இந்த ஆண்டு ஜூலை நடுப்பகுதியில் இருந்து “கோதா கோ கம” (கோதா வீட்டிற்குச் செல்லுங்கள்) பிரச்சாரத்தில் பணியாற்றிய ஆர்வலர்கள் மீதான அரசின் அடக்குமுறை, இதன் விளைவாக இந்த ஆர்வலர்கள் சிலர் திடீரென காணாமல் போனது, அரசு இயந்திரம் மேற்கொண்டு வருகிறது என்பதைத் தெளிவாகக் காட்டுகிறது. அரசியல் முதலாளிகளின் அனைத்து உத்தரவுகளும்.",
        "உண்மையில், ஒரு சில மாதங்களுக்கு முன்பு நாட்டை மூழ்கடித்த தன்னிச்சையான மக்கள் புரட்சி ஒரு ஜனாதிபதியையும் மற்றவர்களையும் பதவி நீக்கம் செய்ய முடிந்த போதிலும், ஒரு கனமான கையால் அடக்கப்பட்டது. இது வரலாற்றின் மிகக் குறுகிய புரட்சியாக மாறிவிடும்.",
        "கோட்டாபயவின் கட்சியான SLPP, அடிப்படையில் குடும்பம் நடத்தும் நிறுவனமானது, கடந்த மாதத்தில் சிங்கள அரசியல்வாதிகள் அடைந்த வெற்றிகளை ஒருங்கிணைக்க, பங்குகளை எடுக்கும் பயிற்சியை சமீபத்தில் தொடங்கியது. கட்சி ஏற்கனவே நிலைமைக்குத் திரும்புவதை எதிர்பார்த்துக்கொண்டிருக்கிறது என்பதை உணர்த்தும் வகையில், முன்னாள் அமைச்சரும் கோத்தபாயவின் சகோதரருமான பசில் ராஜபக்ச, ஜூலை மாதம் தப்பிச் செல்ல முயன்றபோது விமான நிலையத்திலிருந்து திருப்பி அனுப்பப்பட்ட கூட்டத்திற்கு தலைமை தாங்கினார்.",
        "ஜூலை 9 அன்று கோபமடைந்த ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்குள் நுழைந்து அதை ஆக்கிரமித்ததை அடுத்து கோத்தபய தப்பியோடினார். முதலில் மாலத்தீவில் இறங்கிய அவர் பின்னர் சிங்கப்பூர் சென்றார். கோட்டாபய தப்பிச் செல்வதற்கு ஒரு வாரத்திற்கு முன்னர் இலங்கைப் புலனாய்வுத் துறைத் தலைவர் துபாயில் காணப்பட்ட போதிலும், முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸுக்குப் பயணம் செய்யாமல் தாய்லாந்திற்குச் சென்றார், அங்கு அவர் இலங்கை அரசியல் நிலைமை சீராகும் வரை காத்திருந்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "கொழும்பு",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்க சர்வதேசம்",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்க சர்வதேசம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு வாரங்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்களவர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நள்ளிரவு தாண்டியது",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 3",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அமைச்சர்கள்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சில வாரங்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிடைத்தது ஒரு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிடைத்தது ஒரு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு ஜூலை நடுப்பகுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு சில மாதங்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்களவர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை புலனாய்வு சேவைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் ஒரு வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}