{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132188",
  "time_ut": 1658721233,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "அமைச்சராகிறார் வஜிர ? சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தில் அங்கம் வகிக்கும் சகல அரசியல் கட்சிகளுக்கும் அமைச்சு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Will Vajira become a minister? Ministry for all political parties that are part of a multi-party government",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "United National Party Secretary Vajira Abeywardhana will be sworn in as a Member of Parliament on the 27th. After that, he is expected to be sworn in as a cabinet minister.",
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe, who was elected to Parliament through the United National Party's national list, was elected as the 8th President through a secret ballot held in Parliament on the 20th.",
        "Subsequently, he resigned as a Member of Parliament after taking the oath of office as the President on the 21st. The Secretary General of the Parliament informed the National Elections Commission last week about the vacancy of the Member of Parliament.",
        "The National Elections Commission issued a gazette notification last week to confirm the nomination of United National Party Secretary Vajira Abeywardena's name to the National Elections Commission.",
        "Accordingly, Vajira Abeywardhana will take the oath of office as a member of Parliament in the upcoming Parliament session on the 27th.",
        "Negotiations have been carried out under the leadership of the President to bring together all the political parties that are members of the Parliament to establish an all-party government in a couple of weeks. It is expected to form a cabinet comprising 30 ministries.",
        "It is also known that it has been decided to give ministries to all the political parties that are part of the all-party government."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Will Vajira",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vajira Abeywardhana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 27th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 20th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 21st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Elections Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The National Elections Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vajira Abeywardena's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Elections Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vajira Abeywardhana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 27th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "a couple of weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වජිර ඇමති වෙයිද? බහු පක්ෂ ආණ්ඩුවක කොටසක් වන සියලුම දේශපාලන පක්ෂ සඳහා අමාත්‍යාංශය",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ ලේකම් වජිර අබේවර්ධන මහතා ලබන 27 වනදා පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ලෙස දිවුරුම් දීමට නියමිතයි. ඉන් අනතුරුව ඔහු කැබිනට් අමාත්‍යවරයෙකු ලෙස දිවුරුම් දීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට තේරී පත් වූ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා 8 වැනි ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස පසුගිය 20 වැනිදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී පැවැති රහස් ඡන්දයෙන් තේරී පත් විය.",
        "ඉන් අනතුරුව පසුගිය 21 වැනිදා ජනාධිපති ධූරයේ දිවුරුම් දීමෙන් අනතුරුව ඔහු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස් වූ අතර පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධුරය පුරප්පාඩු වීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම්වරයා ජාතික මැතිවරණ කොමිසම වෙත පසුගිය සතියේ දැනුම් දුන්නා.",
        "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ ලේකම් වජිර අබේවර්ධන මහතාගේ නම ජාතික මැතිවරණ කොමිෂන් සභාවට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීම තහවුරු කිරීම සඳහා ජාතික මැතිවරණ කොමිෂන් සභාව පසුගිය සතියේ ගැසට් නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කළේය.",
        "ඒ අනුව වජිර අබේවර්ධන මහතා ලබන 27 වැනිදා පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසිවාරයේදී පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ලෙස දිවුරුම් දීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "තව සති දෙකකින් සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සිටින සියලුම දේශපාලන පක්ෂ ඒකරාශී කර ගැනීමට ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් සාකච්ඡා කර තිබෙනවා.අමාත්‍යාංශ 30කින් සමන්විත කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයක් පිහිටුවීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා.",
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවේ කොටස්කරුවන් වන සියලුම දේශපාලන පක්ෂවලට අමාත්‍යාංශ ලබාදීමට තීරණය කර ඇති බවද දැනගන්නට ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "විල් වජිර",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වජිර අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික මැතිවරණ කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික මැතිවරණ කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වජිර අබේවර්ධනගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික මැතිවරණ කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වජිර අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அமைச்சராகிறார் வஜிர ? சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தில் அங்கம் வகிக்கும் சகல அரசியல் கட்சிகளுக்கும் அமைச்சு",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சியின் தவிசாளர் வஜிர  அபேவர்தன எதிர்வரும் 27ஆம் திகதி பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக பதவி பிரமாணம் செய்யவுள்ளார். அதனை தொடர்ந்து அவர் அமைச்சரவை அமைச்சராகவும் பதவி பிரமாணம் செய்துக்கொள்ளவுள்ளதாகவும் எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சியின் தேசிய பட்டியல் ஊடாக பாராளுமன்றிற்கு தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்ட ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க கடந்த 20ஆம் திகதி பாராளுமன்றில் இடம் பெற்ற இரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பின் ஊடாக 8ஆவது ஜனாதிபதியாக தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டார்.",
        "அதனை தொடர்ந்து கடந்த 21 ஆம் திகதி அவர் ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவி பிரமாணம் செய்ததன் பின்னர் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பதவியை இராஜினாமா செய்தார்.வெற்றிடமாகியுள்ள பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பதவி தொடர்பில் பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் கடந்த வாரம் தேசிய தேர்தல்கள் ஆணைக்குழுவிற்கு அறிவித்தார்.",
        "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சியின் தவிசாளர் வஜிர அபேவர்தனவின் பெயர் தேசிய தேர்தல்கள் ஆணைக்குழுவிற்கு பரிந்துரை செய்யப்பட்டதை தொடர்ந்து அதனை உறுதிப்படுத்தும் வகையில் தேசிய தேர்தல்கள் ஆணைக்குழு கடந்த வாரம் வர்த்தமானி அறிவித்ததை வெளியிட்டது.",
        "அதற்கமைய வஜிர அபேவர்தன எதிர்வரும் 27ஆம் திகதி கூடவுள்ள பாராளுமன்ற அமர்வில் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக பதவி பிரமாணம் செய்துக்கொள்ளவுள்ளார்.அதனை தொடர்ந்து அவர் அமைச்சு பதவியையும் பொறுப்பேற்பார் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "பாராளுமன்றில் அங்கம் வகிக்கும் சகல அரசியல் கட்சிகளையும் ஒன்றினைத்து இன்னும் ஓரிரு வாரங்களில் சர்வக்கட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை ஸ்தாபிக்க ஜனாதிபதி தலைமையில் பேச்சுவார்த்தைகள் முன்னெடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.30 அமைச்சுக்களை உள்ளடக்கிய வகையில் அமைச்சரவையினை அமைக்க எதிர்பார்க்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அத்துடன் சர்வக்கட்சி அரசாங்கத்தில் அங்கம் வகிக்கும் சகல அரசியல் கட்சிகளுக்கும் அமைச்சுக்களை வழங்க தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் அறிய முடிகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வில் வஜிரா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய தேர்தல் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய தேர்தல் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபேவர்தனவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய தேர்தல் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}