{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lankas-22nd-constitutional-amendment-bill-is-not-a-restoration-of-19as-essence-experts-96784/",
  "time_ut": 1656749880,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s 22nd constitutional amendment bill is not a restoration of 19A’s essence: experts",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s 22nd constitutional amendment bill is not a restoration of 19A’s essence: experts",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Provisions in the proposed 22nd amendment to Sri Lanka’s constitution that were supposed to restore the essence of the more progressive 19th amendment are missing from the now-gazetted 22nd amendment bill, experts said.",
        "Executive Director of People’s Action for Free and Fair Elections (PAFFREL) Rohana Hettiarachchi told reporters on Saturday July 02 that the amendment bill sees a continuation of the concentration of power around one individual.",
        "Hettiarachchi made this comment after a meeting held with Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "“This draft amendment does not contain the positive provisions that we expected: the independence of the public service, transfer of power to parliament, checks and balances, the transfer of powers between president and PM.",
        "“We see a continuation of the centralisation of power around one individual in this bill. The fundamentals of public finance and accountability are also absent from this amendment,” he said.",
        "The PAFFREL director said Prime Minister Wickremesinghe had previously said consensus was obtained from all political parties to restore the main provisions of the 19th amendment to the constitution that was enacted during his previous tenure.",
        "“But even those aren’t there in this bill. We stress that it is the will of the public that must become law,” he said.",
        "Hettiarachchi also asked that the version of the 22nd amendment that President Gotabaya Rajapaksa had previously agreed to be presented instead.",
        "Prof Rohan Samarajiva, head of LirneAsia, a regional think tank, tweeted on Saturday that the 22nd amendment bill does not restore the substance of the 19th amendment.",
        "@GotabayaR said on May 11 that he will get us \"a Constitutional Amendment that would restore the substance of the 19th Amendment.\" Gazetted 22A does not restore the substance of 19A. Below are 3 changes to be made to make it acceptable. 1/4",
        "In order to make it more acceptable, Samarajiva proposed three changes: not allowing the president to hold any portfolio, removing interim powers granted to the president to appoint minsters without the advice of the prime minister (to be granted under the 22nd amendment temporarily until the 10th parliament), and removing the president’s discretion to dissolve parliament early.",
        "Justice Minister Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe, who authored the 22nd amendment, had previously claimed that the amendment will largely be a restoration of the 19th amendment which will see some of the powers conferred on the president by the controversial 20th amendment will be repealed.",
        "The Centre for Policy Alternatives (CPA) said on June 30 that the 22nd amendment bill does not curtail the powers of the president nor introduce checks and balances in any meaningful manner, contrary to the demands of the people of Sri Lanka.",
        "In the absence of any genuine attempt to address the inherent problems of governance, this attempt at reform will only worsen the existing political and economic crisis and destroy whatever little remaining faith citizens might have in constitutional governance, the organisation said in a statement, calling the bill a diluted version of itself.",
        "Sri Lanka’s gazetted 22nd amendment bill is a diluted version of itself: CPA",
        "The 19th amendment to the constitution, enacted during the Yahapalana government of former President Maithripala Sirisena and then Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe saw some of the executive powers of the president curtailed and parliament significantly strengthened. That amendment was rolled back by President Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) government after its 20th amendment to the constitution was passed in parliament, conferring the office of the president with even more sweeping powers.",
        "Sri Lanka’s prevailing economic crisis which has precipitated a political crisis has brought to the fore the need to speedily introduce constitutional reforms, and Minister Rajapakshe’s 21st amendment (referred to in the bill as the 22nd amendment) promised to be a restoration of the more progressive provisions of the 19th."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "22nd",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "19A",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "22nd amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "People’s Action for Free and Fair Elections",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday July 02",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hettiarachchi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hettiarachchi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prof Rohan Samarajiva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "LirneAsia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "19th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "@GotabayaR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a Constitutional Amendment",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 19th Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "19A.",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1/4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samarajiva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Centre for Policy Alternatives",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yahapalana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapakshe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "21st",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 19th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ 22 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධන පනත් කෙටුම්පත 19A හි හරය ප්‍රතිෂ්ඨාපනය කිරීමක් නොවේ: විශේෂඥයෝ",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ යෝජිත 22 වැනි සංශෝධනයේ වඩාත් ප්‍රගතිශීලී 19 වැනි ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනයේ සාරය ප්‍රතිෂ්ඨාපනය කිරීමට නියමිතව තිබූ ප්‍රතිපාදන දැන් ගැසට් කර ඇති 22 වැනි සංශෝධන පනත් කෙටුම්පතේ නැති බව විශේෂඥයෝ පවසති.",
        "නිදහස් හා සාධාරණ මැතිවරණයක් සඳහා වූ ජනතා ක්‍රියාකාරීත්වයේ (පැෆ්රල්) විධායක අධ්‍යක්ෂ රෝහණ හෙට්ටිආරච්චි ජූලි 02 සෙනසුරාදා මාධ්‍යවේදීන් අමතමින් කියා සිටියේ සංශෝධන පනත් කෙටුම්පත එක් පුද්ගලයෙකු වටා බලය සංකේන්ද්‍රණය වීම අඛණ්ඩව සිදුවන බවයි.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවකින් අනතුරුව හෙට්ටිආරච්චි මහතා මේ බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "“රාජ්‍ය සේවයේ ස්වාධීනත්වය, පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට බලය පැවරීම, චෙක්පත් සහ තුලනය, ජනාධිපති සහ අගමැති අතර බලතල පැවරීම යන අප බලාපොරොත්තු වූ ධනාත්මක ප්‍රතිපාදන මෙම කෙටුම්පත සංශෝධනයේ අඩංගු නොවේ.",
        "“මෙම පනතේ එක් පුද්ගලයෙකු වටා බලය කේන්ද්‍රගත කිරීමේ අඛණ්ඩ පැවැත්මක් අපි දකිමු. රාජ්‍ය මූල්‍ය සහ වගවීම යන මූලික කරුණු ද මෙම සංශෝධනයෙන් නොමැත.",
        "පැෆ්රල් සංවිධානයේ අධ්‍යක්ෂවරයා පැවසුවේ, අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මීට පෙර තම පාලන සමයේදී පනවන ලද 19 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනයේ ප්‍රධාන විධිවිධාන යළි ස්ථාපිත කිරීම සඳහා සියලු දේශපාලන පක්ෂවල එකඟතාව ලබා ගත් බව පැවසූ බවයි.",
        "“ඒත් ඒවත් මේ පනතේ නැහැ. නීතියක් බවට පත් විය යුත්තේ මහජන කැමැත්ත බව අපි අවධාරණය කරමු,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ඒ වෙනුවට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මීට පෙර එකඟ වූ 22 වැනි සංශෝධනයේ පිටපත ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලෙසද හෙට්ටිආරච්චි ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "කලාපීය චින්තන මණ්ඩලයක් වන LirneAsia හි ප්‍රධානී මහාචාර්ය රොහාන් සමරජීව සෙනසුරාදා ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ 22 වන සංශෝධන පනත් කෙටුම්පත 19 වන සංශෝධනයේ හරය ප්‍රතිෂ්ඨාපනය නොකරන බවයි.",
        "@GotabayaR මැයි 11 වෙනිදා කිව්වා \"19 වැනි සංශෝධනයේ හරය නැවත ඇති කරන ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනයක්\" ඔහු අපට ලබා දෙන බව. ගැසට් 22A මගින් 19A හි ද්‍රව්‍යය ප්‍රතිෂ්ඨාපනය නොකරයි. එය පිළිගත හැකි පරිදි සිදු කළ යුතු වෙනස්කම් 3ක් පහත දැක්වේ. 1/4",
        "එය වඩාත් පිළිගත හැකි වන පරිදි, සමරජීව විසින් වෙනස්කම් තුනක් යෝජනා කළේය: ජනාධිපතිවරයාට කිසිදු අමාත්‍ය ධුරයක් දැරීමට ඉඩ නොදීම, අගමැතිවරයාගේ උපදෙස් නොමැතිව අමාත්‍යවරුන් පත් කිරීමට ජනාධිපතිවරයාට ලබා දී ඇති අතුරු බලතල ඉවත් කිරීම (22 වැනි සංශෝධනය යටතේ තාවකාලිකව ලබා දීම. 10 වැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව), සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ඉක්මනින් විසුරුවා හැරීමට ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ අභිමතය ඉවත් කිරීම.",
        "ආන්දෝලනාත්මක 20 වැනි ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනයෙන් ජනාධිපතිවරයාට ලබා දී ඇති බලතලවලින් කොටසක් ඉවත් කෙරෙනු ඇති 19 වැනි ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය බොහෝ දුරට ප්‍රතිෂ්ඨාපනය කිරීමක් වනු ඇති බව 22 වැනි ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය සකස් කළ අධිකරණ අමාත්‍ය විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ මීට පෙර ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබුණි.",
        "22 වැනි සංශෝධන පනත් කෙටුම්පත මගින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවගේ ඉල්ලීම්වලට පටහැනිව ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ බලතල කප්පාදු කිරීම හෝ කිසිදු අර්ථාන්විත ආකාරයකින් චෙක්පත් සහ ශේෂයන් හඳුන්වාදීමක් සිදු නොවන බව විකල්ප ප්‍රතිපත්ති කේන්ද්‍රය (CPA) ජුනි 30 වැනිදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "පාලනයේ නෛසර්ගික ගැටළු විසඳීමට කිසිදු සැබෑ උත්සාහයක් නොමැති විට, මෙම ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ උත්සාහය පවතින දේශපාලන හා ආර්ථික අර්බුදය තවත් නරක අතට හැරෙනු ඇති අතර ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත පාලනය කෙරෙහි පුරවැසියන්ට ඉතිරිව ඇති සුළු විශ්වාසයක් විනාශ කිරීම පමණක් බව සංවිධානය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය. එහිම තනුක කළ අනුවාදයක් බිල් කරන්න.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ගැසට් කරන ලද 22 වැනි සංශෝධන පනත් කෙටුම්පත එහිම තනුක කළ අනුවාදයකි: CPA",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන සහ එවකට අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ යහපාලන රජය සමයේ 19 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය මගින් ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ විධායක බලතල කිහිපයක් කප්පාදු කර පාර්ලිමේන්තුව සැලකිය යුතු ලෙස ශක්තිමත් කරන ලදී. එම සංශෝධනය ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ (SLPP) රජය විසින් 20 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී සම්මත කිරීමෙන් පසු ජනාධිපති ධුරයට ඊටත් වඩා විශාල බලතල ප්‍රදානය කිරීමෙන් පසු ඉවත් කරන ලදී.",
        "දේශපාලන අර්බුදයකට තුඩු දී ඇති ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදය ව්‍යවස්ථාමය ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ කඩිනමින් හඳුන්වා දීමේ අවශ්‍යතාව කරළියට ගෙන ඇති අතර, අමාත්‍ය රාජපක්ෂගේ 21 වැනි සංශෝධනය (22 වැනි සංශෝධනය ලෙස පනත් කෙටුම්පතේ සඳහන් වේ) වඩාත් ප්‍රගතිශීලී ප්‍රතිපාදන යළි පිහිටුවීමක් බවට පොරොන්දු විය. 19 වෙනිදා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "22 වැනි",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "19A",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් හා සාධාරණ මැතිවරණයක් සඳහා ජනතා ක්‍රියාමාර්ගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 02 සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට්ටිආරච්චි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට්ටිආරච්චි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහාචාර්ය රොහාන් සමරජීව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "LirneAsia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "@ගෝඨාභය ආර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථා සංශෝධනයක්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "19A.",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1/4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමරජීව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විකල්ප ප්‍රතිපත්ති මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යහපාලන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் 22வது அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தச் சட்டமூலம் 19A இன் சாரத்தை மீட்டெடுப்பது அல்ல: நிபுணர்கள்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையின் அரசியலமைப்பின் முன்மொழியப்பட்ட 22 வது திருத்தத்தில் மிகவும் முற்போக்கான 19 வது திருத்தத்தின் சாரத்தை மீட்டெடுக்கும் விதிகள் இப்போது வர்த்தமானியில் வெளியிடப்பட்ட 22 வது திருத்த மசோதாவில் இல்லை என்று நிபுணர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "சுதந்திரமான மற்றும் நியாயமான தேர்தலுக்கான மக்கள் நடவடிக்கையின் (PAFFREL) நிறைவேற்றுப் பணிப்பாளர் ரோஹன ஹெட்டியாராச்சி ஜூலை 02 சனிக்கிழமை செய்தியாளர்களிடம் கூறுகையில், ஒரு தனிநபரை சுற்றி அதிகாரம் குவிக்கப்படுவதை இந்த திருத்தச் சட்டமூலம் பார்க்கிறது.",
        "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுடன் இடம்பெற்ற சந்திப்பின் பின்னர் ஹெட்டியாராச்சி இதனைத் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "“இந்த வரைவு திருத்தத்தில் நாங்கள் எதிர்பார்த்த சாதகமான விதிகள் இல்லை: பொதுச் சேவையின் சுதந்திரம், அதிகாரத்தை பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு மாற்றுதல், காசோலைகள் மற்றும் நிலுவைகள், ஜனாதிபதிக்கும் பிரதமருக்கும் இடையிலான அதிகாரங்கள் பரிமாற்றம்.",
        "“இந்த மசோதாவில் ஒரு தனி நபரைச் சுற்றி அதிகார மையப்படுத்தலின் தொடர்ச்சியை நாங்கள் காண்கிறோம். பொது நிதி மற்றும் பொறுப்புக்கூறல் ஆகியவற்றின் அடிப்படைகளும் இந்த திருத்தத்தில் இல்லை” என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "தனது முந்தைய ஆட்சிக் காலத்தில் நிறைவேற்றப்பட்ட அரசியலமைப்பின் 19 ஆவது திருத்தத்தின் முக்கிய ஏற்பாடுகளை மீளப் பெறுவதற்கு அனைத்து அரசியல் கட்சிகளிடமும் இணக்கப்பாடு பெறப்பட்டதாக பிரதமர் விக்ரமசிங்க முன்னர் தெரிவித்ததாக பெஃப்ரல் அமைப்பின் பணிப்பாளர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“ஆனால் அவை கூட இந்த மசோதாவில் இல்லை. பொதுமக்களின் விருப்பமே சட்டமாக மாற வேண்டும் என்பதை வலியுறுத்துகிறோம்,'' என்றார்.",
        "அதற்கு பதிலாக ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ முன்னர் ஒப்புக்கொண்ட 22 வது திருத்தத்தின் பதிப்பை முன்வைக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் ஹெட்டியாராச்சி கேட்டுக் கொண்டார்.",
        "22ஆவது திருத்தச் சட்டமூலம் 19ஆவது திருத்தச் சட்டத்தின் உட்பொருளை மீட்டெடுக்கவில்லை என பிராந்திய சிந்தனைக் குழுவான லிர்னேஏசியாவின் தலைவர் பேராசிரியர் ரொஹான் சமரஜீவ சனிக்கிழமை ட்வீட் செய்தார்.",
        "\"19வது திருத்தத்தின் உட்பொருளை மீட்டெடுக்கும் அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தத்தை\" எமக்கு பெற்றுத் தருவதாக மே 11 அன்று @கோட்டாபயஆர் கூறினார். வர்த்தமானி 22A 19A இன் பொருளை மீட்டெடுக்காது. அதை ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளும் வகையில் செய்ய வேண்டிய 3 மாற்றங்கள் கீழே உள்ளன. 1/4",
        "அதை மேலும் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளும் வகையில், சமரஜீவ மூன்று மாற்றங்களை முன்மொழிந்தார்: ஜனாதிபதிக்கு எந்தவொரு இலாகாவையும் வைத்திருக்க அனுமதிக்காதது, பிரதமரின் ஆலோசனையின்றி அமைச்சர்களை நியமிக்க ஜனாதிபதிக்கு வழங்கப்பட்ட இடைக்கால அதிகாரங்களை நீக்குதல் (22வது திருத்தத்தின் கீழ் தற்காலிகமாக வழங்கப்படும். 10வது பாராளுமன்றம்), மற்றும் பாராளுமன்றத்தை முன்கூட்டியே கலைப்பதற்கான ஜனாதிபதியின் விருப்புரிமையை நீக்குதல்.",
        "22வது திருத்தத்தை உருவாக்கிய நீதி அமைச்சர் விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ, சர்ச்சைக்குரிய 20வது திருத்தச் சட்டத்தின் மூலம் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ள சில அதிகாரங்கள் இரத்து செய்யப்படும் 19வது திருத்தத்தின் மீளமைப்பாகவே இந்த திருத்தம் இருக்கும் என முன்னர் கூறியிருந்தார்.",
        "இலங்கை மக்களின் கோரிக்கைகளுக்கு மாறாக, 22வது திருத்தச் சட்டமூலம் ஜனாதிபதியின் அதிகாரங்களைக் குறைக்கவோ அல்லது காசோலைகள் மற்றும் சமநிலைகளை எந்தவொரு அர்த்தமுள்ள விதத்திலும் அறிமுகப்படுத்தவோ இல்லை என்று மாற்றுக் கொள்கைகளுக்கான மையம் (CPA) ஜூன் 30 அன்று கூறியது.",
        "ஆளுகையின் உள்ளார்ந்த பிரச்சனைகளுக்கு தீர்வு காண உண்மையான முயற்சி எதுவும் இல்லாத நிலையில், இந்த சீர்திருத்த முயற்சி தற்போதுள்ள அரசியல் மற்றும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை மேலும் மோசமாக்கும் மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு நிர்வாகத்தில் குடிமக்கள் வைத்திருக்கும் நம்பிக்கையை அழித்துவிடும் என்று அந்த அமைப்பு ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. அதன் நீர்த்த பதிப்பை பில்.",
        "இலங்கையின் வர்த்தமானியில் வெளியிடப்பட்ட 22வது திருத்தச் சட்டமூலம் அதன் நீர்த்த வடிவமாகும்: CPA",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன மற்றும் அப்போதைய பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஆகியோரின் யஹபாலன அரசாங்கத்தின் போது நிறைவேற்றப்பட்ட அரசியலமைப்பின் 19 வது திருத்தத்தின் மூலம் ஜனாதிபதியின் நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரங்கள் சில குறைக்கப்பட்டு பாராளுமன்றம் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க வகையில் பலப்படுத்தப்பட்டது. ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன (SLPP) அரசாங்கத்தால் அந்தத் திருத்தம் திரும்பப் பெறப்பட்டது, அதன் 20 வது அரசியலமைப்புத் திருத்தம் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நிறைவேற்றப்பட்டது, மேலும் ஜனாதிபதியின் அலுவலகத்திற்கு இன்னும் அதிகமான அதிகாரங்களை வழங்கியது.",
        "அரசியல் நெருக்கடியைத் தூண்டிய இலங்கையின் நிலவும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியானது அரசியலமைப்பு சீர்திருத்தங்களை விரைவாக அறிமுகப்படுத்த வேண்டியதன் அவசியத்தை முன்னுக்குக் கொண்டு வந்துள்ளது, மேலும் அமைச்சர் ராஜபக்ஷவின் 21வது திருத்தம் (22வது திருத்தம் என சட்டமூலத்தில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது) மேலும் முற்போக்கான ஏற்பாடுகளை மீட்பதாக உறுதியளித்துள்ளது. 19 ஆம் தேதி."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "22வது",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "19A",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "22வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரமான மற்றும் நியாயமான தேர்தலுக்கான மக்கள் நடவடிக்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 02 சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹெட்டியாராச்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹெட்டியாராச்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பேராசிரியர் ரொஹான் சமரஜீவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிர்னேஏசியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "19வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "@கோட்டாபய ஆர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தம்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "19வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "19A.",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1/4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமரஜீவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாற்றுக் கொள்கைகளுக்கான மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யஹபாலன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}