{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Opposition-nominates-Eran-Kabir-as-COPE-COPA-heads/108-243078",
  "time_ut": 1660549578,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Opposition nominates Eran, Kabir as COPE, COPA heads",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Opposition nominates Eran, Kabir as COPE, COPA heads",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Whilst confirming that the opposition groups in Parliament have nominated his name as the new Chairman of the Committee on Public Enterprises ( COPE), Samagi Jana Balawegaya MP Eran Wickramaratne today said it is up to the government to decide on a policy to give the chairmanship to members of Opposition.",
        "Mr. Wickramaratne was responding to the reports which said he had been nominated as the Chairman of COPE and MP Kabir Hashim as the Chairman of Committee on Public Accounts( COPA).",
        "\"I am aware that our names have been nominated for the posts. A final decision has to be made by the government which has the majority of members in the two committees. There have been instances where government adopted a policy of giving the chairmanships of the committee to the opposition,\" he told Dailymirror.",
        "Meanwhile, Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardene last week assured that opposition members will be appointed as chairpersons of committees. He said this when Chief Opposition Whip Lakshman Kiriella made an inquiry in Parliament. (Yohan Perera)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Eran",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kabir",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "COPE",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "COPA",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Committee on Public Enterprises",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eran Wickramaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickramaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kabir Hashim",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Committee on Public Accounts",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yohan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විපක්ෂය කෝප්, කෝපා ප්‍රධානීන් ලෙස එරාන්, කබීර් නම් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාවේ (කෝප්) නව සභාපතිවරයා ලෙස පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ විපක්ෂයේ කණ්ඩායම් තමාගේ නම නම් කර ඇති බව තහවුරු කරන අතර සමඟි ජන බලවේගයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඉරාන් වික්‍රමරත්න මහතා අද ප්‍රකාශ කළේ සභාපතිත්වය ලබාදීමේ ප්‍රතිපත්තියක් තීරණය කිරීම රජය සතු බවයි. විපක්ෂ සාමාජිකයන්.",
        "තමන් කෝප් කමිටුවේ සභාපතිවරයා ලෙසත්, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී කබීර් හෂීම් රාජ්‍ය ගිණුම් පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාවේ (කෝපා) සභාපතිවරයා ලෙසත් නම් කර ඇති බවට පළ වූ වාර්තාවලට ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වමින් වික්‍රමරත්න මහතා මේ බව පැවසීය.",
        "“මම දන්නවා තනතුරුවලට අපේ නම් යෝජනා වෙලා තියෙන්නේ. අවසන් තීරණයක් ගත යුත්තේ කමිටු දෙකේ බහුතර මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සිටින රජයයි. සභාපතිකම් ලබාදීමේ ප්‍රතිපත්තියක් රජය අනුගමනය කළ අවස්ථා තිබෙනවා. කමිටුව විපක්ෂයට,” ඔහු ඩේලිමිරර් වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "මේ අතර කාරක සභා සභාපතිවරුන් ලෙස විපක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පත් කරන බවට කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා පසුගිය සතියේ සහතික විය. ඔහු මේ බව පැවසුවේ විපක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී කළ විමසීමකදීය. (යොහාන් පෙරේරා)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එරන්",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "කබීර්",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "කෝප්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "COPA",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "එරාන් වික්‍රමරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කබීර් හෂීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය ගිණුම් පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යොහාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரான், கபீர் ஆகியோரை COPE, COPA தலைவர்களாக எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் பரிந்துரைக்கின்றன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொது நிறுவனங்கள் தொடர்பான குழுவின் (கோப்) புதிய தலைவராக தனது பெயரை நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் பரிந்துரைத்துள்ளதை உறுதிப்படுத்திய சமகி ஜன பலவேகய நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் எரான் விக்ரமரத்ன, தலைவர் பதவியை வழங்குவது தொடர்பான கொள்கையை அரசாங்கம் தீர்மானிக்க வேண்டும் என தெரிவித்துள்ளார். எதிர்க்கட்சி உறுப்பினர்கள்.",
        "தாம் கோப் அமைப்பின் தலைவராகவும், பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் கபீர் ஹாஷிம் பொதுக் கணக்குகள் குழுவின் (கோபா) தலைவராகவும் பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்டதாக வெளியான செய்திகளுக்குப் பதிலளிக்கையிலேயே திரு. விக்கிரமரத்ன இவ்வாறு கூறினார்.",
        "\"பதவிகளுக்கு எங்கள் பெயர்கள் பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன என்பதை நான் அறிவேன். இரண்டு குழுக்களிலும் பெரும்பான்மை உறுப்பினர்களைக் கொண்ட அரசாங்கத்தால் இறுதி முடிவு எடுக்கப்பட வேண்டும். தலைவர் பதவிகளை வழங்கும் கொள்கையை அரசாங்கம் ஏற்றுக்கொண்ட நிகழ்வுகள் உள்ளன. எதிர்க்கட்சிக்கு குழு,” என்று அவர் டெய்லிமிரரிடம் கூறினார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன கடந்த வாரம் எதிர்க்கட்சி உறுப்பினர்கள் குழுக்களின் தலைவர்களாக நியமிக்கப்படுவார்கள் என உறுதியளித்திருந்தார். எதிர்க்கட்சியின் பிரதம கொறடாவான லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல பாராளுமன்றத்தில் வினவியபோதே அவர் இதனைத் தெரிவித்தார். (யோஹான் பெரேரா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஈரான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கபீர்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கோப்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "COPA",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது நிறுவனங்களுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "எரான் விக்கிரமரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கபீர் ஹாசிம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது கணக்குகளுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோஹான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}