{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ලක්ෂ-200-මෝටර්-රථය-ගිනි-රකුසාට-බිලි/1-617130",
  "time_ut": 1658915900,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ලක්ෂ 200 මෝටර් රථය ගිනි රකුසාට බිලි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "200 lakh car sacrificed to the fire monster",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Kataragama Police say that a luxury car coming from Wattala to Kataragama caught fire suddenly at Tammananawa Menikwala Junction.",
        "The driver told the police that this car is worth around 210 lakh rupees.",
        "A resident of Wattala, Ederamulla, railway station along with his friend was coming to Kataragama via Mattala Lunugamwehera on the expressway at around 11:00 pm when the car caught fire on the south side and stopped the car and jumped out with his friend. The Kataragama police have stated that it was not."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "200",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Wattala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kataragama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tammananawa Menikwala Junction",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "210",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wattala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kataragama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mattala Lunugamwehera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "around 11:00 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kataragama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලක්ෂ 200 මෝටර් රථය ගිනි රකුසාට බිලි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "වත්තල සිට  කතරගම පැමිණෙමින් සුඛෝපභෝගී මෝටර් රථයක්  තම්මැන්නාව මැණික් වල සීමාව හංදීයේදී හදිසියේ ගිණිගෙන විනාශවී ඇතැයි කතරගම පොලීසිය කියයි.",
        "මෙම මෝටර් රථය රුපියල් ලක්ෂ 210 ක් පමණ වටිනාකමක් ඇතැයි රියදුරා පොලීසියට පවසි ඇත.",
        "වත්තල, එඩෙරමුල්ල, දුම්රිය පොල පදිංචි පුද්ගලයකු සිය මිතුරකු ද සමගින් අධිවේගී මාර්ගය ඔස්සේ මත්තල ලුණුගම්වෙහෙර හරහා කතරගම බලා පැමිණෙමින් සිටියදී රාත්‍රී 11ට පමණ මෝටර් රථයේ දකුණු දෙසින් දුමක් මතුවී ගිනි ගත් බවත්, මෝටර් රථය නතර කොට මිතුරාත් සමග එලියට පැන ගත් බවත්, ඔවුන් දෙදෙනාට කිසිදු අනතුරක් නොවූ බවත් කතරගම පොලිසියට ප්‍රකාශ කොට ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "200",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වත්තල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කතරගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තම්මනනාව මැණික්වල හන්දිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "210",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වත්තල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කතරගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මත්තල ලුණුගම්වෙහෙර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "11:00 පමණ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "කතරගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "200 லட்சம் கார் தீ அசுரனுக்கு பலி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வத்தளையிலிருந்து கதிர்காமம் நோக்கி வந்த சொகுசு கார் ஒன்று தம்மனனாவ மெனிக்வல சந்தியில் திடீரென தீப்பிடித்து எரிந்துள்ளதாக கதிர்காமம் பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "இந்த கார் சுமார் 210 இலட்சம் ரூபா பெறுமதியானது என சாரதி பொலிஸாரிடம் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "வத்தளை, எடரமுல்லை, புகையிரத நிலையத்தைச் சேர்ந்த ஒருவர் தனது நண்பருடன் இரவு 11.00 மணியளவில் அதிவேக நெடுஞ்சாலையில் மத்தள லுணுகம்வெஹெர ஊடாக கதிர்காமத்திற்கு வந்து கொண்டிருந்த போது காரின் தென்பகுதியில் கார் தீப்பிடித்த போது காரை நிறுத்திவிட்டு வெளியே குதித்துள்ளார். அது இல்லை என கதிர்காமம் பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "200",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வத்தளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கதிர்காமம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மனனாவ மெனிக்வல சந்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "210",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வத்தளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கதிர்காமம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்தல லுனுகம்வெஹர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 11:00 இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கதிர்காமம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}