{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83239/petrol-shipment-further-delayed-minister-says",
  "time_ut": 1656077280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Petrol shipment further delayed, minister says",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Petrol shipment further delayed, minister says",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC) has been informed by the supplier that the petrol shipment which was scheduled to arrive on the island today would be delayed further, Minister of Power & Energy Kanchana Wijesekara says.",
        "A new date of arrival will be confirmed later today, the lawmaker added taking to his official Twitter account.",
        "Minister Wijesekara, giving an update on the arrival of the shipment of 92,000 MT of petrol yesterday, had stated that it would experience a delay of one day. Accordingly, the fuel consignment was expected today.",
        "However, the supplier has informed the CPC of a further delay, the minister said further."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Power & Energy Kanchana Wijesekara",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "later today",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "92,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පෙට්‍රල් තොග යැවීම තවදුරටත් ප්‍රමාද වන බව අමාත්‍යවරයා පවසයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "අද දිවයිනට පැමිණීමට නියමිතව තිබූ පෙට්‍රල් තොගය තවදුරටත් ප්‍රමාද වන බවට සැපයුම්කරු විසින් ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවට දන්වා ඇති බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර මහතා පවසයි.",
        "නව පැමිණීමේ දිනයක් අද පසුව තහවුරු කෙරෙනු ඇති බව නීති සම්පාදකවරයා සිය නිල ට්විටර් ගිණුමට එක් කර ඇත.",
        "ඊයේ දිනයේ පෙට්‍රල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 92,000ක් නැව්ගත කිරීම පිළිබඳව යාවත්කාලීනයක් ලබාදෙමින් අමාත්‍ය විජේසේකර ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබුණේ එය දිනක ප්‍රමාදයක් අත්වන බවයි. ඒ අනුව අද දිනයේ මෙම ඉන්ධන තොගය බලාපොරොත්තු විය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, තවදුරටත් ප්‍රමාදයක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් සැපයුම්කරු ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවට දන්වා ඇති බවද අමාත්‍යවරයා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලය සහ බලශක්ති කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද පසුව",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "92,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பெட்ரோல் ஏற்றுமதி மேலும் தாமதமாகிறது என்கிறார் அமைச்சர்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "இன்று இலங்கைக்கு வரவிருந்த பெற்றோல் ஏற்றுமதி மேலும் தாமதமாகும் என சப்ளையர் மூலம் இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்திற்கு (CPC) அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "புதிய வருகை தேதி இன்று பின்னர் உறுதிப்படுத்தப்படும், சட்டமியற்றுபவர் தனது அதிகாரப்பூர்வ ட்விட்டர் கணக்கில் சேர்த்துக்கொண்டார்.",
        "நேற்று 92,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் பெற்றோல் ஏற்றுமதி குறித்த அறிவிப்பை வெளியிட்ட அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகர, இது ஒரு நாள் தாமதத்தை சந்திக்கும் என தெரிவித்திருந்தார். அதன்படி, இன்று எரிபொருள் ஏற்றுமதி எதிர்பார்க்கப்பட்டது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், சப்ளையர் மேலும் தாமதம் குறித்து CPC க்கு அறிவித்துள்ளார், அமைச்சர் மேலும் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பவர் & எனர்ஜி காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பின்னர் இன்று",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "92,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Petrol shipment further delayed, minister says",
  "body_lines": [
    "The Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC) has been informed by the supplier that the petrol shipment which was scheduled to arrive on the island today would be delayed further, Minister of Power & Energy Kanchana Wijesekara says.",
    "A new date of arrival will be confirmed later today, the lawmaker added taking to his official Twitter account.",
    "Minister Wijesekara, giving an update on the arrival of the shipment of 92,000 MT of petrol yesterday, had stated that it would experience a delay of one day. Accordingly, the fuel consignment was expected today.",
    "However, the supplier has informed the CPC of a further delay, the minister said further."
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Petrol shipment further delayed, minister says",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC) has been informed by the supplier that the petrol shipment which was scheduled to arrive on the island today would be delayed further, Minister of Power & Energy Kanchana Wijesekara says.",
        "A new date of arrival will be confirmed later today, the lawmaker added taking to his official Twitter account.",
        "Minister Wijesekara, giving an update on the arrival of the shipment of 92,000 MT of petrol yesterday, had stated that it would experience a delay of one day. Accordingly, the fuel consignment was expected today.",
        "However, the supplier has informed the CPC of a further delay, the minister said further."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Power & Energy Kanchana Wijesekara",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "later today",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "92,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පෙට්‍රල් තොග යැවීම තවදුරටත් ප්‍රමාද වන බව අමාත්‍යවරයා පවසයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "අද දිවයිනට පැමිණීමට නියමිතව තිබූ පෙට්‍රල් තොගය තවදුරටත් ප්‍රමාද වන බවට සැපයුම්කරු විසින් ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවට දන්වා ඇති බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර මහතා පවසයි.",
        "නව පැමිණීමේ දිනයක් අද පසුව තහවුරු කෙරෙනු ඇති බව නීති සම්පාදකවරයා සිය නිල ට්විටර් ගිණුමට එක් කර ඇත.",
        "ඊයේ දිනයේ පෙට්‍රල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 92,000ක් නැව්ගත කිරීම පිළිබඳව යාවත්කාලීනයක් ලබාදෙමින් අමාත්‍ය විජේසේකර ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබුණේ එය දිනක ප්‍රමාදයක් අත්වන බවයි. ඒ අනුව අද දිනයේ මෙම ඉන්ධන තොගය බලාපොරොත්තු විය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, තවදුරටත් ප්‍රමාදයක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් සැපයුම්කරු ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවට දන්වා ඇති බවද අමාත්‍යවරයා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලය සහ බලශක්ති කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද පසුව",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "92,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பெட்ரோல் ஏற்றுமதி மேலும் தாமதமாகிறது என்கிறார் அமைச்சர்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "இன்று இலங்கைக்கு வரவிருந்த பெற்றோல் ஏற்றுமதி மேலும் தாமதமாகும் என சப்ளையர் மூலம் இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்திற்கு (CPC) அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "புதிய வருகை தேதி இன்று பின்னர் உறுதிப்படுத்தப்படும், சட்டமியற்றுபவர் தனது அதிகாரப்பூர்வ ட்விட்டர் கணக்கில் சேர்த்துக்கொண்டார்.",
        "நேற்று 92,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் பெற்றோல் ஏற்றுமதி குறித்த அறிவிப்பை வெளியிட்ட அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகர, இது ஒரு நாள் தாமதத்தை சந்திக்கும் என தெரிவித்திருந்தார். அதன்படி, இன்று எரிபொருள் ஏற்றுமதி எதிர்பார்க்கப்பட்டது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், சப்ளையர் மேலும் தாமதம் குறித்து CPC க்கு அறிவித்துள்ளார், அமைச்சர் மேலும் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பவர் & எனர்ஜி காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பின்னர் இன்று",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "92,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}