{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/columns/The-outcome-of-Sri-Lankan-education-system-Quality-or-quantity/4-736814",
  "time_ut": 1656446035,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "The outcome of Sri Lankan education system: Quality or quantity?",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The outcome of Sri Lankan education system: Quality or quantity?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Weightage of the bag is something related to ‘quantity’ which we need to revisit while improving the ‘quality’",
        "Now we are witnessing the worst economic crisis in Sri Lanka with all the hardships for common people. As per my reading, all we can see are only the ‘symptoms’ of the ‘real problem’ and underlying causes need to be investigated. In this scenario, I observe the ‘education system in Sri Lanka’ as part of this ‘real problem’.",
        "As we know, with the blessings of ‘free education’ by Dr. Kannanagara, Sri Lanka has advanced in education in the past. You can explain this with a better literacy rate as one indicator. Unfortunately, the education system has not changed for years aligning with the requirement of society. I have seen certain experts discuss different best practices in education in countries such as Sweden in many forums in Sri Lanka but no real impact on the system itself. We have witnessed many negative outcomes (in terms of deteriorating the quality of people in society, ranking of education in Sri Lanka) by questioning the ‘quality education in Sri Lanka’. In this article, I am going to discuss one facet of this ‘real problem’ and which is related to the ‘size of the schoolbag’ which I consider part and parcel of this problem.",
        "In Sri Lanka, we can observe a student weighing 25 kilos bringing a schoolbag of 10 kilos! I consider this as one measurement to indicate the disaster of our education system. Most of the children coming under the category of grades six to 10 have around 10 subjects per day questioning whether Sri Lankan educationists have done the justice for our next generation (which we need to discuss in a separate article).",
        "In India, the Ministry of Human Resource Development (HRD) prescribed a weight limit of schoolbags for each class last year. Accordingly, the weight of schoolbags for students of classes one and two should not exceed 1.5 kg, while the schoolbag of students of classes three to five should weigh between 2 kg to 3 kg. The schoolbag of students in classes six and seven should not be more than 4 kg, while the weight of schoolbags of classes eight and nine students should not be above 4.5 kg. The schoolbag of a class 10 student should not weigh above 5 kg. Even in Peshawar, Pakistan the elementary and secondary education department has decided that the schoolbag’s weight will not be more than 15% of the student’s.",
        "It can be observed that a grade seven student in Sri Lanka is bringing more than 200% of the stipulated weight limit which would lead to many ergonomic problems. A report by the US Consumer Product Safety Commission published that over 22,000 students suffer back pain-related injuries in the year 2013 (Khan, 2018). The majority of them carry as much as 25% of their body weight.",
        "A study in Al-Ahsa, Saudi Arabia, reveals that 1,860 (around 73%) of the students among 2,567 students carry bags that weigh more than 15% of their body weight and back pain was reported by 42% of the students. In India, the burden of satchels, as estimated in some of the Telangana districts, weighs about 6 to 12 kg at the primary level and 12 to 17 kg at the high school level (Khan, 2018). In Sri Lanka, it can be suggested to have a proper study on this to investigate the gravity of the problem with a weight limit of schoolbags.",
        "There is a grave need for a revisit of the education system in Sri Lanka in terms of many aspects. But in this article, I would like to emphasise ‘the quantity vs. quality’ of the education system of the country. Weightage of the bag is something related to ‘quantity’ which we need to revisit while improving the ‘quality’. As I mentioned earlier this is one of the symptoms of the ‘real problem’ we are facing in the country and authorities should take this seriously as a matter of priority.",
        "(The writer is a Professor in Management Studies, Faculty of Management Studies, The Open University of Sri Lanka. You can reach him on nalinabeyseekra@gmail.com.)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kannanagara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sweden",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 kilos",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 kilos",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "six to 10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Human Resource Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "HRD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.5 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "three to five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "between 2 kg to 3 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "eight",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.5 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peshawar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 15%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 200%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Consumer Product Safety Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 22,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year 2013",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "as much as 25%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Al-Ahsa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudi Arabia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,860",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "around 73%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,567",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 15%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "42%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Telangana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Faculty of Management Studies",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Open University of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අධ්‍යාපන ක්‍රමයේ ප්‍රතිඵලය: ගුණාත්මකභාවය හෝ ප්‍රමාණය?",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "බෑගයේ බර යනු 'ප්‍රමාණය' හා සම්බන්ධ දෙයක් වන අතර එය 'ගුණාත්මකභාවය' වැඩි දියුණු කරන අතරම අප නැවත සලකා බැලිය යුතුය.",
        "දැන් අපි දකින්නේ සාමාන්‍ය මිනිසුන්ගේ සියලු දුෂ්කරතා සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයයි. මගේ කියවීමට අනුව, අපට දැකිය හැක්කේ 'සැබෑ ගැටලුවේ' 'රෝග ලක්ෂණ' පමණක් වන අතර එයට යටින් පවතින හේතු විමර්ශනය කළ යුතුය. මෙම තත්ත්වය තුළ, මෙම ‘සැබෑ ගැටලුවේ’ කොටසක් ලෙස ‘ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අධ්‍යාපන ක්‍රමය’ මම නිරීක්ෂණය කරමි.",
        "අප දන්නා පරිදි ආචාර්ය කන්නනගරගේ ‘නිදහස් අධ්‍යාපනයේ’ ආශිර්වාදයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතීතයේ අධ්‍යාපනය අතින් ඉදිරියට පැමිණ ඇත. ඔබට මෙය එක් දර්ශකයක් ලෙස වඩා හොඳ සාක්ෂරතා අනුපාතයකින් පැහැදිලි කළ හැකිය. අවාසනාවකට, අධ්‍යාපන ක්‍රමය වසර ගණනාවක් තිස්සේ සමාජයේ අවශ්‍යතාවයට අනුකූලව වෙනස් වී නොමැත. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බොහෝ සංසදවලදී ස්වීඩනය වැනි රටවල අධ්‍යාපනයේ විවිධ හොඳම භාවිතයන් පිළිබඳව ඇතැම් ප්‍රවීණයන් සාකච්ඡා කරන නමුත් පද්ධතියට සැබෑ බලපෑමක් සිදු නොවන බව මම දැක ඇත්තෙමි. ‘ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ගුණාත්මක අධ්‍යාපනය’ ප්‍රශ්න කිරීම තුළින් (සමාජයේ මිනිසුන්ගේ ගුණාත්මක භාවය පිරිහීම, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අධ්‍යාපනය ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම යන කරුණු අනුව) බොහෝ ඍණාත්මක ප්‍රතිඵල අප දැක ඇත. මෙම ලිපියෙන් මම සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට යන්නේ මෙම 'සැබෑ ගැටලුවේ' එක් පැතිකඩක් සහ මෙම ගැටලුවේ කොටසක් ලෙස මා සලකන 'පාසල් බෑගයේ ප්‍රමාණය' හා සම්බන්ධය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කිලෝ 25ක් බර සිසුවෙක් කිලෝ 10ක පාසල් බෑගයක් රැගෙන එන අයුරු අපට නිරීක්ෂණය කළ හැක! මෙය අපේ අධ්‍යාපන ක්‍රමයේ ව්‍යසනය පෙන්නුම් කරන එක් මිනුමක් ලෙස මම සලකමි. හයේ සිට 10 ශ්‍රේණිය යටතේ එන බොහෝ ළමයින්ට දිනකට විෂයයන් 10ක් පමණ ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය අධ්‍යාපනඥයන් අපගේ ඊළඟ පරම්පරාවට සාධාරණය ඉටු කර ඇත්දැයි ප්‍රශ්න කරති (ඒවා වෙනම ලිපියකින් සාකච්ඡා කළ යුතුය).",
        "ඉන්දියාවේ, මානව සම්පත් සංවර්ධන අමාත්‍යාංශය (HRD) පසුගිය වසරේ සෑම පන්තියක් සඳහාම පාසල් බෑග්වල බර සීමාවක් නියම කළේය. ඒ අනුව, එක හා දෙක පන්තිවල සිසුන්ගේ පාසල් බෑගයේ බර කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 1.5 නොඉක්මවිය යුතු අතර, තුනේ සිට පහේ පන්තිවල සිසුන්ගේ පාසල් බෑගය කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 2 සිට 3 දක්වා බරින් යුක්ත විය යුතුය. හය සහ හත පන්තිවල සිසුන්ගේ පාසල් බෑගය කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 4 ට නොවැඩි විය යුතු අතර අටේ සහ නවයේ පන්තිවල සිසුන්ගේ පාසල් බෑගයේ බර කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 4.5 ට වැඩි නොවිය යුතුය. 10 පන්තියේ සිසුවෙකුගේ පාසල් බෑගය කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 5 ට වඩා බර නොවිය යුතුය. පාකිස්ථානයේ පෙෂාවර් හි පවා ප්‍රාථමික හා ද්විතීයික අධ්‍යාපන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව තීරණය කර ඇත්තේ පාසල් බෑගයේ බර සිසුන්ගේ බරින් 15%කට වඩා වැඩි නොවිය යුතු බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ හත ශ්‍රේණියේ ඉගෙනුම ලබන සිසුවෙකු නියමිත බර සීමාවෙන් 200%කට වඩා ගෙන ඒම නිසා බොහෝ ergonomic ගැටලු ඇති වන බව නිරීක්ෂණය කළ හැක. 2013 වසරේ (ඛාන්, 2018) සිසුන් 22,000 කට අධික සංඛ්‍යාවක් කොන්දේ වේදනාව හා සම්බන්ධ තුවාල වලට ගොදුරු වූ බව එක්සත් ජනපද පාරිභෝගික නිෂ්පාදන ආරක්ෂණ කොමිසමේ වාර්තාවක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කළේය. ඔවුන්ගෙන් බහුතරයක් තම සිරුරේ බරෙන් 25% ක් පමණ උසුලයි.",
        "සෞදි අරාබියේ අල්-අහ්සා හි අධ්‍යයනයකින් හෙළි වූයේ සිසුන් 2,567 ක් අතර සිසුන් 1,860 ක් (73% ක් පමණ) ඔවුන්ගේ ශරීර බරෙන් 15% ට වඩා බර බෑග් රැගෙන යන අතර සිසුන්ගෙන් 42% ක් විසින් කොන්දේ වේදනාව වාර්තා කර ඇති බවයි. ඉන්දියාවේ, සමහර තෙලංගානා දිස්ත්‍රික්කවල ඇස්තමේන්තු කර ඇති පරිදි සැචල්වල බර ප්‍රාථමික මට්ටමේදී කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 6 සිට 12 දක්වා සහ උසස් පාසල් මට්ටමේදී කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 12 සිට 17 දක්වා බරයි (ඛාන්, 2018). ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ පාසල් බෑග්වල බර සීමාවක් සමඟ ගැටලුවේ බරපතලකම විමර්ශනය කිරීම සඳහා මේ පිළිබඳව නිසි අධ්‍යයනයක් කිරීමට යෝජනා කළ හැකිය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අධ්‍යාපන ක්‍රමයේ බොහෝ පැති සම්බන්ධයෙන් නැවත බැලීමක දැඩි අවශ්‍යතාවක් පවතී. නමුත් මෙම ලිපියෙන්, රටේ අධ්‍යාපන ක්‍රමයේ ‘ප්‍රමාණය එදිරිව ගුණාත්මක බව’ අවධාරණය කිරීමට මම කැමැත්තෙමි. බෑගයේ බර යනු 'ප්‍රමාණය' හා සම්බන්ධ දෙයක් වන අතර එය 'ගුණාත්මකභාවය' වැඩිදියුණු කරන අතරම අප නැවත සලකා බැලිය යුතුය. මා මුලින් සඳහන් කළ පරිදි මෙය අප රට තුළ මුහුණ දී සිටින ‘සැබෑ ප්‍රශ්නයේ’ එක් රෝග ලක්‍ෂණයක් වන අතර බලධාරීන් මෙය ප්‍රමුඛතාවක් ලෙස සැලකිය යුතුය.",
        "(ලේඛකයා ශ්‍රී ලංකා විවෘත විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ කළමනාකරණ අධ්‍යයන පීඨයේ කළමනාකරණ අධ්‍යයන පිළිබඳ මහාචාර්යවරයෙකි. ඔබට ඔහු වෙත nalinabeyseekra@gmail.com වෙත සම්බන්ධ විය හැකිය.)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kannanagara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්වීඩනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ 25 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ 10 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය සිට 10 දක්වා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මානව සම්පත් සංවර්ධන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "HRD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය අවුරුද්දේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 1.5 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන සිට පහ දක්වා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 2 සිට 3 දක්වා",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අට",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 4.5 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 5 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙෂාවර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15% ට වඩා",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200% කට වඩා",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාරිභෝගික නිෂ්පාදන ආරක්ෂණ කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22,000 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2013 වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25% තරම්",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අල්-අහ්සා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවුදි අරාබිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,860 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "73% පමණ",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,567 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "15% ට වඩා",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "42%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙලන්ගානා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 12 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 17 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කළමනාකරණ අධ්‍යයන පීඨය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා විවෘත විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை கல்வி முறையின் விளைவு: தரம் அல்லது அளவு?",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பையின் எடை என்பது 'அளவு' தொடர்பான ஒன்று, 'தரத்தை' மேம்படுத்தும் போது நாம் மறுபரிசீலனை செய்ய வேண்டும்.",
        "இப்போது இலங்கையில் மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை நாம் காண்கிறோம். எனது வாசிப்பின்படி, நாம் காணக்கூடியவை அனைத்தும் 'உண்மையான பிரச்சனையின்' 'அறிகுறிகள்' மட்டுமே மற்றும் அடிப்படை காரணங்களை ஆராய வேண்டும். இந்தச் சூழ்நிலையில், இந்த ‘உண்மையான பிரச்சினையின்’ ஒரு பகுதியாகவே ‘இலங்கையில் உள்ள கல்வி முறை’யை நான் அவதானிக்கிறேன்.",
        "கலாநிதி கண்ணனகராவின் ‘இலவசக் கல்வி’யின் ஆசீர்வாதத்துடன் இலங்கை கடந்த காலங்களில் கல்வியில் முன்னேறியிருப்பது நாம் அறிந்ததே. சிறந்த கல்வியறிவு விகிதத்தை ஒரு குறிகாட்டியாக நீங்கள் இதை விளக்கலாம். துரதிர்ஷ்டவசமாக, சமூகத்தின் தேவைக்கேற்ப கல்வி முறை பல ஆண்டுகளாக மாறவில்லை. ஸ்வீடன் போன்ற நாடுகளில் கல்வியில் பல்வேறு சிறந்த நடைமுறைகள் பற்றி சில நிபுணர்கள் இலங்கையில் பல மன்றங்களில் விவாதிப்பதை நான் பார்த்திருக்கிறேன். ‘இலங்கையில் தரமான கல்வி’ பற்றி கேள்வி எழுப்பியதன் மூலம் பல எதிர்மறையான விளைவுகளை (சமூகத்தில் உள்ள மக்களின் தரம் மோசமடைதல், இலங்கையில் கல்வியின் தரவரிசை ஆகியவற்றின் அடிப்படையில்) நாம் கண்டிருக்கிறோம். இந்தக் கட்டுரையில், இந்த 'உண்மையான பிரச்சனையின்' ஒரு அம்சத்தைப் பற்றி நான் விவாதிக்கப் போகிறேன், இது இந்தப் பிரச்சனையின் ஒரு பகுதியாகவும் பார்சலாகவும் நான் கருதும் 'பள்ளிப் பையின் அளவு' தொடர்பானது.",
        "இலங்கையில் 25 கிலோ எடையுள்ள மாணவர் ஒருவர் 10 கிலோ எடையுள்ள பள்ளிப் பையை எடுத்து வருவதை அவதானிக்க முடிகிறது! நமது கல்வி முறையின் பேரழிவைக் குறிக்கும் ஒரு அளவீடாக இதை நான் கருதுகிறேன். ஆறு முதல் 10 ஆம் வகுப்பு வரையிலான பிரிவின் கீழ் வரும் பெரும்பாலான குழந்தைகள், இலங்கையின் கல்வியாளர்கள் நமது அடுத்த தலைமுறைக்கு நீதியை செய்திருக்கிறார்களா என்று கேள்வி எழுப்பும் நாளொன்றுக்கு சுமார் 10 பாடங்கள் உள்ளன (இதை நாம் ஒரு தனி கட்டுரையில் விவாதிக்க வேண்டும்).",
        "இந்தியாவில், மனிதவள மேம்பாட்டு அமைச்சகம் (HRD) கடந்த ஆண்டு ஒவ்வொரு வகுப்பிற்கும் பள்ளிப் பைகளின் எடை வரம்பை நிர்ணயித்தது. அதன்படி, ஒன்று மற்றும் இரண்டாம் வகுப்பு மாணவர்களின் பள்ளி பையின் எடை 1.5 கிலோவுக்கு மிகாமல் இருக்க வேண்டும், மூன்று முதல் ஐந்தாம் வகுப்பு மாணவர்களின் பள்ளி பையின் எடை 2 கிலோ முதல் 3 கிலோ வரை இருக்க வேண்டும். ஆறு மற்றும் ஏழாம் வகுப்பு மாணவர்களின் பள்ளிப் பை 4 கிலோவுக்கு மேல் இருக்கக் கூடாது, எட்டு மற்றும் ஒன்பதாம் வகுப்பு மாணவர்களின் பள்ளிப் பையின் எடை 4.5 கிலோவுக்கு மேல் இருக்கக் கூடாது. 10-ம் வகுப்பு மாணவர்களின் பள்ளிப் பையின் எடை 5 கிலோவுக்கு மேல் இருக்கக்கூடாது. பாகிஸ்தானின் பெஷாவரில் கூட பள்ளிப் பையின் எடை மாணவர்களின் எடையில் 15%க்கு மேல் இருக்காது என்று தொடக்க மற்றும் இடைநிலைக் கல்வித் துறை முடிவு செய்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையில் தரம் ஏழாவது மாணவர் நிர்ணயிக்கப்பட்ட எடை வரம்பில் 200% க்கும் அதிகமான எடையைக் கொண்டு வருவதை அவதானிக்க முடியும், இது பல பணிச்சூழலியல் சிக்கல்களுக்கு வழிவகுக்கும். 2013 ஆம் ஆண்டில் (கான், 2018) 22,000 மாணவர்கள் முதுகுவலி தொடர்பான காயங்களுக்கு ஆளாகியுள்ளனர் என்று அமெரிக்க நுகர்வோர் தயாரிப்பு பாதுகாப்பு ஆணையத்தின் அறிக்கை வெளியிடப்பட்டது. அவர்களில் பெரும்பாலோர் தங்கள் உடல் எடையில் 25% வரை சுமக்கிறார்கள்.",
        "சவூதி அரேபியாவின் அல்-அஹ்ஸாவில் நடத்தப்பட்ட ஒரு ஆய்வில், 2,567 மாணவர்களில் 1,860 (சுமார் 73%) மாணவர்கள் தங்கள் உடல் எடையில் 15%க்கும் அதிகமான எடையுள்ள பைகளை எடுத்துச் செல்கின்றனர் மற்றும் முதுகுவலி 42% மாணவர்களால் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. இந்தியாவில், தெலுங்கானா மாவட்டங்களில் சிலவற்றில் புடவைகளின் சுமை ஆரம்ப நிலையில் 6 முதல் 12 கிலோ வரையிலும், உயர்நிலைப் பள்ளி அளவில் 12 முதல் 17 கிலோ வரையிலும் இருக்கும் (கான், 2018). இலங்கையில், பள்ளிப் பைகளின் எடை வரம்பைக் கொண்டு பிரச்சினையின் தீவிரத்தன்மையை ஆராய்வதற்கு இது குறித்து முறையான ஆய்வு நடத்த பரிந்துரைக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "பல அம்சங்களின் அடிப்படையில் இலங்கையின் கல்வி முறையை மீள்பரிசீலனை செய்ய வேண்டிய தேவை உள்ளது. ஆனால் இந்தக் கட்டுரையில், நாட்டின் கல்வி முறையின் ‘அளவு மற்றும் தரம்’ என்பதை வலியுறுத்த விரும்புகிறேன். பையின் எடை என்பது 'அளவு' தொடர்பான ஒன்று, இது 'தரத்தை' மேம்படுத்தும் போது நாம் மறுபரிசீலனை செய்ய வேண்டும். நான் முன்னரே குறிப்பிட்டது போல், நாட்டில் நாம் எதிர்நோக்கும் 'உண்மையான பிரச்சனையின்' அறிகுறிகளில் இதுவும் ஒன்றாகும், மேலும் அதிகாரிகள் இதை ஒரு முன்னுரிமையாக தீவிரமாக எடுத்துக் கொள்ள வேண்டும்.",
        "(எழுத்தாளர் இலங்கை திறந்த பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் முகாமைத்துவ கற்கைகள் பீடத்தின் முகாமைத்துவ கற்கைகள் பேராசிரியராக உள்ளார். நீங்கள் அவரை nalinabeyseekra@gmail.com இல் தொடர்புகொள்ளலாம்.)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kannanagara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்வீடன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு முதல் 10 வரை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனிதவள மேம்பாட்டு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "HRD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.5 கி.கி",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று முதல் ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 கிலோ முதல் 3 கிலோ வரை",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.5 கி.கி",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெஷாவர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15%க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200%க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுகர்வோர் தயாரிப்பு பாதுகாப்பு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22,000க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2013 ஆம் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25% வரை",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அல்-அஹ்ஸா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவூதி அரேபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,860",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 73%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,567",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "15%க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "42%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெலுங்கானா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேலாண்மை ஆய்வுகள் பீடம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை திறந்த பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}