{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/features/22-වැනි-සංශෝධනයට-සියලු-පක්ෂවල-අනුමැතිය-ගනිමු/2-618377",
  "time_ut": 1660885371,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනයට සියලු පක්ෂවල අනුමැතිය ගනිමු",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Let's get the approval of all the parties for the 22nd amendment",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The 1978 Constitution, which introduced the executive presidential system in Sri Lanka, has been submitted to the House of Representatives for the 22nd amendment. In the past, many major parties of the opposition said that the solution to many problems in the country is a constitutional amendment. Accordingly, the relevant work has been completed. While political groups with liberal opinions expressed their praise for this, a number of organizations that stand for the cause of nationality have already expressed their strong opposition to the 22nd amendment. Dr. Gunadasa Amarasekara submitted his objection in writing to the Speaker on behalf of the group of organizations.",
        "One of the common features seen in the field of constitution making in this country in the past is the bringing of constitutional amendments from government to government. JR Every government from the time of President Jayawardena until now amended the constitution from time to time. Each of those governments based the constitutional amendment on the policies of their respective political parties and sometimes the personal ambitions of different political parties. Especially from the 17th amendment of the Constitution to the 22nd amendment presented this time, this characteristic is strongly noticeable.",
        "Many countries in the world make constitutions to achieve the aspirations of their country and nation. The jurist Dr. B.R. who drafted the Constitution of India in 1950. Ambedkar conducted an extensive political poll before the constitution. Also, we got the model of the first constitution introduced in this country from England's Whitehall constitutional authority, but the constitutional expert Sir Ivor Jennings, who refined it in this country, conducted an opinion poll of the main political parties and minor party leaders before drafting the constitution. Along with that, he also examined the various political opinions represented before the Solebury Commission, which recommended giving us freedom. Accordingly, the first constitution of 1948, which was drafted by Sir Jennings, was in full force until 1972 when Sri Lanka became a republic.",
        "Our second constitution was drafted by a constitutional scholar, Dr. Colvin R. De Silva. We remember that the entire Parliament was made into a constitution-making body to get proposals for that. The Republic Constitution of 1972, which suspended the last official ties of the British Crown with the country by making Sri Lanka a Republic, remained in place without any problem until it was changed in 1978.",
        "1978 JR. Under the chairmanship of Mr. Jayawardena, H.W. The 1978 constitution drafted by a group of lawyers led by Jayawardena has been amended 21 times in the past 44 years. The 22nd Amendment has now been tabled in the House. This changes the 20th amendment passed by the previous government. The Gotabhaya Rajapaksa government established the 20th amendment after coming to power to repeal the 19th amendment adopted by the Yahapalana government. It is their election promise. The Yahapalana government brought the 19th amendment to repeal the 18th amendment passed by the previous Mahinda Rajapaksa government. The Mahinda Rajapaksa government brought the 18th amendment to repeal the 17th amendment that had been implemented before that. Thus, when we compare the precedents of constitution making, it is seen that from the 17th amendment to the 22nd amendment, constitutions have been amended from government to government. It is a clear fact that the personal agendas of each political party were at the root of this.",
        "Constitution making is a broad matter of national importance. It should not be used for personal political purposes. Also, the drafting of a constitution should not be done by any politician alone. For that, a broad dialogue and referendum is needed. If not, the constitutional amendment will be amended again in the next government. It has been stated that the 22nd constitutional amendment that has been presented this time includes proposals to expand the powers of the Matisaba. While congratulating on that, it should be noted that the implementation of the constitutional amendment in a way that is widely accepted by society is an essential factor for its future existence."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22nd",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "1978",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the House of Representatives",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunadasa Amarasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "17th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "B.R.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Constitution of India",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1950",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambedkar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "England",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ivor Jennings",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Solebury Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jennings",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1972",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colvin R. De Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Republic Constitution of",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1972",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1978",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1978",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayawardena",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past 44 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yahapalana",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yahapalana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matisaba",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනයට සියලු පක්ෂවල අනුමැතිය ගනිමු",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "විධායක ජනාධිපති ක්‍රමය මෙරටට හඳුන්වා දුන් 1978 ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව 22 වැනි වරටත් සංශෝධනය සඳහා මැතිසබයට කෙටුම්පත් ඉදිරිපත් කර තිබේ. පසුගිය කාලයේ විපක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන පක්ෂ ගණනාවකින්ම කියැවුණේ රටේ තිබෙන බොහෝ ප්‍රශ්නවලට විසඳුම ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනයක් බවය. ඒ අනුව අදාළ කටයුත්ත ඉටුවී ඇත. ලිබරල්වාදී මත දරන දේශපාලන කණ්ඩායම් මෙයට ප්‍රශංසාව පළකරද්දී ජාතිකත්ව අරමුණ වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටින සංවිධාන ගණනාවක් දැනටමත් 22 සංශෝධනයට සිය දැඩි විරෝධය පළකර තිබේ. එම සංවිධාන එකතුව වෙනුවෙන් ආචාර්ය ගුණදාස අමරසේකර සිය විරෝධය කතානායකවරයාට ලිඛිතවම ඉදිරිපත් කළේය.",
        "පසුගිය කාලයේ මෙරට ව්‍යවස්ථා සම්පාදන ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ දක්නට ලැබුණ එක්තරා පොදු ලක්ෂණ වන්නේ ආණ්ඩුවෙන් ආණ්ඩුවට ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධන ගෙන ඒමයි. ජේ.ආර්. ජයවර්ධන ජනාධිපතිතුමාගේ කාලයේ සිට මේ දක්වා පැවති හැම ආණ්ඩුවක්ම වරින්වර ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව සංශෝධනය කළේය. ඒ සෑම රජයක්ම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනයට පදනම් කරගත්තේ තම තමන්ගේ දේශපාලන පක්ෂවල ප්‍රතිපත්ති සහ ඇතැම්විට විවිධ දේශපාලන පක්ෂවල පෞද්ගලික අභිලාෂයන්ය. විශේෂයෙන්ම ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 17 වැනි සංශෝධනයේ සිට මෙවර ඉදිරිපත් කර තිබෙන 22 වැනි සංශෝධනය දක්වා මෙම ලක්ෂණය තදින්ම කැපී පෙනෙයි.",
        "ලෝකයේ බොහෝ රටවල් ව්‍යවස්ථා සම්පාදනය කරන්නේ තම තමන්ගේ රටේ සහ ජාතියේ අභිලාෂ සාක්ෂාත් කර ගැනීමටයි. ඉන්දියාවට 1950දී ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව සම්පාදනය කළ නීති විශාරද ආචාර්ය බී.ආර්. අම්බෙඩ්කාර් ව්‍යවස්ථාව සම්පාදනයට පෙර පුළුල් දේශපාලන මත විමසුමක් කළේය. එසේම මෙරටට හඳුන්වා දුන් ප්‍රථම ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ මොඩලය එංගලන්තයේ වයිට්ගෝල් ව්‍යවස්ථා සම්පාදක අධිකාරියෙන් අපට ලැබුණ ද එය මෙරට දී පිරිපහදු කළ ව්‍යවස්ථා විශාරද ශ්‍රීමත් අයිවර් ජෙනිංග්ස් ව්‍යවස්ථාව කෙටුම්පත් කිරීමට පෙර ප්‍රධාන දේශපාලන පක්ෂවල හා සුළු පක්ෂ නායකයන්ගේ මත විමසුමක් කළේය. ඒ සමඟ අපට නිදහස ලබාදීමට නිර්දේශ කළ සෝල්බරි කොමිසම හමුවේ නියෝජනය වූ විවිධ දේශපාලන මතද විමසා බැලීය. ඒ අනුව ශ්‍රීමත් ජෙනිංග්ස් කෙටුම්පත් කළ 1948 ප්‍රථම ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව 1972 ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජනරජයක් වනතෙක්ම නිර්බාධිතවම ක්‍රියාත්මක විය.",
        "අපේ දෙවැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව සම්පාදනය කළේ ව්‍යවස්ථා විශාරදයකු වන ආචාර්ය කොල්වින් ආර්. ද සිල්වාය. ඒ සඳහා යෝජනා ලබාගන්නට මුළු පාර්ලිමේන්තුවම ව්‍යවස්ථා සම්පාදන මණ්ඩලයක් බවට පත්කළ බව අපට මතකය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජනරජයක් කරමින් මෙරට සමඟ බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය කිරීටයට තිබූ අවසන් නිල බැඳීම අත්හිට වූ 1972 ජනරජ ව්‍යවස්ථාව ද 1978 වෙනසට භාජන වනතුරුම ගැටලු‍වකින් තොරව නිසියාකාරව පැවතුණි.",
        "1978 ජේ.ආර්. ජයවර්ධන මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් රාජ නීතිඥ එච්.ඩබ්ලිව්. ජයවර්ධන ප්‍රමුඛ නීතිඥ පිරිසක් විසින් සැකසූ 1978 ව්‍යවස්ථාව ගත වූ වසර 44 තුළ මේ වනවිට වාර 21 ක් සංශෝධනය කර තිබේ. 22 වැනි සංශෝධනය මැති සබයට දැන් ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇත. මෙමගින් වෙනස් කරන්නේ පසුගිය රජය සම්මත කළ 20 වැනි සංශෝධනයයි. එදා ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ ආණ්ඩුව බලයට පත්වූ පසු ගෙනා 20 වැනි සංශෝධනය ස්ථාපිත කළේ යහපාලන රජය සම්මත කරගත් 19 වැනි සංශෝධනය අහෝසි කරන්නටය. එය ඔවුන්ගේ මැතිවරණ පොරොන්දුවකි. යහපාලන රජය 19 වැනි සංශෝධනය ගෙන ආවේ ඊට පෙර පැවැති මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ රජයේ සම්මත කර තිබූ 18 වැනි සංශෝධනය අහෝසියටය. මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ රජය 18 වැනි සංශෝධනය ගෙන ආවේ ඊට පෙර ක්‍රියාත්මක කර තිබූ 17 වැනි සංශෝධනය අහෝසි කරන්නටය. මෙලෙස ව්‍යවස්ථා සම්පාදනයේ පූර්වාපර සන්ධි ගළපා බලන විට පෙනී යන්නේ 17 වැනි සංශෝධනයේ සිට 22 වැනි සංශෝධනය දක්වා ආණ්ඩුවෙන් ආණ්ඩුවට ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධන කර ඇති බවය. ඒ ඒ දේශපාලන පක්ෂවල පෞද්ගලික න්‍යාය පත්‍ර ඒ සඳහා මුල් වූ බව මෙහි දී පැහැදිලිව පෙනෙන කරුණකි.",
        "ව්‍යවස්ථා සම්පාදනය යනු ජාතික වශයෙන් වැදගත් වන පුළුල් කාරණාවකි. එය පෞද්ගලික දේශපාලන අරමුණුවලට ලඝු නොකළ යුතුය. එසේම ව්‍යවස්ථාවක් සම්පාදනය කිසියම් දේශපාලනඥයකු විසින් තනිව කළ යුත්තක් නොවේ. ඒ සඳහා පුළුල් සංවාදායක් හා ජනමත විමසුමක් අවශ්‍යය. එසේ නොවුණහොත් ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය ඊළඟ ආණ්ඩුවක දී නැවතත් සංශෝධනය වන බව පසුගිය වසර කිහිපය තිස්සේ සිදුවූ ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධන ක්‍රියාවලිය අධ්‍යයනය කරන විට පැහැදිලි වෙයි. මෙවර ඉදිරිපත් කර තිබෙන 22 වැනි ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනයට මැතිසබා බලතල පුළුල් කෙරෙන යෝජනා ඇතුළත් බව ප්‍රකාශ වී ඇත. ඒ ගැන සුබපතන අතරම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය පුළුල් සමාජ පිළිගැනීමකට ලක්වන ලෙස ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම එහි මතු පැවැත්ම සඳහා අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සාධකයක් බව සඳහන් කළ යුතුය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22 වැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "1978",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නියෝජිත මන්ත්‍රී මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunadasa Amarasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බී.ආර්.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1950",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්බෙඩ්කාර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එංගලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයිවර් ජෙනිංස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝල්බරි කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෙනිංස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1972",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොල්වින් ආර් ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනරජ ව්‍යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1972",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1978",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1978",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසර 44 තුළ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යහපාලන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "යහපාලන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැටිසබා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "22வது திருத்தத்திற்கு அனைத்து கட்சிகளின் ஒப்புதலை பெறுவோம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையில் நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதி முறைமையை அறிமுகப்படுத்திய 1978 ஆம் ஆண்டு அரசியலமைப்பு 22 ஆவது திருத்தத்திற்காக பிரதிநிதிகள் சபையில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. கடந்த காலங்களில் நாட்டின் பல பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தமே தீர்வு என எதிர்க்கட்சிகளின் பல பிரதான கட்சிகள் தெரிவித்திருந்தன. அதன்படி, அதற்கான பணிகள் முடிவடைந்துள்ளன. தாராளவாதக் கருத்துக்களைக் கொண்ட அரசியல் குழுக்கள் இதற்குப் பாராட்டுகளைத் தெரிவித்த அதேவேளை, தேசியத்தின் காரணத்திற்காக நிற்கும் பல அமைப்புகள் ஏற்கனவே 22 வது திருத்தத்திற்கு தங்கள் கடுமையான எதிர்ப்பை வெளிப்படுத்தியுள்ளன. அமைப்புக்கள் குழு சார்பில் கலாநிதி குணதாச அமரசேகர எழுத்து மூலம் சபாநாயகரிடம் தமது ஆட்சேபனையை சமர்ப்பித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கடந்த காலங்களில் இந்த நாட்டில் அரசியலமைப்பு உருவாக்கத்தில் காணப்பட்ட பொதுவான அம்சங்களில் ஒன்று அரசமைப்புத் திருத்தங்களை அரசாங்கத்திலிருந்து அரசாங்கத்திற்குக் கொண்டுவருவது. ஜே.ஆர் ஜனாதிபதி ஜயவர்தனவின் காலம் முதல் தற்போது வரை ஒவ்வொரு அரசாங்கமும் அவ்வப்போது அரசியலமைப்பை திருத்தியது. அந்த அரசாங்கங்கள் ஒவ்வொன்றும் அந்தந்த அரசியல் கட்சிகளின் கொள்கைகள் மற்றும் சில சமயங்களில் வெவ்வேறு அரசியல் கட்சிகளின் தனிப்பட்ட அபிலாஷைகளின் அடிப்படையில் அரசியலமைப்புத் திருத்தத்தை அடிப்படையாகக் கொண்டது. குறிப்பாக அரசியலமைப்பின் 17வது திருத்தம் முதல் இம்முறை முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட 22வது திருத்தம் வரை இந்தப் பண்பு வலுவாக கவனிக்கத்தக்கது.",
        "உலகின் பல நாடுகள் தங்கள் நாட்டின் மற்றும் தேசத்தின் அபிலாஷைகளை அடைவதற்காக அரசியலமைப்பை உருவாக்குகின்றன. 1950ல் இந்திய அரசியலமைப்புச் சட்டத்தை உருவாக்கிய சட்ட அறிஞர் டாக்டர் பி.ஆர். அம்பேத்கர் அரசியல் சாசனத்திற்கு முன் ஒரு விரிவான அரசியல் கருத்துக்கணிப்பை நடத்தினார். மேலும், இந்த நாட்டில் அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்ட முதல் அரசியலமைப்பின் மாதிரியை நாங்கள் இங்கிலாந்தின் வைட்ஹால் அரசியலமைப்பு அதிகாரத்திடமிருந்து பெற்றோம், ஆனால் இந்த நாட்டில் அதைச் செம்மைப்படுத்திய அரசியலமைப்பு நிபுணர் சர் ஐவர் ஜென்னிங்ஸ், வரைவுக்கு முன் முக்கிய அரசியல் கட்சிகள் மற்றும் சிறு கட்சித் தலைவர்களின் கருத்துக் கணிப்பை நடத்தினார். அரசியலமைப்பு. அதனுடன், சோல்பரி கமிஷனின் முன் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தப்பட்ட பல்வேறு அரசியல் கருத்துக்களையும் அவர் ஆய்வு செய்தார், அது எங்களுக்கு சுதந்திரம் வழங்க பரிந்துரைத்தது. அதன்படி சேர் ஜென்னிங்ஸ் அவர்களால் உருவாக்கப்பட்ட 1948 ஆம் ஆண்டின் முதலாவது அரசியலமைப்பு 1972 ஆம் ஆண்டு இலங்கை குடியரசாக மாறும் வரை முழுமையாக அமுலில் இருந்தது.",
        "நமது இரண்டாவது அரசியலமைப்பை அரசியலமைப்பு அறிஞர் டாக்டர் கொல்வின் ஆர். டி சில்வா. அதற்கான முன்மொழிவுகளைப் பெறுவதற்காக முழு நாடாளுமன்றமும் அரசியலமைப்பை உருவாக்கும் அமைப்பாக மாற்றப்பட்டதை நாங்கள் நினைவில் கொள்கிறோம். இலங்கையை குடியரசாக மாற்றியதன் மூலம் பிரித்தானிய மகுடத்தின் கடைசி உத்தியோகபூர்வ உறவுகளை 1972 ஆம் ஆண்டு இடைநிறுத்திய குடியரசு அரசியலமைப்பு 1978 இல் மாற்றப்படும் வரை எந்த பிரச்சனையும் இல்லாமல் நடைமுறையில் இருந்தது.",
        "1978 ஜே.ஆர். ஜயவர்தன தலைமையில், எச்.டபிள்யூ. ஜயவர்தன தலைமையிலான சட்டத்தரணிகள் குழுவினால் உருவாக்கப்பட்ட 1978ஆம் ஆண்டு அரசியலமைப்பு கடந்த 44 வருடங்களில் 21 தடவைகள் திருத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது. 22ஆவது திருத்தச் சட்டம் தற்போது சபையில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. இது கடந்த அரசாங்கத்தினால் நிறைவேற்றப்பட்ட 20வது திருத்தத்தை மாற்றியுள்ளது. கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச அரசாங்கம் ஆட்சிக்கு வந்த பின்னர் யஹபாலன அரசாங்கத்தினால் நிறைவேற்றப்பட்ட 19 ஆவது திருத்தத்தை நீக்குவதற்காக 20 ஆவது திருத்தத்தை ஏற்படுத்தியது. இது அவர்களின் தேர்தல் வாக்குறுதி. கடந்த மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ அரசாங்கத்தினால் நிறைவேற்றப்பட்ட 18 ஆவது திருத்தத்தை இரத்துச் செய்ய யஹபாலன அரசாங்கம் 19 ஆவது திருத்தத்தை கொண்டு வந்தது. அதற்கு முன்னர் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட்ட 17ஆவது திருத்தத்தை இரத்துச் செய்யும் வகையில் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ அரசாங்கம் 18ஆவது திருத்தத்தைக் கொண்டு வந்தது. இவ்வாறாக, அரசியலமைப்பு உருவாக்கத்தின் முன்னுதாரணங்களை ஒப்பிட்டுப் பார்க்கும் போது, ​​17வது திருத்தத்திலிருந்து 22வது திருத்தம் வரை, அரசியலமைப்புகள் அரசாங்கத்திலிருந்து அரசாங்கத்திற்கு திருத்தப்பட்டிருப்பதைக் காணமுடிகிறது. ஒவ்வொரு அரசியல் கட்சிகளின் தனிப்பட்ட நிகழ்ச்சி நிரல்களே இதற்குக் காரணம் என்பது தெளிவான உண்மை.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பு உருவாக்கம் என்பது தேசிய முக்கியத்துவம் வாய்ந்த ஒரு பரந்த விஷயம். தனிப்பட்ட அரசியல் நோக்கங்களுக்காக அதை பயன்படுத்தக் கூடாது. அத்துடன் அரசியலமைப்புச் சட்டத்தை உருவாக்குவது எந்தவொரு அரசியல்வாதியாலும் மட்டும் செய்யப்படக் கூடாது. அதற்கு பரந்துபட்ட உரையாடல் மற்றும் வாக்கெடுப்பு தேவை. இல்லை என்றால், அடுத்த அரசாங்கத்தில் மீண்டும் அரசியலமைப்புத் திருத்தம் திருத்தப்படும். இம்முறை முன்வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள 22வது அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தத்தில் மதிசபாவின் அதிகாரங்களை விஸ்தரிக்கும் யோசனைகள் உள்ளடக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. அதற்கு வாழ்த்து தெரிவிக்கும் அதே வேளையில், சமூகத்தால் பரவலாக ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்படும் வகையில் அரசியலமைப்புத் திருத்தத்தை அமுல்படுத்துவது அதன் எதிர்கால இருப்புக்கு இன்றியமையாத காரணியாகும் என்பதைக் குறிப்பிட வேண்டும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22வது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "1978",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரதிநிதிகள் சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunadasa Amarasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "17வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பி.ஆர்.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1950",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பேத்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இங்கிலாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐவர் ஜென்னிங்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோல்பரி கமிஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜென்னிங்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1972",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொல்வின் ஆர். டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடியரசு அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1972",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1978",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1978",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த 44 ஆண்டுகளாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யஹபாலன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "யஹபாலன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதிசபா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}