{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132356",
  "time_ut": 1658917801,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "நல்லாட்சியை முன்னெடுக்க தொடர்ந்தும் அமெரிக்கா ஒத்துழைக்கும் - ஜனாதிபதியிடம் அமெரிக்கத் தூதுவர் தெரிவிப்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "US will continue to cooperate to advance good governance - US Ambassador to President",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "US Ambassador to Sri Lanka Julie Chung said that the United States will continue to provide cooperation to Sri Lanka to advance good governance that respects human rights and listens to the aspirations of the people.",
        "He said this while meeting President Ranil Wickremesinghe at the President's Office today.",
        "During this we discussed how the political and economic crises in Sri Lanka have developed and how the two countries can travel together towards a brighter future.",
        "Our country and its people have been maintaining friendly relations with Sri Lanka for 70 years.",
        "Accordingly, the United States will continue to provide cooperation to advance good governance in Sri Lanka that respects human rights and listens to the aspirations of the people.' mentioned that.",
        "This is the second meeting with the US Ambassador since the inauguration of President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "It is worth noting that the US ambassador met President Ranil Wickremesinghe on the 22nd and discussed the attacks on the demonstrators."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 22nd",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යහපාලනය ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාමට අමෙරිකාව අඛණ්ඩව සහයෝගයෙන් කටයුතු කරනවා - ජනපතිගේ ඇමෙරිකානු තානාපති",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "මානව හිමිකම්වලට ගරු කරන, ජනතා අභිලාෂයන්ට සවන් දෙන යහපාලනය ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාමට අමෙරිකාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අඛණ්ඩව සහයෝගීතාව ලබා දෙන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අමෙරිකානු තානාපතිනි ජුලී චුන්ග් මහත්මිය පැවසුවාය.",
        "ඔහු මේ බව පැවසුවේ අද ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේ දී ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ හමුවූ අවස්ථාවේදී ය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දේශපාලන හා ආර්ථික අර්බුද වර්ධනය වී ඇති ආකාරය සහ දෙරට එක්ව දීප්තිමත් අනාගතයක් කරා ගමන් කරන්නේ කෙසේද යන්න පිළිබඳව අපි මෙහිදී සාකච්ඡා කළා.",
        "අපේ රට සහ එහි ජනතාව වසර 70 ක් තිස්සේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ මිත්‍රශීලී සබඳතා පවත්වයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව මානව හිමිකම්වලට ගරු කරන, ජනතා අභිලාෂයන්ට සවන් දෙන යහපාලනය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාමට අමෙරිකාව අඛණ්ඩව සහයෝගය ලබා දෙනවා.' බව සඳහන් කළා.",
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පදවි ප්‍රාප්තියෙන් පසු ඇමරිකානු තානාපතිවරයා හමුවන දෙවන අවස්ථාව මෙයයි.",
        "අමෙරිකානු තානාපතිවරයා පසුගිය 22 වැනිදා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ හමුවී විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට එල්ල වූ ප්‍රහාර සම්බන්ධයෙන් සාකච්ඡා කළ බව සඳහන් කිරීම වටී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 70 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நல்லாட்சியை முன்னெடுக்க தொடர்ந்தும் அமெரிக்கா ஒத்துழைக்கும் - ஜனாதிபதியிடம் அமெரிக்கத் தூதுவர் தெரிவிப்பு",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "மனித உரிமைகளுக்கு மதிப்பளித்து, மக்களின் அபிலாஷைகளுக்கு செவி சாய்க்கும் நல்லாட்சியை முன்னெடுத்துச் செல்வதற்கு இலங்கைக்கு அமெரிக்கா தொடர்ந்தும் ஒத்துழைப்புக்களை வழங்கும் என்று இலங்கைக்கான அமெரிக்க தூதுவர் ஜூலி சுங் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை இன்று புதன்கிழமை ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகத்தில் சந்தித்த போதே அவர் இவ்வாறு தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் அரசியல் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிகள் எவ்வாறு உருவாகின என்பது தொடர்பிலும் , சுபீட்சமான எதிர்காலமொன்றை நோக்கிச் செல்வதற்கு எவ்வாறு இரு நாடுகளும் இணைந்து பயணிக்க முடியும் என்பது தொடர்பிலும் இதன் போது கலந்துரையாடினோம்",
        "எமது நாடும், நாட்டு மக்களும் 70 ஆண்டுகளாக இலங்கையுடன் நட்புறவைப் பேணி வருகின்றன.",
        "அதற்கமைய மனித உரிமைகளுக்கு மதிப்பளித்து, மக்களின் அபிலாஷைகளுக்கு செவிசாய்க்கும் நல்லாட்சியை இலங்கையில் முன்னெடுத்துச் செல்வதற்கு அமெரிக்கா தொடர்ந்தும் ஒத்துழைப்புக்களை வழங்கும்.' என்று குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பதவியேற்றதன் பின்னர் அமெரிக்க தூதுவருடன் இடம்பெற்ற இரண்டாவது சந்திப்பு இதுவாகும்.",
        "கடந்த 22 ஆம் திகதி ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை சந்தித்த அமெரிக்க தூதுவர் , ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் மீது மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட தாக்குதல்கள் தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடியிருந்தமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}