{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/President-directs-quicker-streamlined-fuel-distribution/56-737870",
  "time_ut": 1658689601,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President directs quicker streamlined fuel distribution",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President directs quicker streamlined fuel distribution",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe has instructed the relevant officials to accelerate and regularise the islandwide fuel distribution process.",
        "The President gave these instructions during a discussion held at the Prime Minister’s Office on Saturday on the fuel issue and its next steps. There was a wide-ranging discussion regarding regularising and expediting the distribution of fuel needed for private and government buses used for public transportation, as well as fuel needed for education, fishing, tourism and agriculture sectors.",
        "Education Minister Susil Premajayantha drew the attention of the President regarding the provision of necessary transportation facilities for the school children as the schools will be opened throughout the island from next Monday. Accordingly, President instructed the Minister of Transport to issue fuel for buses and vans transporting school children from 3 p.m. today at all Sri Lanka Transport Board depots (SLTB) across the island.",
        "According to the previous system, it was decided to issue fuel from SLTB depots and at the three armed forces camps all over the island for agricultural activities including fertiliser distribution, fishing, tourism as well as for public transport activities.",
        "Attention was also paid to the smuggling of fuel obtained from fuel stations and selling at higher prices. The President instructed the Police to expand raids and strictly enforce the law against the individuals and groups involved in black marketing.",
        "The implementation of the introduced QR code system was also discussed. There was also a long discussion between President, officials of the Finance Ministry and the State banks on fuel procurement and the provision of the necessary funds for purchase of fuel.",
        "Ministers Susil Premajayantha, Bandula Gunawardena, Mahinda Amaraweera, Ali Sabri, Kanchana Wijesekera, Tiran Alles, MP Nimal Lanza, Presidential Adviser Sagala Ratnayake, Secretary to the President Saman Ekanayake and Secretaries of line Ministries, senior officials of the President’s Office, the Ministry of Finance and the State Bank were present at this discussion."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Susil Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "next Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Minister of Transport",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Transport Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Finance Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Susil Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tiran Alles",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nimal Lanza",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sagala Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the President’s Office",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the State Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කඩිනම් ඉන්ධන බෙදා හැරීමට ජනපති උපදෙස් දෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දීප ව්‍යාප්ත ඉන්ධන බෙදා හැරීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය කඩිනම් කර විධිමත් කරන ලෙස ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අදාළ නිලධාරීන්ට උපදෙස් දී තිබේ.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා මෙම උපදෙස් ලබා දුන්නේ ඉන්ධන ගැටලුව සහ එහි ඉදිරි ක්‍රියාමාර්ග පිළිබඳව සෙනසුරාදා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයේ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවකදීය. අධ්‍යාපන, ධීවර, සංචාරක, කෘෂිකර්ම යන ක්ෂේත්‍රවලට අවශ්‍ය ඉන්ධන මෙන්ම පොදු ප්‍රවාහනය සඳහා භාවිත කරන පෞද්ගලික සහ රජයේ බස් රථ සඳහා අවශ්‍ය ඉන්ධන විධිමත් කිරීම සහ කඩිනම් කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් මෙහිදී පුළුල් සාකච්ඡාවක් ඇති විය.",
        "ලබන සඳුදා සිට දිවයින පුරා පාසල් විවෘත කිරීමට නියමිත බැවින් පාසල් දරුවන්ට අවශ්‍ය ප්‍රවාහන පහසුකම් සැලසීම පිළිබඳව අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍ය සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ අවධානය යොමු කළා. ඒ අනුව පාසල් සිසුන් ප්‍රවාහනය කරන බස් රථ සහ වෑන් රථ සඳහා පස්වරු 3 සිට ඉන්ධන නිකුත් කරන ලෙස ජනාධිපතිතුමා ප්‍රවාහන අමාත්‍යවරයාට උපදෙස් දුන්නේය. අද දිවයින පුරා පිහිටි සියලුම ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයේ ඩිපෝ (ශ්‍රී ලංගම) වලදී.",
        "පොහොර බෙදා හැරීම, ධීවර කර්මාන්තය, සංචාරක කර්මාන්තය මෙන්ම පොදු ප්‍රවාහන කටයුතු ඇතුළු කෘෂිකාර්මික කටයුතු සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංගම ඩිපෝවලින් සහ දිවයින පුරා පිහිටි ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදා කඳවුරුවලින් ඉන්ධන නිකුත් කිරීමට පෙර පැවැති ක්‍රමයට තීරණය විය.",
        "ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල්වලින් ලබාගන්නා ඉන්ධන හොර රහසේ ගෙනැවිත් වැඩි මිලට අලෙවි කිරීම පිළිබඳව ද අවධානය යොමු විය. වැටලීම් පුළුල් කර කළු අළෙවි කරන පුද්ගලයන්ට සහ කණ්ඩායම්වලට එරෙහිව නීතිය දැඩිව ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන ලෙස ජනාධිපතිවරයා පොලිසියට උපදෙස් දුන්නේය.",
        "හඳුන්වා දුන් QR කේත පද්ධතිය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම පිළිබඳව ද මෙහිදී සාකච්ඡා කෙරිණි. ඉන්ධන මිලදී ගැනීම සහ ඉන්ධන මිලදී ගැනීම සඳහා අවශ්‍ය මුදල් ලබාදීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ද ජනාධිපතිවරයා, මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයේ සහ රාජ්‍ය බැංකු නිලධාරීන් අතර දීර්ඝ වශයෙන් සාකච්ඡා කෙරිණි.",
        "අමාත්‍යවරුන් වන සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත, බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන, මහින්ද අමරවීර, අලි සබ්‍රි, කාංචන විජේසේකර, ටිරාන් අලස්, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී නිමල් ලාන්සා, ජනාධිපති උපදේශක සාගල රත්නායක, ජනාධිපති ලේකම් සමන් ඒකනායක සහ රේඛීය අමාත්‍යාංශ ලේකම්වරුන්, ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරීන්, ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරීන්, මෙම සාකච්ඡාවට මූල්‍ය සහ රාජ්‍ය බැංකුව එක්ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රවාහන ඇමති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 ප.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටිරාන් අලස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිමල් ලාන්සා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගල රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "விரைவான நெறிப்படுத்தப்பட்ட எரிபொருள் விநியோகத்தை ஜனாதிபதி வழிநடத்துகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் எரிபொருள் விநியோக நடவடிக்கைகளை துரிதப்படுத்தி முறைப்படுத்துமாறு ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க உரிய அதிகாரிகளுக்கு பணிப்புரை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "எரிபொருள் பிரச்சினை மற்றும் அதன் அடுத்த கட்ட நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்து பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்தில் நேற்று சனிக்கிழமை இடம்பெற்ற கலந்துரையாடலின் போதே ஜனாதிபதி இந்த அறிவுறுத்தல்களை வழங்கினார். கல்வி, மீன்பிடி, சுற்றுலா, விவசாயம் ஆகிய துறைகளுக்கு தேவையான எரிபொருளையும், பொது போக்குவரத்திற்கு பயன்படுத்தப்படும் தனியார் மற்றும் அரசு பஸ்களுக்கு தேவையான எரிபொருளை முறைப்படுத்துவது மற்றும் விரைவுபடுத்துவது குறித்து விரிவான விவாதம் நடைபெற்றது.",
        "எதிர்வரும் திங்கட்கிழமை முதல் நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் பாடசாலைகள் திறக்கப்படவுள்ள நிலையில் பாடசாலை மாணவர்களுக்கு தேவையான போக்குவரத்து வசதிகளை ஏற்படுத்திக் கொடுப்பது தொடர்பில் கல்வி அமைச்சர் சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த ஜனாதிபதியின் கவனத்திற்கு கொண்டுவந்தார். இதன்படி, பாடசாலை மாணவர்களை ஏற்றிச் செல்லும் பஸ்கள் மற்றும் வான்களுக்கான எரிபொருளை பிற்பகல் 3 மணி முதல் வழங்குமாறு போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சருக்கு ஜனாதிபதி பணிப்புரை விடுத்தார். இன்று நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் அனைத்து இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை டிப்போக்களிலும் (SLTB)",
        "முன்னைய முறைப்படி உர விநியோகம், மீன்பிடித்தல், சுற்றுலா மற்றும் பொதுப் போக்குவரத்துச் செயற்பாடுகள் உள்ளிட்ட விவசாய நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் களஞ்சியசாலைகள் மற்றும் முப்படை முகாம்களில் இருந்து எரிபொருளை வழங்குவதற்கு தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையங்களில் இருந்து பெறப்படும் எரிபொருளை கடத்தல் மற்றும் அதிக விலைக்கு விற்பனை செய்வது தொடர்பிலும் கவனம் செலுத்தப்பட்டது. கறுப்புச் சந்தைகளில் ஈடுபடும் நபர்கள் மற்றும் குழுக்களுக்கு எதிராக சோதனைகளை விரிவுபடுத்துமாறும் சட்டத்தை கடுமையாக அமுல்படுத்துமாறும் ஜனாதிபதி பொலிஸாருக்கு பணிப்புரை விடுத்தார்.",
        "அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்ட QR குறியீடு முறையை செயல்படுத்துவது குறித்தும் விவாதிக்கப்பட்டது. ஜனாதிபதி, நிதி அமைச்சின் அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் அரச வங்கிகளுக்கு இடையில் எரிபொருள் கொள்வனவு மற்றும் எரிபொருளை கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்கு தேவையான நிதியை வழங்குவது தொடர்பில் நீண்ட கலந்துரையாடல் இடம்பெற்றது.",
        "அமைச்சர்களான சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த, பந்துல குணவர்தன, மஹிந்த அமரவீர, அலி சப்ரி, காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர, திரான் அலஸ், பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் நிமல் லான்சா, ஜனாதிபதியின் ஆலோசகர் சாகல ரத்நாயக்க, ஜனாதிபதியின் செயலாளர் சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க மற்றும் அமைச்சுக்களின் செயலாளர்கள், ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலக சிரேஷ்ட அதிகாரிகள். இந்த விவாதத்தில் நிதி மற்றும் ஸ்டேட் வங்கி கலந்து கொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த திங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதியம் 3 மணி.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிரன் அலஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிமல் லான்சா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகல ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்டேட் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}