{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131689",
  "time_ut": 1658129745,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "50 கண்ணீர் புகை குண்டுகளுடன் ஒருவர் கைது",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "One arrested with 50 tear gas shells",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Police Media Unit has informed that a person has been arrested in connection with the incident of attacking a group of police officers and stealing 50 teargas shells from them during a demonstration near Poltua Junction, Pattaramullai on 13th July.",
        "Commenting on the incident, Police Media Spokesperson, Senior Superintendent of Police Nihal Talduwa said,",
        "During the anti-government demonstration near Poltua Junction, a police team carrying 50 tear gas shells on a three-wheeler blocked the three-wheeler and attacked the police officers and 50 tear gas shells were stolen from them by the protesters.",
        "In this case, the suspect in connection with the said incident, Obeysekara, has been arrested by the Welikadai police in Pura Nanayakkara Mavathi.",
        "Also, Poralai is a temporary resident of Gotami area and has hidden 50 tear gas shells in his dormitory room.",
        "He further informed that the arrested person is a 31-year-old from Polonnaruwa area and the suspect will be produced in the Magistrate's Court."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "One",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "50",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Police Media Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poltua Junction",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13th July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Poltua Junction",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Obeysekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welikadai",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pura Nanayakkara Mavathi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Poralai",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotami",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "31-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polonnaruwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කඳුළු ගෑස් උණ්ඩ 50ක් සමඟ අයෙක් අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "පසුගිය ජුලි 13 වනදා පත්තරමුල්ල, පොල්තුවා හන්දිය අසල පැවති විරෝධතාවයේදී පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් පිරිසකට පහර දී කඳුළු ගෑස් උණ්ඩ 50ක් සොරකම් කිරීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් පුද්ගලයෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති බව පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය ඒකකය දැනුම් දී තිබේ.",
        "සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අදහස් දැක්වූ පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක, ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නිහාල් තල්දූව.",
        "පොල්තුවා හන්දිය අසලදී රජයට එරෙහි විරෝධතාවයේදී ත්‍රිරෝද රථයකින් කඳුළු ගෑස් උණ්ඩ 50ක් රැගෙන පැමිණි පොලිස් කණ්ඩායමක් ත්‍රිරෝද රථය අවහිර කර පොලිස් නිලධාරීන්ට පහර දී ඔවුන් සතුව තිබූ කඳුළු ගෑස් උණ්ඩ 50ක් විරෝධතාකරුවන් විසින් පැහැරගෙන ගොස් තිබේ.",
        "මෙම සිද්ධියට අදාළව ඔබේසේකර නමැති සැකකරු වැලිකඩ පොලිසිය විසින් පුර නානායක්කාර මාවති ප්‍රදේශයේදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "එමෙන්ම පොරලෙයි ගෝතමී ප්‍රදේශයේ තාවකාලික පදිංචිකරුවෙකු වන අතර ඔහු තම නේවාසිකාගාරයේ කඳුළු ගෑස් උණ්ඩ 50ක් සඟවාගෙන ඇත.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් පුද්ගලයා පොළොන්නරුව ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 31 හැවිරිදි අයෙකු බවත් සැකකරු මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කරන බවත් ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් දන්වා සිටියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "50",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොල්තුවා හන්දිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොල්තුවා හන්දිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඔබේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුර නානායක්කාර මාවති",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොරලෙයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotami",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "31 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොළොන්නරුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "50 கண்ணீர் புகை குண்டுகளுடன் ஒருவர் கைது",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "பத்தரமுல்லை, பொல்துவ சந்திக்கு அருகில் ஜூலை மாதம் 13 ஆம் திகதி நடைபெற்ற ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தின் போது பொலிஸ் அதிகாரிகள் குழுவொன்றை தாக்கி அவர்களிடமிருந்து 50 கண்ணீர் புகை குண்டுகளை திருடிச் சென்ற சம்பவத்துடன் தொடர்புடைய ஒருவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸ் ஊடகப்பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் பொலிஸ் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர், சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகருமான நிஹால் தல்துவ கருத்து தெரிவிக்கையில்,",
        "பொல்துவ  சந்திக்கு அருகில் இடம்பெற்ற அரச எதிர்ப்பு ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தின் போது பொலிஸ் குழுவொன்று முச்சக்கர வண்டியில் 50 கண்ணீர் புகை குண்டுகளை ஏற்றிச் சென்ற போது முச்சக்கரவண்டியை வழி மறித்து பொலிஸ் அதிகாரிகளை தாக்கி அவர்களிடமிருந்து 50 கண்ணீர் புகை குண்டுகள் போராட்டக்காரர்களால் திருடப்பட்டது.",
        "இந்நிலையில், குறித்த சம்பவத்துடன் தொடர்புடைய சந்தேக நபர் ஒபேசேகர, புர நாணயக்கார மாவத்தையில் வைத்து வெலிக்கடை பொலிஸாரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "மேலும்,பொரளை, கோதமி பிரதேசத்தில் தற்காலிகமாக தங்கியிருப்பவர் என்றும் அவரது தங்குமிட அறையில் 50 கண்ணீர் புகை குண்டுகளை மறைத்து வைத்துள்ளார்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர் 31 வயதுடைய பொலன்னறுவை பிரதேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்தவர் என்றும் சந்தேகநபரை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றில் ஆஜர்படுத்தப்பட உள்ளதாகவும் அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஒன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "50",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொலிஸ் ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொல்டுவா சந்திப்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொல்டுவா சந்திப்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒபேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வேலிக்கடை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புற நாணயக்கார மாவதி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொறளை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotami",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "31 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலன்னறுவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}