{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/28/grace-period-for-vehicle-revenue-licenses/",
  "time_ut": 1656430920,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Grace period for vehicle revenue licenses",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Grace period for vehicle revenue licenses",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); A grace period has been granted for vehicles registered in the Western Province to obtain vehicle revenue licenses.",
        "A statement issued by the Chief Secretary of the Western Province, Jayanthi Wijetunga states that a grace period will be given until the 29th of July.",
        "The statement adds that no fines will be levied during the relevant grace period."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayanthi Wijetunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 29th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වාහන ආදායම් බලපත්‍ර සඳහා සහන කාලයක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); බස්නාහිර පළාතේ ලියාපදිංචි වාහන සඳහා වාහන ආදායම් බලපත්‍ර ලබාගැනීම සඳහා සහන කාලයක් ලබාදී තිබෙනවා.",
        "බස්නාහිර පළාත් ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් ජයන්ති විජේතුංග මහත්මිය නිකුත් කළ නිවේදනයක දැක්වෙන්නේ ජූලි 29 වැනිදා දක්වා සහන කාලයක් ලබාදෙන බවයි.",
        "අදාළ සහන කාලය තුළ කිසිදු දඩ මුදලක් අය නොකරන බවද එම නිවේදනයේ වැඩිදුරටත් දැක්වෙයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ති විජේතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 29 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வாகன வருவாய் உரிமங்களுக்கான சலுகை காலம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); மேல்மாகாணத்தில் பதிவு செய்யப்பட்ட வாகனங்களுக்கு வாகன வருமான அனுமதிப்பத்திரத்தை பெற்றுக் கொள்வதற்கு கால அவகாசம் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "எதிர்வரும் ஜுலை மாதம் 29 ஆம் திகதி வரை கால அவகாசம் வழங்கப்படும் என மேல்மாகாண பிரதம செயலாளர் ஜெயந்தி விஜேதுங்க விடுத்துள்ள அறிக்கையில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "தொடர்புடைய சலுகைக் காலத்தில் அபராதம் விதிக்கப்பட மாட்டாது என்றும் அந்த அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயந்தி விஜேதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 29 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}