{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/02/injunction-order-issued-against-nurses-tu-action/",
  "time_ut": 1662132960,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Injunction order issued against Nurses TU action",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Injunction order issued against Nurses TU action",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); An injunction order was issued to the Public Service United Nurses Association, by the Colombo District Court.",
        "The court has ordered for the immediate suspension of the nursing trade union action in the southern province, with Mahmodara Hospital as the primary focus.",
        "The order was issued after facts were presented before Justice Poornima Paranagama of the Colombo District Court citing that the patients will be affected by the trade union action which is taking place due to controversy between family health officers and nurses.",
        "The Attorney General's Department had requested the relevant injunction order from the court."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Nurses TU",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Public Service United Nurses Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo District Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahmodara Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Poornima Paranagama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo District Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the trade union",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හෙද TU ක්‍රියාවට එරෙහිව වාරණ නියෝගයක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); කොළඹ දිසා අධිකරණය මගින් රාජ්‍ය සේවා එක්සත් හෙද සංගමයට වාරණ නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කරන ලදී.",
        "මහමෝදර රෝහල මූලික කරගනිමින් දකුණු පළාතේ හෙද වෘත්තීය සමිති ක්‍රියාමාර්ගය වහාම අත්හිටුවන ලෙස අධිකරණය නියෝග කර තිබේ.",
        "පවුල් සෞඛ්‍ය නිලධාරීන් සහ හෙදියන් අතර පවතින මතභේදයක් හේතුවෙන් ක්‍රියාත්මක වන වෘත්තීය සමිති ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයෙන් රෝගීන් පීඩාවට පත්වන බව පවසමින් කොළඹ දිසා අධිකරණයේ විනිසුරු පූර්ණිමා පරණගම මහත්මිය හමුවේ කරුණු ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුව මෙම නියෝගය නිකුත් කර ඇත.",
        "නීතිපති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව අදාළ වාරණ නියෝගය අධිකරණයෙන් ඉල්ලා තිබුණා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හෙදියන් TU",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්‍ය සේවා එක්සත් හෙද සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ දිසා අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහමෝදර රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පූර්ණිමා පරණගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ දිසා අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෘත්තීය සමිතිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "செவிலியர்கள் TU நடவடிக்கைக்கு தடை உத்தரவு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பொதுச் சேவை ஐக்கிய தாதியர் சங்கத்திற்கு கொழும்பு மாவட்ட நீதிமன்றத்தினால் தடை உத்தரவு பிறப்பிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "மஹ்மோதர வைத்தியசாலையை முதன்மையாகக் கொண்டு தென் மாகாணத்தில் முன்னெடுக்கப்படும் தாதியர் தொழிற்சங்க நடவடிக்கையை உடனடியாக இடைநிறுத்துமாறு நீதிமன்றம் உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "குடும்ப சுகாதார உத்தியோகத்தர்களுக்கும் தாதியர்களுக்கும் இடையில் இடம்பெற்றுவரும் தொழிற்சங்க நடவடிக்கையினால் நோயாளர்கள் பாதிக்கப்படுவார்கள் என கொழும்பு மாவட்ட நீதிமன்ற நீதியரசர் பூர்ணிமா பரணகம முன்னிலையில் ஆஜர்படுத்தப்பட்ட போதே இந்த உத்தரவு பிறப்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இது தொடர்பான தடை உத்தரவை சட்டமா அதிபர் திணைக்களம் நீதிமன்றத்திடம் கோரியிருந்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "செவிலியர்கள் TU",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது சேவை ஐக்கிய செவிலியர் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு மாவட்ட நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹ்மோதரா மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பூர்ணிமா பரணகம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு மாவட்ட நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொழிற்சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}