{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/தடை-நீக்கப்பட்ட-அமைப்புகளே-குற்றச்சாட்டை-முன்வைத்தன/175-302648",
  "time_ut": 1660936134,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "தடை நீக்கப்பட்ட அமைப்புகளே குற்றச்சாட்டை முன்வைத்தன",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "It was the de-banned organizations that made the allegations",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Today, it was the diaspora organizations whose ban was lifted that passed the motion in Geneva that the Sri Lankan Army was involved in war allegations.",
        "Former Chairperson of the Sri Lankan Human Rights Commission Professor Pradeepa Mahanamaheva said that the reason for lifting the ban on them is unknown.",
        "He said the above while addressing a meeting held yesterday (19) at the Government Information Department regarding media reporting on national security and law.",
        "During the Tsunami, the Triforce and the Police performed well. There was no talk in Geneva about the humanitarian action of the triads in this matter. Even during the corona infection, the soldiers performed well in the corona quarantine stations. Our country's media did not say anything about this. He said that while this is the case, people in Geneva will not have a chance to learn about the humanitarian activities of our country's soldiers.",
        "Today, six diaspora organizations have been banned in Sri Lanka. He said he did not know why the ban on the said organizations was lifted. A priest and I, a member of one of the said organizations, had a face-to-face discussion of the war accusations during the Geneva session.",
        "It was they who passed the resolution in Geneva that the Sri Lankan army was guilty of war. So now the government should use this opportunity to stop the propaganda being put forward by them against the army.",
        "It is people from these 6 organizations who are teaching students in classes that the military committed inhumane war crimes on May 19, 2009. He said that it was the members of these organizations who gave the list of names of soldiers to foreign countries to take legal action against them, saying that many people in the army were involved in war crimes."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Geneva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pradeepa Mahanamaheva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government Information Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tsunami",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Geneva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Geneva",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Geneva",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Geneva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 19, 2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තහනම් කළ සංවිධාන තමයි චෝදනා කළේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අද ශ්‍රී ලංකා හමුදාව යුද චෝදනාවලට සම්බන්ධ බවට ජිනීවාහිදී යෝජනාව සම්මත කළේ තහනම ඉවත් කළ ඩයස්පෝරා සංවිධානයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසමේ හිටපු සභාපතිනී මහාචාර්ය ප්‍රදීපා මහානාමහේවා කියා සිටියේ ඔවුන්ට පනවා තිබූ තහනම ඉවත් කිරීමට හේතුව නොදන්නා බවයි.",
        "ජාතික ආරක්ෂාව සහ නීතිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ඊයේ (19) පැවති රැස්වීමක් අමතමින් ඔහු ඉහත ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "සුනාමියේදී ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාව සහ පොලිසිය හොඳින් ක්‍රියා කළා. මේ කාරණයේදී ත්‍රිත්වයේ මානුෂීය ක්‍රියාමාර්ගය ගැන ජිනීවාවල කතා වුණේ නැහැ. කොරෝනා ආසාදනය වූ අවස්ථාවේදී පවා සෙබළුන් කොරෝනා නිරෝධායන මධ්‍යස්ථානවල හොඳින් ක්‍රියා කළා. අපේ රටේ මාධ්‍ය මේ ගැන කිසිම දෙයක් කිව්වේ නැහැ. තත්ත්වය එසේ තිබියදී අපේ රටේ සෙබළුන්ගේ මානුෂීය ක්‍රියාකාරකම් ගැන ඉගෙන ගැනීමට ජිනීවා ජනතාවට අවස්ථාවක් නොලැබෙන බවද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "අද ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඩයස්පෝරා සංවිධාන හයක් තහනම් කර ඇත. එම සංවිධානවලට පනවා තිබූ තහනම ඉවත් කළේ මන්දැයි තමන් නොදන්නා බවද ඔහු පැවසීය. ජිනීවා සැසිවාරයේදී යුද චෝදනා සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉහත කී එක් සංවිධානයක සාමාජිකයකු වන පූජකවරයකු සහ මම මුහුණට මුහුණ සාකච්ඡා කළෙමු.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා හමුදාව යුද්ධයට වැරදිකරු බවට ජිනීවාහිදී යෝජනාව සම්මත කළේ ඔවුන්ය. ඉතින් දැන්වත් ආණ්ඩුව මේ අවස්ථාව යොදාගත යුතුයි ඔවුන් හමුදාවට එරෙහිව ගෙන යන ප්‍රචාර නතර කරන්න.",
        "2009 මැයි 19 වෙනිදා හමුදාව අමානුෂික යුද අපරාධ කළා කියලා සිසුන්ට පන්තිවල උගන්වන්නේ මේ සංවිධාන 6ක අය. යුද හමුදාවේ බොහෝ පිරිසක් යුද අපරාධවලට සම්බන්ධ බව පවසමින් ඔවුන්ට එරෙහිව නීතිමය ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගැනීමට විදේශ රටවලට සෙබළුන්ගේ නාම ලේඛනය ලබා දුන්නේ මෙම සංවිධානවල සාමාජිකයන් බව ද ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිනීවා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රදීපා මහානාමහේවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුනාමිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිනීවා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිනීවා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිනීවා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජිනීවා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයා",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009 මැයි 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தடை நீக்கப்பட்ட அமைப்புகளே குற்றச்சாட்டை முன்வைத்தன",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "இன்று  தடை நீக்கப்பட்டுள்ள புலம்பெயர் அமைப்புகள் தான் ஜெனிவாவில் இலங்கை இராணுவத்தினர் யுத்தக் குற்றச்சாட்டில் ஈடுபட்டதாக ஜெனிவாவில் பிரேரணையை  நிறைவேற்றினர்.",
        "அவர்கள் மீதான தடை நீக்கப்பட காரணம் என்னவென தெரியவில்லை என இலங்கை மனித உரிமை ஆணைக்குழுவின் முன்னாள் தலைவர் பேராசிரியர் பிரதீபா மஹாநாமஹேவா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "தேசிய பாதுகாப்பு, சட்டம் தொடர்பில் ஊடக அறிக்கையிடல் தொடர்பில் அரச தகவல் திணைக்களத்தில் நேற்று (19) இடம்பெற்ற செயலமர்வில் கலந்துகொண்டு உரையாற்றும் போது அவர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சுனாமியின் போது முப்படையினரும் பொலிஸாரும் சிறப்பாக செயற்பட்டனர். இந்த விடயத்தில் முப்படையினரின் மனிதாபிமான நடவடிக்கை குறித்து ஜெனீவாவில் பேசப்படவில்லை. கொரோனா தொற்றின் போதும் கொரோனா தனிமைப்படுத்தல் நிலையங்களில் இராணுவத்தினரின் சிறப்பாக  செயற்பட்டனர். இது தொடர்பில் எமது நாட்டு ஊடகங்கள் எதனையும் பேசவில்லை.  இவ்வாறு இருக்கும் போது ஜெனீவாவில் உள்ளவர்களுக்கு எமது நாட்டு படையினரின் மனிதாபிமான செயற்பாடுகள் குறித்து அறிந்துகொள்ள வாய்ப்பில்லை என்றார்.",
        "இன்று இலங்கையில் ஆறு புலம்பெயர் அமைப்புகளின் தடைகள் நீக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன. குறித்த அமைப்புகள் மீதான தடை ஏன் நீக்கப்பட்டதென தெரியவில்லை என்றார். குறித்த அமைப்புகளில் ஒன்றின் உறுப்பினான பாதிரியாரும் நானும்  ஜெனிவா அமர்வின் போது, யுத்தக் குற்றசாட்டுகள் குறித்து நேருக்கு நேர் விவாதித்துக்கொண்டோம்.",
        "அவர்கள் தான் இலங்கை இராணுவத்தினர் யுத்தக் குற்றச்சாட்டில் ஈடுபட்டதாக ஜெனிவாவில் பிரேரணை நிறைவேற்றினர். எனவே இப்போது இந்த சந்தர்ப்பத்தை பயன்படுத்தி அரசாங்கம் ,இராணுவத்தினருக்கு எதிராக அவர்களால் முன்வைக்கப்படும் பிரசாரங்களை நிறுத்த நடவடிக்கை எடுக்க வேண்டும்.",
        "இந்த 6 அமைப்புகளில் உள்ளவர்கள் தான் 2009 மே 19ஆம் திகதி இராணுவத்தினர் மனிதாபிமானமற்ற  யுத்தக் குற்றச்செயல்களில் ஈடுபட்டதாக வகுப்புகளில் மாணவர்களுக்கு கற்பிக்கின்றனர்.  இராணுவத்தில்  பலர் யுத்த குற்றச்சாட்டுகளில் ஈடுபட்டார்கள் என தெரிவித்து அவர்களுக்கு எதிராக சட்ட நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு இராணுவத்தினரின் பெயர் பட்டியலை வெளிநாடுகளுக்கு வழங்கியதே இந்த அமைப்புகளின் உறுப்பினர்கள் தான் என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெனீவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ப்ரதீபா மஹாநாமஹேவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுனாமி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெனீவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெனீவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெனீவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெனீவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 19, 2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}