{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/union-assurance%e2%80%afcrowns-excellence/",
  "time_ut": 1656680220,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Union Assurance crowns excellence",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Union Assurance crowns excellence",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "Union Assurance PLC held the Annual Awards 2021 to honour its top achievers for their exemplary performance. The ceremony was held at the Monarch Imperial on 8th May 2022, under the theme ‘Crowning Excellence.’ This event, which crowned the champions, was graced by a distinguished leadership team that included Chairman of John Keells Holdings, Krishan Balendra , and Chief Executive Officer of Union Assurance, Jude Gomes.",
        "The awards ceremony recognised the exceptional performance of over 670 award winners, making it the highest number of annual award winners in the Company’s history, a feat driven by a record-breaking performance in 2021. The winners comprised advisors, agency leaders, regional managers, and zonal managers from the island-wide Agency network. The top achievers in the Agency channel (including Best Zone and Best Region) were honoured, while the Ultimate Champion Kalum Jayasinghe was rewarded with a flashy Mercedes-Benz car. Chanaka Appuhamy was also presented with a Mercedes-Benz for his Top of the Table Club achievement.",
        "The CEO of Union Assurance, Jude Gomes lauded the winners for delivering outstanding results. He described their achievements as remarkable since 2021 was full of challenges arising from the pandemic.",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Union Assurance PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Annual Awards 2021",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "8th May 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "John Keells Holdings",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Krishan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Union Assurance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "over 670",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "annual",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Agency",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ultimate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayasinghe",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mercedes-Benz",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chanaka Appuhamy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mercedes-Benz",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Union Assurance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jude Gomes",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Union Assurancecrowns විශිෂ්ටත්වය",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "යුනියන් ඇෂුවරන්ස් පීඑල්සී 2021 වාර්ෂික සම්මාන උලෙළ පවත්වනු ලැබුවේ ඔවුන්ගේ ආදර්ශමත් කාර්ය සාධනය වෙනුවෙන් එහි ස්ථාපකයින්ට ගෞරව කිරීම සඳහා ය. මෙම උත්සවය 2022 මැයි 8 වැනි දින Monarch Imperial හිදී පැවැත්වුණේ 'Crowning Excellence' යන තේමාව යටතේයි. ශූරයන් ලෙස කිරුළු පැළඳි මෙම උත්සවය ජෝන්කීල්ස් හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් හි සභාපති ක්‍රිෂාන් බාලේන්ද්‍ර සහ ප්‍රධාන විධායක ඇතුළු කීර්තිමත් නායකත්ව කණ්ඩායමක් විසින් පිරිනමන ලදී. යුනියන් ඇෂුවරන්ස් නිලධාරි ජූඩ් ගෝමස්.",
        "670 කට අධික සම්මානලාභීන්ගේ සුවිශේෂී කාර්ය සාධනය සම්මාන උළෙල ඇගයීමට ලක් කරන ලද අතර, එය සමාගමේ ඉතිහාසයේ වැඩිම වාර්ෂික සම්මාන ලාභීන් සංඛ්‍යාවක් බවට පත් කරමින්, 2021 දී වාර්තාගත කාර්ය සාධනයක් මගින් මෙහෙයවන ලද ජයග්‍රහණයකි. සහ දීප ව්‍යාප්ත නියෝජිතායතන ජාලයේ කලාප කළමනාකරුවන්. ඒජන්සි නාලිකාවේ (BestZone සහ BestRegion ඇතුළුව) ඉහළම දක්ෂතා දැක්වූවන් ගෞරවාදරයට පාත්‍ර වූ අතර, අවසාන ශූර කැලුම් ජයසිංහ හට දීප්තිමත් Mercedes-Benz මෝටර් රථයෙන් ත්‍යාග පිරිනමන ලදී. චානක අප්පුහාමිට මේස සමාජයේ ඉහළම ජයග්‍රහණය වෙනුවෙන් Mercedes-Benz මෝටර් රථයක් ද පිරිනැමිණි.",
        "යුනියන් ඇෂුවරන්ස් හි ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී ජූඩ් ගෝමස් මහතා විශිෂ්ට ප්‍රතිඵල ලබා දීම වෙනුවෙන් ජයග්‍රාහකයින් අගය කළේය. 2021 සිට ඔවුන් ලබා ඇති විශිෂ්ට ජයග්‍රහණ වසංගතයෙන් මුහුණ දුන් අභියෝගවලින් පිරී ඇති බව ඔහු විස්තර කළේය.",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "යුනියන් ඇෂුවරන්ස් පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික සම්මාන 2021",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 මැයි 8",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝන්කීල්ස් හෝල්ඩින්ග්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්‍රිෂාන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුනියන් ඇෂුවරන්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "670 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නියෝජිතායතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසානයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයසිංහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mercedes-Benz",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චානක අප්පුහාමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mercedes-Benz",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුනියන් ඇෂුවරන්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූඩ් ගෝමස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "யூனியன் அஷ்யூரன்ஸ் சிறந்து விளங்குகிறது",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "யூனியன் அஷ்யூரன்ஸ் பிஎல்சி தனது முன்மாதிரியான செயல்திறனுக்காக 2021 ஆண்டு விருதுகளை நடத்தியது. 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு மே 8 ஆம் தேதி மோனார்க் இம்பீரியலில், 'கிரவுனிங் எக்ஸலன்ஸ்' என்ற தொனிப்பொருளில் இந்த விழா நடைபெற்றது. இந்த நிகழ்வில், சாம்பியன் பட்டத்தை சூட்டியது, ஜான்கீல்ஸ் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் தலைவர், கிரிஷன் பாலேந்திரா மற்றும் தலைமை நிர்வாகி ஆகியோர் அடங்கிய சிறப்புமிக்க தலைமைக் குழுவால் நடத்தப்பட்டது. யூனியன் அஷ்யூரன்ஸ் அதிகாரி, ஜூட் கோம்ஸ்.",
        "670 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட விருது வென்றவர்களின் விதிவிலக்கான செயல்திறனுக்கான விருது வழங்கும் விழா அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்டது, இது நிறுவனத்தின் வரலாற்றில் அதிக எண்ணிக்கையிலான ஆண்டு விருதுகளை வென்றவர்களின் சாதனையாக ஆக்கியது, இது 2021 இல் சாதனை படைத்த செயல்திறனால் உந்தப்பட்டது. வெற்றியாளர்கள் ஆலோசகர்கள், ஏஜென்சி தலைவர்கள், பிராந்திய மேலாளர்கள், மற்றும் தீவு முழுவதும் உள்ள ஏஜென்சி நெட்வொர்க்கின் மண்டல மேலாளர்கள். ஏஜென்சி சேனலில் (பெஸ்ட்ஜோன் மற்றும் பெஸ்ட் ரீஜியன் உட்பட) டாப்சீவர்ஸ் கௌரவிக்கப்பட்டார். சானக அப்புஹாமிக்கு அவரது டாப் ஆஃப் தி டேபிள் கிளப் சாதனைக்காக Mercedes-Benz ஒன்றும் வழங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "யூனியன் அஷ்யூரன்ஸின் CEO, ஜூட் கோம்ஸ் சிறந்த முடிவுகளை வழங்கியதற்காக வெற்றியாளர்களைப் பாராட்டினார். 2021 ஆம் ஆண்டிலிருந்து அவர்களின் சாதனைகள் குறிப்பிடத்தக்கவை என்று விவரித்தார்.",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "யூனியன் அஷ்யூரன்ஸ் பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு விருதுகள் 2021",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 மே 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான்கீல்ஸ் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிருஷ்ணன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யூனியன் அஷ்யூரன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "670க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏஜென்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அல்டிமேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசிங்க",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mercedes-Benz",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சானக அப்புஹாமி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mercedes-Benz",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யூனியன் அஷ்யூரன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூட் கோம்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}