{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/international/භූ-කම්පනයෙන්-විපතට-පත්-අය-බැලීමට-මාර්කෝස්-යයි/3-395827",
  "time_ut": 1659000559,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "භූ කම්පනයෙන් විපතට පත් අය බැලීමට මාර්කෝස් යයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Marcos visits earthquake victims",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ferdinand Marcos has come with other government officials to observe the areas affected by the severe earthquake that affected the province of Abra in the Philippines.",
        "Marcos said during a briefing on the situation in the provincial capital, Bangud, that the government would provide aid to the affected people.",
        "A strong earthquake of magnitude 7 struck Abra Province and four people have died and at least 131 people have been injured.",
        "After the earthquake, the country's government has acted to immediately send rescue and relief teams to Abra."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Marcos",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ferdinand Marcos",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Philippines",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Marcos",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangud",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abra Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "at least 131",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "භූ කම්පනයෙන් විපතට පත් අය බැලීමට මාර්කෝස් යයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පිලිපීනයේ අබ්‍රා පළාතට බලපෑ දරුණු භූ මිකම්පාවෙන් පීඩාවට පත් ප්‍රදේශ නිරීක්ෂණයට එරට ජනාධිපති ෆර්ඩිනැන්ඩ් මාර්කෝස් එරට අනෙකුත් රාජ්‍ය නිලධාරීන් සමග පැමිණ තිබේ.",
        "විපතට පත් පුද්ගලයින්ට රජයෙන් ආධාර ලබාදෙන බව පළාත් අගනුවර බංගුඩ් හි පැවති තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳ දැනුවත් කිරීමකදී මාකෝස් පැවසීය.",
        "අබ්‍රා පළාතට රක්ටර් පරිමාණ 7ක ප්‍රබල භූමිකම්පාවක් ඇති වූ අතර මේ වනවිට පුද්ගලයින් සිව් දෙනෙකු මිය ගොස් අවම වශයෙන් පුද්ගලයින් 131දෙනෙකු තුවාල ලබා ඇත.",
        "භූ කම්පනය ඇතිවීමත් සමග අබ්‍රා වෙත ගලවා ගැනීමේ සහ සහන කණ්ඩායම් වහාම යැවීමට එරට රජය ක්‍රියාකර තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මාකෝස්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆර්ඩිනන්ඩ් මාකෝස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිලිපීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාකෝස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්ගුඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබ්රා පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් 131",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබ්රා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பூகம்பத்தால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர்களை மார்கோஸ் பார்வையிடுகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிலிப்பைன்ஸில் உள்ள அப்ரா மாகாணத்தில் ஏற்பட்ட கடுமையான நிலநடுக்கத்தால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட பகுதிகளை பார்வையிட மற்ற அரசு அதிகாரிகளுடன் அதிபர் ஃபெர்டினாண்ட் மார்கோஸ் வந்துள்ளார்.",
        "மாகாணத் தலைநகர் பாங்குடில் நிலைமை குறித்த விளக்கமளிக்கும் போது, ​​பாதிக்கப்பட்ட மக்களுக்கு அரசாங்கம் உதவிகளை வழங்கும் என்று மார்கோஸ் கூறினார்.",
        "அப்ரா மாகாணத்தில் 7 ரிக்டர் அளவிலான சக்திவாய்ந்த நிலநடுக்கம் ஏற்பட்டது மற்றும் நான்கு பேர் இறந்தனர் மற்றும் குறைந்தது 131 பேர் காயமடைந்துள்ளனர்.",
        "நிலநடுக்கத்திற்குப் பிறகு, உடனடியாக மீட்பு மற்றும் நிவாரணக் குழுக்களை அப்ராவுக்கு அனுப்ப அந்நாட்டு அரசாங்கம் நடவடிக்கை எடுத்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மார்கோஸ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃபெர்டினாண்ட் மார்கோஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிலிப்பைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மார்கோஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாங்குட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அப்ரா மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 131",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அப்ரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}