{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84560/more-activists-arrested-over-forcible-entry-to-state-buildings-granted-bail-",
  "time_ut": 1661512980,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "More activists arrested over forcible entry to state buildings granted bail",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "More activists arrested over forcible entry to state buildings granted bail",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Colombo Fort Magistrate’s Court granted bail to 07 remanded suspects including Dhaniz Ali who were in remand custody over the forcible entry to the Presidential residence.",
        "The order was issued by the Colombo Fort Magistrate Thilina Gamage.",
        "In addition, two more suspects including Lahiru Weerasekara who were named as the suspects in the case were also granted bail today. They were released on surety bail of Rs. 500,000 each.",
        "In the meantime, Colombo Fort Magistrate Thilina Gamage ordered two activists of ‘Aragalaya’ protest movement Piyath Nikeshala and Ven. Balangoda Kashyapa Thero to be released on surety bail of each worth Rs. 500,000.",
        "The two suspects were arrested and remanded in custody on charges of forcible entry to the Prime Minister’s office and damaging its property.",
        "The magistrate issued the order considering the bail requests made by the attorneys who appeared on behalf of the suspects arrested by the Criminal Investigation Department (CID)."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Colombo Fort Magistrate’s Court",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhaniz Ali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Fort Magistrate",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thilina Gamage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lahiru Weerasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "500,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo Fort Magistrate Thilina Gamage",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Piyath Nikeshala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ven",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Balangoda Kashyapa Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "500,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රාජ්‍ය ගොඩනැගිලිවලට බලහත්කාරයෙන් ඇතුළුවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් තවත් ක්‍රියාකාරීන්ට ඇප නියම විය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති නිල නිවසට බලහත්කාරයෙන් ඇතුළුවීමේ සිද්ධියක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් රිමාන්ඩ් භාරයේ සිටි ධනීස් අලි ඇතුළු රක්‍ෂිත බන්ධනාගාරගතව සිටි සැකකරුවන් 07 දෙනෙකුට කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය ඇප නියම කළා.",
        "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් තිළිණ ගමගේ මහතා විසින් මෙම නියෝගය නිකුත් කර ඇත.",
        "ඊට අමතරව මෙම නඩුවේ සැකකරුවන් ලෙස නම් කර සිටි ළහිරු වීරසේකර ඇතුළු තවත් සැකකරුවන් දෙදෙනෙකුට ද අද ඇප නියම කෙරුණා. රුපියල් ලක්ෂයක ශරීර ඇප මත ඔවුන් මුදා හැරිණි. 500,000 බැගින්.",
        "මේ අතර කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් තිළිණ ගමගේ මහතා විසින් අරගලය විරෝධතා ව්‍යාපාරයේ ක්‍රියාකාරීන් දෙදෙනෙකු වන පියත් නිකේෂල සහ පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය ධම්මාලංකාර හිමියන්ට නියෝග කළේය. බලංගොඩ කාශ්‍යප හිමියන් රුපියල් ලක්ෂ 10 බැගින් වූ ශරීර ඇප මත මුදා හැරීමට... 500,000 කි.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයට බලහත්කාරයෙන් ඇතුළුවීම සහ එහි දේපළවලට හානි කිරීම යන චෝදනා මත සැකකරුවන් දෙදෙනා අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කර තිබේ.",
        "මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා මෙම නියෝගය නිකුත් කළේ අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව (CID) විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරුවන් වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි නීතීඥවරුන් විසින් කරන ලද ඇප ඉල්ලීම් සලකා බලමිනි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධනීස් අලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිළිණ ගමගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලහිරු වීරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "500,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් තිළිණ ගමගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පියත් නිකේෂලා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හාමුදුරුවෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලංගොඩ කාශ්‍යප හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "500,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசு கட்டிடங்களுக்குள் வலுக்கட்டாயமாக நுழைந்ததற்காக கைது செய்யப்பட்ட மேலும் பல ஆர்வலர்களுக்கு ஜாமீன் வழங்கப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி இல்லத்திற்குள் பலவந்தமாக பிரவேசித்தமை தொடர்பில் விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த தனிஸ் அலி உள்ளிட்ட 07 சந்தேகநபர்களுக்கு கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம் பிணை வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் திலின கமகே இந்த உத்தரவை பிறப்பித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அத்துடன், இந்த வழக்கில் சந்தேகநபர்களாக குறிப்பிடப்பட்டிருந்த லஹிரு வீரசேகர உள்ளிட்ட மேலும் இரண்டு சந்தேக நபர்களுக்கும் இன்று பிணை வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. அவர்கள் ரூ.1000 பிணையில் விடுவிக்கப்பட்டனர். தலா 500,000.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் திலின கமகே, ‘அறகலய’ போராட்ட இயக்கத்தின் செயற்பாட்டாளர்களான பியத் நிகேஷல மற்றும் வண. பலாங்கொட காஷ்யப தேரர் ஒவ்வொருவருக்கும் ஒரு இலட்சம் ரூபா பெறுமதியான சரீரப் பிணையில் விடுவிக்கப்படவுள்ளார். 500,000.",
        "பிரதமரின் அலுவலகத்திற்குள் பலவந்தமாக நுழைந்து அதன் சொத்துக்களுக்கு சேதம் விளைவித்த குற்றச்சாட்டின் பேரில் சந்தேகநபர்கள் இருவரும் கைது செய்யப்பட்டு விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினரால் (CID) கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேகநபர்கள் சார்பில் ஆஜரான சட்டத்தரணிகள் முன்வைத்த பிணைக் கோரிக்கையை கருத்திற்கொண்டே நீதவான் இந்த உத்தரவை பிறப்பித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனிஸ் அலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "திலின கமகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லஹிரு வீரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "500,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் திலின கமகே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பியத் நிகேஷலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வண",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பலாங்கொட காஷ்யப தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "500,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}