{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84652/amber-flood-warning-for-low-lying-areas-of-several-rivers",
  "time_ut": 1661880540,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "‘Amber’ flood warning for low-lying areas of several rivers",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "‘Amber’ flood warning for low-lying areas of several rivers",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Department of Irrigation today (Aug 30) issued an ‘Amber’ flood warning for the low-lying areas adjoining the Attanagalu Oya, Kelani River, Kalu River, Gin River and Mahaweli River.",
        "Accordingly, people living in flood-prone areas of aforementioned river basins have been advised to be vigilant in this regard.",
        "In an advisory issued earlier today, Director of Irrigation (Hydrology) Eng. S.P.C. Sugeeshwara urged them to be attentive when riding boats or bathing in or crossing these rivers or their tributaries, especially in upstream areas of those river basins in order to safeguard the lives of people and properties."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department of Irrigation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Attanagalu Oya",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalu River",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gin River",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahaweli River",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "earlier today",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "S.P.C. Sugeeshwara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගංගා කිහිපයක පහත් බිම් සඳහා ‘ඇම්බර්’ ගංවතුර අනතුරු ඇඟවීමක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අත්තනගලු ඔය, කැලණි ගඟ, කළු ගඟ, ගිං ගඟ සහ මහවැලි ගඟ ආශ්‍රිත පහත් බිම් සඳහා වාරිමාර්ග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව අද (අගෝස්තු 30) ‘ඇම්බර්’ ගංවතුර අනතුරු ඇඟවීමක් නිකුත් කළේය.",
        "ඒ අනුව ඉහත සඳහන් ගංගා ද්‍රෝණි ආශ්‍රිත ගංවතුර අවදානම් ප්‍රදේශවල ජීවත්වන ජනතාවට මේ පිළිබඳව අවධානයෙන් පසුවන ලෙසට දැනුම් දී ඇත.",
        "අද දිනට පෙර නිකුත් කරන ලද උපදේශනයකදී වාරිමාර්ග අධ්‍යක්ෂ (ජල විද්‍යා) ඉංජිනේරු. එස්.පී.සී. සුගීෂ්වර ඔවුන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ බෝට්ටු පැදීමේදී හෝ දිය නෑමේදී හෝ මෙම ගංගාවල හෝ ඒවායේ අතු ගංගාවල, විශේෂයෙන් එම ගංගා ද්‍රෝණිවල ඉහළ ප්‍රදේශවල මිනිසුන්ගේ සහ දේපළවල ජීවිත ආරක්ෂා කර ගැනීම සඳහා අවධානයෙන් සිටින ලෙසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වාරිමාර්ග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අත්තනගලු ඔය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළු ගඟ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිං ගඟ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහවැලි ගඟ",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද කලින්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.පී.සී. සුගීෂ්වර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பல ஆறுகளின் தாழ்வான பகுதிகளுக்கு ‘ஆம்பர்’ வெள்ள எச்சரிக்கை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அத்தனகலு ஓயா, களனி ஆறு, களு ஆறு, ஜின் ஆறு மற்றும் மகாவலி ஆற்றை அண்டிய தாழ்நிலப் பகுதிகளுக்கு நீர்ப்பாசனத் திணைக்களம் இன்று (ஆகஸ்ட் 30) ​​'ஆம்பர்' வெள்ள அபாய எச்சரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி, மேற்குறிப்பிட்ட ஆற்றுப்படுகைகளில் வெள்ளப்பெருக்கு ஏற்படும் பகுதிகளில் வசிக்கும் மக்கள் இது தொடர்பில் அவதானமாக இருக்குமாறு அறிவுறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இன்று முன்னதாக வெளியிடப்பட்ட ஆலோசனையில், நீர்ப்பாசன இயக்குநர் (நீரியல்) இன்ஜி. எஸ்.பி.சி. சுகீஸ்வரா அவர்கள் படகுகளில் சவாரி செய்யும் போது அல்லது குளிக்கும் போது அல்லது இந்த ஆறுகள் அல்லது அவற்றின் துணை நதிகளை கடக்கும்போது, ​​குறிப்பாக அந்த ஆற்றுப்படுகைகளின் மேல்பகுதிகளில் மக்கள் மற்றும் சொத்துக்களின் உயிர்களைப் பாதுகாப்பதற்காக கவனத்துடன் இருக்குமாறு கேட்டுக் கொண்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நீர்ப்பாசன திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அத்தனகலு ஓயா",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "கலு ஆறு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜின் நதி",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகாவலி ஆறு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "முன்னதாக இன்று",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.பி.சி. சுகீஷ்வரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}