{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84739/litro-gas-to-slash-prices-tomorrow",
  "time_ut": 1662281160,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Litro Gas to slash prices tomorrow",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Litro Gas to slash prices tomorrow",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Litro Gas Company says that the price of domestic gas cylinders will be reduced by between Rs. 100 and Rs. 200 rupees from midnight tomorrow (05).",
        "He stated that in the past 2 months, Litro company has generated a significant profit.",
        "According to Litro Chairman Mr. Muditha Peiris, the profits of the company will exceed Rs. 700 million in the month of August alone.",
        "However, the chairman of the Restaurant Owners’ Association Mr. Asela Sampath stated today (04) that even if the gas price is reduced, the food and beverage prices cannot be lowered.",
        "In the meantime, the Litro company is also preparing to introduce a method in the coming week where a person living in another country can purchase gas cylinders for a person in Sri Lanka by paying with US Dollars.",
        "“From next week, we will introduce an app for people living abroad to purchase gas for any person in Sri Lanka. It can be a friend, parent, or relative of a person in Sri Lanka. Anyone here can get a gas cylinder that fits their monthly needs by making a very small payment in dollars through the app,” Mr. Peiris said.",
        "“For an amount like USD 15 to 16, maybe less than that depending on the exchange rate. You can pay that amount and order that cylinder for the person here. We will keep it safe at the nearest dealer point of that person. We can also deliver it to your home. In particular, we will not invest this money in anything other than buying gas.”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Litro Gas",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "tomorrow",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "midnight tomorrow",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the past 2 months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muditha Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "700 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the month of August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Restaurant Owners’ Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asela Sampath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coming week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US Dollars",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "next week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "monthly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් මිල හෙට සිට පහළට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ගෘහස්ත ගෑස් සිලින්ඩරයක මිල රුපියල් 1000 කින් අඩු කරන බව ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් සමාගම පවසයි. 100 සහ රු. හෙට (05) මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ සිට රුපියල් 200ක්.",
        "පසුගිය මාස 2 තුළ ලිට්‍රෝ සමාගම සැලකිය යුතු ලාභයක් උපයා ඇති බව ඔහු ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ලිට්‍රෝ සභාපති මුදිත පීරිස් මහතාට අනුව සමාගමේ ලාභය රු. අගෝස්තු මාසයේ පමණක් මිලියන 700ක්.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ආපනශාලා හිමියන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති අසේල සම්පත් මහතා අද (04) ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ගෑස් මිල අඩු කළද ආහාර පාන මිල අඩු කළ නොහැකි බවයි.",
        "මේ අතර වෙනත් රටක වෙසෙන අයෙකුට ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් වලින් ගෙවා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිටින පුද්ගලයෙකුට ගෑස් සිලින්ඩර් මිලදී ගත හැකි ක්‍රමයක් ඉදිරි සතියේදී හඳුන්වා දීමටද ලිට්‍රෝ සමාගම සූදානම් වේ.",
        "“ලබන සතියේ සිට විදේශගතව සිටින පුද්ගලයින්ට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඕනෑම පුද්ගලයෙකුට ගෑස් මිලදී ගැනීමට ඇප් එකක් හඳුන්වා දෙනවා. එය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිටින පුද්ගලයෙකුගේ මිතුරෙකු, දෙමාපියෙකු හෝ ඥාතියෙකු විය හැකිය. ඇප් එක හරහා ඩොලර් වලින් ඉතා සුළු මුදලක් ගෙවා මෙහි සිටින ඕනෑම අයෙකුට තම මාසික අවශ්‍යතාවයට සරිලන ගෑස් සිලින්ඩරයක් ලබා ගත හැකියි.” පීරිස් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "“ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් 15 සිට 16 දක්වා වැනි මුදලකට, විනිමය අනුපාතය අනුව ඊට වඩා අඩු විය හැක. ඔබට එම මුදල ගෙවා එම සිලින්ඩරය මෙහි සිටින පුද්ගලයාට ඇණවුම් කළ හැකිය. අපි එය එම පුද්ගලයාගේ ළඟම ඇති අලෙවි නියෝජිත ස්ථානයේ සුරක්ෂිතව තබමු. ඔබගේ නිවසටම ගෙන්වා ගැනීමටද අපට හැකිය. විශේෂයෙන්ම අපි මේ මුදල් ගෑස් මිලදී ගැනීම හැර වෙන කිසිම දෙයකට ආයෝජනය කරන්නේ නැහැ.”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලිට්රෝ ගෑස්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "හෙට",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාස 2",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදිත පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 700 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආපනශාලා හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අසේල සම්පත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "லிட்ரோ எரிவாயுவின் விலை நாளை குறைக்கப்படவுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "உள்நாட்டு எரிவாயு சிலிண்டர்களின் விலை 100 ரூபாவால் குறைக்கப்படும் என லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு நிறுவனம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. 100 மற்றும் ரூ. நாளை (05) நள்ளிரவு முதல் 200 ரூபாய்.",
        "கடந்த 2 மாதங்களில் லிட்ரோ நிறுவனம் கணிசமான லாபத்தை ஈட்டியுள்ளதாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "லிட்ரோ தலைவர் திரு.முதித பீரிஸின் கூற்றுப்படி, நிறுவனத்தின் லாபம் ரூ. ஆகஸ்ட் மாதத்தில் மட்டும் 700 மில்லியன்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், எரிவாயு விலை குறைக்கப்பட்டாலும் உணவு மற்றும் பானங்களின் விலையை குறைக்க முடியாது என உணவக உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் அசேல சம்பத் இன்று (04) தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, இலங்கையில் உள்ள ஒருவருக்கு அமெரிக்க டொலர்களை செலுத்தி வேறு நாட்டில் வசிக்கும் ஒருவர் எரிவாயு சிலிண்டர்களை கொள்வனவு செய்யும் முறையை எதிர்வரும் வாரத்தில் அறிமுகப்படுத்த Litro நிறுவனம் தயாராகி வருகின்றது.",
        "“அடுத்த வாரத்தில் இருந்து, இலங்கையில் உள்ள எந்தவொரு நபருக்கும் எரிவாயுவை கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்கான செயலியை வெளிநாட்டில் வாழும் மக்களுக்கு அறிமுகப்படுத்தவுள்ளோம். அது இலங்கையில் உள்ள ஒருவரின் நண்பராகவோ, பெற்றோராகவோ அல்லது உறவினராகவோ இருக்கலாம். இங்குள்ள எவரும் இந்த செயலி மூலம் டொலரில் மிகக் குறைந்த கட்டணத்தைச் செலுத்துவதன் மூலம் தமது மாதாந்தத் தேவைகளுக்கு ஏற்ற எரிவாயு சிலிண்டரைப் பெற்றுக்கொள்ள முடியும்” என திரு. பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“அமெரிக்க டாலர் 15 முதல் 16 வரை, மாற்று விகிதத்தைப் பொறுத்து அதைவிடக் குறைவாக இருக்கலாம். அந்த தொகையை செலுத்தி அந்த சிலிண்டரை இங்குள்ள நபருக்கு ஆர்டர் செய்யலாம். அந்த நபரின் அருகிலுள்ள டீலர் புள்ளியில் நாங்கள் அதைப் பாதுகாப்பாக வைத்திருப்போம். உங்கள் வீட்டிற்கும் நாங்கள் டெலிவரி செய்யலாம். குறிப்பாக, இந்தப் பணத்தை எரிவாயு வாங்குவதைத் தவிர வேறு எதிலும் முதலீடு செய்ய மாட்டோம்” என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "நாளை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை நள்ளிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த 2 மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதித பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "700 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உணவக உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அசேல சம்பத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதாந்திர",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}