{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/President-denies-allocating-Rs-400-Mn-to-renovate-MRs-residence/342-244070",
  "time_ut": 1661931607,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President denies allocating Rs. 400 Mn to renovate MR’s residence",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President denies allocating Rs. 400 Mn to renovate MR’s residence",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe today denied reports which said a sum of Rs. 400 million has been allocated out of state funds to renovate the residence of Former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa.",
        "The President was responding to an allegation raised by SJB MP Rohana Bandara in the House today.",
        "“We have not spent either Rs. 400 million or just four rupees to renovate the residence of Mr. Rajapaksa. Nevertheless, we are legally bound to look after former Presidents and their widows,” Mr. Wickremesinghe said.",
        "Earlier MP Bandara questioned as to whether rain water is seeping through roof of Mr. Rajapaksa’s residence. (Yohan Perera and Ajith Siriwardana)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "400",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "MR",
          "label": "EVENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "400 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB MP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rohana Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "400 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yohan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Siriwardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රුපියල් මිලියන 100ක් වෙන් කිරීම ජනපති ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරයි. MR ගේ නිවස ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණය කිරීමට මිලියන 400ක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රුපියල් කෝටි 100ක මුදලක් ලබාදුන් බවට පළවන වාර්තා ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අද ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ නිවස ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණය කිරීමට රජයේ මුදලින් රුපියල් මිලියන 400ක් වෙන්කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "ජනාධීපතිවරයා මේ බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේ අද සභාවේදී SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රෝහණ බණ්ඩාර මහතා නැගූ චෝදනාවකට පිළිතුරු ලබාදෙමිනි.",
        "“අපි රු. රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ නිවස ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණය කිරීමට රුපියල් මිලියන 400ක් හෙවත් රුපියල් හතරක් පමණි. එසේ වුවද, හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරුන් සහ ඔවුන්ගේ වැන්දඹුවන් බලා ගැනීමට අපි නීත්‍යානුකූලව බැඳී සිටිනවා.” යැයිද වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ නිවසේ වහලය හරහා වැසි ජලය කාන්දු වන්නේ දැයි පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී බණ්ඩාර මීට පෙර ප්‍රශ්න කළා. (යොහාන් පෙරේරා සහ අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "400",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "මහතා",
          "label": "EVENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 400 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB පා.ම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෝහණ බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 400 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාර ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යොහාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "குடியரசுத் தலைவர் மறுப்பு 2016-10-2017 ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கு ரூ. எம்.ஆர். இல்லத்தை புதுப்பிக்க 400 மில்லியன்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இன்று 2016 ஆம் ஆண்டு 2017 ஆம் ஆண்டு 2017 ஆம் ஆண்டு 2017 ஆம் ஆண்டு 10.00 ம் திகதி 2017 ஆம் ஆண்டு 2016 ஆம் ஆண்டு 2013 ஆம் ஆண்டு 2017 ஆம் ஆண்டு 10.00 ம் திகதி 2000 ஆம் ஆண்டு 2010 ஆம் ஆண்டு 2010 ஆம் ஆண்டு 2017 ஆம் ஆண்டு 17.00 ம் திகதி வரை 1000000 ரூபாவை வழங்கியுள்ளார். முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷவின் இல்லத்தை புனரமைக்க அரச நிதியில் இருந்து 400 மில்லியன் ஒதுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரோஹண பண்டாரவினால் இன்று சபையில் எழுப்பப்பட்ட குற்றச்சாட்டுக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் போதே ஜனாதிபதி மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“நாங்கள் ரூ. 400 மில்லியன் அல்லது வெறும் நான்கு ரூபாய் திரு. ராஜபக்சவின் இல்லத்தை புனரமைக்க. இருந்தபோதிலும், முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதிகள் மற்றும் அவர்களது விதவைகளை கவனிப்பதற்கு சட்டரீதியாக நாங்கள் கடமைப்பட்டுள்ளோம்” என்று திரு விக்கிரமசிங்க கூறினார்.",
        "முன்னதாக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பண்டார, திரு. ராஜபக்சவின் வீட்டின் கூரை வழியாக மழை நீர் வெளியேறுகிறதா என கேள்வி எழுப்பினார். (யோஹான் பெரேரா மற்றும் அஜித் சிறிவர்தன)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "400",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "திரு",
          "label": "EVENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "400 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB எம்.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோஹன பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "400 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோஹான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}