{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-airport-agency-says-usually-profitable-2022-a-currency-loss-99423/",
  "time_ut": 1662291960,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka airport agency says usually profitable, 2022 a currency loss",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka airport agency says usually profitable, 2022 a currency loss",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYEXT – Sri Lanka’s state-run airport authority says a 1.6 billion rupees loss up to June 2022 came from foreign exchange denominated loans and cost on borrowings for Mattala airport and the company is usually profitable.",
        "Sri Lanka’s Airport and Aviation Services Ltd, said it consistently made profits until the Covid-19 pandemic started in 2020.",
        "“Before the economic downturn triggered by the Easter attack in 2019 followed by the pandemic, we were a profit-making enterprise that regularly contributed large amounts of funds to the state coffers by way of dividends and taxes,” Airport and Aviation Sri Lanka said in a statement.",
        "AASL says Sri Lankan airports have been reporting profits  with 2019 recording 15.2 billion rupees.",
        "“Before the economic downturn triggered by the Easter attack in 2019 followed by the pandemic, we were a profit-making enterprise that regularly contributed large amounts of funds to the state coffers by way of dividends and taxes,” Airport and Aviation Sri Lanka said in a statement.",
        "“The overall operating loss of the company was due to the repayment of the loan instalments in foreign exchange on the loans obtained for MRIA.”",
        "The total international aircraft movements handled by all airports operated by AASL had dropped to 66 percent to 20,881 in 2020 from 62,195 in 2019.",
        "The international passenger movements had fallen 76 percent to 2.3 million from 9.9 million.",
        "It says the main Bandaranaike International Airport had earned 3.9 billion rupees in 2021 and 16.7 billion rupees up to June 2022.",
        "But the loss in the six months to June 2021 came forex losses on loans.",
        "Sri Lanka defaulted for the first time in April 2022 in the worst currency crisis."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.6 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mattala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Airport",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aviation Services Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Easter",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15.2 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Easter",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "AASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "66 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "20,881",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "62,195",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "76 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.3 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.9 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bandaranaike International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.9 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16.7 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the six months to June 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "April 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් තොටුපළ නියෝජිතායතනය පවසන්නේ සාමාන්‍යයෙන් ලාභදායී, 2022 මුදල් අලාභයක් බවයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රාජ්‍ය ගුවන් තොටුපළ අධිකාරිය පවසන්නේ 2022 ජූනි මාසය දක්වා රුපියල් බිලියන 1.6 ක පාඩුවක් විදේශ විනිමය නම් කරන ලද ණය සහ මත්තල ගුවන් තොටුපළ සඳහා ණය ගැනීම් සඳහා වූ පිරිවැයෙන් සහ සමාගම සාමාන්‍යයෙන් ලාභ ලබන බවයි.",
        "සීමාසහිත ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන්තොටුපළ සහ ගුවන් සේවා සමාගම, 2020 දී Covid-19 වසංගතය ආරම්භ වන තෙක් අඛණ්ඩව ලාභ ලැබූ බව පැවසීය.",
        "\"2019 පාස්කු ප්‍රහාරයෙන් පසුව ඇති වූ ආර්ථික අවපාතයට පෙර, අපි ලාභාංශ සහ බදු මගින් රාජ්‍ය භාණ්ඩාගාරයට විශාල අරමුදල් ප්‍රමාණයක් ලබා දුන් ලාභ ඉපැයීමේ ව්‍යාපාරයක් විය. ප්රකාශයක්.",
        "AASL පවසන්නේ 2019 වසරේ රුපියල් බිලියන 15.2ක් වාර්තා කරමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ගුවන් තොටුපල ලාභ වාර්තා කර ඇති බවයි.",
        "\"2019 පාස්කු ප්‍රහාරයෙන් පසුව ඇති වූ ආර්ථික අවපාතයට පෙර, අපි ලාභාංශ සහ බදු මගින් රාජ්‍ය භාණ්ඩාගාරයට විශාල අරමුදල් ප්‍රමාණයක් ලබා දුන් ලාභ ඉපැයීමේ ව්‍යාපාරයක් විය. ප්රකාශයක්.",
        "\"සමාගමේ සමස්ත මෙහෙයුම් අලාභය MRIA සඳහා ලබාගත් ණය මත විදේශ විනිමය වශයෙන් ණය වාරික ආපසු ගෙවීම නිසා විය.\"",
        "AASL විසින් මෙහෙයවනු ලබන සියලුම ගුවන් තොටුපළ විසින් හසුරුවන ලද මුළු ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් යානා චලනයන් 2019 දී 62,195 සිට 2020 දී 20,881 දක්වා සියයට 66 දක්වා පහත වැටී ඇත.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මගී ප්‍රවාහනය මිලියන 9.9 සිට මිලියන 2.3 දක්වා සියයට 76 කින් පහත වැටී ඇත.",
        "ප්‍රධාන බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ 2021 දී රුපියල් බිලියන 3.9 ක් සහ 2022 ජුනි දක්වා රුපියල් බිලියන 16.7 ක් උපයා ඇති බව එහි සඳහන් වේ.",
        "නමුත් 2021 ජූනි මාස හයේ පාඩුව වූයේ ණය මත විදේශ විනිමය පාඩුයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව 2022 අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී දරුණුතම මුදල් අර්බුදයකදී ප්‍රථම වතාවට පැහැර හැරියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 1.6 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මත්තල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත ගුවන් සේවා සේවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 15.2 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "AASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 66 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "20,881 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "62,195 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 76 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 2.3 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 9.9 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 3.9 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 16.7 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021 ජුනි සිට මාස හය දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை விமான நிலையம் பொதுவாக லாபம், 2022 நாணய இழப்பு என்று கூறுகிறது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYEXT - இலங்கையின் அரசால் நடத்தப்படும் விமான நிலைய அதிகாரசபையானது 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜூன் மாதம் வரை 1.6 பில்லியன் ரூபா நட்டம் அந்நிய செலாவணி குறிப்பிடப்பட்ட கடன்கள் மற்றும் மத்தள விமான நிலையத்திற்கான கடனுக்கான செலவுகள் மற்றும் நிறுவனம் பொதுவாக இலாபகரமானது என கூறுகிறது.",
        "இலங்கையின் விமான நிலையம் மற்றும் விமான சேவைகள் லிமிடெட், 2020 இல் கொவிட்-19 தொற்றுநோய் தொடங்கும் வரை தொடர்ந்து லாபம் ஈட்டியதாக தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "\"2019 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஈஸ்டர் தாக்குதலால் தூண்டப்பட்ட பொருளாதார வீழ்ச்சிக்கு முன்னர், தொற்றுநோயைத் தொடர்ந்து, இலாபம் ஈட்டும் நிறுவனமாக நாங்கள் இருந்தோம், இது ஈவுத்தொகை மற்றும் வரிகள் மூலம் அரச கருவூலங்களுக்கு தொடர்ந்து பெரிய அளவிலான நிதிகளை வழங்கியது\" என்று விமான நிலையம் மற்றும் விமானப் போக்குவரத்து இலங்கை தெரிவித்துள்ளது. ஒரு அறிக்கை.",
        "இலங்கை விமான நிலையங்கள் 2019 இல் 15.2 பில்லியன் ரூபாயை இலாபமாக பதிவு செய்துள்ளதாக AASL தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "\"2019 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஈஸ்டர் தாக்குதலால் தூண்டப்பட்ட பொருளாதார வீழ்ச்சிக்கு முன்னர், தொற்றுநோயைத் தொடர்ந்து, இலாபம் ஈட்டும் நிறுவனமாக நாங்கள் இருந்தோம், இது ஈவுத்தொகை மற்றும் வரிகள் மூலம் அரச கருவூலங்களுக்கு தொடர்ந்து பெரிய அளவிலான நிதிகளை வழங்கியது\" என்று விமான நிலையம் மற்றும் விமானப் போக்குவரத்து இலங்கை தெரிவித்துள்ளது. ஒரு அறிக்கை.",
        "\"MRIA க்காக பெறப்பட்ட கடன்களின் மீதான அந்நிய செலாவணியில் கடன் தவணைகளை திருப்பிச் செலுத்தியதால் நிறுவனத்தின் ஒட்டுமொத்த இயக்க இழப்பு ஏற்பட்டது.\"",
        "AASL ஆல் இயக்கப்படும் அனைத்து விமான நிலையங்களாலும் கையாளப்பட்ட மொத்த சர்வதேச விமான இயக்கங்கள் 2019 இல் 62,195 இல் இருந்து 2020 இல் 20,881 ஆக 66 சதவீதம் குறைந்துள்ளது.",
        "சர்வதேச பயணிகளின் எண்ணிக்கை 9.9 மில்லியனில் இருந்து 76 சதவீதம் சரிந்து 2.3 மில்லியனாக இருந்தது.",
        "பிரதான பண்டாரநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம் 2021 இல் 3.9 பில்லியன் ரூபாவையும் 2022 ஜூன் வரை 16.7 பில்லியன் ரூபாவையும் ஈட்டியுள்ளதாக அது கூறுகிறது.",
        "ஆனால் ஜூன் 2021 வரையிலான ஆறு மாதங்களில் ஏற்பட்ட இழப்பு, கடன்களில் அந்நிய செலாவணி இழப்புகள்.",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஏப்ரல் மாதம் மிக மோசமான நாணய நெருக்கடியில் இலங்கை முதல் தடவையாக திருப்பிச் செலுத்தவில்லை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.6 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்தல",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏவியேஷன் சர்வீசஸ் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏஏஎஸ்எல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15.2 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏஏஎஸ்எல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "66 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "20,881",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "62,195",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "76 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.3 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.9 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.9 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16.7 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 2021 முதல் ஆறு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}