{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/‘‘කරන්න-බැරිනම්-දමල-ගහල-යා-යුතුයි‘‘/1-615954",
  "time_ut": 1657104243,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "‘‘කරන්න බැරිනම් දමල ගහල යා යුතුයි‘‘",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "\"If you can't do it, you should go to Tamil Nadu.\"",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Gampaha District Councilor Mr. Sarath Fonseka said in the Parliament today 6 that if the opposition gets the mandate to form the government, it should take the government without fear and if it cannot hold its neck, then it should go away.",
        "Mr. Fonseka said that if the government is displeased with the people, if the people are asking the government to go home, if the people are lining up to oust the government and the president, then the opposition should definitely get that mandate.",
        "Mr. Fonseka said that he does not think that an all-party government can be formed from the opposition and that it will not get 113."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Tamil Nadu",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Councilor",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sarath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today 6",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fonseka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fonseka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "113",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘‘කරන්න බැරිනම් දමල ගහල යා යුතුයි‘‘",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආණ්ඩුව කිරීමෙි වරම විපක්ෂයට ලැබුනොත් බය නැතිව ආණ්ඩුව අරගත යුතුයැයි ද බෙල්ල තියල කරන්න බැරි නම් දමල ගහල යා යුතු යැයිද ගම්පහ දිස්ත්‍රික් මන්ත්‍රී සරත් ෆොන්සේකා මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ දී අද 6 පැවසීය.",
        "ආණ්ඩුව ජනතාවට අප්පිරිය වෙලා නම් ජනතාව ආණ්ඩුවට ගෙදර යන්න කියනවා නම් ජනතාව ආණ්ඩුව සහ ජනාධිපති එලවන්න පෙළගැසී සිටිනවා නම් විපක්ෂයට අනිවාර්යයෙන්ම ඒ වරම ලැබිය යුතු බව කී ෆොන්සේකා මහතා වරම ලැබුණොත් බහුතරය සුළුතරය ගැන කතා කර කර ඉන්නේ නැතිව විපක්ෂය වගකීම් බාරගත යුතු බව ෆොන්සේකා මහතා කීය.",
        "විපක්ෂයෙන් සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් හදන්න පුළුවන් යැයි තමා හිතන්නේ නැතැයි ද ඊට 113 හම්බ වෙන්නේ නැතැයි ද ෆොන්සේකා මහතා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්ත්‍රී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද 6",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆොන්සේකා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆොන්සේකා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "113",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முடியாது என்றால் தமிழகம் செல்ல வேண்டும்.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பதற்கு எதிர்க்கட்சிக்கு ஆணை கிடைத்தால் அச்சமின்றி அரசாங்கத்தை கொண்டு செல்ல வேண்டும் எனவும் கழுத்தை பிடிக்க முடியாவிட்டால் அங்கிருந்து வெளியேற வேண்டும் எனவும் கம்பஹா மாவட்ட சபை உறுப்பினர் திரு.சரத் பொன்சேகா இன்று 6ஆம் திகதி பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அரசாங்கம் மக்கள் மீது அதிருப்தி கொண்டிருந்தால், மக்கள் அரசாங்கத்தை வீட்டுக்குப் போகச் சொன்னால், அரசாங்கத்தையும் ஜனாதிபதியையும் வெளியேற்ற மக்கள் அணிவகுத்து நிற்கின்றார்களானால், எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் நிச்சயமாக அந்த ஆணையைப் பெற வேண்டும் என்றும் திரு.பொன்சேகா கூறினார்.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சியில் இருந்து சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க முடியும் என தாம் நினைக்கவில்லை எனவும் அதற்கு 113 கிடைக்காது எனவும் பொன்சேகா தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கவுன்சிலர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று 6",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொன்சேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொன்சேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "113",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}