{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/business/Wacoal-Europe-eyeing-further-expansion-of-manufacturing-base-in-Sri-Lanka/215-244292",
  "time_ut": 1662305386,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Wacoal Europe eyeing further expansion of manufacturing base in Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Wacoal Europe eyeing further expansion of manufacturing base in Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Wacoal, a leading designer and manufacturer of high-quality, plus size lingerie and bra-sized swimwear for the European market says Sri Lanka’s strong competitive advantages as a manufacturing destination for high-end apparel items continue to apply, notwithstanding the current situation.",
        "According to Wacoal Europe Supply Chain Director Andrew Yeomans, Sri Lanka scores high on all key criteria required of a manufacturing base for high-end lingerie in specific and high-end fashion in general.",
        "“In the 1990s and 2000s, lingerie manufacturers saw Sri Lanka as ‘the place to be’. Especially companies like Courtaulds and Coats Viyella made great efforts to transfer skills to Sri Lanka and as a result, there was a large manufacturing shift from the UK to Sri Lanka. Now, especially in lingerie, Sri Lanka has a very high skill base.",
        "Adding to that, Sri Lankan apparel industry pioneers also invested heavily in building a robust raw material supply chain for the industry. Sri Lanka’s location along major shipping routes is also a plus. Before the pandemic, shipping lead time to the UK was only around four weeks,” he added.",
        "Wacoal initially came to Sri Lanka in 2005 through a partnership with a leading Sri Lankan manufacturer. “We have been continually upscaling our operations in Sri Lanka and now employ more than 1200 in our team,” said Yeomans.",
        "He revealed that despite the recent challenges faced by the island nation, production volumes of Wacoal Lanka – the Sri Lankan entity – have been maintained. Wacoal is eyeing further expansion of its manufacturing base in Sri Lanka, with two additional production lines being added in the coming months. In tandem, the company continues to invest in new technology. Wacoal, a market leader in the plus-size lingerie categories, promotes inclusivity and body positivity via women’s intimate wear with its extensive brand portfolio for Wacoal Europe which includes Wacoal, Fantasie, Freya, Elomi and Goddess.",
        "“We saw far more of an impact from the pandemic, which caused challenges across all manufacturing bases, compared with the situation in Sri Lanka right now. We continue to have confidence in the country and believe strongly that we made the correct decision in continuing to invest in the country.",
        "Despite challenges, Sri Lankan authorities understand the importance of the apparel exports industry and have continued to support the sector. Our team on the ground, similar to the rest of the country, has been very resilient and continues to meet every new challenge placed in front of them,” stressed Yeomans."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Wacoal Europe",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Wacoal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "European",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wacoal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Andrew Yeomans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 1990s",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2000s",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Courtaulds",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Coats Viyella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wacoal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 1200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yeomans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wacoal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coming months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wacoal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wacoal Europe",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wacoal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fantasie",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Freya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Elomi and Goddess",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yeomans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Wacoal යුරෝපය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නිෂ්පාදන පදනම තවදුරටත් ව්‍යාප්ත කිරීමට අපේක්ෂා කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "යුරෝපීය වෙළෙඳපොළ සඳහා උසස් තත්ත්වයේ, ප්‍රමාණයේ යට ඇඳුම් සහ බ්‍රා ප්‍රමාණයේ පිහිනුම් ඇඳුම් ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ නිර්මාණකරුවෙකු සහ නිෂ්පාදකයෙකු වන Wacoal පවසන්නේ ඉහළ පෙළේ ඇඟලුම් භාණ්ඩ සඳහා නිෂ්පාදන ගමනාන්තයක් ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පවතින ප්‍රබල තරඟකාරී වාසි වත්මන් තත්ත්වය නොතකා අඛණ්ඩව අදාළ වන බවයි.",
        "Wacoal Europe Supply Chain අධ්‍යක්ෂ Andrew Yeomans ට අනුව, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සාමාන්‍යයෙන් විශේෂිත සහ උසස් මාදිලියේ ඉහළ මට්ටමේ යට ඇඳුම් සඳහා නිෂ්පාදන පදනමක් සඳහා අවශ්‍ය සියලුම ප්‍රධාන නිර්ණායක මත ඉහළ ලකුණු ලබා ඇත.",
        "“1990 ගණන්වල සහ 2000 ගණන්වල යට ඇඳුම් නිෂ්පාදකයින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දුටුවේ ‘සිටිය යුතු ස්ථානය’ ලෙසයි. විශේෂයෙන්ම Courtaulds සහ Coats Viyella වැනි සමාගම් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට නිපුණතා පැවරීමට මහත් පරිශ්‍රමයක් දැරූ අතර එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස එක්සත් රාජධානියේ සිට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට විශාල නිෂ්පාදන මාරුවක් සිදු විය. දැන්, විශේෂයෙන්ම යට ඇඳුම් සම්බන්ධයෙන්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඉතා ඉහළ කුසලතා පදනමක් ඇත.",
        "ඊට අමතරව, ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය ඇඟලුම් කර්මාන්තයේ පුරෝගාමීන් කර්මාන්තය සඳහා ශක්තිමත් අමුද්‍රව්‍ය සැපයුම් දාමයක් ගොඩනැගීම සඳහා විශාල වශයෙන් ආයෝජනය කළහ. ප්‍රධාන නැව් මාර්ග ඔස්සේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පිහිටීම ද ප්ලස් වේ. වසංගතයට පෙර, එක්සත් රාජධානියට නැව්ගත කිරීමේ කාලය සති හතරක් පමණ විය, ”ඔහු තවදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "Wacoal මුලින්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණියේ 2005 දී ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ ශ්‍රී ලාංකික නිෂ්පාදකයෙකු සමඟ හවුල්කාරිත්වයකින්. “අපි ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ අපගේ මෙහෙයුම් අඛණ්ඩව ඉහළ නංවා ඇති අතර දැන් අපගේ කණ්ඩායමේ 1200 කට වැඩි පිරිසක් සේවයේ යොදවා සිටිමු,” යෙමන්ස් පැවසීය.",
        "දිවයින ජාතිය මුහුණ දුන් මෑතකාලීන අභියෝග නොතකා, Wacoal Lanka - ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය ආයතනය - නිෂ්පාදන පරිමාවන් පවත්වා ගෙන යන බව ඔහු අනාවරණය කළේය. Wacoal ඉදිරි මාසවලදී අමතර නිෂ්පාදන මාර්ග දෙකක් එකතු කරමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ සිය නිෂ්පාදන පදනම තවදුරටත් ව්‍යාප්ත කිරීමට බලා සිටී. සමගාමීව, සමාගම නව තාක්ෂණය සඳහා ආයෝජනය කරයි. ප්ලස් ප්‍රමාණයේ යට ඇඳුම් වර්ගවල වෙළඳපල ප්‍රමුඛයෙකු වන Wacoal, Wacoal, Fantasie, Freya, Elomi සහ Goddess ඇතුළත් Wacoal යුරෝපය සඳහා එහි පුළුල් සන්නාම කළඹ සමඟින් කාන්තා සමීප ඇඳුම් හරහා ඇතුළත් කිරීම් සහ ශරීර ධනාත්මක බව ප්‍රවර්ධනය කරයි.",
        "“මේ වන විට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තත්ත්වය හා සසඳන විට සියලුම නිෂ්පාදන කඳවුරු හරහා අභියෝගවලට තුඩු දුන් වසංගතයෙන් වැඩි බලපෑමක් අපි දුටුවෙමු. අපි දිගටම රට ගැන විශ්වාසය තබා රට තුළ ආයෝජනය කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අපි නිවැරදි තීරණය ගත් බව තරයේ විශ්වාස කරනවා.",
        "අභියෝග මධ්‍යයේ වුවද, ඇඟලුම් අපනයන කර්මාන්තයේ වැදගත්කම ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලධාරීන් වටහාගෙන ඇති අතර එම අංශයට අඛණ්ඩව සහයෝගය ලබාදී ඇත. පිටියේ සිටින අපගේ කණ්ඩායම, රටේ සෙසු ප්‍රදේශවලට සමානව, ඉතා ඔරොත්තු දෙන අතර ඔවුන් ඉදිරියේ ඇති සෑම නව අභියෝගයකටම අඛණ්ඩව මුහුණ දෙයි, ”යූමන්ස් අවධාරණය කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Wacoal යුරෝපය",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Wacoal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wacoal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇන්ඩෲ යෝමන්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1990 ගණන්වල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2000 ගණන්වල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උසාවි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝට්ස් වියැල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wacoal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1200 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යෝමන්ස්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wacoal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wacoal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wacoal යුරෝපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wacoal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆැන්ටසි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆ්රේයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එලෝමි සහ දේවතාවිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "යෝමන්ස්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "Wacoal Europe இலங்கையில் உற்பத்தித் தளத்தை மேலும் விரிவுபடுத்தும் நோக்கத்தில் உள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னணி வடிவமைப்பாளரும், ஐரோப்பிய சந்தைக்கான உயர்தர, பிளஸ் சைஸ் உள்ளாடைகள் மற்றும் ப்ரா அளவிலான நீச்சலுடை உற்பத்தியாளருமான Wacoal, உயர்தர ஆடைப் பொருட்களை உற்பத்தி செய்யும் இடமாக இலங்கையின் வலுவான போட்டி நன்மைகள், தற்போதைய சூழ்நிலையில் இருந்தாலும், தொடர்ந்தும் பொருந்தும்.",
        "Wacoal Europe Supply Chain பணிப்பாளர் Andrew Yeomans கருத்துப்படி, பொதுவாக குறிப்பிட்ட மற்றும் உயர்தர பாணியில் உயர்தர உள்ளாடைகளுக்கான உற்பத்தித் தளத்திற்குத் தேவையான அனைத்து முக்கிய அளவுகோல்களிலும் இலங்கை அதிக மதிப்பெண்களைப் பெற்றுள்ளது.",
        "\"1990கள் மற்றும் 2000களில், உள்ளாடை உற்பத்தியாளர்கள் இலங்கையை 'இருக்க வேண்டிய இடம்' என்று பார்த்தனர். குறிப்பாக Courtaulds மற்றும் Coats Viyella போன்ற நிறுவனங்கள் இலங்கைக்கு திறன்களை மாற்றுவதற்கு பெரும் முயற்சிகளை மேற்கொண்டன, இதன் விளைவாக, இங்கிலாந்தில் இருந்து இலங்கைக்கு ஒரு பெரிய உற்பத்தி மாற்றம் ஏற்பட்டது. இப்போது, ​​குறிப்பாக உள்ளாடைகளில், இலங்கை மிக உயர்ந்த திறன் தளத்தைக் கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "அதோடு, இலங்கையின் ஆடைத் தொழில்துறையின் முன்னோடிகளும் தொழில்துறைக்கான வலுவான மூலப்பொருள் விநியோகச் சங்கிலியை கட்டியெழுப்புவதில் பெருமளவு முதலீடு செய்துள்ளனர். முக்கிய கப்பல் வழித்தடங்களில் இலங்கையின் இருப்பிடமும் ஒரு பிளஸ் ஆகும். தொற்றுநோய்க்கு முன், இங்கிலாந்துக்கு கப்பல் போக்குவரத்து நேரம் நான்கு வாரங்கள் மட்டுமே, ”என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "Wacoal ஆரம்பத்தில் 2005 இல் இலங்கைக்கு ஒரு முன்னணி இலங்கை உற்பத்தியாளருடன் கூட்டு சேர்ந்து வந்தது. \"இலங்கையில் நாங்கள் தொடர்ந்து எங்கள் செயல்பாடுகளை மேம்படுத்தி வருகிறோம், இப்போது எங்கள் குழுவில் 1200 க்கும் அதிகமானோர் பணியாற்றி வருகிறோம்\" என்று யோமன்ஸ் கூறினார்.",
        "தீவு நாடு சமீபகாலமாக சவால்களை எதிர்கொண்ட போதிலும், Wacoal Lanka - இலங்கையின் உற்பத்தி அளவுகள் பேணப்பட்டு வருவதாக அவர் வெளிப்படுத்தினார். Wacoal இலங்கையில் அதன் உற்பத்தித் தளத்தை மேலும் விரிவுபடுத்துவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டுள்ளது, மேலும் இரண்டு கூடுதல் உற்பத்திக் கோடுகள் வரவிருக்கும் மாதங்களில் சேர்க்கப்படும். இணைந்து, நிறுவனம் தொடர்ந்து புதிய தொழில்நுட்பத்தில் முதலீடு செய்து வருகிறது. பிளஸ்-சைஸ் உள்ளாடை வகைகளில் சந்தையில் முன்னணியில் இருக்கும் Wacoal, Wacoal, Fantasie, Freya, Elomi மற்றும் Goddess ஆகியவற்றை உள்ளடக்கிய Wacoal ஐரோப்பாவுக்கான அதன் விரிவான பிராண்ட் போர்ட்ஃபோலியோவுடன் பெண்களின் நெருக்கமான உடைகள் மூலம் உள்ளடக்கம் மற்றும் உடல் நேர்மறையை ஊக்குவிக்கிறது.",
        "“இப்போது இலங்கையின் நிலைமையுடன் ஒப்பிடும் போது, ​​அனைத்து உற்பத்தித் தளங்களிலும் சவால்களை ஏற்படுத்திய தொற்றுநோய்களின் தாக்கத்தை நாங்கள் அதிகம் கண்டோம். நாட்டில் தொடர்ந்து நம்பிக்கை வைத்து, நாட்டில் தொடர்ந்து முதலீடு செய்வதில் சரியான முடிவை எடுத்துள்ளோம் என்று உறுதியாக நம்புகிறோம்.",
        "சவால்கள் இருந்தபோதிலும், இலங்கை அதிகாரிகள் ஆடை ஏற்றுமதி தொழில்துறையின் முக்கியத்துவத்தை புரிந்து கொண்டு, அத்துறைக்கு தொடர்ந்து ஆதரவளித்து வருகின்றனர். நாட்டின் மற்ற பகுதிகளைப் போலவே மைதானத்தில் உள்ள எங்கள் அணி, மிகவும் நெகிழ்ச்சியுடன் உள்ளது மற்றும் அவர்களுக்கு முன் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள ஒவ்வொரு புதிய சவாலையும் தொடர்ந்து எதிர்கொள்கிறது, ”என்று யோமன்ஸ் வலியுறுத்தினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Wacoal ஐரோப்பா",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வகோல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வகோல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்ட்ரூ யோமன்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1990கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2000கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றாலங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்ஸ் வியெல்லா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வகோல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1200க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோமன்ஸ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வகோல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வகோல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wacoal ஐரோப்பா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வகோல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கற்பனை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃப்ரேயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எலோமி மற்றும் தெய்வம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோமன்ஸ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}