{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84515/visiting-imf-delegation-calls-on-president-ranil",
  "time_ut": 1661343780,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Visiting IMF delegation calls on President Ranil",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Visiting IMF delegation calls on President Ranil",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The visiting delegation of the International Monetary Fund (IMF) has called on Sri Lanka President Ranil Wickremesinghe this evening (Aug 24) to discuss the current situation of the economic crisis the nation is grappling with at present.",
        "The meeting with the Head of State came after the delegates of the global lender kicked off discussions with Governor of Central Bank of Sri Lanka, Dr. Nandalal Weerasinghe this morning, to finalize a staff-level agreement for a possible USD 3 billion bailout package, including restructuring debt of about USD 29 billion.",
        "IMF’s Resident Representative for Sri Lanka, Tubagus Feridhanusetyawan and Finance Secretary Mahinda Siriwardana also participated in the talks at the Central Bank premises.",
        "The IM delegation will be in Colombo from August 24 to 31. Another round of discussion is scheduled to take place on August 26.",
        "During the meeting with President Wickremesinghe, the IMF delegates decided to hold further discussions with the Central Bank officials on technical issues, the President’s Media Division (PMD) said.",
        "Chief of the Debt Capital Markets Division of IMF’s Monetary and Capital Market Department Mr. Peter Breuer, Secretary to President Saman Ekanayake, President’s Chief of Staff Sagala Ratnayake and Central Bank Governor Dr. Nanadalal Weerasinghealso joined the discussion."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD 3 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "about USD 29 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF’s Resident Representative for",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Siriwardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 24 to 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PMD",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Debt Capital Markets Division of IMF’s Monetary and",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Capital Market Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peter Breuer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sagala Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanadalal Weerasinghealso",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නියෝජිත පිරිසක් ජනාධිපති රනිල් හමුවෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ (IMF) සංචාරයක නිරත වූ නියෝජිත පිරිස අද (අගෝස්තු 24) සවස ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා හමුවී ජාතිය වර්තමානයේ පොරබදමින් සිටින ආර්ථික අර්බුදයේ වත්මන් තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කර තිබේ.",
        "ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 3 ක ඇපදීමේ පැකේජයක් සඳහා කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමක් අවසන් කිරීම සඳහා ගෝලීය ණය දෙන්නාගේ නියෝජිතයින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවේ අධිපති ආචාර්ය නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ මහතා සමඟ අද පෙරවරුවේ සාකච්ඡා ආරම්භ කිරීමෙන් පසුව රාජ්‍ය නායකයා සමඟ මෙම හමුව සිදුවිය. ඩොලර් බිලියන 29 ක පමණ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම ඇතුළුව.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා වන නේවාසික නියෝජිත Tubagus Feridhanusetyawan සහ මුදල් ලේකම් මහින්ද සිරිවර්ධන ද මහ බැංකු පරිශ්‍රයේ පැවති සාකච්ඡා සඳහා සහභාගී වූහ.",
        "IM නියෝජිත පිරිස අගෝස්තු 24 සිට 31 දක්වා කොළඹ සිටින අතර තවත් සාකච්ඡාවක් අගෝස්තු 26 වැනිදා පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතය.",
        "ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවේදී තාක්ෂණික ගැටලු සම්බන්ධයෙන් මහ බැංකු නිලධාරීන් සමඟ තවදුරටත් සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට IMF නියෝජිතයින් තීරණය කළ බව ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය (PMD) පැවසීය.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ මූල්‍ය හා ප්‍රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ණය ප්‍රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ අංශයේ ප්‍රධානී පීටර් බෲවර් මහතා, ජනාධිපති ලේකම් සමන් ඒකනායක මහතා, ජනාධිපති කාර්ය මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානී සාගල රත්නායක මහතා සහ මහ බැංකු අධිපති ආචාර්ය නානදලාල් වීරසිංහ මහතා ද සාකච්ඡාවට එක් විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 3 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 29 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳහා IMF හි නේවාසික නියෝජිතයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 24 සිට 31 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීඑම්ඩී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ණය ප්‍රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ අංශය සහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peter Breuer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගල රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නානදලාල් වීරසිංහත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வருகை தந்துள்ள சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகள் ஜனாதிபதி ரணிலை சந்தித்தனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்த சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் (IMF) பிரதிநிதிகள் இன்று (ஆகஸ்ட் 24) மாலை இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை சந்தித்து நாடு தற்போது போராடி வரும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியின் தற்போதைய நிலைமை குறித்து கலந்துரையாடியுள்ளனர்.",
        "3 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர் பெறுமதியான பிணை எடுப்புப் பொதிக்கான பணியாளர் மட்ட உடன்படிக்கையை இறுதி செய்வதற்கு உலகளாவிய கடன் வழங்குநரின் பிரதிநிதிகள் இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கியின் ஆளுநர் கலாநிதி நந்தலால் வீரசிங்கவுடன் இன்று காலை கலந்துரையாடலை ஆரம்பித்த பின்னர் அரச தலைவருடனான சந்திப்பு இடம்பெற்றது. சுமார் USD 29 பில்லியன் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு உட்பட.",
        "மத்திய வங்கி வளாகத்தில் நடைபெற்ற பேச்சுவார்த்தையில் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் இலங்கைக்கான வதிவிடப் பிரதிநிதி டுபாகஸ் பெரிதானுசெட்டியவான் மற்றும் நிதிச் செயலாளர் மஹிந்த சிறிவர்தன ஆகியோரும் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "ஐஎம் குழு ஆகஸ்ட் 24 முதல் 31 வரை கொழும்பில் இருக்கும். மற்றொரு சுற்று பேச்சுவார்த்தை ஆகஸ்ட் 26 அன்று நடைபெற உள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்கவுடனான சந்திப்பின் போது, ​​IMF பிரதிநிதிகள் மத்திய வங்கி அதிகாரிகளுடன் தொழில்நுட்ப பிரச்சினைகள் குறித்து மேலும் கலந்துரையாடல்களை நடத்த தீர்மானித்ததாக ஜனாதிபதியின் ஊடகப் பிரிவு (PMD) தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் நாணய மற்றும் மூலதன சந்தைத் திணைக்களத்தின் கடன் மூலதனச் சந்தைப் பிரிவின் பிரதானி திரு. பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர், ஜனாதிபதியின் செயலாளர் சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க, ஜனாதிபதியின் தலைமை அதிகாரி சாகல ரத்நாயக்க மற்றும் மத்திய வங்கியின் ஆளுநர் கலாநிதி நானாடலால் வீரசிங்க ஆகியோரும் கலந்துரையாடலில் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD 3 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 29 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF இன் வதிவிடப் பிரதிநிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.எம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 24 முதல் 31 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிஎம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் கடன் மூலதன சந்தைப் பிரிவு மற்றும்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூலதன சந்தை துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகல ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நானாடலால் வீரசிங்கவும்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}