{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/CID-records-statement-from-Maithripala/108-243365",
  "time_ut": 1660901325,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "CID records statement from Maithripala",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CID records statement from Maithripala",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Criminal Investigations Department (CID) has recorded a statement from former President Maithripala Sirisena on Wednesday in connection with granting a presidential pardon to Royal Park murder convict Shramantha Jayamaha.",
        "The CID team had visited the former President's residence to record the statment.The recorded statement had been forwarded to the Attorney General.",
        "Shramantha Jayamaha was sentenced to death for the murder of Yvonne Jonsson at the Royal Park Condominium complex in Rajagiriya in 2005. Former President Maithripala Sirisena granted him a presidential pardon in 2016.",
        "Parliamentarian Ven. Athureliya Rathana Thera had earlier filed a complaint with the Criminal Investigations Department (CID) calling for an inquiry into a statement made by former President Maithripala Sirisena over granting a presidential pardon to the Royal Park murder convict Shramantha Jayamaha."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CID",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Maithripala",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Criminal Investigations Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Royal Park",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shramantha Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shramantha Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yvonne Jonsson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Royal Park Condominium",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajagiriya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarian Ven",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Athureliya Rathana Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigations Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Royal Park",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shramantha Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "CID මෛත්‍රීගෙන් ප්‍රකාශයක් සටහන් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රෝයල් පාර්ක් ඝාතනයේ වරදකරු වූ ශ්‍රමන්ත ජයමහට ජනාධිපති සමාව ලබාදීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව (CID) හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතාගෙන් බදාදා ප්‍රකාශයක් සටහන් කරගෙන තිබේ.",
        "ප්‍රකාශය සටහන් කර ගැනීම සඳහා අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තු කණ්ඩායම හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ නිවසට පැමිණ තිබේ.",
        "2005 වසරේ රාජගිරිය රෝයල් පාර්ක් සහාධිපත්‍ය සංකීර්ණයේදී ඉවෝන් ජොන්සන් ඝාතනය කිරීමේ චෝදනාවට මරණ දඬුවම නියම වූ ශ්‍රමන්ත ජයමහට 2016 වසරේදී හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා ජනාධිපති සමාව ලබා දුන්නේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී හාමුදුරුවෝ. රෝයල් පාර්ක් ඝාතනයේ වරදකරු වූ ශ්‍රමන්ත ජයමහට ජනාධිපති සමාව ලබාදීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන කළ ප්‍රකාශයක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා අතුරලියේ රතන හිමියන් මීට පෙර අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට (CID) පැමිණිල්ලක් ගොනු කර තිබුණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CID",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජකීය උද්යානය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රමන්ත ජයමහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රමන්ත ජයමහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉවෝන් ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෝයල් පාර්ක් සහාධිපත්‍යය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජගිරිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී හාමුදුරුවෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අතුරලියේ රතන හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජකීය උද්යානය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රමන්ත ජයමහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மைத்திரிபாலவிடம் CID வாக்குமூலம் பதிவு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ரோயல் பார்க் கொலைக் குற்றவாளி ஷ்ரமந்த ஜயமஹாவுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி பொதுமன்னிப்பு வழங்கியமை தொடர்பில் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேனவிடம் குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களம் (CID) புதன்கிழமை வாக்குமூலம் பதிவு செய்துள்ளது.",
        "வாக்குமூலத்தைப் பதிவு செய்வதற்காக குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினர் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியின் இல்லத்திற்குச் சென்றிருந்தனர். பதிவு செய்யப்பட்ட வாக்குமூலம் சட்டமா அதிபருக்கு அனுப்பி வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "2005 ஆம் ஆண்டு இராஜகிரிய ரோயல் பார்க் காண்டோமினிய வளாகத்தில் இவோன் ஜோன்சன் படுகொலை செய்யப்பட்ட குற்றத்திற்காக ஷ்ரமந்த ஜயமஹாவிற்கு மரண தண்டனை விதிக்கப்பட்டது. முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன அவருக்கு 2016 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு வழங்கினார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் வண. ரோயல் பார்க் கொலைக் குற்றவாளி ஷ்ரமந்த ஜயமஹாவுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி பொதுமன்னிப்பு வழங்கியமை தொடர்பில் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன தெரிவித்த கருத்து தொடர்பில் விசாரணை நடத்துமாறு கோரி அத்துரெலிய ரத்ன தேரர் குற்றப் புலனாய்வு திணைக்களத்தில் (CID) இதற்கு முன்னர் முறைப்பாடு செய்திருந்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "மைத்திரிபால",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராயல் பார்க்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஶ்ரமந்த ஜயமஹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஶ்ரமந்த ஜயமஹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இவோன் ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராயல் பார்க் காண்டோமினியம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜகிரிய",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் வண",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அத்துரெலிய ரத்தன தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராயல் பார்க்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஶ்ரமந்த ஜயமஹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}