{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/‘‘ණය-ප්‍රතිව්‍යූහගත-කිරීමේදී-කාටත්-සමාන-විය-යුතුයි‘‘/101-616054",
  "time_ut": 1657261628,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "‘‘ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යූහගත කිරීමේදී කාටත් සමාන විය යුතුයි‘‘",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "\"Everyone should be equal in debt restructuring\"",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mrs. Julie Chang, the American Ambassador to Sri Lanka, said that China or any other country should not give special consideration to Sri Lanka in debt restructuring and all parties that have given loans to Sri Lanka should be treated equally.",
        "American Ambassador Mrs. Julie Chang said that the only solution available to recover from the current economic crisis in Sri Lanka is to get the support of the International Monetary Fund.",
        "She mentioned that it is something that not only the United States of America, the international community, but even the Sri Lankan people believe in.",
        "Mrs. Julie Chang stated that not only America, Japan and India but also the international community as well as economists recommended that Sri Lanka should get the support of the International Monetary Fund at the beginning of the current economic crisis in Sri Lanka and Sri Lanka was late in getting the support of the International Monetary Fund.",
        "Mrs. Julie Chang said that the debt restructuring process and its transparency should not be done just because the International Monetary Fund recommends it, and it will also benefit Sri Lanka.",
        "Mrs. Julie Chung stated that it will be very difficult for Sri Lanka to implement the policies and decisions they recommend to support the International Monetary Fund. She noted that implementing the recommendations of the International Monetary Fund is a difficult task not only for Sri Lanka but for any country in the world.",
        "Ms. Julie Chang said that Sri Lanka, as bilateral partners of the International Monetary Fund and the United States of America, should take care to protect the vulnerable people as well as the poor in implementing those recommendations. That is why humanitarian assistance is important to Sri Lanka. did",
        "Ms. Julie Chung said that the United States of America and Paris Club partners are supporting the recovery of Sri Lanka's economy. But she added that not only Western countries, Japan and India but also China should come forward to support Sri Lanka at this time.",
        "Ms. Julie Chung stated that the international community should decide what kind of assistance can be given to Sri Lanka and provide it. She also stated that assistance should be given to the parties that have given loans to Sri Lanka to restructure their debt."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Julie Chang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "American",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "American",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Chang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the United States of America",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Julie Chang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "America",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Julie Chang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Julie Chang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States of America",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States of America",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paris Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘‘ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යූහගත කිරීමේදී කාටත් සමාන විය යුතුයි‘‘",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යූහගත කිරීමේදී චීනයට හෝ වෙනත් කිසිම රටකට විශේෂ සැලකිල්ලක් නොදැක්විය යුතු බවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ණය ලබා දුන් සියලු පාර්ශ්වයන්ට එක සමාන ලෙස සැලකිය යුතු බවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඇමෙරිකානු තානාපති ජුලී චන්ග් මහත්මිය ප්‍රකාශ කළාය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඇති වී තිබෙන වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩ ඒමට තිබෙන එකම විසඳුම ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සහාය ලබා ගැනීම බව ඇමෙරිකානු තානාපති ජුලී චන්ග් මහත්මිය පැවසුවාය.",
        "එය ඇමෙරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය,ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාව පමණක් නොව ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනතාව පවා විශ්වාස කරන දෙයක් බව ඇය සඳහන් කළාය.",
        "ඇමෙරිකාව,ජපානය සහ ඉන්දියාව පමණක් නොව ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සහාය ලබා ගත යුතු යැයි ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාව මෙන්ම ආර්ථික විද්‍යාඥයන් ද ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදය ආරම්භයේදී නිර්දේශ කළ බවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සහාය ලබා ගැනීමට ප්‍රමාද වූ බවත් ජුලී චන්ග් මහත්මිය ප්‍රකාශ කළාය.",
        "ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යූහගත කිරීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය සහ එහි විනිවිදභාවය ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල නිර්දේශ කළ පමණින් කළ යුතු දෙයක් නොවන බවත් ඉන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවටද  යහපතක් සිදු වන බවත් ජුලී චන්ග් මහත්මිය පැවසුවාය.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සහාය ලබා දීම සඳහා ඔවුන් නිර්දේශ කරන ප්‍රතිපත්ති සහ තීරණ ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඉතාමත් අපහසු වනු ඇතැයි ජුලී චන්ග් මහත්මිය ප්‍රකාශ කළාය.ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නිර්දේශ ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පමණක් නොව ලෝකයේ ඕනෑම රටකට අපහසු කටයුත්තක් බව ඇය සඳහන් කළාය.",
        "නමුත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව එම නිර්දේශ ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමේදී ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල සහ ඇමෙරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය ද්වි පාර්ශ්වික හවුල් කරුවන් ලෙස අපි දැඩි අවදානමකට ලක්වූ ජනතාව මෙන්ම දුප්පත් ජනතාව ආරක්ෂා කර ගැනීමට වගබලා ගත යුතු බව ජුලී චන්ග් මහත්මිය පැවසුවාය.ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට මානුෂීය සහාය වැදගත් වන්නේ එම නිසා බව ඇය සඳහන් කළාය.",
        "ඇමෙරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය සහ පැරිස් ක්ලබ් හවුල් කරුවන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථිකය නැවත යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් කිරීමට සහාය දක්වන බව ජුලී චන්ග් මහත්මිය පැවසුවාය. නමුත් බටහිර රටවල්,ජපානය සහ ඉන්දියාව පමණක් නෙවෙයි චීනයද මේ වෙලාවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය දැක්වීමට ඉදිරියට පැමිණිය යුතු බව ඇය වැඩි දුරටත් පැවසුවාය.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාව  ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබා දිය හැක්කේ කුමන ආකාරයක සහායක් දැයි තීරණය කර එය ලබා දිය යුතු බව ජුලී චන්ග් මහත්මිය ප්‍රකාශ කළාය.ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ණය ලබා දී ඇති පාර්ශ්ව ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යූහගත කිරීම සඳහා සහාය ලබා දිය යුතු බවද ඇය සඳහන් කළාය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චෑන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චෑන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චෑන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චෑන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චෑන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැරිස් සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பில் அனைவரும் சமமாக இருக்க வேண்டும்\"",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பில் சீனாவோ அல்லது வேறு எந்த நாடுகளோ இலங்கைக்கு விசேட கவனம் செலுத்தக் கூடாது எனவும், இலங்கைக்கு கடன் வழங்கிய அனைத்து தரப்பினரையும் சமமாக நடத்த வேண்டும் எனவும் இலங்கைக்கான அமெரிக்கத் தூதுவர் திருமதி ஜூலி சாங் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து மீள்வதற்கு சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் ஆதரவைப் பெறுவதே ஒரே தீர்வு என அமெரிக்கத் தூதுவர் திருமதி ஜூலி சாங் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இது அமெரிக்கா, சர்வதேச சமூகம் மட்டுமன்றி, இலங்கை மக்களும் கூட நம்புகின்ற ஒன்று என அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "அமெரிக்கா, ஜப்பான் மற்றும் இந்தியா மட்டுமன்றி சர்வதேச சமூகம் மற்றும் பொருளாதார நிபுணர்களும் இலங்கை மற்றும் இலங்கையில் தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியின் ஆரம்பத்தில் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் ஆதரவை இலங்கை பெற வேண்டும் என்று பரிந்துரைத்ததாக திருமதி ஜூலி சாங் தெரிவித்தார். சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் ஆதரவைப் பெறுவதில் தாமதம்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் சிபாரிசு செய்வதால் மட்டும் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு செயல்முறையும் அதன் வெளிப்படைத்தன்மையும் செய்யப்படக்கூடாது என்றும் அது இலங்கைக்கும் நன்மை பயக்கும் என்றும் திருமதி ஜூலி சாங் கூறினார்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தை ஆதரிப்பதற்காக அவர்கள் பரிந்துரைக்கும் கொள்கைகள் மற்றும் தீர்மானங்களை நடைமுறைப்படுத்துவது இலங்கைக்கு மிகவும் கடினமாக இருக்கும் என்று கூறிய திருமதி ஜூலி சுங், சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பரிந்துரைகளை அமுல்படுத்துவது இலங்கைக்கு மாத்திரமன்றி கடினமான பணியாகும். உலகின் எந்த நாட்டிற்கும்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் மற்றும் அமெரிக்காவின் இருதரப்பு பங்காளிகள் என்ற வகையில் இலங்கை, அந்த பரிந்துரைகளை நடைமுறைப்படுத்துவதில் பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடிய மக்களையும் ஏழைகளையும் பாதுகாப்பதில் அக்கறை செலுத்த வேண்டும் என்றும், அதனால்தான் மனிதாபிமான உதவி முக்கியமானது என்றும் திருமதி ஜூலி சாங் கூறினார். இலங்கை செய்தது",
        "இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரத்தை மீட்பதற்கு அமெரிக்கா மற்றும் பாரிஸ் கிளப் பங்காளிகள் ஆதரவளிப்பதாக திருமதி ஜூலி சுங் தெரிவித்தார். ஆனால் மேற்கத்திய நாடுகள், ஜப்பான், இந்தியா மட்டுமன்றி சீனாவும் இந்த நேரத்தில் இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவளிக்க முன்வர வேண்டும் எனவும் அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கு எவ்வாறான உதவிகளை வழங்குவது என்பதை சர்வதேச சமூகம் தீர்மானித்து வழங்க வேண்டும் என தெரிவித்த திருமதி ஜூலி சுங், இலங்கைக்கு கடன் வழங்கிய தரப்பினருக்கு கடனை மறுசீரமைக்க உதவிகள் வழங்கப்பட வேண்டுமெனவும் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சாங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சாங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சாங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சாங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சாங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ் கிளப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}