{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Counting-of-votes-begins-in-Parliament/342-241440",
  "time_ut": 1658298354,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Counting of votes begins in Parliament",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Counting of votes begins in Parliament",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Casting votes to elect the next President concluded in Parliament a short while ago and the counting has begun.",
        "A total of 223 MPs including the Speaker voted while two MPS abstained from the voting.",
        "Meanwhile, the speaker announced that all the three candidates could monitor the counting of the votes or they can nominate a representative.",
        "However, the Speaker informed no mobile phones will be permitted during the counting.",
        "Accordingly, Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe nominated MP Harin Fernando while Dullas Alahapperuma has nominated MP Dillan Perera and Anura Kumara Dissanayake has nominated MP Vijitha Herath to monitor the counting process.",
        "Currently the valid votes are being separated and the count will take place from the valid votes."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MPS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dillan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ඡන්ද ගණන් කිරීම ආරම්භ වේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මීළඟ ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමේ ඡන්ද විමසීම මීට සුළු මොහොතකට පෙර පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී අවසන් වූ අතර ගණන් කිරීම ආරම්භ වී තිබේ.",
        "කථානායකවරයා ඇතුළු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 223 දෙනෙකු ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළ අතර මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් දෙදෙනෙකු ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් වැළකී සිටියා.",
        "මේ අතර අපේක්ෂකයින් තිදෙනාටම ඡන්ද ගණන් කිරීම නිරීක්ෂණය කළ හැකි බව හෝ නියෝජිතයෙකු නම් කළ හැකි බව කථානායකවරයා නිවේදනය කළේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ගණන් කිරීමේ දී ජංගම දුරකථන සඳහා අවසර ලබා නොදෙන බව කථානායකවරයා දැනුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "ඒ අනුව වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා නම් කළ අතර ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩිලාන් පෙරේරා මහතා නම් කර ඇති අතර අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක මහතා විසින් ඡන්ද ගණන් කිරීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය නිරීක්ෂණය කිරීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී විජිත හේරත් මහතා නම් කර ඇත.",
        "දැනට වලංගු ඡන්ද වෙන්කරමින් පවතින අතර වලංගු ඡන්දවලින් ගණන් කිරීම සිදු කෙරේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.පී.එස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩිලාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் வாக்கு எண்ணிக்கை தொடங்கியது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அடுத்த ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான வாக்குப்பதிவு சற்று முன்னர் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நிறைவடைந்து வாக்கு எண்ணிக்கை ஆரம்பமாகியுள்ளது.",
        "சபாநாயகர் உட்பட 223 எம்.பி.க்கள் வாக்களித்ததுடன், இரண்டு எம்.பி.க்கள் வாக்கெடுப்பில் கலந்து கொள்ளவில்லை.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், மூன்று வேட்பாளர்களும் வாக்கு எண்ணிக்கையை கண்காணிக்கலாம் அல்லது அவர்கள் ஒரு பிரதிநிதியை நியமிக்கலாம் என்று சபாநாயகர் அறிவித்தார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், வாக்கு எண்ணிக்கையின் போது கையடக்கத் தொலைபேசிகள் எதுவும் அனுமதிக்கப்பட மாட்டாது என சபாநாயகர் அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதன்படி, பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோவை நியமித்துள்ளதுடன், டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டிலான் பெரேராவையும், அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் விஜித ஹேரத்தை எண்ணும் செயற்பாடுகளை கண்காணிக்கவும் பரிந்துரைத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "தற்போது செல்லுபடியாகும் வாக்குகள் பிரிக்கப்பட்டு, செல்லுபடியாகும் வாக்குகளில் இருந்து எண்ணிக்கை நடைபெறும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.பி.எஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிலான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}