{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/21/shooting-in-sri-lanka-s-south-two-dead/",
  "time_ut": 1661097720,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Shooting in Sri Lanka’s South: Two dead",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Shooting in Sri Lanka’s South: Two dead",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Colombo (News 1st): Two people were gunned down at a hotel in Ambalangoda on Sunday (21) evening.",
        "Sri Lanka Police said that the shooting took place at an upper floor of a hotel located in Delduwa, Ambalangoda.",
        "No further details were available about the shooter or shooters, or the motive for the shooting.",
        "World Bank impose strict regulations for fertilizer imports – Report"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21) evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Delduwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දකුණේ වෙඩි තැබීමක්: දෙදෙනෙකු මරුට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st) – ඉරිදා (21) සවස අම්බලන්ගොඩ හෝටලයකදී පුද්ගලයන් දෙදෙනෙකු වෙඩි තබා ඝාතනය කර තිබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය පැවසුවේ අම්බලන්ගොඩ දෙල්දූව ප්‍රදේශයේ පිහිටි හෝටලයක ඉහළ මහලකදී මෙම වෙඩි තැබීම සිදුව ඇති බවයි.",
        "වෙඩික්කරු හෝ වෙඩික්කරුවන් හෝ වෙඩි තැබීමට හේතුව පිළිබඳව වැඩිදුර තොරතුරු නොමැත.",
        "ලෝක බැංකුව පොහොර ආනයනය සඳහා දැඩි රෙගුලාසි පනවයි – වාර්තාව"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙල්දූව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் தெற்கில் துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு: இருவர் பலி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "Colombo (News 1st) அம்பலாங்கொடையில் உள்ள ஹோட்டல் ஒன்றில் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை (21) மாலை இருவர் சுட்டுக் கொல்லப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "அம்பலாங்கொடை தெல்துவ பகுதியில் அமைந்துள்ள ஹோட்டல் ஒன்றின் மேல் தளத்தில் துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாக இலங்கை பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தியவர் அல்லது துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தியவர் குறித்த கூடுதல் விவரங்கள் அல்லது துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தியதற்கான காரணம் எதுவும் கிடைக்கவில்லை.",
        "உர இறக்குமதிக்கு உலக வங்கி கடுமையான கட்டுப்பாடுகளை விதித்துள்ளது – அறிக்கை"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21) மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெல்டுவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}