{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84710/second-reading-of-interim-budget-2022-passed-in-parliament",
  "time_ut": 1662120540,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Second Reading of Interim Budget 2022 passed in parliament",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Second Reading of Interim Budget 2022 passed in parliament",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Second Reading of the Appropriation (Amendment) Bill for the remainder of the fiscal year 2022 was passed in Parliament with amendments today (Sep 02) by a majority of 115 votes.",
        "Announcing the results of the division which followed the conclusion of the debate on the Second Reading of the Interim Budget 2022, the Speaker said that 120 lawmakers had voted in favour while 05 voted against.",
        "The Appropriation Bill presented by the former Minister Basil Rajapaksa, who was the Minister of Finance at the time, was passed in Parliament following a debate held on the Bill for the purpose of providing necessary service expenses and arrangements for the fiscal year 2022.",
        "Thereby, the Appropriation Bill was endorsed and certified as an Act on December 10, 2021 and was herein called the Appropriation Act No. 30 of 2021.",
        "After Ranil Wickremesinghe assumed the office of President, the parliament was prorogued on July 28, 2022 and the third session of the Ninth Parliament was declared open on August 03, 2022. While presenting his government’s policy statement, President Wickremesinghe stated that he would soon present a new budget.",
        "As a result, this Appropriation Bill for the remainder of the 2022 fiscal year as a new government is presented to parliament as an amendment to the previously presented Appropriation Bill.",
        "Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena, on behalf of the Minister of Finance, presented the Appropriation (Amendment) Bill to amend the Appropriation Act No. 30 of 2021 to the Parliament for the first reading on August 09, 2022.",
        "On August 30, President Wickremesinghe, in his capacity as the Minister of Finance, Economic Stabilization and National Policies, delivered the interim budget speech or the second reading of the Appropriation (Amendment) Bill when the parliament convened at 1.00 p.m.",
        "After the Interim Budget 2022 was delivered, the parliament was adjourned for the day and the debate kicked off the following day (Aug 31)."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Second Reading of Interim Budget 2022",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Second Reading of the Appropriation (Amendment",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the fiscal year 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "115",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "120",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bill",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the fiscal year 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "December 10, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Appropriation Act No.",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 28, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ninth Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 03, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Appropriation (Amendment) Bill",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Appropriation Act No.",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 09, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Economic Stabilization",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Appropriation (Amendment) Bill",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.00 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Interim Budget 2022",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the following day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "2022 අතුරු අයවැය දෙවන වර කියවීම පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී සම්මත විය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "2022 මුදල් වර්ෂයේ ඉතිරි කාලය සඳහා වූ විසර්ජන (සංශෝධන) පනත් කෙටුම්පත දෙවැනි වර කියවීම සංශෝධන සහිතව අද (සැප් 02) වැඩි ඡන්ද 115 කින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී සම්මත විය.",
        "2022 අතුරු අයවැය දෙවැනිවර කියවීමේ විවාදය අවසන් වීමෙන් අනතුරුව පැවැති කොට්ඨාසයේ ප්‍රතිඵල ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරමින් කථානායකවරයා කියා සිටියේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 120 දෙනෙකු පක්ෂව ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළ අතර විපක්ෂව ඡන්ද 05ක් ලැබුණු බවයි.",
        "2022 මුල්‍ය වර්ෂය සඳහා අවශ්‍ය සේවා වියදම් සහ විධිවිධාන සැලසීම සඳහා වූ පනත් කෙටුම්පත පිළිබඳ පැවති විවාදයකින් අනතුරුව එවකට මුදල් අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කළ හිටපු අමාත්‍ය බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉදිරිපත් කළ විසර්ජන පනත් කෙටුම්පත පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී සම්මත විය.",
        "එමගින්, විසර්ජන පනත් කෙටුම්පත 2021 දෙසැම්බර් 10 වැනි දින පනතක් ලෙස අනුමත කර සහතික කරන ලද අතර මෙහි 2021 අංක 30 දරන විසර්ජන පනත ලෙස හැඳින්වේ.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපති ධූරයට පත්වීමෙන් පසු 2022 ජූලි 28 වැනි දින පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කල් තැබූ අතර නවවැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ තෙවැනි සැසිවාරය 2022 අගෝස්තු 03 වැනි දින විවෘත කරන ලදී. තම රජයේ ප්‍රතිපත්ති ප්‍රකාශය ඉදිරිපත් කරමින් ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ තමන් ළඟදීම ඉදිරිපත් කරන බවයි. නව අයවැයක්.",
        "එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස නව රජයක් ලෙස 2022 මුදල් වර්ෂයේ ඉතිරි කාලය සඳහා වන මෙම විසර්ජන පනත් කෙටුම්පත මීට පෙර ඉදිරිපත් කළ විසර්ජන පනත් කෙටුම්පතට සංශෝධනයක් ලෙස පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කෙරේ.",
        "2021 අංක 30 දරන විසර්ජන පනත සංශෝධනය කිරීම සඳහා වූ විසර්ජන (සංශෝධන) පනත් කෙටුම්පත 2022 අගෝස්තු 09 වැනි දින පළමු කියවීම සඳහා මුදල් අමාත්‍යවරයා වෙනුවෙන් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා විසින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලදී.",
        "අගෝස්තු 30 වැනි දින, මුදල්, ආර්ථික ස්ථායීකරණ සහ ජාතික ප්‍රතිපත්ති අමාත්‍යවරයා වශයෙන් ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා, පාර්ලිමේන්තුව පස්වරු 1.00 ට රැස් වූ විට අතුරු අයවැය කතාව හෝ විසර්ජන (සංශෝධන) පනත් කෙටුම්පත දෙවැනි වර කියවීම සිදු කළේය.",
        "2022 අතුරු අයවැය ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමෙන් පසු පාර්ලිමේන්තුව දිනය සඳහා කල් තැබූ අතර විවාදය පසුදා (අගෝස්තු 31) ආරම්භ විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "2022 අතුරු අයවැය දෙවන වර කියවීම",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "විසර්ජන දෙවන වර කියවීම (සංශෝධන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 මුදල් වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "115",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "120",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිල්පත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 මුදල් වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙසැම්බර් 10, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විසර්ජන පනත අංක.",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවවැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 03",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විසර්ජන (සංශෝධන) පනත් කෙටුම්පත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විසර්ජන පනත අංක.",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්ථික ස්ථාවරත්වය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විසර්ජන (සංශෝධන) පනත් කෙටුම්පත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.00 ප.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 අතුරු අයවැය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ දවසේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "2022 இடைக்கால பட்ஜெட் இரண்டாம் வாசிப்பு நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் நிறைவேற்றப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் எஞ்சிய நிதியாண்டுக்கான ஒதுக்கீட்டு (திருத்த) சட்டமூலத்தின் இரண்டாம் வாசிப்பு இன்று (செப். 02) 115 மேலதிக வாக்குகளால் திருத்தங்களுடன் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நிறைவேற்றப்பட்டது.",
        "2022 இடைக்கால வரவுசெலவுத்திட்டத்தின் இரண்டாம் வாசிப்பு மீதான விவாதம் முடிவடைந்ததைத் தொடர்ந்து நடைபெற்ற பிரிவினை முடிவுகளை அறிவிக்கும் சபாநாயகர், 120 நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் ஆதரவாகவும் 05 பேர் எதிராகவும் வாக்களித்ததாக தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "2022ஆம் நிதியாண்டுக்கு தேவையான சேவைச் செலவுகள் மற்றும் ஏற்பாடுகளை வழங்குவதற்கான சட்டமூலம் மீதான விவாதத்தை அடுத்து, அப்போதைய நிதி அமைச்சராக இருந்த முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் பசில் ராஜபக்ஷவினால் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட ஒதுக்கீட்டுச் சட்டமூலம் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நிறைவேற்றப்பட்டது.",
        "இதன் மூலம், ஒதுக்கீட்டு மசோதா டிசம்பர் 10, 2021 அன்று ஒரு சட்டமாக அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்டு சான்றளிக்கப்பட்டது மற்றும் இங்கு 2021 ஆம் ஆண்டின் ஒதுக்கீட்டுச் சட்டம் எண். 30 என்று அழைக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியேற்ற பின்னர், 2022 ஜூலை 28 இல் பாராளுமன்றம் ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்டது மற்றும் ஒன்பதாவது பாராளுமன்றத்தின் மூன்றாவது அமர்வு ஆகஸ்ட் 03, 2022 அன்று திறக்கப்பட்டது. தனது அரசாங்கத்தின் கொள்கை அறிக்கையை சமர்ப்பித்து, ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க விரைவில் சமர்ப்பிப்பதாக தெரிவித்தார். ஒரு புதிய பட்ஜெட்.",
        "இதன் விளைவாக, புதிய அரசாங்கமாக 2022 நிதியாண்டின் எஞ்சிய காலத்திற்கான இந்த ஒதுக்கீட்டுச் சட்டமூலம், முன்னர் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்ட ஒதுக்கீட்டுச் சட்டமூலத்தில் திருத்தமாக பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "2021 ஆம் ஆண்டின் 30 ஆம் இலக்க ஒதுக்கீட்டுச் சட்டத்தை திருத்துவதற்கான ஒதுக்கீட்டு (திருத்தம்) சட்டமூலத்தை நிதியமைச்சர் சார்பாக பிரதமர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தன, ஆகஸ்ட் 09, 2022 அன்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் முதல் வாசிப்புக்காக முன்வைத்தார்.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 30 அன்று, ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க, நிதி, பொருளாதார ஸ்திரப்படுத்தல் மற்றும் தேசிய கொள்கைகள் அமைச்சர் என்ற வகையில், இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட உரையை அல்லது ஒதுக்கீட்டு (திருத்த) சட்டமூலத்தின் இரண்டாம் வாசிப்பை பாராளுமன்றம் பிற்பகல் 1.00 மணிக்கு கூடியபோது நிகழ்த்தினார்.",
        "2022 இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்டம் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்ட பின்னர், பாராளுமன்றம் நாள் முழுவதும் ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்டது மற்றும் விவாதம் மறுநாள் (ஆகஸ்ட் 31) தொடங்கியது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "2022 இடைக்கால பட்ஜெட் இரண்டாம் வாசிப்பு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒதுக்கீட்டின் இரண்டாவது வாசிப்பு (திருத்தம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 நிதியாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "115",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "120",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ர சி து",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 நிதியாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டிசம்பர் 10, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒதுக்கீட்டுச் சட்டம் எண்.",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 28, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பதாவது பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 03, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒதுக்கீடு (திருத்தம்) மசோதா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒதுக்கீட்டுச் சட்டம் எண்.",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 09, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொருளாதார ஸ்திரத்தன்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒதுக்கீடு (திருத்தம்) மசோதா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதியம் 1.00 மணி.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இடைக்கால பட்ஜெட் 2022",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}