{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Colombo-Expat-Cultural-Association-Messiah-for-the-children/56-737774",
  "time_ut": 1658445556,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Colombo Expat Cultural Association: Messiah for the children",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Colombo Expat Cultural Association: Messiah for the children",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "“Feed a Child, Build a Future” – A bold statement undertaken by the Colombo Expats Cultural Association during the need of the hour came with a lot of determination and vision. CECA, which is group of Expats Community in Sri Lanka comprising of Indian, Bangladeshi, Nepali nationality as well as Sri Lankans, immediately stood up to the unforeseen challenge of the current economic crisis prevailing in the Island.",
        "In the wake of this growing economic crisis and anticipated food shortage, CECA which has been involved in multiple CSR focused on helping the orphanages in Sri Lanka, was recently approached by Department of Probation and Child Care Services of Sri Lanka to support with bare necessities for about 10,600 kids living in 379 orphanages across Sri Lanka. It only took one meeting of its Executive members under the competent leadership of Capt. Anirban Banerjee to accept the challenge.",
        "CECA henceforth strategised a provision for all the 10,600 kids to include essential commodities and prioritise on the most important nutritional requirement and demand. It was decided that the effort be undertaken to stockpile and support these orphanages for a minimum sustainable period of 100 days (three months and 10 days), so there is significant time for the Government to stabilise politically and economically.",
        "CECA mobilised a special task team for a massive fundraising campaign to support this mammoth task. With the ease of India-Sri Lanka import policies and Government approval, it was decided that all these commodities be purchased in India and brought into Sri Lanka.",
        "Through the 30-day fundraising campaign, CECA was successfully able to fundraise enough to provide 306,500 kg of dry ration. All thanks to families, friends, relatives and corporates who poured their support in ways that was beyond expectation.",
        "Through a lot of planning, perseverance and exemplary leadership of CECA Executive members and Mentors, CECA took pride to have achieved a major milestone as the first shipment that got flagged off from Kolkata Port.",
        "The entire effort and consignments are  scheduled to be shipped, unloaded and distributed to the last mile (379 orphanages) with the help of 20 trucks before 31 July 2022. CECA will make sure that all 10,600 kids living in 379 orphanages get their 100-day dry ration to their doorstep – CECA will ensure no kids are left behind. The first shipment confirmed to be arriving at the Colombo Port Docks on 15 July 2022.",
        "nIn 2020, amidst the COVID-19 struck island, orphanages across the country were reeling with scarcity of supplies and were detaching from continued education, CECA in all its capacity came forward to contribute dry ration and essentials for 30 days that helped 52 orphanages in the Western Province.",
        "nIn 2021, CECA organised an island-wide painting competition for orphanages where 5275 kids participated. About 60 talented kids from these orphanages were brought to Colombo for a grand finale. They were accommodated in a 5-star Hotel for two days which provided them a lifetime of memories and aspirations such as Hop On City Tour, a movie day at Cinema Scopes and loads of gifts and a cash prize."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Colombo Expat Cultural Association: Messiah for the children",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Feed a Child, Build a Future",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Expats Cultural Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangladeshi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nepali",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Island",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Department of Probation and Child Care Services of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 10,600",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "379",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Executive",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,600",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three months and",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India-Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "306,500 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CECA Executive",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mentors",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kolkata Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "379",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 trucks",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "31 July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,600",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "379",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Port Docks",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "struck island",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5275",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "About 60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hotel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Scopes",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Colombo Expat Cultural Association: Messiah for the children",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "\"දරුවෙකුට පෝෂණය කරන්න, අනාගතයක් ගොඩනඟමු\" - කාලීන අවශ්‍යතාවයේ දී කොළඹ විදේශිකයන්ගේ සංස්කෘතික සංගමය විසින් සිදු කරන ලද නිර්භීත ප්‍රකාශයක් බොහෝ අධිෂ්ඨානශීලී හා දැක්මකින් යුක්ත විය. ඉන්දියානු, බංගලිදේශ, නේපාල ජාතිකයින් මෙන්ම ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ගෙන් සමන්විත ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විගමණික ප්‍රජාවේ කණ්ඩායමක් වන CECA, දිවයිනේ පවතින වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදයේ අනපේක්ෂිත අභියෝගයට වහා නැගී සිටියේය.",
        "මෙම වර්ධනය වන ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සහ අපේක්ෂිත ආහාර හිඟය හමුවේ, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අනාථ නිවාසවලට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා බහු ආයතනික සමාජ වගකීම් වලට සම්බන්ධ වී ඇති CECA, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පරිවාස හා ළමාරක්ෂක සේවා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් අත්‍යවශ්‍ය අවශ්‍යතා සඳහා සහාය වීම සඳහා මෑතකදී සම්බන්ධ විය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පුරා ළමා නිවාස 379 ක ළමුන් 10,600 ක් පමණ ජීවත් වෙති. අභියෝගය භාර ගැනීමට කපිතාන් අනිර්බන් බැනර්ජිගේ දක්ෂ නායකත්වය යටතේ එහි විධායක සාමාජිකයින්ගේ රැස්වීමක් පමණක් ගත විය.",
        "CECA මින් ඉදිරියට සියලුම ළමුන් 10,600 සඳහා අත්‍යවශ්‍ය භාණ්ඩ ඇතුළත් කිරීමටත්, වඩාත් වැදගත් පෝෂණ අවශ්‍යතා සහ ඉල්ලුමට ප්‍රමුඛත්වය දීමටත් ප්‍රතිපාදන සකස් කර ඇත. අවම වශයෙන් දින 100ක (මාස තුනයි දින 10ක) තිරසාර කාලයක් සඳහා මෙම අනාථ නිවාස තොග ගබඩා කිරීමට සහ ආධාර කිරීමට උත්සාහ කළ යුතු බවට තීරණය කරන ලදී, එබැවින් රජයට දේශපාලන හා ආර්ථික වශයෙන් ස්ථාවර වීමට සැලකිය යුතු කාලයක් තිබේ.",
        "මෙම දැවැන්ත කාර්යයට සහය වීම සඳහා CECA විසින් දැවැන්ත අරමුදල් රැස් කිරීමේ ව්‍යාපාරයක් සඳහා විශේෂ කාර්ය කණ්ඩායමක් බලමුලු ගන්වන ලදී. ඉන්දියා - ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආනයන ප්‍රතිපත්තිවල පහසුව සහ රජයේ අනුමැතිය මත මේ සියලු භාණ්ඩ ඉන්දියාවෙන් මිලදී ගෙන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ගෙන ඒමට තීරණය විය.",
        "දින 30ක අරමුදල් රැස්කිරීමේ ව්‍යාපාරය හරහා වියළි සලාක කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 306,500ක් සැපයීමට ප්‍රමාණවත් අරමුදල් රැස්කිරීමට CECA සමත් විය. අපේක්‍ෂා කළ නොහැකි අන්දමින් තම සහයෝගය ලබා දුන් පවුල්වලට, මිතුරන්ට, ඥාතීන්ට සහ ආයතනිකයින්ට සියලු ස්තූතිය.",
        "CECA විධායක සාමාජිකයින්ගේ සහ උපදේශකයින්ගේ සැලසුම්, නොපසුබට උත්සාහය සහ ආදර්ශමත් නායකත්වය හේතුවෙන්, කොල්කටා වරායෙන් ආරම්භ කරන ලද පළමු නැව්ගත කිරීම ලෙස ප්‍රධාන සන්ධිස්ථානයක් අත්කර ගැනීමට CECA ආඩම්බර විය.",
        "2022 ජූලි 31 දිනට පෙර ට්‍රක් රථ 20ක සහාය ඇතිව සම්පූර්ණ ප්‍රයත්නය සහ තොග අවසන් සැතපුම දක්වා (අනාථ නිවාස 379) නැව්ගත කිරීමට, බෑමට සහ බෙදා හැරීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇත. අනාථ නිවාස 379ක වෙසෙන සියලුම දරුවන් 10,600කට ඔවුන්ගේ දින 100 ලබා ගැනීමට CECA වග බලා ගනී. වියළි සලාකයක් ඔවුන්ගේ දොරකඩට - CECA විසින් කිසිදු දරුවෙකු ඉතිරි නොවන බව සහතික කරනු ඇත. පළමු නැව්ගත කිරීම 2022 ජූලි 15 වන දින කොළඹ වරාය තටාකයට පැමිණෙන බව තහවුරු විය.",
        "n 2020 දී, COVID-19 හි බලපෑමට ලක් වූ දිවයින මධ්‍යයේ, රට පුරා ඇති අනාථ නිවාස සැපයුම් හිඟයෙන් පෙළෙමින් පවතින අතර අඛණ්ඩ අධ්‍යාපනයෙන් ඈත් වෙමින් සිටි අතර, CECA සිය උපරිම ශක්තියෙන් දින 30 ක් සඳහා වියළි සලාක සහ අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය ලබා දීමට ඉදිරිපත් වූ අතර එමඟින් අනාථ නිවාස 52 කට උපකාර විය. බස්නාහිර පළාත.",
        "n2021 දී, CECA විසින් ළමා නිවාස සඳහා දීප ව්‍යාප්ත චිත්‍ර තරඟයක් සංවිධානය කරන ලද අතර එහිදී ළමුන් 5275ක් සහභාගී විය. මේ ළමා නිවාසවල දක්ෂ ළමයි 60ක් පමණ අවසන් මහා තරගයක් සඳහා කොළඹට ගෙන ආවා. ඔවුන්ට දින දෙකක් තරු 5 හෝටලයක නවාතැන් ලබා දුන් අතර එමඟින් ඔවුන්ට ජීවිත කාලය පුරාම මතකයන් සහ අභිලාෂයන් ලබා දෙන ලදී, එනම් Hop On City Tour, Cinema Scopes හි චිත්‍රපට දිනයක් සහ තෑගි රාශියක් සහ මුදල් ත්‍යාගයක්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Colombo Expat Cultural Association: Messiah for the children",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දරුවෙකුට පෝෂණය කරන්න, අනාගතයක් ගොඩනඟන්න",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ විදේශිකයන්ගේ සංස්කෘතික සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නේපාල",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පරිවාස හා ළමාරක්ෂක සේවා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,600 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "379",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විධායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,600 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 100 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස තුනක් සහ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 10 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව-ශ්‍රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30-දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 306,500 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CECA විධායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උපදේශකයින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොල්කටා වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "379",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්රක් රථ 20 ක්",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,600 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "379",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 100",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ වරාය නැව් තටාකාංගනය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිවයිනට පහර දුන්නා",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5275",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෝටල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විෂය පථයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "Colombo Expat Cultural Association: குழந்தைகளுக்கான மேசியா",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "\"ஒரு குழந்தைக்கு உணவளிக்கவும், எதிர்காலத்தை உருவாக்கவும்\" - காலத்தின் தேவையின் போது கொழும்பு புலம்பெயர்ந்தோர் கலாச்சார சங்கம் மேற்கொண்ட துணிச்சலான அறிக்கையானது நிறைய உறுதியுடனும் தொலைநோக்குடனும் வந்தது. இலங்கையில் உள்ள இந்திய, பங்களாதேஷ், நேபாளி மற்றும் இலங்கையர்களை உள்ளடக்கிய வெளிநாட்டினர் சமூகத்தின் குழுவான CECA, தீவில் நிலவும் தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியின் எதிர்பாராத சவாலை உடனடியாக எதிர்கொண்டது.",
        "இந்த வளர்ந்து வரும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி மற்றும் எதிர்பார்க்கப்படும் உணவுப் பற்றாக்குறையை அடுத்து, இலங்கையிலுள்ள அனாதை இல்லங்களுக்கு உதவுவதில் கவனம் செலுத்தும் பல சமூகப் பொறுப்பில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள CECA, இலங்கையின் நன்னடத்தை மற்றும் குழந்தை பராமரிப்பு சேவைத் திணைக்களத்தால், தேவைகளுக்கு ஆதரவளிக்க சமீபத்தில் அணுகியது. இலங்கை முழுவதும் 379 அனாதை இல்லங்களில் சுமார் 10,600 குழந்தைகள் வாழ்கின்றனர். சவாலை ஏற்க கேப்டன் அனிர்பன் பானர்ஜியின் திறமையான தலைமையின் கீழ் அதன் நிர்வாக உறுப்பினர்களின் ஒரு கூட்டம் மட்டுமே தேவைப்பட்டது.",
        "CECA இனி 10,600 குழந்தைகளுக்கும் அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களைச் சேர்ப்பதற்கும், மிக முக்கியமான ஊட்டச்சத்து தேவை மற்றும் தேவைக்கு முன்னுரிமை அளிப்பதற்கும் ஒரு ஏற்பாடு செய்துள்ளது. குறைந்தபட்சம் 100 நாட்களுக்கு (மூன்று மாதங்கள் மற்றும் 10 நாட்கள்) இந்த அனாதை இல்லங்களை இருப்பு வைப்பதற்கும் ஆதரவளிப்பதற்கும் முயற்சி மேற்கொள்ளப்பட வேண்டும் என்று முடிவு செய்யப்பட்டது, எனவே அரசாங்கம் அரசியல் ரீதியாகவும் பொருளாதார ரீதியாகவும் ஸ்திரப்படுத்தப்படுவதற்கு குறிப்பிடத்தக்க நேரம் உள்ளது.",
        "இந்த மாபெரும் பணியை ஆதரிப்பதற்காக CECA ஒரு பெரிய நிதி திரட்டும் பிரச்சாரத்திற்காக ஒரு சிறப்பு பணிக் குழுவைத் திரட்டியது. இந்தியா-இலங்கை இறக்குமதிக் கொள்கைகள் மற்றும் அரசாங்க அனுமதியின் எளிமையுடன், இந்த பொருட்கள் அனைத்தும் இந்தியாவில் வாங்கப்பட்டு இலங்கைக்கு கொண்டு வர முடிவு செய்யப்பட்டது.",
        "30 நாள் நிதி திரட்டும் பிரச்சாரத்தின் மூலம், CECA 306,500 கிலோ உலர் உணவுகளை வழங்குவதற்கு போதுமான நிதியை வெற்றிகரமாக சேகரிக்க முடிந்தது. எதிர்ப்பார்க்க முடியாத வகையில் தங்கள் ஆதரவை வழங்கிய குடும்பத்தினர், நண்பர்கள், உறவினர்கள் மற்றும் கார்ப்பரேட் நிறுவனங்களுக்கு நன்றி.",
        "CECA நிர்வாக உறுப்பினர்கள் மற்றும் வழிகாட்டிகளின் பல திட்டமிடல், விடாமுயற்சி மற்றும் முன்மாதிரியான தலைமைத்துவத்தின் மூலம், கொல்கத்தா துறைமுகத்தில் இருந்து கொடியேற்றப்பட்ட முதல் கப்பலாக ஒரு பெரிய மைல்கல்லை எட்டியதில் CECA பெருமிதம் கொண்டது.",
        "முழு முயற்சியும் சரக்குகளும்  20 டிரக்குகளின் உதவியுடன் கடைசி மைலுக்கு (379 அனாதை இல்லங்கள்) அனுப்பப்பட்டு, இறக்கப்பட்டு விநியோகிக்கப்படும் அவர்களின் வீட்டு வாசலுக்கு உலர் உணவு - CECA எந்த குழந்தைகளும் பின்தங்கியிருப்பதை உறுதி செய்யும். முதல் ஏற்றுமதி 15 ஜூலை 2022 அன்று கொழும்பு துறைமுக கப்பல்துறையை வந்தடைவது உறுதி செய்யப்பட்டது.",
        "n 2020ல், கோவிட்-19 தாக்குதலுக்கு உள்ளான தீவிற்கு மத்தியில், நாடு முழுவதும் உள்ள அனாதை இல்லங்கள் பொருட்கள் பற்றாக்குறையால் தத்தளித்து, தொடர் கல்வியில் இருந்து விலகிய நிலையில், CECA ஆனது 30 நாட்களுக்கு உலர் உணவு மற்றும் அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களை வழங்க முன்வந்தது, இது 52 அனாதை இல்லங்களுக்கு உதவியது. மேல் மாகாணம்.",
        "n 2021 ஆம் ஆண்டில், CECA அனாதை இல்லங்களுக்காக 5275 குழந்தைகள் பங்கேற்ற ஒரு தீவு முழுவதும் ஓவியப் போட்டியை ஏற்பாடு செய்தது. இந்த அனாதை இல்லங்களில் இருந்து திறமையான சுமார் 60 சிறுவர்கள் இறுதிப்போட்டிக்காக கொழும்புக்கு அழைத்து வரப்பட்டனர். ஹாப் ஆன் சிட்டி டூர், சினிமா ஸ்கோப்பில் ஒரு திரைப்பட நாள் மற்றும் ஏராளமான பரிசுகள் மற்றும் ரொக்கப் பரிசு போன்ற வாழ்நாள் நினைவுகள் மற்றும் அபிலாஷைகளை அவர்களுக்கு இரண்டு நாட்கள் 5-நட்சத்திர ஹோட்டலில் தங்கவைத்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Colombo Expat Cultural Association: குழந்தைகளுக்கான மேசியா",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு குழந்தைக்கு உணவளிக்கவும், ஒரு எதிர்காலத்தை உருவாக்கவும்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு வெளிநாட்டவர்கள் கலாச்சார சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேபாளி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தீவு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் நன்னடத்தை மற்றும் குழந்தை பராமரிப்பு சேவைகள் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 10,600",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "379",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிர்வாகி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,600",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று மாதங்கள் மற்றும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா-இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30-நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "306,500 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CECA நிர்வாகி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வழிகாட்டிகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொல்கத்தா துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "379",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 லாரிகள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "31 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,600",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "379",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100-நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு துறைமுக கப்பல்துறை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தீவை தாக்கியது",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CECA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5275",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹோட்டல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நோக்கங்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}