{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130953",
  "time_ut": 1657165542,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இன்று பல மாகாணங்களில் மழை  பெய்யலாம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Rain may occur in many provinces today",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sabaragamuwa province and Nuwara Eliya and Kandy districts are likely to experience occasional rain.",
        "Upper and North-West Provinces and Galle and Matara districts will experience several spells of rain.",
        "Occasional gusty winds (40-50 km/h) are expected in the western slopes of Central Highlands and Southern Province.",
        "Temporarily gusty winds may occur in these areas during periods of thundershowers. The public is advised to take necessary precautions to minimize the damage caused by lightning strikes.",
        "Rain or thundershowers are expected at many places along coastal areas from Puttalam through Colombo and Galle to Ambantota.",
        "Wind will be blowing from West to Southwest direction with wind speed of 30-40 kmph. Wind speed may increase to 50-60 kmph over coastal areas from Puttalam to Pottuvil through Colombo, Galle and Ambantota.",
        "The sea surface from Puttalam through Colombo, Galle and Ambantota to Pottuvil is turbulent. Other seas surrounding the country are expected to be moderate.",
        "Waves (about 2.5 – 3.0 m) may increase in offshore areas from Puttalam to Pottuvil through Colombo, Galle and Ambantota.",
        "The navy and fishing communities engaged in fishing and naval activities in the waters from Puttalam to Pottu through Colombo, Galle and Ambandottai have been requested to be vigilant in this regard."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Nuwara Eliya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40-50",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "km/h",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Highlands",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southern Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Southwest",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "30-40 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "50-60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Puttalam through Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 2.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambandottai",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අද පළාත් රැසකට වැසි ඇති විය හැක",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "සබරගමුව පළාතේ සහ නුවරඑළිය සහ මහනුවර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවල විටින් විට වැසි ඇති විය හැක.",
        "ඉහළ සහ වයඹ පළාත්වලත් ගාල්ල සහ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් වැසි වාර කිහිපයක් ඇති වේ.",
        "මධ්‍යම කඳුකරයේ සහ දකුණු පළාතේ බටහිර බෑවුම් ප්‍රදේශවල විටින් විට තද සුළං (පැ.කි.මී. 40-50) අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇති වන විට එම ප්‍රදේශවල තාවකාලිකව තද සුළං ඇති විය හැක. අකුණු මඟින් සිදුවන අනතුරු අවම කර ගැනීමට අවශ්‍ය පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස මහජනතාවට දැනුම් දෙනු ලැබේ.",
        "පුත්තලම සිට කොළඹ සහ ගාල්ල හරහා අඹන්තොට දක්වා වෙරළබඩ ප්‍රදේශවල බොහෝ ස්ථානවල වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "සුළගේ වේගය පැ.කි.මී. 30-40 පමණ වන අතර බස්නාහිර සිට නිරිත දෙසින් සුළං හමා යනු ඇත. පුත්තලම සිට කොළඹ, ගාල්ල සහ අම්බන්තොට හරහා පොතුවිල් දක්වා වෙරළබඩ ප්‍රදේශවල සුළගේ වේගය පැ.කි.මී.50-60 දක්වා වැඩි විය හැක.",
        "පුත්තලම සිට කොළඹ, ගාල්ල, අඹන්තොට හරහා පොතුවිල් දක්වා වන මුහුදු මතුපිට කැළඹිලි ස්වභාවයක් ගනී. රට වටා ඇති අනෙකුත් මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ මධ්‍යස්ථව පවතිනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "පුත්තලම සිට කොළඹ, ගාල්ල සහ අම්බන්තොට හරහා පොතුවිල් දක්වා වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල රළ (මීටර් 2.5 - 3.0 පමණ) වැඩි විය හැක.",
        "පුත්තලම සිට කොළඹ, ගාල්ල සහ අඹන්තොට හරහා පොතු දක්වා මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයේ ධීවර හා නාවික කටයුතුවල නිරත වන නාවික සහ ධීවර ප්‍රජාවගෙන් මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමසිලිමත් වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටියි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නුවරඑළිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40-50",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "km/h",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්‍යම කඳුකරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිරිතදිග",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "30-40 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "50-60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ හරහා පුත්තලම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2.5 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්බන්ඩොට්ටයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இன்று பல மாகாணங்களில் மழை  பெய்யலாம்",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "சப்ரகமுவ மாகாணம் மற்றும் நுவரெலியா மற்றும் கண்டி மாவட்டங்களில் அவ்வப்போது மழை பெய்யக்கூடும்.",
        "மேல் மற்றும் வடமேற்கு மாகாணங்களிலும் காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறை மாவட்டங்களிலும் பல தடவைகள் மழை பெய்யும்.",
        "மத்திய மலைநாட்டின் மேற்கு சரிவுகளிலும், தென் மாகாணத்திலும் அவ்வப்போது காற்று (40-50) கி.மீ வரை பலத்த காற்று வீசக்கூடும் என எதிர்ப்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை பெய்யும் வேளைகளில் அப் பிரதேசங்களில் தற்காலிகமாக பலத்த காற்றும் வீசக்கூடும். மின்னல் தாக்கங்களினால் ஏற்படக்கூடிய பாதிப்புகளை குறைத்துக்கொள்ள தேவையான முன்னெச்சரிக்கை நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுத்துக் கொள்ளுமாறு பொதுமக்கள் அறிவுறுத்தப்படுகின்றார்கள்.",
        "புத்தளத்திலிருந்து கொழும்பு மற்றும் காலி ஊடாக அம்பாந்தோட்டை வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளில் பல இடங்களில் மழை அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை பெய்யும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "காற்று மேற்கிலிருந்து தென்மேற்கு திசையில் வீசும் மற்றும் காற்றின் வேகம் மணிக்கு 30-40 கி.மீ. புத்தளத்திலிருந்து கொழும்பு, காலி மற்றும் அம்பாந்தோட்டை ஊடாக பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளில் காற்றின் வேகமானது மணித்தியாலத்துக்கு 50-60 கிலோ மீற்றர் வரை அதிகரித்து வீசக்கூடும்.",
        "புத்தளத்திலிருந்து கொழும்பு, காலி மற்றும் அம்பாந்தோட்டை ஊடாக பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்பரப்புக்கள் கொந்தளிப்புடன் காணப்படும். நாட்டைச் சூழவுள்ள ஏனைய கடற்பரப்புக்கள் மிதமானதாக காணப்படும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "புத்தளத்திலிருந்து கொழும்பு, காலி மற்றும் அம்பாந்தோட்டை ஊடாக பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்கரைக்கு அப்பாற்பட்ட கடற்பரப்புகளில் அலைகள் (சுமார் 2.5 – 3.0 மீ) வரை அதிகரிக்கலாம்.",
        "புத்தளத்திலிருந்து கொழும்பு, காலி மற்றும் அம்பாந்தோட்டை ஊடாக பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளில் மீன்பிடி மற்றும் கடற்படை நடவடிக்கைகளில் ஈடுபடும் கடற்படை மற்றும் மீனவ சமூகங்கள் இது தொடர்பில் அவதானமாக இருக்குமாறு கோரப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நுவரெலியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40-50",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிமீ/ம",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய மலைநாடு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தென்மேற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 30-40 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "50-60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு வழியாக புத்தளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 2.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}