{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/front_page/Govt-employees-leave-form-for-foreign-employment-reduced-to-2-pages/238-243913",
  "time_ut": 1661743034,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Govt. employees leave form for foreign employment reduced to 2 pages",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Govt. employees leave form for foreign employment reduced to 2 pages",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Ministry of Public Administration, Home Affairs, Local Government and Provincial Councils has decided to reduce the pages of the form that employees have to submit when they seek to leave for employment abroad.",
        "The number of pages of the application form has been reduced to two pages from four according to the ministry.",
        "This decision has been made following the instructions of the subject minister, Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena.",
        "The cost of printing the application form is said to be reduced by 50 per cent through this move. The cost of printing the application forms is said to be high, as many workers attached to the institutions under the ministry are seeking leave for employment abroad.",
        "The new two-page form has already been sent to the Department of State Printing."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "2",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Public Administration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Home Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Local Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Provincial Councils",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of State Printing",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රජය විදේශ රැකියා සඳහා සේවක නිවාඩු පත්‍රය පිටු 2 දක්වා අඩු කෙරේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රාජ්‍ය පරිපාලන, ස්වදේශ කටයුතු, පළාත් පාලන සහ පළාත් සභා අමාත්‍යාංශය විසින් විදේශ රැකියා සඳහා පිටත්ව යාමට අපේක්ෂා කරන සේවකයින් ඉදිරිපත් කළ යුතු පෝරමයේ පිටු අඩු කිරීමට තීරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "අයදුම් පත්‍රයේ පිටු සංඛ්‍යාව පිටු 4 සිට 2 දක්වා අඩු කර ඇති බව අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි.",
        "විෂය භාර අමාත්‍ය, අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතාගේ උපදෙස් පරිදි මෙම තීරණය ගෙන ඇත.",
        "මෙම පියවර හරහා අයදුම් පත්‍රය මුද්‍රණය කිරීමේ පිරිවැය සියයට 50කින් අඩු වන බව පැවසේ. අමාත්‍යාංශය යටතේ පවතින ආයතනවලට අනුයුක්ත ශ්‍රමිකයින් රැසක් විදේශ රැකියා සඳහා නිවාඩු ලබා ගැනීමට අපේක්ෂාවෙන් සිටින බැවින් අයදුම්පත් මුද්‍රණය කිරීමට අධික පිරිවැයක් දැරීමට සිදුවන බව පැවසේ.",
        "පිටු දෙකකින් යුත් නව පෝරමය දැනටමත් රාජ්‍ය මුද්‍රණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව වෙත යවා ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "2",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය පරිපාලන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්වදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළාත් පාලන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළාත් සභා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 50 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය මුද්රණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசு வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்புக்கான ஊழியர்களின் விடுப்பு படிவம் 2 பக்கங்களாக குறைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொது நிர்வாகம், உள்நாட்டலுவல்கள், உள்ளூராட்சி மற்றும் மாகாண சபைகள் அமைச்சு, வெளிநாட்டில் வேலைக்காகச் செல்ல முற்படும் போது, ​​ஊழியர்கள் சமர்ப்பிக்க வேண்டிய படிவத்தின் பக்கங்களைக் குறைக்கத் தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "விண்ணப்பப் படிவத்தின் பக்கங்களின் எண்ணிக்கை நான்கில் இருந்து இரண்டு பக்கங்களாக குறைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அமைச்சு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "பிரதியமைச்சர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தனவின் பணிப்புரைக்கு அமைய இந்த தீர்மானம் எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த நடவடிக்கையின் மூலம் விண்ணப்பப் படிவத்தை அச்சிடுவதற்கான செலவு 50 சதவீதம் குறையும் என்று கூறப்படுகிறது. அமைச்சின் கீழ் உள்ள நிறுவனங்களில் பணிபுரியும் தொழிலாளர்கள் பலர் வெளிநாட்டில் வேலைக்காக விடுமுறை கோரி வருவதால், விண்ணப்பப் படிவங்களை அச்சிடுவதற்கான செலவு அதிகமாக உள்ளதாக கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "புதிய இரண்டு பக்க படிவம் ஏற்கனவே அரச அச்சகத் திணைக்களத்திற்கு அனுப்பப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "2",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொது நிர்வாக அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உள்நாட்டு விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உள்ளூர் அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாகாண சபைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநில அச்சிடும் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}