{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/IMF--නියෝජිතයන්-24-දා-එයි/11-396461",
  "time_ut": 1660967870,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "IMF  නියෝජිතයන් 24 දා එයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "IMF representatives are coming on the 24th",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The International Monetary Fund said in a statement that a delegation of the International Monetary Fund will visit Sri Lanka from the 24th to the 31st of August in order to reach staff-level agreements for providing a detailed credit facility to Sri Lanka.",
        "However, the International Monetary Fund says that it expects sufficient guarantees from the creditors during the visit of its representatives to Sri Lanka.",
        "It has been stated that in order to provide the facilities of the financial fund, a certificate obtained from the creditor regarding the debt restructuring in Sri Lanka is required.",
        "The International Monetary Fund also said that economic and financial reforms and policies will be discussed with the Sri Lankan authorities during this visit.",
        "As Sri Lanka's public debt has been assessed as unsustainable, IMF Executive Board approval of the Extended Credit Facility Program requires adequate assurances from Sri Lanka's creditors that debt sustainability will be restored, the IMF said.",
        "The IMF further announced that the IMF staff will work with other stakeholders during the visit and that the team will be led by Mr. Peter Brewer and Mr. Masahiro Nozaki."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "24th",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 24th to the 31st of August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF Executive Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Extended Credit Facility Program",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peter Brewer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "IMF  නියෝජිතයන් 24 දා එයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට විස්තර්ණ ණය පහසුකමක් ලබාදීම වෙනුවෙන් වූ කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ එකඟතාවන් ඇති කර ගැනීම වෙනුවෙන් ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නියෝජිත පිරිසක් ඒළැඹෙන අගෝස්තු 24 දා සිට 31 දා තෙක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංචාරයක නිරතවන බව ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල නිවේදනක් නිකුත් කරමින් පවසයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් තම නියෝජිතයින් පිරිසක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිදුකරන සංචාරයේදී ණය හිමියන්ගේ ප්‍රමාණවත් සහතිකයක් අපේක්ෂා කරන බවද ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල පවසයි.",
        "මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ පහසුකම් ලබාදීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යහුවගත කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ණය හිමියන්ගෙන් ලබා ගන්නා සහතිකයක් අවශ්‍ය වන බවට ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබේ.",
        "මෙම සංචාරයේදී ආර්ථික හා මූල්‍ය ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සහ ප්‍රතිපත්ති පිළිබඳව ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලධාරීන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට නියමිත බවද ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල පවසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රාජ්‍ය ණය තිරසාර නොවන ලෙස තක්සේරු කර ඇති බැවින්, විස්තීරණ ණය පහසුකම් වැඩසටහනේ IMF විධායක මණ්ඩලයේ අනුමැතිය සඳහා ණය තිරසාර බව ප්‍රතිෂ්ඨාපනය කරන බවට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය හිමියන්ගේ ප්‍රමාණවත් සහතික කිරීම් අවශ්‍ය බවද මූල්‍ය අරමුදල පවසයි.",
        "IMF කාර්ය මණ්ඩලයේ සංචාරය අතරතුර අනෙකුත් පාර්ශවකරුවන් සමඟ කටයුතු කරන බවත් මෙම කණ්ඩායම පීටර් බෲවර් මහතා සහ මසාහිරෝ නොසාකි මහතා විසින් මෙහෙයවන බවත් මූල්‍ය අරමුදල වැඩිදුරටත් නිවේදනය කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "24 වැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 24 සිට 31 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF විධායක මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විස්තීරණ ණය පහසුකම් වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීටර් බෲවර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஐஎம்எப் பிரதிநிதிகள் 24ம் தேதி வருகிறார்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கைக்கு விரிவான கடன் வசதியை வழங்குவதற்கான பணியாளர் மட்ட உடன்பாடுகளை எட்டுவதற்காக சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகள் குழுவொன்று ஆகஸ்ட் 24ஆம் திகதி முதல் 31ஆம் திகதி வரை இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்யவுள்ளதாக சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் அறிக்கையொன்றில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் தனது பிரதிநிதிகளின் இலங்கை விஜயத்தின் போது கடன் வழங்குநர்களிடமிருந்து போதுமான உத்தரவாதங்களை எதிர்பார்ப்பதாக கூறுகிறது.",
        "நிதி நிதியத்தின் வசதிகளை வழங்குவதற்கு, இலங்கையில் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு தொடர்பாக கடன் வழங்குநரிடமிருந்து பெறப்பட்ட சான்றிதழ் தேவை என்று தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த விஜயத்தின் போது இலங்கை அதிகாரிகளுடன் பொருளாதார மற்றும் நிதி சீர்திருத்தங்கள் மற்றும் கொள்கைகள் குறித்து கலந்துரையாடப்படும் எனவும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையின் பொதுக் கடன் தாங்க முடியாதது என மதிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ள நிலையில், IMF நிறைவேற்று சபையின் விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட கடன் வசதித் திட்டத்திற்கு அனுமதி வழங்குவதற்கு, கடன் நிலைத்தன்மையை மீட்டெடுப்பதற்கு இலங்கையின் கடனாளிகளிடமிருந்து போதுமான உத்தரவாதம் தேவை என IMF தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்த விஜயத்தின் போது IMF ஊழியர்கள் மற்ற பங்குதாரர்களுடன் இணைந்து பணியாற்றுவார்கள் என்றும் திரு. பீட்டர் ப்ரூவர் மற்றும் திரு. மசாஹிரோ நோசாகி ஆகியோர் குழுவை வழிநடத்துவார்கள் என்றும் IMF மேலும் அறிவித்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "24வது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 24 முதல் 31 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF நிர்வாக வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட கடன் வசதி திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீட்டர் ப்ரூவர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}