{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Court-grants-bail-to-8-protesters-including-Damita-and-Ratta/56-738500",
  "time_ut": 1660087861,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Court grants bail to 8 protesters including Damita and Ratta",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Court grants bail to 8 protesters including Damita and Ratta",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Colombo Fort Magistrate yesterday granted bail to 8 protesters, who were charged with unlawful assembly and obstruction of duties of police officers at the entry road to Colombo Fort Magistrate’s Court on 25 May.",
        "Colombo Fort Magistrate Thilina Gamage ordered to release the suspects on personal bail.",
        "According to the notice issued earlier by the court, eight suspects including Father Satyavel, actress Damita Abeyratne, YouTuber Rathidu Senaratne alias Ratta, Actor Jagath Manuvarana, Ceylon Teachers’ Union head Joseph Stalin appeared before the court.",
        "Presenting submissions, Slave Island Police told the Magistrate that the suspects were produced before the court in connection with obstructing the Police officers on duty at the entry road to the Colombo Magistrate’s Court and a bus through unlawful assembly on 25 May.",
        "Upul Jayasuriya PC, who appeared on behalf of the suspects, stated that the case was filed fraudulently by the Police.",
        "After considering the facts presented by both sides, the Magistrate released the suspects on personal bail and ordered the case to be called again on 28 November.",
        "The Magistrate accepting a request by the Police ordered the concerned suspects to record statements with the Slave Island Police today."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Court",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "8",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Damita",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ratta",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Fort Magistrate’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 May",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "eight",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Satyavel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Damita Abeyratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "YouTuber Rathidu Senaratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratta",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jagath Manuvarana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Teachers’ Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joseph Stalin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Slave Island Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Magistrate’s Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 May",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 November",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Slave Island Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දමිතා, රත්තා ඇතුළු විරෝධතාකරුවන් 8 දෙනෙකුට අධිකරණය ඇප",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මැයි 25 වැනි දින කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයට ඇතුළු වන මාර්ගයේදී නීති විරෝධී ලෙස රැස්වීම් සහ පොලිස් නිලධාරීන්ගේ රාජකාරියට බාධා කිරීම යන චෝදනා යටතේ විරෝධතාකරුවන් 8 දෙනෙකුට කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා ඊයේ ඇප නියම කළේය.",
        "සැකකරුවන් පුද්ගලික ඇප මත මුදා හැරීමට කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් තිළිණ ගමගේ මහතා නියෝග කළේය.",
        "මීට පෙර අධිකරණය විසින් නිකුත් කරන ලද නොතීසියට අනුව සත්‍යවේල් පියතුමා, නිළි දමිතා අබේරත්න, යූ ටියුබර් රතිදු සේනාරත්න හෙවත් රත්තා, නළු ජගත් මනුවරණ, ලංකා ගුරු සංගමයේ ප්‍රධානී ජෝසප් ස්ටාලින් ඇතුළු විත්තිකරුවන් අට දෙනෙක් අධිකරණය හමුවේ පෙනී සිටියහ.",
        "කරුණු ඉදිරිපත් කරමින් කොම්පඤ්ඤවීදිය පොලිසිය මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයාට ප්‍රකාශ කළේ මැයි 25 වැනිදා කොළඹ මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයට ඇතුළු වන මාර්ගයේ රාජකාරියේ යෙදී සිටි පොලිස් නිලධාරීන්ට සහ බස් රථයකට නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස රැස්වීම්වලට බාධා කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සැකකරුවන් අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කළ බවයි.",
        "සැකකරුවන් වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ උපුල් ජයසූරිය මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ මෙම නඩුව පොලිසිය විසින් වංචනික ලෙස පවරා ඇති බවයි.",
        "දෙපාර්ශ්වය ඉදිරිපත් කළ කරුණු සලකා බැලූ මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා සැකකරුවන් පෞද්ගලික ඇප මත මුදා හරිමින් නඩුව නොවැම්බර් මස 28 වැනිදා යළි කැඳවීමට නියෝග කළේය.",
        "පොලිසිය කළ ඉල්ලීමක් පිළිගත් මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා අදාළ සැකකරුවන්ට අද කොම්පඤ්ඤවීදිය පොලිසියට ප්‍රකාශ සටහන් කරගන්නා ලෙස නියෝග කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අධිකරණය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "8",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "දමිතා",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "රට්ටා",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අට",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සත්‍යවේල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දමිතා අබේරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "YouTuber රතිදු සේනාරත්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රට්ටා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජගත් මනුවරන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ගුරු සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝසප් ස්ටාලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොම්පඤ්ඤවීදි පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොවැම්බර් 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොම්පඤ්ඤවීදි පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தமிதா, ரட்டா உள்ளிட்ட 8 போராட்டக்காரர்களுக்கு நீதிமன்றம் ஜாமீன் வழங்கியது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கடந்த மே 25ஆம் திகதி கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றத்தின் நுழைவுப் பாதையில் பொலிஸ் உத்தியோகத்தர்களின் கடமைகளுக்கு இடையூறு விளைவித்தமை மற்றும் சட்டவிரோதமான முறையில் ஒன்றுகூடியமை தொடர்பில் குற்றஞ்சாட்டப்பட்ட 8 ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களுக்கு கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் நேற்று பிணை வழங்கியுள்ளார்.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்களை சொந்த பிணையில் விடுவிக்குமாறு கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் திலின கமகே உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "முன்னதாக நீதிமன்றம் பிறப்பித்த நோட்டீஸின் படி, தந்தை சத்தியவேல், நடிகை தமிதா அபேரத்ன, யூடியூபர் ரதிது சேனாரத்ன என்ற ரட்டா, நடிகர் ஜகத் மனுவரன, இலங்கை ஆசிரியர் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் ஜோசப் ஸ்டாலின் உள்ளிட்ட 8 பேர் நீதிமன்றத்தில் ஆஜராகினர்.",
        "மே 25ஆம் திகதி கொழும்பு நீதவான் நீதிமன்றத்தின் நுழைவுப் பாதையில் கடமையில் ஈடுபட்டிருந்த பொலிஸ் உத்தியோகத்தர்களுக்கு இடையூறு விளைவித்தமை மற்றும் சட்டவிரோதமான முறையில் பேரூந்து ஒன்று கூடுவதற்கு இடையூறு விளைவித்தமை தொடர்பில் சந்தேகநபர்களை நீதிமன்றத்தில் ஆஜர்படுத்தியதாக கொம்பைத்தீவு பொலிஸார் சமர்ப்பணங்களை முன்வைத்தனர்.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்கள் சார்பில் ஆஜரான சட்டத்தரணி உபுல் ஜயசூரிய, பொலிஸாரால் மோசடியான முறையில் வழக்குப் பதிவு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாகத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இரு தரப்பிலும் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட உண்மைகளை பரிசீலித்த நீதவான் சந்தேக நபர்களை சொந்த பிணையில் விடுவித்ததுடன், வழக்கை எதிர்வரும் நவம்பர் மாதம் 28ஆம் திகதி மீண்டும் விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக் கொள்ளுமாறு உத்தரவிட்டார்.",
        "பொலிஸாரின் கோரிக்கையை ஏற்றுக்கொண்ட நீதவான், குறித்த சந்தேக நபர்களை இன்றைய தினம் கொம்பைத்தீவு பொலிஸாரிடம் வாக்குமூலம் பதிவு செய்யுமாறு உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நீதிமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "8",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "தமிதா",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரட்டா",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "எட்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சத்தியவேல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிதா அபேரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யூடியூபர் ரதிது சேனாரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரட்டா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜகத் மனுவரன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ஆசிரியர் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜோசப் ஸ்டாலின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அடிமை தீவு போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 நவம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்லேவ் தீவு போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}