{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Consider-European-countries-as-friends-of-Sri-Lanka-EU-Ambassadors/108-239727",
  "time_ut": 1656067648,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Consider European countries as friends of Sri Lanka: EU Ambassadors",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Consider European countries as friends of Sri Lanka: EU Ambassadors",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "Ambassadors of the European Countries have assured the continuous support to Sri Lanka at this challenging time.",
        "These remarks were made by European Ambassadors when they met with President Gotabaya Rajapaksa at the President’s House in Colombo, today (24), President's Media Division said.",
        "The delegation members pointed out that a firm message about the future plans of building the country’s economy will certainly pave the way for the international community to assist Sri Lanka.",
        "Nearly 90% of the country's population lives in rural areas and 75% of those people depend on agriculture.",
        "The President said that by providing them with the required fertilizer and fuel, many problems as well as the issues related to the supply of food could be solved.",
        "Steps have been taken to provide uncultivated government lands to those interested in agriculture as a solution to the land issue.",
        "President Rajapaksa explained the initiatives launched by the Government to provide a lasting solution considering the humanitarian situation that has arisen after the war as well as the fair manner maintained in the process of enforcing law without any party affiliation and interfering to the Ambassadors.",
        "A number of areas, including investment, tourism and education, were discussed at length.",
        "EU Ambassador to Sri Lanka Denis Chaibi , Eric Lavertu, Ambassador of France to Sri Lanka, Rita Mannella, Ambassador of Italy, Norwegian Ambassador to Sri Lanka Trine Jøranli Eskedal, Tanja Gonggrijp , Ambassador for the Kingdom of the Netherlands, Ambassador of the Republic of Germany Holger Lothar Seubert, Victor Chiujdea, Ambassador of Romania, Ambassador of Turkey Rakibe Şekercioğlu, Swiss Ambassador to Sri Lanka Dominik Furgler, Chief of Staff to the President Anura Dissanayake and Admiral Jayanath Colombage were also present at this discussion."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "European",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "EU",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the European Countries",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "European Ambassadors",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House in Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nearly 90%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "75%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambassadors",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Denis Chaibi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eric Lavertu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "France",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rita Mannella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Italy",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Norwegian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Trine Jøranli Eskedal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tanja Gonggrijp",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kingdom of the Netherlands",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Republic of Germany Holger",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lothar Seubert",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Victor Chiujdea",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Romania",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Turkey",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Swiss",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Dominik Furgler",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayanath Colombage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යුරෝපීය රටවල් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මිතුරන් ලෙස සලකන්න: යුරෝපා සංගම් තානාපතිවරු",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "මෙම අභියෝගාත්මක අවස්ථාවේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අඛණ්ඩව සහයෝගය ලබා දෙන බවට යුරෝපා රටවල තානාපතිවරු සහතික වී ඇත.",
        "අද (24) කොළඹ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ දී ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා හමු වූ අවස්ථාවේදී යුරෝපා තානාපතිවරුන් මෙම අදහස් පළ කළ බව ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "රටේ ආර්ථිකය ගොඩනැගීමේ අනාගත සැලසුම් පිළිබඳ ස්ථිර පණිවිඩයක් මගින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහය වීමට ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාවට නිසැක වශයෙන්ම මග සැලසෙන බව නියෝජිත පිරිස පෙන්වා දුන්හ.",
        "රටේ ජනගහනයෙන් 90% කට ආසන්න ප්‍රමාණයක් ග්‍රාමීය ප්‍රදේශවල ජීවත් වන අතර එම ජනතාවගෙන් 75% කෘෂිකාර්මික ක්ෂේත්‍රයෙන් යැපේ.",
        "ඔවුන්ට අවශ්‍ය පොහොර සහ ඉන්ධන ලබාදීමෙන් ආහාර සැපයීමේ ගැටලු මෙන්ම ගැටලු රැසකට විසඳුම් ලබාදිය හැකි බව ද ජනාධිපතිතුමා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ඉඩම් ප්‍රශ්නයට විසඳුමක් ලෙස වගා නොකළ රජයේ ඉඩම් කෘෂිකර්මාන්තයට උනන්දුවක් දක්වන අයට ලබාදීමට පියවර ගෙන ඇත.",
        "යුද්ධයෙන් පසු උද්ගතව ඇති මානුෂීය තත්ත්වය මෙන්ම පක්ෂ භේදයකින් තොරව තානාපතිවරුන්ට ඇඟිලි ගැසීම්වලින් තොරව නීතිය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමේ ක්‍රියාවලියේ සාධාරණත්වය ද සලකා ස්ථීරසාර විසඳුමක් ලබාදීමට රජය දියත් කළ වැඩපිළිවෙළ ජනාධිපතිතුමා පැහැදිලි කළේය.",
        "ආයෝජන, සංචාරක, අධ්‍යාපන ඇතුළු ක්ෂේත්‍ර ගණනාවක් පිළිබඳව මෙහිදී දීර්ඝ වශයෙන් සාකච්ඡා කෙරිණි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ යුරෝපා සංගම් තානාපති Denis Chaibi, Eric Lavertu, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රංශ තානාපති, Rita Mannella, ඉතාලියේ තානාපති, Trine Jøranli Eskedal, Tanja Gonggrijp, නෙදර්ලන්ත තානාපති, නෙදර්ලන්ත තානාපති ජර්මනියේ Holger Lothar Seubert, Victor Chiujdea, රුමේනියාවේ තානාපති, තුර්කියේ තානාපති Rakibe Şekercioğlu, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ස්විට්සර්ලන්ත තානාපති ඩොමිනික් ෆර්ග්ලර්, ජනාධිපති කාර්ය මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානී අනුර දිසානායක සහ අද්මිරාල් ජයනාත් කොළඹගේ යන මහත්වරු ද මෙම සාකච්ඡාවට එක්ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "යුරෝපා",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "EU",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපීය රටවල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපීය තානාපතිවරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "90%කට ආසන්න",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "75%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තානාපතිවරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඩෙනිස් චයිබි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එරික් ලැවර්ටු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රංශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රීටා මැන්නැල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉතාලිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෝර්වීජියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Trine Jøranli Eskedal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tanja Gonggrijp",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෙදර්ලන්ත රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මානු ජනරජය හොල්ගර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝතර් සීබර්ට්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්ටර් චියුජ්ඩියා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුමේනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුකුමා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්විස්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඩොමිනික් ෆර්ග්ලර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයනාත් කොළඹගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஐரோப்பிய நாடுகளை இலங்கையின் நண்பர்களாக கருதுங்கள்: ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றிய தூதுவர்கள்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்த சவாலான நேரத்தில் இலங்கைக்கு தொடர்ந்து ஆதரவளிப்பதாக ஐரோப்பிய நாடுகளின் தூதுவர்கள் உறுதியளித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இன்று (24) கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை சந்தித்த போது ஐரோப்பிய தூதுவர்கள் இந்த கருத்துக்களை வெளியிட்டதாக ஜனாதிபதி ஊடகப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரத்தை கட்டியெழுப்புவதற்கான எதிர்காலத் திட்டங்கள் குறித்த உறுதியான செய்தியானது இலங்கைக்கு சர்வதேச சமூகம் உதவுவதற்கு நிச்சயமாக வழி வகுக்கும் என தூதுக்குழு உறுப்பினர்கள் சுட்டிக்காட்டினர்.",
        "நாட்டின் மக்கள்தொகையில் கிட்டத்தட்ட 90% கிராமப்புறங்களில் வாழ்கிறார்கள் மற்றும் அவர்களில் 75% மக்கள் விவசாயத்தை நம்பியுள்ளனர்.",
        "அவர்களுக்குத் தேவையான உரம் மற்றும் எரிபொருளை வழங்குவதன் மூலம் உணவு விநியோகம் தொடர்பான பல பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு தீர்வு காண முடியும் என ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நிலப்பிரச்சினைக்கு தீர்வாக விவசாயத்தில் ஆர்வம் உள்ளவர்களுக்கு விவசாயம் செய்யப்படாத அரச காணிகளை வழங்க நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "யுத்தத்தின் பின்னர் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள மனிதாபிமான நிலைமையை கருத்திற்கொண்டு நிரந்தரமான தீர்வை வழங்குவதற்கு அரசாங்கம் முன்னெடுத்துள்ள முயற்சிகள் மற்றும் கட்சி பேதமின்றி தூதுவர்களின் தலையீடுகள் இன்றி சட்டத்தை அமுல்படுத்துவதில் நியாயமான முறையில் பேணப்பட்டமை தொடர்பில் ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ விளக்கமளித்தார்.",
        "முதலீடு, சுற்றுலா, கல்வி உள்ளிட்ட பல்வேறு துறைகள் குறித்து விரிவாக விவாதிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றிய தூதுவர் டெனிஸ் சாய்பி, எரிக் லாவெர்டு, இலங்கைக்கான பிரான்ஸ் தூதுவர், இத்தாலி தூதர் ரீட்டா மன்னெல்லா, இலங்கைக்கான நோர்வே தூதுவர் ட்ரைன் ஜொரன்லி எஸ்கெடல், தஞ்சா கோங்கிரிஜ், நெதர்லாந்தின் குடியரசுத் தூதுவர். ஜேர்மனி Holger Lothar Seubert, Victor Chiujdea, Romania தூதுவர், துருக்கி தூதுவர் Rakibe Şekercioğlu, இலங்கைக்கான சுவிஸ் தூதுவர் Dominik Furgler, ஜனாதிபதியின் தலைமை அதிகாரி அனுர திஸாநாயக்க மற்றும் அட்மிரல் ஜயநாத் கொலம்பகே ஆகியோரும் இந்த கலந்துரையாடலில் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஐரோப்பிய",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "EU",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய தூதர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 90%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "75%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தூதர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை டெனிஸ் சாய்பி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எரிக் லாவெர்டு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரான்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரீட்டா மன்னெல்லா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இத்தாலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நார்வேஜியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை டிரைன் ஜொரன்லி எஸ்கெடல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தஞ்சா கோங்கிரிஜ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நெதர்லாந்து இராச்சியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மனி ஹோல்கர் குடியரசு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லோதர் சீபர்ட்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்டர் சியுஜ்டியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ருமேனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துருக்கி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுவிஸ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை டொமினிக் ஃபர்க்லர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜயநாத் கொலம்பகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Consider European countries as friends of Sri Lanka: EU Ambassadors",
  "body_lines": [
    "Ambassadors of the European Countries have assured the continuous support to Sri Lanka at this challenging time.",
    "These remarks were made by European Ambassadors when they met with President Gotabaya Rajapaksa at the President’s House in Colombo, today (24), President's Media Division said.",
    "The delegation members pointed out that a firm message about the future plans of building the country’s economy will certainly pave the way for the international community to assist Sri Lanka.",
    "Nearly 90% of the country's population lives in rural areas and 75% of those people depend on agriculture.",
    "The President said that by providing them with the required fertilizer and fuel, many problems as well as the issues related to the supply of food could be solved.",
    "Steps have been taken to provide uncultivated government lands to those interested in agriculture as a solution to the land issue.",
    "President Rajapaksa explained the initiatives launched by the Government to provide a lasting solution considering the humanitarian situation that has arisen after the war as well as the fair manner maintained in the process of enforcing law without any party affiliation and interfering to the Ambassadors.",
    "A number of areas, including investment, tourism and education, were discussed at length.",
    "EU Ambassador to Sri Lanka Denis Chaibi , Eric Lavertu, Ambassador of France to Sri Lanka, Rita Mannella, Ambassador of Italy, Norwegian Ambassador to Sri Lanka Trine Jøranli Eskedal, Tanja Gonggrijp , Ambassador for the Kingdom of the Netherlands, Ambassador of the Republic of Germany Holger Lothar Seubert, Victor Chiujdea, Ambassador of Romania, Ambassador of Turkey Rakibe Şekercioğlu, Swiss Ambassador to Sri Lanka Dominik Furgler, Chief of Staff to the President Anura Dissanayake and Admiral Jayanath Colombage were also present at this discussion."
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Consider European countries as friends of Sri Lanka: EU Ambassadors",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "Ambassadors of the European Countries have assured the continuous support to Sri Lanka at this challenging time.",
        "These remarks were made by European Ambassadors when they met with President Gotabaya Rajapaksa at the President’s House in Colombo, today (24), President's Media Division said.",
        "The delegation members pointed out that a firm message about the future plans of building the country’s economy will certainly pave the way for the international community to assist Sri Lanka.",
        "Nearly 90% of the country's population lives in rural areas and 75% of those people depend on agriculture.",
        "The President said that by providing them with the required fertilizer and fuel, many problems as well as the issues related to the supply of food could be solved.",
        "Steps have been taken to provide uncultivated government lands to those interested in agriculture as a solution to the land issue.",
        "President Rajapaksa explained the initiatives launched by the Government to provide a lasting solution considering the humanitarian situation that has arisen after the war as well as the fair manner maintained in the process of enforcing law without any party affiliation and interfering to the Ambassadors.",
        "A number of areas, including investment, tourism and education, were discussed at length.",
        "EU Ambassador to Sri Lanka Denis Chaibi , Eric Lavertu, Ambassador of France to Sri Lanka, Rita Mannella, Ambassador of Italy, Norwegian Ambassador to Sri Lanka Trine Jøranli Eskedal, Tanja Gonggrijp , Ambassador for the Kingdom of the Netherlands, Ambassador of the Republic of Germany Holger Lothar Seubert, Victor Chiujdea, Ambassador of Romania, Ambassador of Turkey Rakibe Şekercioğlu, Swiss Ambassador to Sri Lanka Dominik Furgler, Chief of Staff to the President Anura Dissanayake and Admiral Jayanath Colombage were also present at this discussion."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "European",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "EU",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the European Countries",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "European Ambassadors",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House in Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nearly 90%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "75%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambassadors",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Denis Chaibi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eric Lavertu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "France",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rita Mannella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Italy",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Norwegian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Trine Jøranli Eskedal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tanja Gonggrijp",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kingdom of the Netherlands",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Republic of Germany Holger",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lothar Seubert",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Victor Chiujdea",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Romania",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Turkey",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Swiss",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Dominik Furgler",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayanath Colombage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යුරෝපීය රටවල් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මිතුරන් ලෙස සලකන්න: යුරෝපා සංගම් තානාපතිවරු",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "මෙම අභියෝගාත්මක අවස්ථාවේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අඛණ්ඩව සහයෝගය ලබා දෙන බවට යුරෝපා රටවල තානාපතිවරු සහතික වී ඇත.",
        "අද (24) කොළඹ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ දී ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා හමු වූ අවස්ථාවේදී යුරෝපා තානාපතිවරුන් මෙම අදහස් පළ කළ බව ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "රටේ ආර්ථිකය ගොඩනැගීමේ අනාගත සැලසුම් පිළිබඳ ස්ථිර පණිවිඩයක් මගින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහය වීමට ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාවට නිසැක වශයෙන්ම මග සැලසෙන බව නියෝජිත පිරිස පෙන්වා දුන්හ.",
        "රටේ ජනගහනයෙන් 90% කට ආසන්න ප්‍රමාණයක් ග්‍රාමීය ප්‍රදේශවල ජීවත් වන අතර එම ජනතාවගෙන් 75% කෘෂිකාර්මික ක්ෂේත්‍රයෙන් යැපේ.",
        "ඔවුන්ට අවශ්‍ය පොහොර සහ ඉන්ධන ලබාදීමෙන් ආහාර සැපයීමේ ගැටලු මෙන්ම ගැටලු රැසකට විසඳුම් ලබාදිය හැකි බව ද ජනාධිපතිතුමා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ඉඩම් ප්‍රශ්නයට විසඳුමක් ලෙස වගා නොකළ රජයේ ඉඩම් කෘෂිකර්මාන්තයට උනන්දුවක් දක්වන අයට ලබාදීමට පියවර ගෙන ඇත.",
        "යුද්ධයෙන් පසු උද්ගතව ඇති මානුෂීය තත්ත්වය මෙන්ම පක්ෂ භේදයකින් තොරව තානාපතිවරුන්ට ඇඟිලි ගැසීම්වලින් තොරව නීතිය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමේ ක්‍රියාවලියේ සාධාරණත්වය ද සලකා ස්ථීරසාර විසඳුමක් ලබාදීමට රජය දියත් කළ වැඩපිළිවෙළ ජනාධිපතිතුමා පැහැදිලි කළේය.",
        "ආයෝජන, සංචාරක, අධ්‍යාපන ඇතුළු ක්ෂේත්‍ර ගණනාවක් පිළිබඳව මෙහිදී දීර්ඝ වශයෙන් සාකච්ඡා කෙරිණි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ යුරෝපා සංගම් තානාපති Denis Chaibi, Eric Lavertu, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රංශ තානාපති, Rita Mannella, ඉතාලියේ තානාපති, Trine Jøranli Eskedal, Tanja Gonggrijp, නෙදර්ලන්ත තානාපති, නෙදර්ලන්ත තානාපති ජර්මනියේ Holger Lothar Seubert, Victor Chiujdea, රුමේනියාවේ තානාපති, තුර්කියේ තානාපති Rakibe Şekercioğlu, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ස්විට්සර්ලන්ත තානාපති ඩොමිනික් ෆර්ග්ලර්, ජනාධිපති කාර්ය මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානී අනුර දිසානායක සහ අද්මිරාල් ජයනාත් කොළඹගේ යන මහත්වරු ද මෙම සාකච්ඡාවට එක්ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "යුරෝපා",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "EU",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපීය රටවල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපීය තානාපතිවරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "90%කට ආසන්න",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "75%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තානාපතිවරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඩෙනිස් චයිබි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එරික් ලැවර්ටු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රංශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රීටා මැන්නැල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉතාලිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෝර්වීජියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Trine Jøranli Eskedal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tanja Gonggrijp",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෙදර්ලන්ත රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මානු ජනරජය හොල්ගර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝතර් සීබර්ට්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්ටර් චියුජ්ඩියා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුමේනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුකුමා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්විස්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඩොමිනික් ෆර්ග්ලර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයනාත් කොළඹගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஐரோப்பிய நாடுகளை இலங்கையின் நண்பர்களாக கருதுங்கள்: ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றிய தூதுவர்கள்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்த சவாலான நேரத்தில் இலங்கைக்கு தொடர்ந்து ஆதரவளிப்பதாக ஐரோப்பிய நாடுகளின் தூதுவர்கள் உறுதியளித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இன்று (24) கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை சந்தித்த போது ஐரோப்பிய தூதுவர்கள் இந்த கருத்துக்களை வெளியிட்டதாக ஜனாதிபதி ஊடகப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரத்தை கட்டியெழுப்புவதற்கான எதிர்காலத் திட்டங்கள் குறித்த உறுதியான செய்தியானது இலங்கைக்கு சர்வதேச சமூகம் உதவுவதற்கு நிச்சயமாக வழி வகுக்கும் என தூதுக்குழு உறுப்பினர்கள் சுட்டிக்காட்டினர்.",
        "நாட்டின் மக்கள்தொகையில் கிட்டத்தட்ட 90% கிராமப்புறங்களில் வாழ்கிறார்கள் மற்றும் அவர்களில் 75% மக்கள் விவசாயத்தை நம்பியுள்ளனர்.",
        "அவர்களுக்குத் தேவையான உரம் மற்றும் எரிபொருளை வழங்குவதன் மூலம் உணவு விநியோகம் தொடர்பான பல பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு தீர்வு காண முடியும் என ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நிலப்பிரச்சினைக்கு தீர்வாக விவசாயத்தில் ஆர்வம் உள்ளவர்களுக்கு விவசாயம் செய்யப்படாத அரச காணிகளை வழங்க நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "யுத்தத்தின் பின்னர் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள மனிதாபிமான நிலைமையை கருத்திற்கொண்டு நிரந்தரமான தீர்வை வழங்குவதற்கு அரசாங்கம் முன்னெடுத்துள்ள முயற்சிகள் மற்றும் கட்சி பேதமின்றி தூதுவர்களின் தலையீடுகள் இன்றி சட்டத்தை அமுல்படுத்துவதில் நியாயமான முறையில் பேணப்பட்டமை தொடர்பில் ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ விளக்கமளித்தார்.",
        "முதலீடு, சுற்றுலா, கல்வி உள்ளிட்ட பல்வேறு துறைகள் குறித்து விரிவாக விவாதிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றிய தூதுவர் டெனிஸ் சாய்பி, எரிக் லாவெர்டு, இலங்கைக்கான பிரான்ஸ் தூதுவர், இத்தாலி தூதர் ரீட்டா மன்னெல்லா, இலங்கைக்கான நோர்வே தூதுவர் ட்ரைன் ஜொரன்லி எஸ்கெடல், தஞ்சா கோங்கிரிஜ், நெதர்லாந்தின் குடியரசுத் தூதுவர். ஜேர்மனி Holger Lothar Seubert, Victor Chiujdea, Romania தூதுவர், துருக்கி தூதுவர் Rakibe Şekercioğlu, இலங்கைக்கான சுவிஸ் தூதுவர் Dominik Furgler, ஜனாதிபதியின் தலைமை அதிகாரி அனுர திஸாநாயக்க மற்றும் அட்மிரல் ஜயநாத் கொலம்பகே ஆகியோரும் இந்த கலந்துரையாடலில் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஐரோப்பிய",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "EU",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய தூதர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 90%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "75%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தூதர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை டெனிஸ் சாய்பி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எரிக் லாவெர்டு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரான்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரீட்டா மன்னெல்லா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இத்தாலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நார்வேஜியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை டிரைன் ஜொரன்லி எஸ்கெடல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தஞ்சா கோங்கிரிஜ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நெதர்லாந்து இராச்சியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மனி ஹோல்கர் குடியரசு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லோதர் சீபர்ட்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்டர் சியுஜ்டியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ருமேனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துருக்கி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுவிஸ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை டொமினிக் ஃபர்க்லர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜயநாத் கொலம்பகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}