{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/business/ආර්ථික-අභියෝග-තුළ-උසස්-අධ්‍යාපනයට-මූල්‍ය-සහායක්/7-393935",
  "time_ut": 1653964966,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ආර්ථික අභියෝග තුළ උසස් අධ්‍යාපනයට මූල්‍ය සහායක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Financial support for higher education in times of economic challenges",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Moneta has introduced the 'Study Now, Pay Later' solution in collaboration with Achievers Lanka Business School, a leader in Sri Lanka's higher education sector.",
        "Accordingly, through the mobile app under the Moneta brand of Fintech Hive private company, students can get financial support for their professional education or higher education, and they have the opportunity to repay the amount without interest in 4 installments.",
        "There, students have the opportunity to acquire qualifications such as CIM, CIMA and ACCA, and because this service uses state-of-the-art digital technologies including artificial intelligence, financial service requests can be completed within 10 minutes without long paperwork or queues. Says it can. This application can be downloaded from Google Play and App Store.",
        "Present at the launch were Achievers Lanka Business School Chairman Azad Hai, Manager (Academics & Operations) Amar Aufar, Business Head Anushan Sadanandasarma, Manager (Marketing & Sales) Amjad Maulana, Group Accountant Ajurdeen Azharuddin and Moneta Founder & CEO Kanaganayagam Shayanthan. , Mr. Randu Perera, Business Development Manager participated."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Moneta",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Achievers Lanka Business School",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Moneta",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fintech Hive",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CIMA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ACCA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Google Play",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "App Store",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Achievers Lanka Business School",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Azad Hai",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Academics & Operations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amar Aufar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anushan Sadanandasarma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marketing & Sales",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajurdeen Azharuddin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moneta Founder &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanaganayagam Shayanthan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Randu Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ආර්ථික අභියෝග තුළ උසස් අධ්‍යාපනයට මූල්‍ය සහායක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Moneta විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ උසස් අධ්‍යාපන ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ ප්‍රමුඛයෙකු වන Achievers Lanka Business School සමග එක්ව, 'Study Now, Pay Later' විසඳුම හඳුන්වාදී තිබේ.",
        "ඒ අනුව, Fintech Hive පුද්ගලික සමාගමේ Moneta සන්නාමය යටතේ වූ මොබයිල් ඇප් එක හරහා සිසු සිසුවියන්ට තම වෘත්තීය අධ්‍යාපන හෝ උසස් අධ්‍යාපන කටයුතු සඳහා මූල්‍ය සහාය ලබාගත හැකි අතර, වාරික 4කින් පොලී රහිතව එම මුදල ආපසු ගෙවීමට අවස්ථාව හිමිවන බව ඔවුන් කියයි.",
        "එහිදී, CIM, CIMA සහ ACCA වැනි සුදුසුකම් හිමිකර ගැනීම සඳහා සිසු සිසුවියන්ට අවස්ථාව උදාවන අතර, මෙම සේවාව සඳහා කෘත්‍රිම බුද්ධිය ඇතුළුව අතිනවීන ඩිජිටල් තාක්ෂණයන් භාවිත වන නිසා, දීර්ඝ ලිපිලේඛන කටයුතු හෝ පෝලිම්වලින් තොරව, විනාඩි 10ක් වැනි කෙටි කාලයක් ඇතුළත මූල්‍ය සේවා ඉල්ලීම් සම්බන්ධ කටයුතු සම්පූර්ණ කළ හැකි බව කියයි. Google Play සහ App Store මෙම යෙදවුම ඩවුන්ලෝඩ් කරගත හැකිය.",
        "මෙය හඳුන්වාදීමේ අවස්ථාවට Achievers Lanka Business School හි සභාපති අසාද් හයි, කළමනාකරු (අධ්‍යයන කටයුතු සහ මෙහෙයුම්) අමර් අවුෆර්, ව්‍යාපාර ප්‍රධානී අනූෂන් සදානන්දසර්මා, කළමනාකරු (අලෙවි හා විකිණුම්) අම්ජාඩ් මවුලානා, සමූහ ගණකාධිකාරී අජූර්ඩීන් අසාරුදීන් සහ Moneta හි නිර්මාතෘ සහ ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී කනගනායගම් ශයන්තන්, ව්‍යාපාර සංවර්ධන කළමනාකරු රන්දු පෙරේරා යන මහත්වරු සහභාගී වූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මොනේටා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Achievers Lanka ව්‍යාපාරික පාසල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මොනේටා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆින්ටෙක් හයිව්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CIMA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ACCA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විනාඩි 10 යි",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Google Play",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යෙදුම් වෙළඳසැල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Achievers Lanka ව්‍යාපාරික පාසල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අසාද් හායි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්‍යයන සහ මෙහෙයුම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමර් අවුෆර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුෂාන් සදානන්දසර්ම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලෙවිකරණය සහ විකුණුම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජුර්ඩීන් අසාරුදීන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moneta නිර්මාතෘ සහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කනගනායගම් ශයන්තන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්දු පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பொருளாதார சவால்களின் போது உயர் கல்விக்கான நிதி உதவி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் உயர்கல்வித் துறையில் முன்னணியில் இருக்கும் Achievers Lanka Business School உடன் இணைந்து 'Study Now, Pay later' என்ற தீர்வை Moneta அறிமுகப்படுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "அதன்படி, Fintech Hive தனியார் நிறுவனத்தின் Moneta பிராண்டின் கீழ் மொபைல் செயலி மூலம், மாணவர்கள் தங்கள் தொழில்முறை கல்வி அல்லது உயர்கல்விக்கான நிதியுதவியைப் பெற முடியும், மேலும் அவர்கள் 4 தவணைகளில் வட்டி இல்லாமல் தொகையை திருப்பிச் செலுத்தும் வாய்ப்பு உள்ளது.",
        "அங்கு, மாணவர்கள் CIM, CIMA மற்றும் ACCA போன்ற தகுதிகளைப் பெறுவதற்கான வாய்ப்பைப் பெற்றுள்ளனர், மேலும் இந்த சேவை செயற்கை நுண்ணறிவு உள்ளிட்ட அதிநவீன டிஜிட்டல் தொழில்நுட்பங்களைப் பயன்படுத்துவதால், நிதி சேவை கோரிக்கைகள் நீண்ட ஆவணங்கள் அல்லது வரிசைகள் இல்லாமல் 10 நிமிடங்களில் முடிக்கப்படுகின்றன. அது முடியும். இந்த அப்ளிகேஷனை கூகுள் ப்ளே மற்றும் ஆப் ஸ்டோரிலிருந்து பதிவிறக்கம் செய்யலாம்.",
        "வெளியீட்டு விழாவில் Achievers Lanka வணிகப் பள்ளியின் தலைவர் Azad Hai, முகாமையாளர் (கல்வி மற்றும் செயற்பாடுகள்) அமர் ஔஃபர், வணிகத் தலைவர் அனுஷன் சதானந்தசர்மா, முகாமையாளர் (சந்தைப்படுத்தல் மற்றும் விற்பனை) அம்ஜத் மௌலானா, குழுக் கணக்காளர் அஜுர்தீன் அசாருதீன் மற்றும் மொனெட்டா, நிறுவனர் மற்றும் CEO கனகநாயகம், ஷயான் கம்மன் ஆகியோர் கலந்து கொண்டனர். வர்த்தக அபிவிருத்தி முகாமையாளர் ரண்டு பெரேரா கலந்துகொண்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மொனெட்டா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Achievers Lanka Business School",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மொனெட்டா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபின்டெக் ஹைவ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CIMA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ACCA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 நிமிடங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கூகிள் விளையாட்டு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப் ஸ்டோர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Achievers Lanka Business School",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசாத் ஹை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்வி மற்றும் செயல்பாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமர் ஆஃபர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுஷன் சதானந்தசர்மா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்தைப்படுத்தல் & விற்பனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜுர்தீன் அசாருதீன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொனெட்டா நிறுவனர் &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனகநாயகம் ஷயந்தன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரண்டு பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}