{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84716/slfp-unanimously-approves-amendments-to-partys-constitution",
  "time_ut": 1662143340,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SLFP unanimously approves amendments to party’s constitution",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SLFP unanimously approves amendments to party’s constitution",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The working committee of Sri Lanka Freedom Party (SLFP) has unanimously approved key amendments to the party’s constitution.",
        "The SLFP celebrated its 71st anniversary today under the patronage of party’s chairman, former President Maithripala Sirisena.",
        "The event was held at the National Youth Services Council in Maharagama.",
        "Before the anniversary celebrations kicked off, the meeting of the SLFP’s working committee was held, where the party’s general secretary Dayasiri Jayasekara presented the proposed amendments to the constitution of the SLFP."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "71st",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the National Youth Services Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dayasiri Jayasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රීලනිපය පක්ෂ ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධන ඒකමතිකව අනුමත කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ (ශ්‍රීලනිප) කෘත්‍යාධිකාරී මණ්ඩලය පක්ෂ ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ ප්‍රධාන සංශෝධන ඒකමතිකව අනුමත කර තිබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රීලනිපයේ 71 වැනි සංවත්සරය එම පක්ෂයේ සභාපති හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් අද පැවැත්විණි.",
        "මෙම උත්සවය මහරගම ජාතික තරුණ සේවා සභාවේදී පැවැත්විණි.",
        "සංවත්සර උත්සවය ආරම්භ වීමට පෙර ශ්‍රීලනිප කෘත්‍යාධිකාරී මණ්ඩල රැස්වීම පැවැති අතර එහිදී ශ්‍රීලනිප මහලේකම් දයාසිරි ජයසේකර මහතා විසින් ශ්‍රීලනිප ව්‍යවස්ථාවට යෝජිත සංශෝධන ඉදිරිපත් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "71 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික තරුණ සේවා සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීලනිප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දයාසිරි ජයසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SLFP கட்சியின் அரசியலமைப்பில் திருத்தங்களை ஏகமனதாக ஏற்றுக்கொண்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் (SLFP) செயற்குழு, கட்சியின் அரசியலமைப்பில் முக்கிய திருத்தங்களுக்கு ஏகமனதாக ஒப்புதல் அளித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் 71வது ஆண்டு நிறைவு விழா இன்று கட்சியின் தலைவர் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன தலைமையில் நடைபெற்றது.",
        "மஹரகமவில் உள்ள தேசிய இளைஞர் சேவைகள் மன்றத்தில் இந்த நிகழ்வு இடம்பெற்றது.",
        "ஆண்டு விழா ஆரம்பமாவதற்கு முன்னர், ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் செயற்குழுக் கூட்டம் இடம்பெற்றது, அங்கு கட்சியின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் தயாசிறி ஜயசேகர ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் அரசியலமைப்பில் உத்தேச திருத்தங்களை முன்வைத்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "71வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய இளைஞர் சேவைகள் மன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தயாசிறி ஜயசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}