{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/28/thriposha-distribution-underway-for-mothers/",
  "time_ut": 1658987220,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Thriposha distribution underway for mothers",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Thriposha distribution underway for mothers",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka Thriposha Ltd announced that it commenced distributing Thriposha to all beneficiaries including all pregnant mothers and all breastfeeding mothers ( Up to the completion of 06 months for the infant) who are undergoing nutritious requirements.",
        "Sri Lanka Thriposha Ltd Deepthi Kularatna speaking to News 1st that 850,000 Triposha packets have been distributed, however, Triposha for children is yet to be delivered.",
        "Deepthi Kularatna said that due to the shortage of maize and soybean it has become impossible to streamline the production of Triposha in the country.",
        "However, he said that agreements will be inked with suppliers to import Maize and Soy beans under the Indian Credit Line.",
        "He further said that steps will be taken to produce Thriposha for children as well.",
        "However, he said that due to the shortage of fuel, problems have arisen in the distribution of triposha."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Thriposha Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06 months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Thriposha Ltd Deepthi Kularatna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "850,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Deepthi Kularatna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Triposha",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maize",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Soy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Credit Line",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මව්වරුන් සඳහා ත්‍රිපෝෂ බෙදාදීම සිදු කෙරේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා ත්‍රිපෝෂ ලිමිටඩ් නිවේදනය කළේ පෝෂණ අවශ්‍යතා ඇති සියලුම ගැබිනි මවුවරුන් සහ සියලුම කිරි දෙන මව්වරුන් (ළදරු සඳහා මාස 06 සම්පූර්ණ වීම දක්වා) ඇතුළු සියලුම ප්‍රතිලාභීන් සඳහා ත්‍රිපෝෂ බෙදා හැරීම ආරම්භ කර ඇති බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ත්‍රිපෝෂ සීමාසහිත දීප්ති කුලරත්න News 1st වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් ත්‍රිපෝෂ පැකට් 850,000ක් බෙදා හැර ඇති නමුත් ළමුන් සඳහා වන ත්‍රිපෝෂ තවමත් ලබාදී නොමැත.",
        "දීප්ති කුලරත්න කියා සිටියේ බඩඉරිඟු සහ සෝයා හිඟය හේතුවෙන් මෙරට ත්‍රිපෝෂ නිෂ්පාදනය විධිමත් කිරීමට නොහැකි තත්ත්වයකට පත්ව ඇති බවයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ඉන්දීය ණය රේඛාව යටතේ බඩඉරිඟු සහ සෝයා බෝංචි ආනයනය කිරීමට සැපයුම්කරුවන් සමඟ ගිවිසුම් අත්සන් කරන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ළමුන් සඳහා ද ත්‍රිපෝෂ නිෂ්පාදනය කිරීමට පියවර ගන්නා බව ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් ඉන්ධන හිඟය හේතුවෙන් ත්‍රිපෝෂ බෙදා හැරීමේ ගැටළු මතුව ඇති බවයි ඔහු කියා සිටියේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත ශ්‍රී ලංකා ත්‍රිපෝෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස 06 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත ශ්‍රී ලංකා ත්‍රිපෝෂ දීප්ති කුලරත්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "850,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දීප්ති කුලරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රිපෝෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බඩ ඉරිඟු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු ණය රේඛාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தாய்மார்களுக்கு திரிபோஷ விநியோகம் நடைபெற்று வருகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); அனைத்து கர்ப்பிணித் தாய்மார்கள் மற்றும் அனைத்து பாலூட்டும் தாய்மார்கள் (குழந்தைக்கு 06 மாதங்கள் நிறைவடையும் வரை) ஊட்டச்சத்து தேவைகளுக்கு உட்பட்ட அனைத்து பயனாளிகளுக்கும் திரிபோஷ விநியோகத்தை ஆரம்பித்துள்ளதாக Sri Lanka Thriposha Ltd அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "850,000 திரிபோஷ பொதிகள் விநியோகிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும், எனினும் குழந்தைகளுக்கான திரிபோஷ இன்னும் வழங்கப்படவில்லை எனவும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா திரிபோஷ லிமிடெட் தீப்தி குலரத்ன நியூஸ் 1ஸ்டிடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சோளம் மற்றும் சோயாபீன் பற்றாக்குறை காரணமாக நாட்டில் திரிபோஷ உற்பத்தியை சீரமைக்க முடியாத நிலை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக தீப்தி குலரத்ன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், மக்காச்சோளம் மற்றும் சோயா பீன்ஸ் ஆகியவற்றை இந்திய கடன் வரியின் கீழ் இறக்குமதி செய்ய சப்ளையர்களுடன் ஒப்பந்தம் செய்து கொள்ளப்படும் என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "குழந்தைகளுக்கும் திரிபோஷ உற்பத்தி செய்ய நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்படும் என அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எனினும் எரிபொருள் தட்டுப்பாடு காரணமாக திரிபோஷ விநியோகத்தில் சிக்கல்கள் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா திரிபோஷா லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06 மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா திரிபோஷா லிமிடெட் தீப்தி குலரத்னா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "850,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தீப்தி குலரத்னா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திரிபோஷா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சோளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய கடன் வரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}