{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/31/united-we-stand-longest-painting-by-sri-lankan-students/",
  "time_ut": 1661962620,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "United We Stand – Longest painting by Sri Lankan Students",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "United We Stand – Longest painting by Sri Lankan Students",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sirasa TV and the Education Ministry joined hands to launch a program to create one of the longest paintings in Sri Lanka on Wednesday (31).",
        "Incidentally, school children from across the island will contribute to this 1000 feet long work of art.",
        "United We Stand is the theme for the longest painting by Sri Lankan school children that is being created for World Childrens Day 2022, which falls on the 1st of October.",
        "This work of art is expected to be 1000 feet long, and the launch of the painting took place at the Independence Sqaure in Colombo.",
        "Secretary of the education ministry Nihal Ranasinghe along with several other officials of the ministry and senior officials of the Capital Maharaja Group were present for the launch.",
        "Two painting from each of the 25 districts will be brought together to create one massive painting in Colombo.",
        "Painting Tools & Supplies were officially handed over to the students on Wednesday to mark the launch of the program",
        "On Thursday, the paintings from the Jaffna District will be added to the canvas, and the official vehicle that will travel across the island was also unveiled.",
        "One-month-old infant abandoned at a motor garage with a letter",
        "Are you a victim of Cyber Crime? Police Unit ready to crackdown crime in the cyberspace"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sirasa TV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Education Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday (31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "this 1000 feet",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "World Childrens Day",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 1st of October",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1000 feet",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Independence Sqaure in Colombo",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nihal Ranasinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Capital Maharaja Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Painting Tools & Supplies",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Jaffna District",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One-month-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cyber Crime",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යුනයිටඩ් වී ස්ටෑන්ඩ් - ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය සිසුන්ගේ දිගම චිත්‍රය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); සිරස රූපවාහිනිය සහ අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍යාංශය එක්ව බදාදා (31) ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දිගම චිත්‍රයක් නිර්මාණය කිරීමේ වැඩසටහනක් දියත් කරන ලදී.",
        "මීට අමතරව, අඩි 1000ක් දිග මෙම කලා නිර්මාණය සඳහා දිවයිනේ නන් දෙසින් සිටින පාසල් සිසුන් දායක වනු ඇත.",
        "2022 ඔක්තෝබර් 01 වැනිදාට යෙදෙන ලෝක ළමා දිනය වෙනුවෙන් නිර්මාණය කෙරෙන ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය පාසල් ළමුන්ගේ දිගම චිත්‍රය සඳහා තේමාව වන්නේ United We Stand යන්නයි.",
        "මෙම කලා කෘතිය අඩි 1000ක් දිගින් යුක්ත වනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කරන අතර, චිත්‍රය එළිදැක්වීම කොළඹ නිදහස් චතුරශ්‍රයේදී සිදු විය.",
        "අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම් නිහාල් රණසිංහ මහතා ඇතුළු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ නිලධාරීන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු සහ කැපිටල් මහරාජා සමූහ ව්‍යාපාරයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරීන් පිරිසක් මෙම එළිදැක්වීම සඳහා එක්ව සිටියහ.",
        "දිස්ත්‍රික්ක 25න් චිත්‍ර දෙකක් බැගින් ගෙන කොළඹ දැවැන්ත චිත්‍රයක් නිර්මාණය කිරීමට නියමිතය.",
        "වැඩසටහන දියත් කිරීම සනිටුහන් කරමින් පින්තාරු කිරීමේ මෙවලම් සහ සැපයුම් බදාදා සිසුන් වෙත නිල වශයෙන් භාර දෙන ලදී.",
        "බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා යාපනය දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ චිත්‍ර කැන්වසයට එක් කෙරෙන අතර, දිවයින හරහා ගමන් කරන නිල රථය ද නිරාවරණය කෙරිණි.",
        "ලිපියක් සමඟ මෝටර් රථ ගරාජයක දමා ගිය මාසයක් වයසැති ළදරුවා",
        "ඔබ සයිබර් අපරාධයට ගොදුරු වූවෙක්ද? සයිබර් අවකාශයේ සිදුවන අපරාධ මර්දනයට පොලිස් ඒකකය සූදානම්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරස ටී.වී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්යාපන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා (31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ අඩි 1000",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක ළමා දිනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔක්තෝබර් 1 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඩි 1000 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ නිදහස් චතුරශ්‍රයේ",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිහාල් රණසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැපිටල් මහරාජා සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පින්තාරු කිරීමේ මෙවලම් සහ සැපයුම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාසයක් වයසැති",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සයිබර් අපරාධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "யுனைடெட் வி ஸ்டாண்ட் - இலங்கை மாணவர்களின் நீளமான ஓவியம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); சிரச தொலைக்காட்சியும் கல்வி அமைச்சும் இணைந்து இலங்கையின் மிக நீளமான ஓவியம் ஒன்றை உருவாக்கும் வேலைத்திட்டத்தை புதன்கிழமை (31) ஆரம்பித்துள்ளன.",
        "தற்செயலாக, இந்த 1000 அடி நீளமான கலைப் படைப்புக்கு தீவு முழுவதிலுமுள்ள பள்ளி மாணவர்கள் பங்களிப்பார்கள்.",
        "யுனைடெட் வீ ஸ்டாண்ட் என்பது இலங்கைப் பள்ளி மாணவர்களின் மிக நீளமான ஓவியத்திற்கான கருப்பொருளாகும், இது 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு அக்டோபர் 1 ஆம் தேதி உலக குழந்தைகள் தினத்திற்காக உருவாக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இந்த கலைப் படைப்பு 1000 அடி நீளமாக இருக்கும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது, மேலும் இந்த ஓவியத்தின் வெளியீட்டு விழா கொழும்பில் உள்ள சுதந்திர சதுக்கத்தில் நடைபெற்றது.",
        "கல்வி அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் நிஹால் ரணசிங்க மற்றும் அமைச்சின் பல அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் கெப்பிட்டல் மஹாராஜா குழுமத்தின் சிரேஷ்ட அதிகாரிகள் இந்த அறிமுக நிகழ்வில் கலந்து கொண்டனர்.",
        "கொழும்பில் ஒரு பாரிய ஓவியத்தை உருவாக்க 25 மாவட்டங்களில் இருந்தும் தலா இரண்டு ஓவியங்கள் இணைக்கப்படும்.",
        "நிகழ்ச்சியின் தொடக்கத்தைக் குறிக்கும் வகையில் புதன்கிழமை மாணவர்களுக்கு ஓவியக் கருவிகள் மற்றும் பொருட்கள் அதிகாரப்பூர்வமாக வழங்கப்பட்டன.",
        "வியாழன் அன்று யாழ்.மாவட்டத்தின் ஓவியங்கள் கேன்வாஸில் சேர்க்கப்படவுள்ளதுடன், நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் பயணிக்கும் உத்தியோகபூர்வ வாகனமும் திரையிடப்பட்டது.",
        "கடிதத்துடன் மோட்டார் கேரேஜில் கைவிடப்பட்ட ஒரு மாத கைக்குழந்தை",
        "நீங்கள் சைபர் கிரைம் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவரா? சைபர்ஸ்பேஸ் குற்றங்களை ஒடுக்க போலீஸ் பிரிவு தயார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிரச டி.வி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்வி அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்கிழமை (31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த 1000 அடி",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக குழந்தைகள் தினம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அக்டோபர் 1 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1000 அடி",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் உள்ள சுதந்திர சதுக்கம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிஹால் ரணசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைநகர் மகாராஜா குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஓவியம் கருவிகள் & பொருட்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாண மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாத வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சைபர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}