{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/පාතාල-ක්‍රියාකරුගේ-සිරුරු-කාමරයෙන්-හමු-වේ/101-615483",
  "time_ut": 1656322967,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පාතාල ක්‍රියාකරුගේ සිරුරු කාමරයෙන් හමු වේ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Body of underworld activist found in room",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former underworld activist S. The body of Dayananda alias Kotadaya was found lying under a bed in a two storey house on Ratna Mawatha in Arawwala today, Maharagama Police said.",
        "Police suspect the 55-year-old may have died a few days ago for some reason.",
        "The victims' permanent residence is in the Mirihana Ambuldeniya area, police said.",
        "Police investigations have revealed that he had rented a room upstairs in the two-storey house and was living alone.",
        "The body was found by the 119 Police Emergency Response Unit after receiving information that there was a strong stench in the house.",
        "Police found his mobile phone and earphones under the bed",
        "Police say there was a strong odor when the body was found"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dayananda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kotadaya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "storey house",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratna Mawatha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arawwala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maharagama Police",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "55-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a few days ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mirihana Ambuldeniya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 119",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාතාල ක්‍රියාකරුගේ සිරුරු කාමරයෙන් හමු වේ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු පාතාල කල්ලි ක්‍රියාකාරිකයකු වූ එස්. දයානන්ද නොහොත් කොටදයා නැමැත්තාගේ මළ සිරුර ඇරව්වල රත්න මාවතේ දෙමහල් නිවසක ඇඳක් පාමුල වැටී තිබියදී අද සොයාගත් බව මහරගම පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "වයස අවුරුදු 55 ක් වූ ඔහු මීට දින කිහිපයකට ඉහත දී කිසියම් හෝ හේතුවකින් මියයන්නට ඇතැයි පොලිසිය සැක කරයි.",
        "මියගිය අයගේ ස්ථිර පදිංචිය මිරිහාන ඇඹුල්දෙණිය ප්‍රදේශයේ බව පොලීසිය කියයි.",
        "ඔහු දෙමහල් නිවසේ උඩු මහලේ කාමරයක් කුලියට ගෙන තනිව ජීවත් ව සිටි බවත් පොලිස් විමර්ශනවලදී අනාවරණය වී ඇත.",
        "එම නිවස තුළින් අධික දුගඳක් හමන බවට 119 පොලිස් හදිසි ඇමතුම් අංශයට ලද තොරතුරක් අනුව මළ සිරුර සොයාගෙන ඇත.",
        "ඔහු පරිහරණය කළ බව කියන ජංගම දුරකථනය සහ කන් රඳවනය ඇඳ යට තිබී පොලිසිය මඟින් සොයාගෙන ඇත",
        "මළ සිරුර සොයා ගන්නා විට අධික දුර්ගන්ධයකින් පැවති බව පොලිසිය කියයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දයානන්දයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටඩය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහල් නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්න මාවත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇරැව්වල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහරගම පොලිසිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "55 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින කිහිපයකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිරිහාන ඇඹුල්දෙණිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "119",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாதாள உலக செயற்பாட்டாளரின் சடலம் அறையில் கண்டெடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் பாதாள உலக செயற்பாட்டாளர் எஸ். ஆரவ்வல, ரத்னா மாவத்தையில் உள்ள இரண்டு மாடி வீடொன்றில் கட்டில் ஒன்றின் கீழ் கிடந்த கோட்டாயா என்ற தயானந்தாவின் சடலம் இன்று கண்டெடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக மஹரகம பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "55 வயதான இவர் சில தினங்களுக்கு முன்னர் ஏதாவது காரணத்தினால் உயிரிழந்திருக்கலாம் என பொலிஸார் சந்தேகிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர்களின் நிரந்தர குடியிருப்பு மிரிஹான அம்புல்தெனிய பிரதேசத்தில் உள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இவர் இரண்டு மாடி வீட்டில் மாடியில் அறையொன்றை வாடகைக்கு எடுத்து தனியாக வசித்து வந்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸ் விசாரணைகளில் இருந்து தெரியவந்துள்ளது.",
        "வீட்டில் கடும் துர்நாற்றம் வீசியதாக கிடைத்த தகவலையடுத்து 119 பொலிஸ் அவசர நடவடிக்கை பிரிவு அதிகாரிகள் சடலத்தை கண்டெடுத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "படுக்கைக்கு அடியில் அவரது செல்போன் மற்றும் இயர்போன்களை போலீசார் கண்டுபிடித்தனர்",
        "சடலம் கண்டெடுக்கப்பட்ட போது கடும் துர்நாற்றம் வீசியதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தயானந்தா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோடடய",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாடி வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரத்னா மாவத்தை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரவ்வாலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹரகம பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "55 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு சில நாட்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மிரிஹான அம்புல்தெனிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "119",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}