{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Incumbent-Cabinet-awaits-finality-on-new-all-party-Govt-before-quitting/56-737351",
  "time_ut": 1657525195,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Incumbent Cabinet awaits finality on new all-party Govt. before quitting",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Incumbent Cabinet awaits finality on new all-party Govt. before quitting",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe today held a discussion with the Cabinet Ministers this at his office.",
        "All the Ministers who participated in the discussion were of the opinion that as soon as there is an agreement to form an All-Party Government, they are ready to hand over their responsibilities to that Government, the Prime Minister's Media Division said.",
        "The Cabinet meeting follows President Gotabaya Rajapaksa today officially informing Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe that he will be resigning as previously announced."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Govt",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cabinet Ministers",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "All-Party Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වත්මන් අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය නව සර්ව පාක්ෂික රජය පිළිබඳ අවසන් තීරණයක් බලාපොරොත්තුවෙන් සිටී. ඉවත් වීමට පෙර",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අද කැබිනට් අමාත්‍යවරුන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡාවක් සිය කාර්යාලයේදී පැවැත්වීය.",
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමට එකඟතාවක් ඇති වූ වහාම එම රජයට සිය වගකීම් පැවරීමට සූදානම් බව සාකච්ඡාවට සහභාගි වූ සියලුම අමාත්‍යවරුන්ගේ මතය වූ බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මාධ්‍ය අංශය සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "පෙර ප්‍රකාශ කළ පරිදි තමන් ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට නිල වශයෙන් දැනුම් දීමෙන් අනතුරුව අද කැබිනට් රැස්වීම පැවැත්විණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රජය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැබිනට් ඇමතිවරු",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புதிய அனைத்துக் கட்சி ஆட்சிக்கான இறுதித் தீர்மானத்திற்காக தற்போதைய அமைச்சரவை காத்திருக்கிறது. விலகுவதற்கு முன்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இன்று தனது அலுவலகத்தில் அமைச்சரவை அமைச்சர்களுடன் கலந்துரையாடினார்.",
        "சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பதற்கு இணக்கம் காணப்பட்டவுடன் அந்த அரசாங்கத்திடம் தமது பொறுப்புக்களை ஒப்படைக்கத் தயார் என கலந்துரையாடலில் கலந்துகொண்ட அமைச்சர்கள் அனைவரும் கருத்து வெளியிட்டதாக பிரதமரின் ஊடகப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ, பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு முன்னர் அறிவித்தபடி பதவி விலகுவதாக இன்று உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக அறிவித்ததைத் தொடர்ந்து அமைச்சரவைக் கூட்டம் நடைபெற்றது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அரசு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சரவை அமைச்சர்கள்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனைத்து கட்சி அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}