{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131634",
  "time_ut": 1658046083,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "யாழ்.மாவட்டத்தில் எரிபொருள் அட்டைக்கே எரிபொருள் விநியோகம் : யாழ்.மாவட்டச் செயலர் மகேசன்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Fuel distribution in Jaffna district through fuel card: Jaffna district secretary Mahesan",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "Jaffna District Secretary K. Maheson said that fuel will be provided only through fuel cards in Jaffna district.",
        "If he did not further inform in this regard, we have started the distribution of fuel cards before the introduction of the national work plan regarding fuel distribution system.",
        "Now a national job program has been introduced. We cannot ignore it. However, Jaffa. He said that the fuel card will continue to be issued in the district and the distribution system will continue to be carried out through it."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Jaffna",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Jaffna",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mahesan",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaffna District",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "K. Maheson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaffa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යාපනය දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ ඉන්ධන කාඩ්පත හරහා ඉන්ධන බෙදා හැරීම: යාපනය දිස්ත්‍රික් ලේකම් මහේසන්",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "යාපනය දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ ඉන්ධන කාඩ්පත් මගින් පමණක් ඉන්ධන ලබා දෙන බව යාපනය දිස්ත්‍රික් ලේකම් කේ.මහේසන් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් දැනුම් දුන්නේ නැතිනම් ඉන්ධන බෙදා හැරීමේ ක්‍රමය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජාතික වැඩ සැලැස්ම හඳුන්වාදීමට පෙර ඉන්ධන කාඩ්පත් බෙදා හැරීම අප ආරම්භ කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "දැන් ජාතික රැකියා වැඩසටහනක් හඳුන්වා දී තිබෙනවා. අපට එය නොසලකා හැරිය නොහැක. කෙසේ වෙතත්, යාපනය. දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ ඉන්ධන කාඩ්පත් නිකුත් කිරීම අඛණ්ඩව සිදු කරන බවත්, ඒ හරහා බෙදා හැරීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය අඛණ්ඩව සිදු කරන බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "යාපනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "යාපනය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "මහේසන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "යාපනය දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේ මහේසන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "யாழ்.மாவட்டத்தில் எரிபொருள் அட்டைக்கே எரிபொருள் விநியோகம் : யாழ்.மாவட்டச் செயலர் மகேசன்",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "யாழ்.மாவட்டத்தில் எரிபொருள் அட்டைக்கே எரிபொருள் வழங்கப்படும் என  யாழ்.மாவட்டச் செயலர் க.மகேசன் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இது தொடர்பில் அவர் மேலும் தெரிவிக்கைநில்  எரிபொருள் விநியோக ஒழுங்கு முறை தொடர்பில் தேசிய ரீதியிலான வேலைத் திட்டம் அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட முன்னரே எரிபொருள் அட்டை விநியோகத்தை நாம் ஆரம்பித்துவிட்டோம்.",
        "இப்போது தேசிய ரீதியான வேலைத் திட்டம் அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது . அதனை நாம் புறக்கணிக்க முடியாது. ஆனாலும், யாழ். மாவட்டத்தில் எரிபொருள் அட்டை தொடர்ந்தும் வழங்கப்பட்டு, அதன் ஊடாக விநியோக ஒழுங்கு தொடர்ந்தும் முன்னெடுக்கப்படும் என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "யாழ்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "யாழ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "மகேசன்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாண மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கே. மகேசன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}