{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Jayasuriya-Mendis-bowl-Sri-Lanka-to-improbable-win/108-241959",
  "time_ut": 1658996807,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Jayasuriya, Mendis bowl Sri Lanka to improbable win",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Jayasuriya, Mendis bowl Sri Lanka to improbable win",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "For all the fears that their delayed declaration on day four may not have left them enough time to bowl out Pakistan on the final day of the second Test, Sri Lanka needed just half a day to complete a series-leveling 246-run win, with Prabath Jayasuriya and Ramesh Mendis sharing the spoils.",
        "Sri Lanka’s route to victory might have been even shorter if not for a partnership of 76 between Babar Azam and Mohammad Rizwan which had Pakistan comfortably placed for much of the morning session.",
        "Jayasuriya broke that stand 26 minutes from lunch, and a little over an hour after the break Pakistan’s innings completely unraveled, bowled out for 231.",
        "Left-arm spinner Jayasuriya, whose sensational start to Test cricket tied him with Australia’s Charlie Turner for the most wickets (23) after playing three Tests, claimed his fourth five-wicket haul with figures of 5 for 117.",
        "While Jayasuriya was the star, Mendis played an equal support, making the first breakthrough of the day on his first ball of the day, dismissing Pakistan opener Imam-ul-Haq for 49.",
        "From there, Pakistan appeared impregnable giving Sri Lanka few chances and scoring more boundaries, with Rizwan proactive in his approach sweeping and skipping down the wicket to accumulate six fours.",
        "Rizwan’s wicket brought Sri Lanka’s attack to life, chances being created, the ball evading the close in fielders, and hits on the pad drawing louder appeals.",
        "With pressure starting to build, Fawad Alam, who had one run in eight balls, called Azam for a single and while his teammate had initially agreed he turned Alam back but not in time to avoid a run out. Azam lost another partner at the stroke of lunch, when Kusal Mendis held onto a catch at short leg, cleverly following Agha Salman’s attempted sweep off Jayasuriya. Sri Lanka’s march gained further ground with the wicket of Azam after lunch, Pakistan’s captain facing 146 balls for 81, before he was trapped LBW to Jayasuriya.",
        "Mohammad Nawaz holed out to Mendis for 12, with Yasir Shah, Hasan Ali and Naseem Shah counter-attacked with boundaries, but Sri Lanka’s efforts were never in danger, Mendis claiming the last wicket to finish with 4 for 101. By Shehan Daniel at the Galle International Stadium"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Jayasuriya",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mendis",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "day four",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the final day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "just half a day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "246",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prabath Jayasuriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramesh Mendis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "76",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Babar Azam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mohammad Rizwan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayasuriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "a little over an hour",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "231",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayasuriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Charlie Turner",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tests",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "fourth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "117",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayasuriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mendis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Imam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "49",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rizwan",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rizwan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fawad Alam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "eight",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Azam",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Azam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kusal Mendis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Agha Salman’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayasuriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Azam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "146",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "81",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayasuriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mohammad Nawaz",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mendis",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yasir Shah",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hasan Ali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Naseem Shah",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mendis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "101",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shehan Daniel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Galle International Stadium",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජයසූරිය සහ මෙන්ඩිස් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අභව්‍ය ජයග්‍රහණයක් කරා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සිව්වන දිනයේ ප්‍රමාද වූ ප්‍රකාශය නිසා දෙවැනි ටෙස්ට් තරගයේ අවසන් දිනයේ දී පාකිස්තානය දවා ගැනීමට ප්‍රමාණවත් කාලයක් ඉතිරි නොවනු ඇතැයි යන සියලු බිය නිසා, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පිලට තරගමාලා මට්ටමින් ලකුණු 246ක ජයග්‍රහණයක් සම්පූර්ණ කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය වූයේ දින භාගයක් පමණි. ප්‍රභාත් ජයසූරිය සහ රමේෂ් මෙන්ඩිස් කොල්ලය බෙදා ගනිමින්.",
        "උදෑසන සැසිවාරයෙන් වැඩි කාලයක් පකිස්තානය පහසු ලෙස තබා ගත් බාබර් අසාම් සහ මොහොමඩ් රිස්වාන් අතර ලකුණු 76 ක සම්බන්ධතාවක් නොතිබුනේ නම් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජයග්‍රහණය කරා යන ගමන තවත් කෙටි වන්නට ඉඩ තිබුණි.",
        "දිවා ආහාරයෙන් මිනිත්තු 26 ක් ඇතුළත ජයසූරිය එම ස්ථාවරය බිඳ දැමූ අතර, විවේකයෙන් පැයකට මඳක් වැඩි කාලයක් ගත වූ පසු පාකිස්තාන ඉනිම සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම බිඳ වැටුණු අතර, ලකුණු 231 කට දැවී ගියේය.",
        "ටෙස්ට් තරග තුනකට ක්‍රීඩා කිරීමෙන් පසු වැඩිම කඩුලු (23) සඳහා ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවේ චාලි ටර්නර් සමඟින් ඔහුව බැඳ තැබූ වමත් දඟ පන්දු යවන ක්‍රීඩක ජයසූරිය, ලකුණු 117 කට කඩුලු 5 ක් ලබා ගනිමින් ඔහුගේ සිව්වැනි කඩුලු 5 දවාලීමට හිමිකම් කීවේය.",
        "ජයසූරිය තරුව සිටියදී මෙන්ඩිස් තම පළමු පන්දුවේදීම දිනයේ පළමු ජයග්‍රහණය කරමින් පාකිස්තාන ආරම්භක පිතිකරු ඉමාම් උල් හක් ලකුණු 49කට දැවී ගියේය.",
        "එතැන් සිට, පකිස්තානය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අවස්ථා කිහිපයක් ලබා දෙමින් සහ තවත් හතරේ පහරවල් ලබා ගනිමින් අපරාජිත ලෙස පෙනී සිටි අතර, රිස්වාන් ඔහුගේ ප්‍රවේශයේදී ක්‍රියාශීලීව කඩුල්ල මුවා කරමින් හතරේ පහර 6ක් රැස් කළේය.",
        "රිස්වාන්ගේ කඩුල්ල ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රහාරයට ජීවය ගෙන දුන්නේ, අවස්ථා නිර්මාණය වීම, පන්දු රකින ක්‍රීඩකයින් අසලින් පන්දුව මග හැරීම සහ පෑඩයේ පහරවල් උස් හඬින් ආයාචනා ලබා දීමයි.",
        "පීඩනය ගොඩනැගීමට පටන් ගැනීමත් සමඟ, පන්දු 8 කදී එක් ලකුණක් ලබා සිටි ෆවාඩ් අලාම්, අසාම්ව තනි ලකුණකට කැඳවූ අතර, ඔහුගේ සගයා මුලින් එකඟ වූ අතර, ඔහු අලාම් ආපසු හරවා යැවූ නමුත් දුවද්දී දැවී යාමක් වළක්වා ගැනීමට නියමිත වේලාවට එය සිදු නොවීය. දිවා ආහාරය වන විට අසාම්ට තවත් සහකරුවෙක් අහිමි විය, කුසල් මෙන්ඩිස් කෙටි පාදයේ උඩපන්දුවක් අල්ලාගෙන සිටි අතර, අගා සල්මාන්ගේ උත්සාහය ජයසූරියට එරෙහිව දක්ෂ ලෙස හඹා ගියේය. දිවා ආහාරයෙන් පසුව අසාම්ගේ කඩුල්ල දවාගැනීමත් සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමන තවත් ශක්තිමත් විය, පාකිස්තාන නායකයා ලකුණු 81කට පන්දු 146කට මුහුණ දෙමින් ජයසූරියට එල්බීඩබ්ලිව්ව හසුවීමට පෙරය.",
        "මොහොමඩ් නවාස් මෙන්ඩිස් ලකුණු 12කට දැවී ගිය අතර, යසීර් ෂා, හසන් අලි සහ නසීම් ෂා හතරේ පහරවල් සමඟින් ප්‍රතිප්‍රහාර එල්ල කළ නමුත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා උත්සාහය කිසිවිටෙක අනතුරට ලක් නොවූ අතර, මෙන්ඩිස් අවසන් කඩුල්ල ලෙස ලකුණු 101කට කඩුලු 4ක් ලබා අවසන් කඩුල්ලට හිමිකම් කීවේය. ෂෙහාන් ඩැනියෙල් විසින් ගාල්ල ජාත්‍යන්තර ක්‍රීඩාංගණය"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජයසූරිය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "මෙන්ඩිස්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දින හතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසාන දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින භාගයක් පමණි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "246",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රභාත් ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රමේෂ් මෙන්ඩිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "76",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බාබර් අසාම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොහොමඩ් රිස්වාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විනාඩි 26 යි",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැයකට ටිකක් වැඩියි",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "231",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චාලි ටර්නර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පරීක්ෂණ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතරවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "117",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙන්ඩිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉමාම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "49",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිස්වාන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රිස්වාන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆවාඩ් අලාම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අට",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අසාම්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලාම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අසාම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුසල් මෙන්ඩිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගා සල්මාන්ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අසාම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "146",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "81",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මොහොමඩ් නවාස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙන්ඩිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යසීර් ෂා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හසන් අලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නසීම් ෂා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙන්ඩිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "101",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂෙහාන් ඩැනියෙල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල ජාත්‍යන්තර ක්‍රීඩාංගණයේදී",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜெயசூர்யா, மெண்டிஸ் பந்துவீச்சில் இலங்கை அசாத்திய வெற்றி பெற்றது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நான்காவது நாளில் தாமதமாக அறிவித்ததால், இரண்டாவது டெஸ்டின் இறுதி நாளில் பாகிஸ்தானை ஆல் அவுட் செய்ய போதுமான நேரம் கிடைக்காமல் போகலாம் என்ற அச்சம் காரணமாக, தொடரை சமன் செய்யும் 246 ரன்கள் வெற்றியை முடிக்க இலங்கைக்கு அரை நாள் மட்டுமே தேவைப்பட்டது. பிரபாத் ஜெயசூர்யா மற்றும் ரமேஷ் மெண்டிஸ் கொள்ளையடித்ததை பகிர்ந்து கொள்கின்றனர்.",
        "பாபர் அசாம் மற்றும் மொஹமட் ரிஸ்வான் இடையேயான 76 ரன்களின் பார்ட்னர்ஷிப் இல்லை என்றால் இலங்கையின் வெற்றிக்கான பாதை இன்னும் குறுகியதாக இருந்திருக்கும்",
        "மதிய உணவில் இருந்து 26 நிமிடங்களில் அந்த நிலைப்பாட்டை ஜெயசூர்யா முறியடித்தார், இடைவேளையின் ஒரு மணி நேரத்திற்குப் பிறகு பாகிஸ்தானின் இன்னிங்ஸ் முற்றிலும் அவிழ்ந்தது, 231 ரன்களுக்கு ஆட்டமிழந்தது.",
        "இடது கை சுழற்பந்து வீச்சாளர் ஜெயசூர்யா, டெஸ்ட் கிரிக்கெட்டில் தனது பரபரப்பான தொடக்கத்தை ஆஸ்திரேலியாவின் சார்லி டர்னருடன் சேர்த்து மூன்று டெஸ்ட் போட்டிகளில் விளையாடிய பிறகு அதிக விக்கெட்டுகளை (23), 117 ரன்களுக்கு 5 விக்கெட்டுகளுடன் தனது நான்காவது ஐந்து விக்கெட்டுகளை கைப்பற்றினார்.",
        "ஜெயசூர்யா நட்சத்திரமாக இருந்தபோது, ​​மெண்டிஸ் சமமான ஆதரவுடன் விளையாடி, தனது முதல் பந்திலேயே முதல் திருப்புமுனையை ஏற்படுத்தினார், பாகிஸ்தான் தொடக்க ஆட்டக்காரர் இமாம்-உல்-ஹக்கை 49 ரன்களில் வெளியேற்றினார்.",
        "அங்கிருந்து, பாகிஸ்தான் இலங்கைக்கு சில வாய்ப்புகளை வழங்கியது மற்றும் அதிக பவுண்டரிகளை அடித்தது, ரிஸ்வான் தனது அணுகுமுறையில் ஸ்வீப்பிங் மற்றும் 6 பவுண்டரிகளை குவிக்க விக்கெட்டை கீழே தள்ளினார்.",
        "ரிஸ்வானின் விக்கெட் இலங்கையின் தாக்குதலை உயிர்ப்பித்தது, வாய்ப்புகளை உருவாக்கியது, பந்து பீல்டர்களை நெருங்குவதைத் தவிர்ப்பது மற்றும் திண்டில் அடித்தது பலத்த முறையீடுகளை ஈர்த்தது.",
        "அழுத்தத்தை உருவாக்கத் தொடங்கியவுடன், எட்டு பந்துகளில் ஒரு ரன் எடுத்திருந்த ஃபவாத் ஆலம், ஆசாமை ஒரு ஒற்றைக்கு அழைத்தார், அவருடைய சக வீரர் ஆரம்பத்தில் ஒப்புக்கொண்டார், ஆனால் ரன் அவுட்டைத் தவிர்க்க சரியான நேரத்தில் ஆலமைத் திரும்பவில்லை. ஆகா சல்மான் ஜெயசூர்யாவை ஸ்வீப் செய்ய முயற்சித்ததை சாதுரியமாகப் பின்தொடர்ந்து, ஷார்ட் லெக்கில் குசல் மெண்டிஸ் ஒரு கேட்ச்சைப் பிடித்தபோது, ​​மதிய உணவின் போது அசாம் மற்றொரு பார்ட்னரை இழந்தார். இலங்கையின் அணிவகுப்பு மதிய உணவிற்குப் பிறகு அசாம் விக்கெட்டைக் கைப்பற்றியது, பாகிஸ்தான் கேப்டன் 81 ரன்களுக்கு 146 பந்துகளை எதிர்கொண்டார், அவர் ஜெயசூர்யாவிடம் எல்பிடபிள்யூவில் சிக்கினார்.",
        "முகமது நவாஸ் 12 ரன்களுக்கு மெண்டிஸிடம் வெளியேறினார், யாசிர் ஷா, ஹசன் அலி மற்றும் நசீம் ஷா ஆகியோர் பவுண்டரிகளுடன் எதிர் தாக்குதல் நடத்தினர், ஆனால் இலங்கையின் முயற்சிகள் ஒருபோதும் ஆபத்தில் சிக்கவில்லை, மெண்டிஸ் கடைசி விக்கெட்டாக 101 ரன்களுக்கு 4 விக்கெட்டுகளை எடுத்தார். By Shehan Daniel at the காலி சர்வதேச மைதானம்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜெயசூர்யா",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "மெண்டிஸ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நாள் நான்கு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இறுதி நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெறும் அரை நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "246",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரபாத் ஜெயசூரிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரமேஷ் மெண்டிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "76",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாபர் அசாம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முகமது ரிஸ்வான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசூர்யா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 நிமிடங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மணி நேரத்திற்கு சிறிது",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "231",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசூர்யா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சார்லி டர்னர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோதனைகள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்காவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "117",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசூர்யா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெண்டிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இமாம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "49",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிஸ்வான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரிஸ்வான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃபவாத் ஆலம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசம்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆலம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குசல் மெண்டிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகா சல்மானின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசூர்யா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "146",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "81",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசூர்யா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முகமது நவாஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெண்டிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாசிர் ஷா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹசன் அலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நசீம் ஷா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெண்டிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "101",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷெஹான் டேனியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி சர்வதேச மைதானம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}