{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/මා-රාජපක්ෂවරුන්ගේ-නොව-ජනතාවගේ-මිතුරෙක්/1-616820",
  "time_ut": 1658405925,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මා රාජපක්ෂවරුන්ගේ නොව ජනතාවගේ මිතුරෙක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "I am not a friend of the Rajapaksa people but a friend of the people",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickramasinghe said that he is not a friend of the Rajapaksas but a friend of the people.",
        "Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe said this while answering the questions asked by the journalists after coming out of the Hunupitiya Gangarama temple in Colombo after taking the oath of office.",
        "Mr. Wickramasinghe said that he worked with the Rajapaksas and they are not his friends."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Rajapaksa",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මා රාජපක්ෂවරුන්ගේ නොව ජනතාවගේ මිතුරෙක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "තමා රාජපක්ෂවරුන්ගේ මිතුරකු නොව ජනතාවගේ මිතුරකු බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ජනාධිපති ධුරයෙහි දිවුරුම් දීමෙන් අනතුරුව කොළඹ හුණුපිටිය ගංගාරාම විහාරස්ථානයට පැමිණ වන්දනාමාන කටයුතු කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුව පිටතට පැමිණෙන දී මාධ්‍යවේදීන් ඇසූ ප්‍රශ්නවලට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් අප රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මේ බව පැවසීය.",
        "රාජපක්ෂවරුන් සමග වැඩ කළා කියා ඔවුන් තමාගේ මිතුරකු නොවන බවද වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நான் ராஜபக்ச மக்களின் நண்பன் அல்ல மக்களின் நண்பன்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தான் ராஜபக்ஷக்களின் நண்பன் அல்ல, மக்களின் நண்பன் என ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கொழும்பு ஹுனுப்பிட்டிய கங்காராம விகாரையில் சத்தியப் பிரமாணம் செய்து கொண்டு வெளியே வந்த பின்னர் ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் கேட்ட கேள்விகளுக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் போதே ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "தாம் ராஜபக்சக்களுடன் இணைந்து செயற்பட்டதாகவும் அவர்கள் தமது நண்பர்கள் அல்ல எனவும் திரு.விக்கிரமசிங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமாதித்தன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}