{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ධම්මිකගේ-පුටුවට-තුනක්-සටනට/1-616903",
  "time_ut": 1658548040,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ධම්මිකගේ පුටුවට තුනක් සටනට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dhammika's chair three to battle",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to sources, a three-cornered fight has been created for the position of National List Member of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna, which has been left vacant by the resignation of prominent businessman Dhammika Perera.",
        "It has been learned that the ruling secretary of the party Renuka Perera, Southern Province Governor Willy Gamage Gamage and S. Amarasinghe are trying to get the seat.",
        "It is said that they have submitted requests to the founder and national organizer of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna Mr. Basil Rajapaksa through various persons."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "National List",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Renuka Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southern Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. Amarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ධම්මිකගේ පුටුවට තුනක් සටනට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ප්‍රකට ව්‍යාපාරික ධම්මික පෙරේරා මහතාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පුරප්පාඩු වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධුරයට තුන් කොන් සටනක් නිර්මාණය වී ඇතැයි ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "එම පක්ෂයේ පාලක ලේකම් රේණුක පෙරේරා, දකුණු පළාත් ආණ්ඩුකාර විලී ගමගේ ගමගේ සහ එස් අමරසිංහ යන මහත්වරුන් එම මන්ත්‍රීධූරය ලබාගැනීමේ උත්සාහයක සිටින බව දැනගන්නට ඇත.",
        "ඔවුන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ නිර්මාතෘ සහ ජාතික සංවිධායක බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට විවිධ පුද්ගලයන් හරහාඑ පිළිබඳව ඉල්ලීම් ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති බවද පැවසේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රේණුකා පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தம்மிக்காவின் நாற்காலி மூன்று போருக்கு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிரபல வர்த்தகர் தம்மிக்க பெரேராவின் இராஜினாமாவால் வெற்றிடமாகிய ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் தேசியப் பட்டியல் உறுப்பினர் பதவிக்கு முக்கோணப் போட்டி உருவாகியுள்ளதாக தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "அக்கட்சியின் ஆளும் செயலாளர் ரேணுகா பெரேரா, தென் மாகாண ஆளுநர் வில்லி கமகே கமகே மற்றும் எஸ்.அமரசிங்க ஆகியோர் இந்த ஆசனத்தை பெற்றுக்கொள்ள முயற்சிப்பதாக தெரியவந்துள்ளது.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் ஸ்தாபகரும் தேசிய அமைப்பாளருமான திரு.பசில் ராஜபக்ஷவிடம் பல்வேறு நபர்கள் ஊடாக கோரிக்கைகளை முன்வைத்துள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பட்டியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரேணுகா பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.அமரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}