{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/COPE-meeting-scheduled-for-today-postponed/56-737385",
  "time_ut": 1657572634,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "COPE meeting scheduled for today postponed",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "COPE meeting scheduled for today postponed",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Committee on Public Enterprises (COPE) has decided to postpone its meetings scheduled for today where the heads of the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation CPC), Ceylon Petroleum Storage Terminal Ltd., and Public Utilities Commission (PUCSL) were to appear.",
        "The decision to postpone the meeting was taken due to the current political situation in the country, COPE Chairman MP Charitha Herath said.",
        "“Due to the personal statement made by the Chairman PUCSL at the last COPE meeting, a great controversy arose in the country regarding the price of petroleum. An investigation into this was to be conducted based on his statement and the Auditor General’s report on the CPC and Ceylon Petroleum Storage Terminal Limited,” Herath said.",
        "He said meetings will resume once the prevailing situation has settled."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "COPE",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Committee on Public Enterprises",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Storage Terminal Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Charitha Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Auditor General’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Storage Terminal Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අද පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතව තිබූ කෝප් කමිටු රැස්වීම කල් යයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව, සීමාසහිත ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් ගබඩා පර්යන්තය සහ මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව (PUCSL) යන ආයතනවල ප්‍රධානීන් පෙනී සිටීමට නියමිතව තිබූ පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව (COPE) අද පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතව තිබූ සිය රැස්වීම් කල් දැමීමට තීරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "රට තුළ පවතින දේශපාලන වාතාවරණය හේතුවෙන් රැස්වීම කල් දැමීමට තීරණය කළ බව කෝප් කමිටු සභාපති පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී චරිත හේරත් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "“පසුගිය කෝප් රැස්වීමේදී මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිසමේ සභාපතිවරයා කළ පෞද්ගලික ප්‍රකාශය නිසා ඛනිජ තෙල් මිල සම්බන්ධයෙන් රට තුළ විශාල ආන්දෝලනයක් ඇති වුණා. ඔහුගේ ප්‍රකාශය සහ CPC සහ Ceylon Petroleum Storage Terminal Limited පිළිබඳ විගණකාධිපතිවරයාගේ වාර්තාව පදනම් කරගෙන මේ පිළිබඳව පරීක්ෂණයක් පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතව තිබුණා.” හේරත් පැවසීය.",
        "පවතින තත්ත්වය සමථයකට පත් වූ පසු යළි රැස්වීම් ආරම්භ කරන බව ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කෝප්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත සිලෝන් පෙට්‍රෝලියම් ස්ටෝරේජ් ටර්මිනල්.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චරිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විගණකාධිපතිගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් ගබඩා පර්යන්තය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இன்று நடைபெறவிருந்த கோப் கூட்டம் ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை பெற்றோலிய கூட்டுத்தாபனம் CPC, Ceylon Petroleum Storage Terminal Ltd, மற்றும் Public Utilities Commission (PUCSL) ஆகியவற்றின் தலைவர்கள் ஆஜராகவிருந்த பொது நிறுவனங்கள் தொடர்பான குழு (COPE) இன்று நடைபெறவிருந்த கூட்டங்களை ஒத்திவைக்க தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "நாட்டில் தற்போது நிலவும் அரசியல் சூழ்நிலை காரணமாக கூட்டத்தை ஒத்திவைக்க தீர்மானம் எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக கோப் தலைவர் எம்.பி சரித ஹேரத் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "“கடந்த கோப் கூட்டத்தில் தலைவர் PUCSL தெரிவித்த தனிப்பட்ட கருத்து காரணமாக, பெற்றோலிய விலை தொடர்பாக நாட்டில் பெரும் சர்ச்சை எழுந்தது. அவரது அறிக்கை மற்றும் CPC மற்றும் Ceylon Petroleum Storage Terminal Limited தொடர்பான கணக்காய்வாளர் நாயகத்தின் அறிக்கையின் அடிப்படையில் இது தொடர்பான விசாரணை நடத்தப்படவுள்ளது” என்று ஹேரத் கூறினார்.",
        "தற்போது நிலவும் சூழல் சுமூகமான பிறகு மீண்டும் கூட்டங்கள் தொடங்கும் என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோப்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொது நிறுவனங்களுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலிய கூட்டுத்தாபனம் CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிலோன் பெட்ரோலியம் ஸ்டோரேஜ் டெர்மினல் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரித ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆடிட்டர் ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிலோன் பெட்ரோலியம் ஸ்டோரேஜ் டெர்மினல் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}