{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130476",
  "time_ut": 1656575698,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "மேலும் நான்கு இலங்கை தமிழர்கள் அகதிகளாக தனுஷ்கோடியில் தஞ்சம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Four more Sri Lankan Tamils ​​seek refuge in Dhanushkodi",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "Due to the severe economic downturn in the country, Sri Lankan Tamils ​​are fleeing into Tamil Nadu via the Danuskodi Sea due to high prices of food and essential commodities and shortages of essential commodities.",
        "Dominic, 42, of Vavuniya district, his wife Sudarshani, 24, three members of the same family as his six-year-old son and Mahendran, 50, of Kilinochchi, set off in a piper boat at around 05.00 this morning. Went down the sand dune.",
        "The Rameswaram Marine Police went to the boat and rescued the Sri Lankan Tamils ​​and took them to the Mandapam Marine Police Station based on the information provided by the fishermen who were fishing in the area about the Sri Lankan Tamils ​​who were trapped in the sand for about 4 hours.",
        "It is noteworthy that 96 Sri Lankan Tamils ​​have come to Tamil Nadu as refugees from March 22 to date due to the economic crisis in Sri Lanka."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Four",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan Tamils",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "​​seek",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dhanushkodi",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Tamils ​​are",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Danuskodi Sea",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "42",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vavuniya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sudarshani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "six-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahendran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kilinochchi",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Tamils ​​and",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Mandapam Marine Police Station",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Tamils ​​who",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 4 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "96",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Tamils",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "March 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තවත් ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ද්‍රවිඩ ජාතිකයන් හතර දෙනෙක් ධනුෂ්කොඩිහි රැකවරණය පතා සිටිති",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "රට තුළ පවතින දැඩි ආර්ථික පසුබෑම හේතුවෙන් ආහාර සහ අත්‍යවශ්‍ය භාණ්ඩවල ඉහළ මිල ගණන් සහ අත්‍යවශ්‍ය භාණ්ඩ හිඟය හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ ජනතාව දනුස්කොඩි මුහුද හරහා තමිල්නාඩුවට පලා යති.",
        "වවුනියාව දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ ඩොමිනික් (42), ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ සුදර්ශනී (24) යන අය එකම පවුලේ තිදෙනෙක් සහ ඔහුගේ හය හැවිරිදි පුත්‍රයා සහ කිලිනොච්චියේ මහේන්ද්‍රන් (50) යන අය අද අලුයම 05.00 ට පමණ නල ඔරුවකින් පිටත් විය. වැලි කන්ද.",
        "එම ප්‍රදේශයේ ධීවර කටයුතුවල නිරතව සිටි ධීවරයින් විසින් කොටුවී සිටි ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ ජාතිකයන් පිළිබඳව ලබාදුන් තොරතුරක් මත රාමේෂ්වරම් සමුද්‍ර පොලිසිය එම බෝට්ටුව වෙත ගොස් ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ ජාතිකයන් බේරාගෙන මණ්ඩපම් සමුද්‍ර පොලිස් ස්ථානය වෙත රැගෙන ගොස් ඇත. පැය 4 ක් පමණ වැලි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් පසුගිය මාර්තු 22 වැනිදා සිට මේ දක්වා ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ ජාතිකයන් 96 දෙනෙකු සරණාගතයින් ලෙස තමිල්නාඩුවට පැමිණ තිබීම විශේෂත්වයක්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හතර",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ ජනතාව",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "සොයන්න",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ධනුෂ්කොඩි",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ ජනතාවයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දනුස්කොඩි මුහුද",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "42",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වවුනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුදර්ශනී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය හැවිරිදි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහේන්ද්‍රන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලිනොච්චි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ ජනතාව සහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩපම් සමුද්‍ර පොලිස් ස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ ජනතාව",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 4 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "96",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ ජනතාව",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மேலும் நான்கு இலங்கை தமிழர்கள் அகதிகளாக தனுஷ்கோடியில் தஞ்சம்",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள கடும் பொருளாதார வீழ்ச்சி காரணமாக உணவு மற்றும் அத்தயாவசிய பொருட்களின் கடும் விலை ஏற்றம் மற்றும் அத்தியவசிய பொருட்களின் தட்டுபாடு காரணமாக இலங்கை தமிழர்கள் தனுஸ்கோடி கடல் வழியாக தமிழகத்திற்குள்  அகதிகளாக சென்ற வண்ணம் உள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்நிலையில் நேற்று இரவு வவுனிய மாவட்டத்தை சேர்ந்த  டோமினிக் (42), அவரது மனைவி சுதர்சனி(24) அவரது ஆறு வயது மகன் என ஒரே குடும்பத்தை சேர்ந்த மூன்று பேர் மற்றும் கிளிநொச்சியை சேர்ந்த மகேந்திரன் (50) ஒள்ளிட்ட 4 பேர் ஒரு பைப்பர் படகில் புறப்பட்டு இன்று காலை சுமார் 05.00 மணி அளவில் தனுஸ்கோடி அடுத்த நான்காம் மணல் திட்டில் சென்று இறங்கியுள்ளனர்.",
        "மணல் திட்டில் சுமார் 4 மணிநேரமாக சிக்கி தவித்த இலங்கை தமிழர்கள் குறித்து அப்பகுதியில் மீன் பிடித்துகொண்டிருந்த மீனவர்கள் அளித்த தகவலின் அடிப்படையில் ராமேஸ்வரம் மரைன் பொலிஸார் படகில் சென்று  இலங்கைத் தமிழர்களை மீட்டு மண்டபம் மெரைன் காவல் நிலையம் அழைத்து சென்று விசாரணை நடத்தி வருகின்றனர்.",
        "இலங்கையில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி காரணமாக கடந்த மார்ச் மாதம் 22 ஆம் திகதி முதல் இன்று வரை இலங்கையில் இருந்து 96 இலங்கை தமிழர்கள் அகதிகளாக தமிழகம் வந்துள்ளது குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நான்கு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கைத் தமிழர்கள்",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "தேடு",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "தனுஷ்கோடி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கைத் தமிழர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனுஸ்கோடி கடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "42",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வவுனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதர்ஷனி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகேந்திரன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிளிநொச்சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தமிழர்கள் மற்றும்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மண்டபம் மரைன் காவல் நிலையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தமிழர்கள் யார்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 4 மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "96",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கைத் தமிழர்கள்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}