{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ආර්ථික-අර්බුදය-ගැන-පැවති-රජය-සත්‍ය-වසන්-කළා/1-616674",
  "time_ut": 1658212939,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ආර්ථික අර්බුදය ගැන පැවති රජය සත්‍ය වසන් කළා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The government hid the truth about the economic crisis",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe said in an interview with CNN that the government hid the truth regarding the economic crisis in Sri Lanka.",
        "Acting President Ranil Wickramasinghe said that the former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa's government hid the fact that Sri Lanka is bankrupt and needs to go to the International Monetary Fund to get rid of it.",
        "Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe mentioned that he knows that the Sri Lankan people are suffering.",
        "Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe pointed out that Sri Lanka's economy has gone backwards and the economy should be built from the grassroots level again.",
        "Mr. Wickramasinghe said that 5-10 years is not necessary to build Sri Lanka's economy.",
        "Mr. Wickramasinghe mentioned that by the end of next year, it will be possible to stabilize the economy of Sri Lanka and specifically by the year 2024, it will be possible to build a growing economy in Sri Lanka.",
        "CNN News Service reported that Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe stated in the interview that he had spoken to former President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa when he went to Maldives and then to Singapore, but at this time he did not know whether Mr. Rajapaksa was in Singapore or somewhere else."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CNN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5-10 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of next year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year 2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CNN News Service",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ආර්ථික අර්බුදය ගැන පැවති රජය සත්‍ය වසන් කළා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් පැවති රජය සත්‍ය වසන් කළ බව වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සී.එන්.එන් පුවත් සේවය සමඟ පැවති සම්මුඛ සාකච්ඡාවකදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව බංකොලොත් භාවයට පත්ව ඇති බවත් එයින් මිදීමට ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල වෙත යෑමට අවශ්‍ය බවත් හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ රජය වසන් කළ බව වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පැවසුවේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනතාව දුක්විඳින බව තමන් දන්නා බව රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආර්ථිකය ආපස්සට ගොස් ඇති බවත් නැවතත් ආර්ථිකය බිම් මට්ටමේ සිට ගොඩනැගිය යුතු බවත් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා එහිදී පෙන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආර්ථිකය ගොඩ නැගීම සඳහා වසර 5-10 ක කාලයක් අවශ්‍ය නොවන බව වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පැවසුවේය.",
        "ලබන වසර අග වනවිට ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආර්ථිකය ස්ථාවර කිරීමට හැකිවෙනු ඇති බවත් නිශ්චිතවම 2024 වසර වන විට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වර්ධනය වන ආර්ථිකයක් ගොඩ නැගීමට හැකියාව ලැබෙනු ඇති බවත් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා මාලදිවයිනටත් ඉන් පසුව සිංගප්පූරුවටත් ගිය අවස්ථාවේ තමන් කථා බහ කළ බවත් නමුත් මේ අවස්ථාවේදී රාජපක්ෂ මහතා  සිංගප්පූරුවේ සිටින්නේද එසේත් නැතිනම් වෙනත් තැනක සිටින්නේද තමන් නොදන්නා බවත් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සම්මුඛ සාකච්ඡාවේදි ප්‍රකාශ කළ බව සී.එන්.එන් පුවත් සේවය වාර්තා කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීඑන්එන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 5-10",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන වසරේ අවසානය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර 2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CNN පුවත් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி குறித்த உண்மையை அரசாங்கம் மறைத்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி தொடர்பில் அரசாங்கம் உண்மையை மறைத்துள்ளதாக பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க சிஎன்என் தொலைக்காட்சிக்கு வழங்கிய நேர்காணலில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை வங்குரோத்து நிலையை அடைந்துள்ளதாகவும், அதிலிருந்து விடுபட சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்திற்கு செல்ல வேண்டும் என்ற உண்மையை முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் அரசாங்கம் மறைத்துள்ளதாகவும் பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை மக்கள் இன்னல்களை அனுபவித்து வருவதை தமக்கு தெரியும் என திரு.ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரம் பின்னோக்கிச் சென்றுள்ளதாகவும், மீண்டும் அடிமட்டத்தில் இருந்து பொருளாதாரம் கட்டியெழுப்பப்பட வேண்டுமெனவும் திரு.ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரத்தை கட்டியெழுப்ப 5-10 வருடங்கள் அவசியமில்லை என திரு.விக்கிரமசிங்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அடுத்த வருட இறுதிக்குள் இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரத்தை ஸ்திரப்படுத்த முடியும் எனவும் குறிப்பாக 2024 ஆம் ஆண்டளவில் இலங்கையில் வளரும் பொருளாதாரத்தை கட்டியெழுப்ப முடியும் எனவும் விக்கிரமசிங்க குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச மாலைதீவுக்கும் பின்னர் சிங்கப்பூருக்கும் சென்ற போது அவருடன் பேசியதாகவும், ஆனால், ராஜபக்ச சிங்கப்பூரில் உள்ளாரா அல்லது வேறு எங்காவது உள்ளாரா என்பது தனக்குத் தெரியாது எனவும் திரு.ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க அந்த நேர்காணலில் தெரிவித்ததாக சிஎன்என் செய்திச் சேவை தெரிவித்துள்ளது. ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஎன்என்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமாதித்தன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5-10 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமாதித்தன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த ஆண்டு இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024 ஆம் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிஎன்என் செய்தி சேவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}