{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/trade-union-action-caused-125mwh-rs-320-mn-loss-sri-lanka-utility-regulator-96891/",
  "time_ut": 1656936540,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Trade union action caused 125Mwh, Rs 320 mn loss: Sri Lanka utility regulator",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Trade union action caused 125Mwh, Rs 320 mn loss: Sri Lanka utility regulator",
      "author": "Dulya de Silva",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Island-wide unscheduled power cuts due to trade union action caused an estimated 125 megwatt-hour loss of hydroelectricity and a consequent additional cost 320 million rupees, the Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka (PUCSL) said in a report.",
        "A strike by the Ceylon Electricity Board Engineers’ Union (CEBEU) on June 09 caused unscheduled power cuts in many parts of the island. The strike was to oppose proposed amendments to the Sri Lanka Electricity Act, which would end competitive bidding for electricity from the private sector.",
        "The union stated that the main purpose of the amendments would pave the way for the controversial 500MW wind power project by India’s Adani Group.",
        "Amendments to the Act would lead to corruption and high tariffs, the CEBEU had claimed.",
        "Controversy erupts over pricing on unsolicited Adani wind power project",
        "However, President Gotabaya Rajapaksa had made electricity an essential service the previous night, making trade union action illegal under the Essential Services Act and the PUCSL Act.",
        "Sri Lanka’s utility regulator to serve enforcement order on CEB over TU action",
        "The PUCSL report said that due to the CEB’s failure to release water through the Randenigala and Rantambe power plants, an estimated 125Mwh of hydroelectricity was lost.",
        "The report stated that the private Sojitz and Westcoast powerplants had started dispatching electricity presumably due to the lack of hydropower generation. The CEB had made no move to dispatch from “their own more economical oil plants (Sapugaskanda),” the report stated.",
        "This had resulted in an additional cost of 320 million rupees.",
        "Power and Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekara tweeted on Monday July 04 that he had instructed officials to internally investigate the incident and assist the Criminal Investigation Department probe, a day after the incident took place.",
        "The Minister had also instructed for the temporary removal of persons responsible for the incident, and “carry out an impartial inquiry and take appropriate legal steps.”",
        "2) On the 10th of June, I had instructed CEB Chairman & GM to internally investigate the incidents, assist the CID in their investigations & to temporally remove the alleged persons responsible from the positions to carry out an impartial inquiry and take appropriate legal steps.",
        "The PUCSL has also served an enforcement order over the strike.",
        "Critics say that such probes lack transparency and do not lead to meaningful change, and are calling for updates to the probe to be made accessible to the public.",
        "PUCSL Chairman Janaka Rathnayake recently said Sri Lanka would have to diversify its energy mix and bring in renewables soon, or the ongoing power cuts could last up to five years.",
        "Sri Lanka’s power cuts to last up to 5-years without renewables PUCSL claims",
        "The country’s dependency on fossil fuels for power generation means that power cut duration could extend in the near future, with the island’s lack of forex and inflation due to money printing making it difficult to procure fuel.",
        "Sri Lanka is also unable to open up letters of credit (LCs), and according to Wijesekara countries that previously gave extended credit periods are now asking for advance payment.",
        "Already Sri Lankans are being impacted by prolonged power cuts, both scheduled and unscheduled. The PUCSL has requested the public to report any unscheduled cuts, but consumers say that complaints make no difference.",
        "The PUCSL had requested the CEB to conduct an inquiry on its failure to operate power plants, unscheduled power cuts, and the operation of the private power plants on June 09.",
        "The report is to be submitted on or before July 18. (Colombo/Jul04/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "125Mwh",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "320",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "an estimated 125",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "320 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Electricity Board Engineers’ Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEBEU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Electricity Act",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "500MW",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "India’s Adani Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Act",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEBEU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Adani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the previous night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Essential Services Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the PUCSL Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "TU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Randenigala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rantambe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sojitz",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Westcoast",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sapugaskanda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "320 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday July 04",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "a day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 10th of June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Janaka Rathnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "up to five years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5-years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijesekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වෘත්තීය සමිති ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයෙන් මෙගාවොට් 125ක්, රුපියල් මිලියන 320ක පාඩුවක් සිදු විය: ශ්‍රී ලංකා උපයෝගිතා නියාමකයා",
      "author": "දුල්යා ද සිල්වා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - වෘත්තීය සමිති ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයක් හේතුවෙන් දීප ව්‍යාප්ත කාලසටහන් නොකළ විදුලිය කප්පාදුව හේතුවෙන් මෙග්වොට් 125 ක ජල විදුලි අලාභයක් සිදු වූ බව ඇස්තමේන්තු කර ඇති අතර එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස රුපියල් මිලියන 320 ක අමතර වියදමක් දැරීමට සිදු වූ බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව (PUCSL) වාර්තාවක සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩල ඉංජිනේරු සංගමය (CEBEU) විසින් ජුනි 09 වැනි දින දියත් කළ වැඩවර්ජනයක් හේතුවෙන් දිවයිනේ බොහෝ ප්‍රදේශවල නියමිත වේලාවට නොතිබූ විදුලිය විසන්ධි විය. පෞද්ගලික අංශයෙන් විදුලිය සඳහා තරගකාරී ලංසු කැඳවීම අවසන් කරන ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදුලිබල පනතට යෝජිත සංශෝධනවලට විරෝධය පළ කිරීම සඳහා මෙම වර්ජනය ක්‍රියාත්මක විය.",
        "සංශෝධනවල ප්‍රධාන අරමුණ ඉන්දියාවේ අදානි සමූහ ව්‍යාපෘතියේ මතභේදයට තුඩු දී ඇති මෙගාවොට් 500 සුළං බල ව්‍යාපෘතිය සඳහා මග පෑදීම බව එම සංගමය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "පනතේ සංශෝධන දූෂණයට සහ ඉහළ තීරුබදු වලට තුඩු දෙනු ඇති බව ලංවිම ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත.",
        "අනවශ්‍ය Adani සුළං බල ව්‍යාපෘතියේ මිල ගණන් සම්බන්ධයෙන් මතභේදයක් පැන නගී",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය සේවා පනත සහ මහජන උපයෝගිතා පනත යටතේ වෘත්තීය ක්‍රියාමාර්ග නීති විරෝධී කරමින් ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පෙරේදා රාත්‍රියේ විදුලිය අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සේවාවක් බවට පත් කර තිබුණි.",
        "TU ක්‍රියාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් ලංවිම මත බලාත්මක කිරීමේ නියෝගයක් ලබා දීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ උපයෝගිතා නියාමකයා",
        "ලංවිම විසින් රන්දෙණිගල සහ රන්ටැඹේ බලාගාර හරහා ජලය මුදා හැරීමට අපොහොසත් වීම නිසා ඇස්තමේන්තුගත ජල විදුලිය මෙගාවොට් 125 ක් අහිමි වූ බව මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිසමේ වාර්තාව පවසයි.",
        "පෞද්ගලික Sojitz සහ Westcoast බලාගාර මගින් විදුලිය යැවීම ආරම්භ කර ඇත්තේ ජල විදුලි උත්පාදනය නොමැතිකම නිසා විය හැකි බව වාර්තාවේ සඳහන් විය. \"ඔවුන්ගේම වඩාත් ආර්ථිකමය තෙල් කම්හල් (සපුගස්කන්ද)\" වෙතින් යැවීමට ලංවිම කිසිදු පියවරක් ගෙන නොතිබුණි.",
        "මේ නිසා රුපියල් මිලියන 320ක අමතර වියදමක් දැරීමට සිදුවී ඇත.",
        "විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර ජූලි 04 සඳුදා ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ සිද්ධිය සිදුවී දිනකට පසු සිද්ධිය අභ්‍යන්තරව විමර්ශනය කර අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තු පරීක්ෂණයට සහාය වන ලෙස තමා නිලධාරීන්ට උපදෙස් දුන් බවයි.",
        "සිද්ධියට වගකිව යුතු පුද්ගලයන් තාවකාලිකව ඉවත් කරන ලෙසත්, “අපක්ෂපාතී පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වා සුදුසු නීතිමය පියවර ගන්නා ලෙසත්” ඇමැතිවරයා උපදෙස් දී තිබිණි.",
        "2) ජූනි මස 10 වැනි දින ලංවිම සභාපතිවරයාට සහ GM හට මෙම සිද්ධීන් අභ්‍යන්තරව විමර්ශනය කරන ලෙසත්, CID වෙත ඔවුන්ගේ පරීක්ෂණ සඳහා සහය වන ලෙසත්, අපක්ෂපාතී පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වා සුදුසු නීතිමය පියවර ගැනීම සඳහා වගකිව යුතු යැයි කියන පුද්ගලයන් තාවකාලිකව එම තනතුරුවලින් ඉවත් කරන ලෙසත් උපදෙස් ලබා දුනිමි.",
        "PUCSL වර්ජනය සම්බන්ධයෙන් බලාත්මක කිරීමේ නියෝගයක් ද ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "එවැනි පරීක්ෂණ විනිවිද භාවයෙන් තොර බවත් අර්ථවත් වෙනසක් ඇති නොකරන බවත් පවසන විචාරකයින්, විමර්ශනය පිළිබඳ යාවත්කාලීන කිරීම් මහජනතාවට ප්‍රවේශ විය හැකි ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටියි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය බලශක්ති මිශ්‍රණය විවිධාංගීකරණය කර ඉක්මනින් පුනර්ජනනීය ද්‍රව්‍ය ගෙන ඒමට සිදුවනු ඇති බව PUCSL සභාපති ජනක රත්නායක මහතා පසුගියදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදුලි කප්පාදුව පුනර්ජනනීය නොවන PUCSL හිමිකම් නොමැතිව වසර 5ක් දක්වා පවතිනු ඇත",
        "බලශක්ති උත්පාදනය සඳහා රට පොසිල ඉන්ධන මත යැපීම යනු නුදුරු අනාගතයේ දී විදුලිය විසන්ධි කිරීමේ කාලසීමාව දිගු විය හැකි අතර, දිවයිනේ විදේශ විනිමය නොමැතිකම සහ මුදල් මුද්‍රණය හේතුවෙන් උද්ධමනය ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීම දුෂ්කර කරයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ද ණයවර ලිපි (LCs) විවෘත කිරීමට නොහැකි වන අතර විජේසේකර පවසන පරිදි මීට පෙර දීර්ඝ ණය කාල සීමාවක් ලබා දුන් රටවල් දැන් අත්තිකාරම් ගෙවීමට ඉල්ලා සිටී.",
        "දැනටමත් ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් කාලසටහන්ගත සහ කාලසටහන් නොකළ දිගු විදුලි කප්පාදුවකින් පීඩාවට පත්ව සිටී. උපලේඛනගත නොකළ කප්පාදුවක් පිළිබඳව වාර්තා කරන ලෙස මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිසම මහජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින නමුත් පාරිභෝගිකයින් පවසන්නේ පැමිණිලිවල වෙනසක් නොමැති බවයි.",
        "විදුලි බලාගාර ක්‍රියාත්මක නොකිරීම, කාලසටහන් නොකළ විදුලි කප්පාදුව සහ පෞද්ගලික බලාගාරවල ක්‍රියාකාරීත්වය පිළිබඳව ජුනි 09 වැනි දින පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන ලෙස මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිසම විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයෙන් ඉල්ලා තිබුණි.",
        "වාර්තාව ජූලි 18 හෝ ඊට පෙර ඉදිරිපත් කළ යුතුය. (කොළඹ/ජූලි 04/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "125Mwh",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "320",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇස්තමේන්තුගත 125",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 320 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩල ඉංජිනේරු සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEBEU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදුලිබල පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "500MW",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාවේ අදානි සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEBEU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අදානි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙර රාත්‍රියේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය සේවා පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "TU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්දෙණිගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ටැඹේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සොජිට්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර වෙරළ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සපුගස්කන්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 320 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 04 සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි 10 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජානක රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර පහක් දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර 5 ක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தொழிற்சங்க நடவடிக்கையால் 125Mwh, 320 மில்லியன் இழப்பு ஏற்பட்டது: இலங்கை பயன்பாட்டு ஒழுங்குமுறை ஆணையம்",
      "author": "துல்யா டி சில்வா",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – தொழிற்சங்க நடவடிக்கையின் காரணமாக நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் திட்டமிடப்படாத மின்வெட்டு காரணமாக 125 மெகாவாட் மணித்தியால நீர்மின்சார இழப்பு ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் அதன் விளைவாக 320 மில்லியன் ரூபா கூடுதல் செலவை ஏற்படுத்தியதாகவும் இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழு (PUCSL) அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை பொறியியலாளர்கள் சங்கம் (CEBEU) ஜூன் 09 அன்று நடத்திய வேலை நிறுத்தம் காரணமாக தீவின் பல பகுதிகளில் திட்டமிடப்படாத மின்வெட்டு ஏற்பட்டது. தனியார் துறையிடமிருந்து மின்சாரத்திற்கான போட்டி ஏலத்தை நிறுத்தும் இலங்கை மின்சாரச் சட்டத்தில் முன்மொழியப்பட்ட திருத்தங்களை எதிர்த்து இந்த வேலைநிறுத்தம் நடத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "இந்த திருத்தங்களின் முக்கிய நோக்கம் இந்தியாவின் அதானி குழுமத்தின் சர்ச்சைக்குரிய 500 மெகாவாட் காற்றாலை மின் திட்டத்திற்கு வழி வகுக்கும் என்று தொழிற்சங்கம் கூறியது.",
        "சட்டத்தில் திருத்தங்கள் ஊழல் மற்றும் அதிக கட்டணங்களுக்கு வழிவகுக்கும், CEBEU கூறியது.",
        "கோரப்படாத அதானி காற்றாலை மின் திட்டத்திற்கான விலை நிர்ணயம் தொடர்பாக சர்ச்சை வெடித்துள்ளது",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ நேற்று இரவு மின்சாரத்தை அத்தியாவசிய சேவையாக மாற்றினார், அத்தியாவசிய சேவைகள் சட்டம் மற்றும் PUCSL சட்டத்தின் கீழ் தொழிற்சங்க நடவடிக்கைகளை சட்டவிரோதமாக்கினார்.",
        "TU நடவடிக்கை தொடர்பாக CEB மீது அமலாக்க உத்தரவை வழங்க இலங்கையின் பயன்பாட்டு ஒழுங்குமுறை ஆணையம்",
        "ரன்தெனிகல மற்றும் ரன்தம்பே மின் உற்பத்தி நிலையங்களின் ஊடாக CEB தண்ணீரை வெளியிடத் தவறியதன் காரணமாக 125Mwh நீர் மின்சாரம் இழக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக PUCSL அறிக்கை கூறுகிறது.",
        "தனியார் சோஜிட்ஸ் மற்றும் வெஸ்ட்கோஸ்ட் மின் உற்பத்தி நிலையங்கள் நீர்மின் உற்பத்தி இல்லாததால் மின்சாரத்தை அனுப்பத் தொடங்கியுள்ளன என்று அறிக்கை கூறுகிறது. CEB \"அவர்களின் சொந்த பொருளாதார எண்ணெய் ஆலைகளில் (சபுகஸ்கந்த)\" இருந்து அனுப்ப எந்த நடவடிக்கையும் எடுக்கவில்லை என்று அறிக்கை கூறியது.",
        "இதனால் 320 மில்லியன் ரூபா கூடுதல் செலவு ஏற்பட்டது.",
        "மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர ஜூலை 04 திங்கட்கிழமை ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார், சம்பவம் நடந்த ஒரு நாளுக்குப் பிறகு, சம்பவம் குறித்து உள்ளக விசாரணை மற்றும் குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை விசாரணைக்கு உதவுமாறு அதிகாரிகளுக்கு பணிப்புரை விடுத்தேன்.",
        "இந்த சம்பவத்திற்கு காரணமானவர்களை தற்காலிகமாக நீக்கவும், \"பாரபட்சமற்ற விசாரணையை நடத்தி உரிய சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுக்கவும்\" அமைச்சர் அறிவுறுத்தினார்.",
        "2) ஜூன் 10 ஆம் தேதி, CEB தலைவர் மற்றும் GM க்கு, இந்த சம்பவங்களை உள்ளக விசாரணை செய்யவும், CID க்கு அவர்களின் விசாரணையில் உதவவும், பாரபட்சமற்ற விசாரணையை மேற்கொள்வதற்கும், பொறுப்புக் கூறப்படும் நபர்களை தற்காலிகமாக பதவியில் இருந்து நீக்கி, உரிய சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுக்கவும் அறிவுறுத்தினேன்.",
        "வேலைநிறுத்தம் தொடர்பாக PUCSL அமலாக்க ஆணையையும் வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "இத்தகைய ஆய்வுகள் வெளிப்படைத்தன்மையைக் கொண்டிருக்கவில்லை மற்றும் அர்த்தமுள்ள மாற்றத்திற்கு வழிவகுக்காது என்று விமர்சகர்கள் கூறுகின்றனர், மேலும் ஆய்வுக்கான புதுப்பிப்புகளை பொதுமக்களுக்கு அணுகுமாறு கோருகின்றனர்.",
        "PUCSL தலைவர் ஜனக ரத்நாயக்க சமீபத்தில் இலங்கை தனது ஆற்றல் கலவையை பன்முகப்படுத்த வேண்டும் மற்றும் புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்கவைகளை விரைவில் கொண்டு வர வேண்டும், அல்லது தற்போதைய மின்வெட்டு ஐந்து ஆண்டுகள் வரை நீடிக்கும் என்று கூறினார்.",
        "PUCSL உரிமைகோரல்கள் இல்லாமல் இலங்கையின் மின்வெட்டு 5 ஆண்டுகள் வரை நீடிக்கும்",
        "மின் உற்பத்திக்காக புதைபடிவ எரிபொருட்களை நாடு நம்பியிருப்பதன் அர்த்தம், எதிர்காலத்தில் மின்வெட்டு காலம் நீட்டிக்கப்படலாம், தீவின் அந்நிய செலாவணி பற்றாக்குறை மற்றும் பணம் அச்சிடுதல் காரணமாக பணவீக்கம் ஆகியவை எரிபொருளை வாங்குவதை கடினமாக்குகிறது.",
        "இலங்கையால் கடன் கடிதங்களை (LCs) திறக்க முடியவில்லை, மேலும் விஜேசேகரவின் கூற்றுப்படி, முன்னர் நீட்டிக்கப்பட்ட கடன் காலங்களை வழங்கிய நாடுகள் இப்போது முன்கூட்டியே பணம் கேட்கின்றன.",
        "ஏற்கனவே திட்டமிடப்பட்ட மற்றும் திட்டமிடப்படாத நீண்ட மின்வெட்டுகளால் இலங்கையர்கள் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர். PUCSL, திட்டமிடப்படாத வெட்டுக்களைப் பற்றிப் புகாரளிக்குமாறு பொதுமக்களைக் கேட்டுக் கொண்டுள்ளது, ஆனால் புகார்கள் எந்த மாற்றத்தையும் ஏற்படுத்தாது என்று நுகர்வோர் கூறுகின்றனர்.",
        "மின் உற்பத்தி நிலையங்களை இயக்கத் தவறியமை, திட்டமிடப்படாத மின்வெட்டு மற்றும் தனியார் மின் உற்பத்தி நிலையங்களின் செயல்பாடுகள் குறித்து ஜூன் 09 அன்று விசாரணை நடத்துமாறு PUCSL CEBயிடம் கோரியிருந்தது.",
        "அறிக்கை ஜூலை 18 அல்லது அதற்கு முன் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட வேண்டும். (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை04/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "125Mwh",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "320",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "125 என மதிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "320 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை பொறியியலாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEBEU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "500மெகாவாட்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியாவின் அதானி குழுமம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாடகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEBEU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அதானி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "அத்தியாவசிய சேவைகள் சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "TU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரந்தெனிகல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரண்டாம்பே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சோஜிட்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெஸ்ட்கோஸ்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சபுகஸ்கந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "320 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 04 திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 10 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனக ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து ஆண்டுகள் வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}