{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/නිමල්-සිරිපාල-සම්බන්ධයෙන්-අල්ලස්-විමර්ශනයක්/101-618154",
  "time_ut": 1660564715,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "නිමල් සිරිපාල සම්බන්ධයෙන් අල්ලස් විමර්ශනයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A bribery investigation regarding Nimal Siripala",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Bribery or Corruption Allegations Investigation Commission started an investigation today (15) regarding the bribery charge leveled against Minister Nimal Siripala de Silva.",
        "The Commission has started this investigation based on a complaint made by the Anti-Corruption Front.",
        "Accordingly, a spokesperson of the commission told Lankadeepa that a statement is to be recorded from Minister Nimal Siripala de Silva in the future.",
        "The allegation was related to an incident where a bribe was demanded from the Japanese company Taisei, which is carrying out the construction work of Katunayake Airport.",
        "In this regard, the Bribery or Corruption Allegations Investigation Commission hopes to inquire from the representatives of that company as well as from the officials of the Japanese Embassy in Sri Lanka in the future.",
        "When the allegation was made, Minister Nimal Siripala de Silva resigned from the ministry as a measure to allow an independent investigation to be conducted.",
        "After that, President Ranil Wickramasinghe appointed a three-member committee headed by retired High Court Judge Mrs. Kusala Sarojani Weerawardena to investigate the allegation and Mr. Nimal Siripala Silva was acquitted of the bribery charge and the report of that committee was released recently.",
        "Accordingly, Mr. Nimal Siripala de Silva was recently re-appointed to the post of Minister of Ports, Shipping and Aviation by President Ranil Wickramasinghe."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Nimal Siripala",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Anti-Corruption Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lankadeepa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taisei",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kusala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ports",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නිමල් සිරිපාල සම්බන්ධයෙන් අල්ලස් විමර්ශනයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අමාත්‍ය නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා මහතාට එරෙහිව  එල්ලවූ අල්ලස් චෝදනාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් අල්ලස් හෝ දූෂණ චෝදනා විමර්ශන කොමිෂන් සභාව අද (15) විමර්ශනයක් ආරම්භ කළේය.",
        "කොමිසම මේ  විමර්ශනය අරඹා ඇත්තේ  දූෂණ විරෝධී පෙරමුණ විසින් කරන ලද පැමිණිල්ලක් අනුවය.",
        "මේ අනුව මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් අමාත්‍ය නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා මහතාගෙන්ද  ඉදිරියේදී ප්‍රකාශයක් සටහන් කර ගැනීමට නියමිතව ඇතැයි එම කොමිසමේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙක්  ලංකාදීපයට පැවැසීය.",
        "කටුනායක ගුවන්තොටුපොළ  ඉදිකිරීම් කටයුතු සිදු කරන ජපානයේ  තායිසේ  සමාගමෙන්  අල්ලස් මුදලක් ඉල්ලා ඇතැයි කියන සිද්ධියක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් එම  චෝදනාව එල්ලවී  තිබුණේය.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් එම සමාගමේ නියෝජිතයන්ගෙන් මෙන්ම  ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජපාන තානාපති කාර්යාලයේ  නිලධාරීන්ගෙන්ද ඉදිරියේදී කරුණු විමසීමට අල්ලස් හෝ දූෂණ චෝදනා විමර්ශන කොමිෂන් සභාව බලාපොරොත්තු",
        "මේ පිළිබඳ  චෝදනාව එල්ල වූ අවස්ථාවේදී  ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් ස්වාධීන පරීක්ෂණයක් පැවැත්වීමට ඉඩකඩ ලබාදීමේ පියවරක් ලෙස  අමාත්‍ය නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා මහතා එම  අමාත්‍යධූරයෙන්   ඉල්ලා අස්විය.",
        "ඉන් අනතුරුව ඒ චෝදනාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමර්ශන පැවැත්වීමට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් විශ්‍රාමික මහාධිකරණ විනිසුරු කුසලා සරෝජනී වීරවර්ධන  මහත්මියගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් යුත් ත්‍රිපුද්ගල කමිටුවක් පත්කෙරුණු අතර  නිමල් සිරිපාල සිල්වා මහතා එම අල්ලස් චෝදනා චෝදනාවෙන් නිදහස් කරමින්  ඒ කමිටු වාර්තාව පසුගියදා නිකුත් කෙරිණ.",
        "ඒ අනුව නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා මහතා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් වරාය නාවික සහ ගුවන් සේවා අමාත්‍ය ධූරයට පසුගියදා  නැවතත් පත් කරනු ලැබීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දූෂණ විරෝධී පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකාදීප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටයිසේයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුසල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වරායන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நிமல் சிறிபால தொடர்பில் இலஞ்ச ஊழல் விசாரணை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அமைச்சர் நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வாவுக்கு எதிராக சுமத்தப்பட்டுள்ள இலஞ்ச குற்றச்சாட்டு தொடர்பில் இலஞ்ச ஊழல் விசாரணை ஆணைக்குழு இன்று (15) விசாரணைகளை ஆரம்பித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஊழல் எதிர்ப்பு முன்னணியின் புகாரின் அடிப்படையில் ஆணையம் இந்த விசாரணையை தொடங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி, எதிர்காலத்தில் அமைச்சர் நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வாவிடம் வாக்குமூலம் பதிவு செய்யப்பட உள்ளதாக ஆணைக்குழுவின் பேச்சாளர் லங்காதீபவிடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையத்தின் நிர்மாணப் பணிகளை மேற்கொள்ளும் ஜப்பானிய நிறுவனமான Taisei நிறுவனத்திடம் இலஞ்சம் கோரப்பட்ட சம்பவம் தொடர்பிலேயே இந்த குற்றச்சாட்டு முன்வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இது தொடர்பில், எதிர்காலத்தில் அந்த நிறுவனத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகளிடமும், இலங்கையில் உள்ள ஜப்பானிய தூதரக அதிகாரிகளிடமும் விசாரணை நடத்த இலஞ்ச ஊழல் குற்றச்சாட்டு விசாரணை ஆணைக்குழு எதிர்பார்க்கிறது.",
        "குற்றச்சாட்டு முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட போது, ​​சுதந்திரமான விசாரணையை நடத்த அனுமதிக்கும் நடவடிக்கையாக அமைச்சர் நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா தனது அமைச்சுப் பதவியை இராஜினாமா செய்தார்.",
        "அதன் பின்னர் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இந்த குற்றச்சாட்டை விசாரிப்பதற்காக ஓய்வுபெற்ற மேல் நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதி திருமதி குசலா சரோஜனி வீரவர்தன தலைமையில் மூவரடங்கிய குழுவொன்றை நியமித்ததோடு திரு நிமல் சிறிபால சில்வா இலஞ்சக் குற்றச்சாட்டில் இருந்து விடுவிக்கப்பட்டு அந்தக் குழுவின் அறிக்கை அண்மையில் வெளியிடப்பட்டது.",
        "இதன்படி, திரு.நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா அண்மையில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் துறைமுகங்கள், கப்பல் போக்குவரத்து மற்றும் விமானப் போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சராக மீண்டும் நியமிக்கப்பட்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊழல் எதிர்ப்பு முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லங்காதீப",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தைசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குசலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறைமுகங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}