{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131175",
  "time_ut": 1657380391,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "கொட்டகலை, தலவாக்கலையில் ஜனாதிபதியை பதவி விலகக்கோரி  போராட்டங்கள் முன்னெடுப்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Protests are taking place in Kotakalai and Thalawakalai demanding the resignation of the President",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "Protests were also carried out in Thalawakalai and Kotakalai today demanding the resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa.",
        "Shops were closed in the said cities and traders also extended their support to the people's protest.",
        "Civil society activists, youth, tricycle drivers joined the protest.",
        "Also, a branch of Kota Ko Gama also sprung up in Thalawakkala town. The Kota Ko Kama branch has been formed to continue the protest until the President and the government headed by him resign.",
        "Many people living in Thalawakalai and its surrounding areas participated in the protest and supported the ongoing protest in Colombo.",
        "Meanwhile, in Kotakalai city, city traders, civil society activists, youth, teachers and children participated in the protest."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kotakalai",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Thalawakalai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kotakalai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kota Ko Gama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thalawakkala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kota Ko Kama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thalawakalai",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kotakalai",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපතිවරයාට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බලකරමින් කොටකාලෙයි සහ තලවාකාලෙයි යන ප්‍රදේශවල මේ වනවිට විරෝධතා පැවැත්වෙනවා",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බලකරමින් තලවාකාලෙයි සහ කොටකාලෙයි යන ප්‍රදේශවලද අද විරෝධතා පැවැත්වුණා.",
        "එම නගරවල කඩසාප්පු වසා දමා තිබූ අතර වෙළෙඳුන් ද ජනතා විරෝධයට සහාය පළ කළහ.",
        "සිවිල් සමාජ ක්‍රියාකාරීන්, තරුණයින්, ත්‍රිරෝද රථ රියදුරන් මෙම විරෝධතාවයට එක්ව සිටියා.",
        "ඒ වගේම කොට කෝ ගම ශාඛාවක් තලවක්කල නගරයේත් ඇති වුණා. කොට කෝ කමා ශාඛාව පිහිටුවා ඇත්තේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ ඔහු ප්‍රමුඛ රජය ඉල්ලා අස්වන තුරු විරෝධතාව පවත්වාගෙන යාම සඳහාය.",
        "මෙම විරෝධතාවයට තලවාකලෙයි සහ ඒ අවට ප්‍රදේශවල පදිංචි බොහෝ පිරිසක් සහභාගී වූ අතර කොළඹ පැවති විරෝධතාවට සහය පළ කළහ.",
        "මේ අතර, කොටකාලෙයි නගරයේ පැවති විරෝධතාවයට නගර වෙළෙන්දෝ, සිවිල් සමාජ ක්‍රියාකාරීන්, තරුණයින්, ගුරුවරුන්, ළමුන් ඇතුළු පිරිසක් එක්ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කොටකාලයි",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තලවකාලයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටකාලයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොට කෝ ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලවක්කල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොට කෝ කාමා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තලවකාලයි",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොටකාලයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கொட்டகலை, தலவாக்கலையில் ஜனாதிபதியை பதவி விலகக்கோரி  போராட்டங்கள் முன்னெடுப்பு",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ பதவி விலக வேண்டும் என வலியுறுத்தி தலவாக்கலை மற்றும் கொட்டகலை நகரிலும் இன்று போராட்டம் முன்னெடுக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "குறித்த நகரங்களில் கடைகள் மூடப்பட்டு, மக்கள் போராட்டத்துக்கு வர்த்தகர்களும் தமது ஆதரவு வழங்கினர்.",
        "சிவில் சமூக செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள், இளைஞர்கள், முச்சரக்கரவண்டி ஓட்டுநர்கள் என பல தரப்பினரும் போராட்டத்தில் குதித்தனர்.",
        "அத்துடன், கோட்டா கோ கம கிளையொன்றும் தலவாக்கலை நகரில் உதயமானது. ஜனாதிபதியும், அவர் தலைமையிலான அரசும் பதவி விலகும்வரை போராட்டத்தை தொடரும் வகையிலேயே கோட்டா கோ கம கிளை உருவாக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "தலவாக்கலையையும், அதனை சூழவுள்ள பகுதிகளில் வாழும் பலர் போராட்டத்தில் பங்கேற்று, கொழும்பில் முன்னெடுக்கப்பட்டுவரும் போராட்டத்துக்கு ஆதரவை வழங்கினர்.",
        "இதேவேளை, கொட்டகலை நகரிலும், நகர வர்த்தகர்கள், சிவில் சமூக செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள், இளைஞர்கள், ஆசிரியர்கள், சிறுவர்கள் என பலரும் கலந்து கொண்டு போராட்டத்தை முன்னெடுத்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கொட்டகலை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தலைவாக்கலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொட்டகலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டா கோ காமா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலவாக்கலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டா கோ காமா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தலைவாக்கலை",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொட்டகலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}