{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/23/turkiye-donates-emergency-medicine-and-medical-supplies-to-the-government-of-sri-lanka/",
  "time_ut": 1661220360,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Turkiye Donates Emergency Medicine and Medical Supplies to the Government of Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Turkiye Donates Emergency Medicine and Medical Supplies to the Government of Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Government of Turkiye donated USD one million worth of emergency medicines and other medical supplies which are urgently required by the hospitals in Sri Lanka.",
        "The first consignment which includes Filgasstrin injections was airlifted to Sri Lanka and was received by the officials of the Ministry of Health of Sri Lanka on 14 August 2022.",
        "Ambassador of Sri Lanka to Turkiye M.Rizvi Hassen during his meeting with the Minister of Foreign Affairs of Turkiye Mevlut Cavusoglu and the Chairman of Turkiye – Sri Lanka Parliamentarian Friendship Group Ahmet Hamdi Camli on 17 August 2022 thanked and expressed gratitude to the President of the Republic of Turkiye Recep Tayyip Erdogan and the Government of Turkiye for the generous donation and the solidarity extended to the Government and people of Sri Lanka.",
        "The two containers of other medicines and medical supplies left the Izmit Sea Port, Turkiye on 17 August 2022 and are expected to reach the Colombo Port by mid-September 2022.",
        "The donation was a result of a request made by Ambassador Hassen during his meeting with the Chairman of Turkiye – Sri Lanka Parliamentarian Friendship Group Ahmet Hamdi Camli and senior officials of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Turkiye in May 2022 to brief about the situation in Sri Lanka with a request to consider assisting the health sector of Sri Lanka.",
        "Subsequently, the Ministry of Health of Turkiye coordinated with the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Turkiye and expedited the dispatch of the medical consignment with the approval of the President of the Republic of Turkiye, Recep Tayyip Erdogan.",
        "Turkiye Donates Emergency Medicine and Medical Supplies to the Government of Sri Lanka",
        "SLPP wants protection & facilities for Gotabaya, upon his return to Sri Lanka"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Government of Turkiye",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Filgasstrin",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Health of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Turkiye",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Turkiye",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hamdi Camli",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Republic of Turkiye",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Turkiye",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "mid-September 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hassen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Turkiye",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hamdi Camli",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Turkiye",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Health of Turkiye",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Turkiye",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Republic of Turkiye",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Recep Tayyip Erdogan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තුර්කියේ හදිසි ඖෂධ සහ වෛද්‍ය සැපයුම් ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයට පරිත්‍යාග කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); තුර්කියේ රජය විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රෝහල්වලට කඩිනමින් අවශ්‍ය වන ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියනයක් වටිනා හදිසි ඖෂධ සහ අනෙකුත් වෛද්‍ය සැපයුම් පරිත්‍යාග කරන ලදී.",
        "Filgasstrin එන්නත් ඇතුළත් පළමු තොගය ගුවන් මගින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ගෙන එන ලද අතර එය 2022 අගෝස්තු 14 වන දින ශ්‍රී ලංකා සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශයේ නිලධාරීන් විසින් භාර ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "තුර්කියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති M.Rizvi Hassen මහතා 2022 අගෝස්තු 17 වන දින තුර්කියේ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය Mevlut Cavusoglu මහතා සහ තුර්කියේ - ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තු මිත්‍රත්ව කණ්ඩායමේ සභාපති Ahmet Hamdi Camli මහතා හමුවූ අවස්ථාවේදී 2022 අගෝස්තු 17 වන දින ජනාධිපතිතුමා වෙත ස්තුතිය පුද කළේය. තුර්කියේ ජනරජය රිසෙප් තායිප් එර්ඩෝගන් සහ තුර්කියේ රජය ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයට සහ ජනතාවට ත්‍යාගශීලී පරිත්‍යාග සහ සහයෝගීතාවය ලබා දුන්හ.",
        "වෙනත් ඖෂධ සහ වෛද්‍ය සැපයුම් බහාලුම් දෙක 2022 අගෝස්තු 17 වන දින තුර්කියේ ඉස්මිත් මුහුදු වරායෙන් පිටත් වූ අතර 2022 සැප්තැම්බර් මැද වන විට කොළඹ වරායට ළඟා වීමට අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "මෙම පරිත්‍යාගය 2022 මැයි මාසයේදී තුර්කියේ - ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තු මිත්‍රත්ව කණ්ඩායමේ සභාපති අහමට් හම්ඩි කැම්ලි සහ තුර්කියේ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරීන් සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව දැනුවත් කිරීම සඳහා තානාපති හසන් විසින් කරන ලද ඉල්ලීමක ප්‍රතිඵලයකි. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සෞඛ්‍ය අංශයට සහාය වීම ගැන සලකා බලන ලෙස ඉල්ලීමක් සමඟින් ලංකාව.",
        "පසුව, තුර්කියේ සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය තුර්කියේ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය සමඟ සම්බන්ධීකරණය කර තුර්කියේ ජනරජයේ ජනාධිපති රෙසෙප් තායිප් එර්ඩෝගන්ගේ අනුමැතිය ඇතිව වෛද්‍ය තොගය යැවීම කඩිනම් කරන ලදී.",
        "තුර්කියේ හදිසි ඖෂධ සහ වෛද්‍ය සැපයුම් ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයට පරිත්‍යාග කරයි",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණට ගෝඨාභය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමෙන් පසු ආරක්ෂාව සහ පහසුකම් අවශ්‍යයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුර්කියේ රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆිල්ගස්ස්ට්රින්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුර්කියේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුර්කියේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්ඩි කැම්ලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුර්කියේ ජනරජය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුර්කියේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 සැප්තැම්බර් මැද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හසන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුර්කියේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්ඩි කැම්ලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුර්කියේ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුර්කියේ සෞඛ්ය අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුර්කියේ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුර්කියේ ජනරජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Recep Tayyip Erdogan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "துர்க்கியே இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்திற்கு அவசரகால மருந்து மற்றும் மருத்துவ பொருட்களை நன்கொடையாக வழங்குகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); துருக்கிய அரசாங்கம் இலங்கையிலுள்ள வைத்தியசாலைகளுக்கு அவசரமாகத் தேவைப்படும் ஒரு மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர் பெறுமதியான அவசரகால மருந்துகள் மற்றும் ஏனைய மருத்துவப் பொருட்களை நன்கொடையாக வழங்கியது.",
        "Filgasstrin ஊசிகளை உள்ளடக்கிய முதலாவது சரக்கு விமானம் மூலம் இலங்கைக்கு கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்டது மற்றும் 14 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022 அன்று இலங்கை சுகாதார அமைச்சின் அதிகாரிகளால் பெறப்பட்டது.",
        "துருக்கிக்கான இலங்கைத் தூதுவர் M.Rizvi Hassen அவர்கள் துர்க்கியே வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் Mevlut Cavusoglu மற்றும் துர்க்கியே - இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்ற நட்புறவுக் குழுவின் தலைவர் Ahmet Hamdi Camli ஆகியோரை 2022 ஆகஸ்ட் 17 அன்று சந்தித்தபோது ஜனாதிபதிக்கு நன்றியும் நன்றியும் தெரிவித்தார். தாராளமான நன்கொடை மற்றும் இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்திற்கும் மக்களுக்கும் வழங்கிய ஒற்றுமைக்காக துருக்கியே குடியரசு குடியரசு மற்றும் துருக்கிய அரசாங்கம்.",
        "மற்ற மருந்துகள் மற்றும் மருத்துவப் பொருட்கள் அடங்கிய இரண்டு கொள்கலன்கள் 17 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022 அன்று துருக்கியிலுள்ள இஸ்மித் கடல் துறைமுகத்தில் இருந்து புறப்பட்டு 2022 செப்டம்பர் நடுப்பகுதியில் கொழும்பு துறைமுகத்தை வந்தடையும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு மே மாதம் துர்க்கியே - இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்ற நட்புறவுக் குழுவின் தலைவர் அஹ்மத் ஹம்டி காம்லி மற்றும் துருக்கியின் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் சிரேஷ்ட அதிகாரிகளை சந்தித்து இலங்கையின் நிலைமையை விளக்குவதற்காக தூதுவர் ஹசன் விடுத்த வேண்டுகோளின் விளைவாக இந்த நன்கொடை வழங்கப்பட்டது. இலங்கையின் சுகாதாரத் துறைக்கு உதவுவது குறித்து பரிசீலிக்க வேண்டும் என்ற கோரிக்கையுடன் இலங்கை.",
        "அதைத் தொடர்ந்து, துருக்கியின் சுகாதார அமைச்சகம் துருக்கியின் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகத்துடன் ஒருங்கிணைத்து, துருக்கி குடியரசுத் தலைவர் ரெசெப் தையிப் எர்டோகனின் ஒப்புதலுடன் மருத்துவச் சரக்குகளை அனுப்புவதை விரைவுபடுத்தியது.",
        "துர்க்கியே இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்திற்கு அவசரகால மருந்து மற்றும் மருத்துவ பொருட்களை நன்கொடையாக வழங்குகிறார்",
        "கோட்டாபய இலங்கை திரும்பியதும் அவருக்கு பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் வசதிகளை SLPP விரும்புகிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துருக்கிய அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபில்காஸ்ட்ரின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் சுகாதார அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துருக்கியே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "துருக்கியே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்டி காம்லி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துருக்கியே குடியரசு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "துருக்கியே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 செப்டம்பர் நடுப்பகுதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹாசன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "துருக்கியே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்டி காம்லி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "துருக்கியின் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துருக்கியின் சுகாதார அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துருக்கியின் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துருக்கியே குடியரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரெசெப் தயிப் எர்டோகன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}