{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-extends-expiry-date-of-pfizer-covid-19-vaccine-by-3-months-on-who-advice-97952/",
  "time_ut": 1658919120,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka extends expiry date of Pfizer Covid-19 vaccine by 3 months on WHO advice",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka extends expiry date of Pfizer Covid-19 vaccine by 3 months on WHO advice",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT –  Sri Lanka’s Health Ministry has extended the expiry date of the Pfizer Covid 19 vaccines already imported by three months on the recommendation of World Health Organization (WHO), Health Ministry said.",
        "Ministry of Health in a statement said the Director of Regulation and Prequalification Department of WHO has communicated to the Director of the UNICEF Supply Division that the shelf life of the Pfizer BioNtech vaccine with unopened vials stored at temperatures between -90 to -60 degree Celsius.has been recommended to extended to 12 months from the earlier 9 months.",
        "Upon the recommendation, the Ministry has officially extended the Pfizer vaccines vials received under FN 5436, FN 2898, FM 9281 and FM 5450 batches till 31.10.2022 from the initial date of expiry of 31.07.2022.",
        "Sri Lanka has bought 18 million Pfizer vials as normal and booster doses. The Health Ministry has already recommended for people above 20 years to have the 2nd booster amid a lukewarm response from the public. The government officials have raised concerns of millions of balance vaccines expiring by end of this month.",
        "In the initial phase, health authorities vaccinated 17.1 million people with the first dose mainly with Chinese Sinopharm and 14.5 million people have been administered with the second dose.",
        "The booster dose was only administered to 8 million people and the second booster dose has been administered to only 15,280 so far.",
        "Sri Lanka has seen a spike in the Covid-19 cases and deaths again since early this month, after relaxation of health restrictions. The health officials have now urged the public to wear masks again in indoor events as well as when traveling in public transport.",
        "The fourth dose is still being administered in all national hospitals and Medical Officer of Health (MOH) offices in all areas. (Colombo/July 26/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3 months",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "WHO",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Health Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "World Health Organization",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Health Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Regulation and Prequalification Department of WHO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the UNICEF Supply Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "-60 degree",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the earlier 9 months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FN 5436",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FN 2898",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FM 5450",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "31.10.2022",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "31.07.2022",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 million Pfizer",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Health Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "millions",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "end of this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17.1 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese Sinopharm",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14.5 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "8 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "only 15,280",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "early this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "fourth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානයේ උපදෙස් මත ශ්‍රී ලංකාව Pfizer Covid-19 එන්නතෙහි කල් ඉකුත් වීමේ දිනය මාස 3කින් දීර්ඝ කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානයේ (WHO) නිර්දේශය මත ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය විසින් දැනටමත් ආනයනය කර ඇති Pfizer Covid 19 එන්නත්වල කල් ඉකුත්වන දිනය මාස තුනකින් දීර්ඝ කර ඇති බව සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි.",
        "සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ WHO හි නියාමන සහ පූර්ව සුදුසුකම් අධ්‍යක්ෂවරයා UNICEF සැපයුම් අංශයේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ වෙත දන්වා ඇත්තේ සෙල්සියස් අංශක -90 ත් -60 ත් අතර උෂ්ණත්වයකදී ගබඩා කර ඇති විවෘත නොකළ කුප්පි සහිත Pfizer BioNtech එන්නතෙහි ආයු කාලය බවයි. කලින් මාස 9 සිට මාස 12 දක්වා දීර්ඝ කිරීමට නිර්දේශ කර ඇත.",
        "නිර්දේශය මත, අමාත්‍යාංශය විසින් FN 5436, FN 2898, FM 9281 සහ FM 5450 කාණ්ඩ යටතේ ලැබුණු Pfizer එන්නත් කුප්පි 2022.07.31 දින කල් ඉකුත්වන ආරම්භක දිනයේ සිට 2022.10.31 දක්වා නිල වශයෙන් දීර්ඝ කර ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සාමාන්‍ය සහ බූස්ටර මාත්‍රා ලෙස Pfizer කුප්පි මිලියන 18ක් මිලදී ගෙන ඇත. මහජනතාවගේ ඇල්මැරුණු ප්‍රතිචාර මධ්‍යයේ සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය අවුරුදු 20 ට වැඩි පුද්ගලයින් සඳහා 2 වන බූස්ටරය ලබා ගැනීමට දැනටමත් නිර්දේශ කර ඇත. මෙම මාසය අවසන් වන විට මිලියන ගණනක ඉතිරි එන්නත් කල් ඉකුත්වීම පිළිබඳ රජයේ නිලධාරීන් කනස්සල්ල මතු කර ඇත.",
        "මූලික අදියරේදී සෞඛ්‍ය බලධාරීන් විසින් පළමු මාත්‍රාවෙන් මිලියන 17.1කට ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් Chinese Sinopharm එන්නත ලබා දුන් අතර මිලියන 14.5ක පිරිසකට දෙවන මාත්‍රාව ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "බූස්ටර මාත්‍රාව මිලියන 8 කට පමණක් ලබා දී ඇති අතර දෙවන බූස්ටර මාත්‍රාව මේ වන විට ලබා දී ඇත්තේ 15,280 කට පමණි.",
        "සෞඛ්‍ය සීමාවන් ලිහිල් කිරීමෙන් පසු මේ මස මුල සිට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව Covid-19 රෝගීන් සහ මරණවල වැඩිවීමක් දැක තිබේ. ගෘහස්ථ උත්සවවලදී මෙන්ම පොදු ප්‍රවාහන සේවයේ ගමන් කිරීමේදී නැවත මුහුණු ආවරණ පැළඳිය යුතු බව සෞඛ්‍ය නිලධාරීන් දැන් ජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා තිබේ.",
        "සිව්වන මාත්‍රාව තවමත් සෑම ප්‍රදේශයකම සියලුම ජාතික රෝහල්වල සහ සෞඛ්‍ය වෛද්‍ය නිලධාරී කාර්යාලවල (MOH) පරිපාලනය කෙරේ. (කොළඹ/ජූලි 26/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "මාස 3 යි",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "කවුද",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක සෞඛ්ය සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්ය අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WHO හි නියාමනය සහ පූර්ව සුදුසුකම් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුනිසෙෆ් සැපයුම් අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "- අංශක 60",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස 12 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කලින් මාස 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FN 5436",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FN 2898",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එෆ්එම් 5450",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022.10.31",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022.07.31",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 18 ෆයිසර්",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම මාසයේ අවසානය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 17.1 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන සිනෝෆාම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 14.5 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 8 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,280 ක් පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ මස මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හතරවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "WHO ஆலோசனையின் பேரில் இலங்கை Pfizer Covid-19 தடுப்பூசியின் காலாவதி தேதியை 3 மாதங்களுக்கு நீட்டித்தது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT -  உலக சுகாதார அமைப்பின் (WHO) பரிந்துரையின் பேரில், இலங்கையின் சுகாதார அமைச்சு ஏற்கனவே இறக்குமதி செய்யப்பட்ட Pfizer Covid 19 தடுப்பூசிகளின் காலாவதி தேதியை மூன்று மாதங்களுக்கு நீட்டித்துள்ளது, சுகாதார அமைச்சகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "WHO இன் ஒழுங்குமுறை மற்றும் முன் தகுதித் துறையின் இயக்குநர் யுனிசெஃப் வழங்கல் பிரிவின் இயக்குநருக்குத் தகவல் தெரிவித்துள்ளதாக சுகாதார அமைச்சகம் ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. 9 மாதங்களில் இருந்து 12 மாதங்களுக்கு நீட்டிக்க பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பரிந்துரையின் பேரில், FN 5436, FN 2898, FM 9281 மற்றும் FM 5450 தொகுதிகளின் கீழ் பெறப்பட்ட ஃபைசர் தடுப்பூசி குப்பிகளை 31.07.2022 முதல் காலாவதியாகும் தேதியிலிருந்து 31.10.2022 வரை அமைச்சகம் அதிகாரப்பூர்வமாக நீட்டித்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை 18 மில்லியன் ஃபைசர் குப்பிகளை சாதாரண மற்றும் பூஸ்டர் டோஸ்களாக வாங்கியுள்ளது. பொதுமக்களின் மந்தமான வரவேற்பிற்கு மத்தியில் 20 வயதுக்கு மேற்பட்டவர்கள் 2வது பூஸ்டரை வைத்திருக்க சுகாதார அமைச்சகம் ஏற்கனவே பரிந்துரை செய்துள்ளது. இந்த மாத இறுதிக்குள் மில்லியன் கணக்கான பேலன்ஸ் தடுப்பூசிகள் காலாவதியாகிவிடும் என்ற கவலையை அரசு அதிகாரிகள் எழுப்பியுள்ளனர்.",
        "ஆரம்ப கட்டத்தில், சுகாதார அதிகாரிகள் 17.1 மில்லியன் மக்களுக்கு முதல் டோஸுடன் முக்கியமாக சீன சினோஃபார்முடன் தடுப்பூசி போட்டனர் மற்றும் 14.5 மில்லியன் மக்களுக்கு இரண்டாவது டோஸ் கொடுக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "பூஸ்டர் டோஸ் 8 மில்லியன் மக்களுக்கு மட்டுமே வழங்கப்பட்டது மற்றும் இரண்டாவது பூஸ்டர் டோஸ் இதுவரை 15,280 பேருக்கு மட்டுமே வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சுகாதாரக் கட்டுப்பாடுகள் தளர்த்தப்பட்ட பின்னர், இந்த மாத தொடக்கத்தில் இருந்து இலங்கை மீண்டும் கொவிட்-19 வழக்குகள் மற்றும் இறப்புகளின் அதிகரிப்பைக் கண்டுள்ளது. உட்புற நிகழ்வுகள் மற்றும் பொது போக்குவரத்தில் பயணம் செய்யும் போது மீண்டும் முகமூடிகளை அணியுமாறு சுகாதார அதிகாரிகள் இப்போது பொதுமக்களை வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளனர்.",
        "நான்காவது டோஸ் இன்னும் அனைத்து தேசிய மருத்துவமனைகள் மற்றும் அனைத்து பகுதிகளிலும் உள்ள சுகாதார மருத்துவ அதிகாரி (MOH) அலுவலகங்களில் நிர்வகிக்கப்படுகிறது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை 26/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3 மாதங்கள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "WHO",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வேர்ல்ட் ஹெல்த் ஆர்கனைசேஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WHO இன் ஒழுங்குமுறை மற்றும் முன் தகுதித் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNICEF விநியோக பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "-60 டிகிரி",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய 9 மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FN 5436",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FN 2898",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FM 5450",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "31.10.2022",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "31.07.2022",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 மில்லியன் ஃபைசர்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 வருடங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மில்லியன்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாத இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17.1 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன சினோபார்ம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14.5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "8 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,280 மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாத தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்காவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}