{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-local-currency-rating-under-observation-fitch-97446/",
  "time_ut": 1657850400,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka local currency rating under observation: Fitch",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka local currency rating under observation: Fitch",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Fitch Ratings has placed Sri Lanka’s local currency rating ‘Under Criteria Observation’ (UCO) following shift in policy to apply + and – modifiers to the agency’s CCC ratings.",
        "Sri Lanka’s long term foreign currency rating has been downgraded to RD but its long term rupee rating is at ‘CCC’.",
        "“The UCO assignment indicates that ratings may change as a direct result of the final criteria,” Fitch said.",
        "“It does not indicate a change in the underlying credit profile, nor does it affect existing Outlooks.",
        "“We will resolve the UCO status within six months. The outcomes will depend on Fitch’s assessment of the appropriate notching based on the new criteria.”",
        "Fitch places Sri Lanka UCO after publication of finaal sovereign rating criteria",
        "Fitch Ratings – Hong Kong – 14 Jul 2022: Fitch Ratings has placed Sri Lanka’s Long-Term Local-Currency Issuer Default Rating (IDR) and associated instruments Under Criteria Observation (UCO) following the conversion of the agency’s Exposure Draft: Sovereign Rating Criteria to final criteria.",
        "A summary of the changes introduced by the new criteria is available at: Fitch Ratings Publishes Final Sovereign Rating Criteria",
        "The UCO assignment indicates that ratings may change as a direct result of the final criteria. It does not indicate a change in the underlying credit profile, nor does it affect existing Outlooks.",
        "We will resolve the UCO status within six months. The outcomes will depend on Fitch’s assessment of the appropriate notching based on the new criteria. Not all issuers on UCO will have a rating change upon resolution.",
        "Introduction of Modifiers at ‘CCC’: The recently published Sovereign Rating Criteria introduces +/- modifiers in the ‘CCC’ category. Sovereigns rated ‘CCC’ could experience a one-notch rating change, potentially migrating from ‘CCC’ to ‘CCC-‘ or ‘CCC+’."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Fitch Ratings",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CCC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "RD",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Outlooks",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "six months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fitch Ratings",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hong Kong",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fitch Ratings",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IDR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fitch Ratings Publishes",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Outlooks",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "six months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sovereign Rating Criteria",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දේශීය මුදල් ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම නිරීක්‍ෂණය යටතේ පවතී: ෆිච්",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - Fitch Ratings විසින් නියෝජිතායතනයේ CCC ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම් සඳහා + සහ - වෙනස් කරන්නන් යෙදීමේ ප්‍රතිපත්ති මාරුවෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දේශීය මුදල් ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම ‘නිර්ණායක නිරීක්ෂණ යටතේ’ (UCO) තබා ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දිගුකාලීන විදේශ විනිමය ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම RD දක්වා පහත හෙළා ඇති නමුත් එහි දිගුකාලීන රුපියල ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම 'CCC' වේ.",
        "\"UCO පැවරුම මගින් පෙන්නුම් කරන්නේ අවසාන නිර්ණායකවල සෘජු ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම් වෙනස් විය හැකි බවයි,\" ෆිච් පැවසීය.",
        "“එය යටින් පවතින ණය පැතිකඩෙහි වෙනසක් නොපෙන්වයි, පවතින ඉදිරි දැක්මට බලපාන්නේ නැත.",
        "“අපි මාස හයක් ඇතුළත UCO තත්ත්වය විසඳන්නෙමු. නව නිර්ණායක මත පදනම්ව යෝග්‍ය ලකුණු කිරීම පිළිබඳ ෆිච්ගේ තක්සේරුව මත ප්‍රතිඵල රඳා පවතිනු ඇත.",
        "අවසාන ස්වෛරී ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීමේ නිර්ණායක ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කිරීමෙන් පසු Fitch ශ්‍රී ලංකා UCO ස්ථානගත කරයි",
        "Fitch Ratings – Hong Kong – 14 Jul 2022: Fitch Ratings විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දිගු කාලීන දේශීය-මුදල් නිකුත් කරන්නාගේ පෙරනිමි ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම (IDR) සහ ඒජන්සියේ Exposure Drafting: Sovereign Rafting බවට පරිවර්තනය කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුව ඒ ආශ්‍රිත උපකරණ නිර්ණායක නිරීක්ෂණ (UCO) යටතේ තබා ඇත. අවසාන නිර්ණායක.",
        "නව නිර්ණායක මගින් හඳුන්වා දෙන ලද වෙනස්කම් වල සාරාංශයක් ලබා ගත හැකිය: Fitch Ratings අවසාන ස්වෛරී ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීමේ නිර්ණායක ප්‍රකාශ කරයි",
        "UCO පැවරුම පෙන්නුම් කරන්නේ අවසාන නිර්ණායකවල සෘජු ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම් වෙනස් විය හැකි බවයි. එය යටින් පවතින ණය පැතිකඩෙහි වෙනසක් නොපෙන්වයි, පවතින ඉදිරි දැක්මට බලපාන්නේ නැත.",
        "අපි මාස හයක් ඇතුළත UCO තත්ත්වය විසඳන්නෙමු. නව නිර්ණායක මත පදනම්ව යෝග්‍ය සටහන් කිරීම පිළිබඳ ෆිච්ගේ තක්සේරුව මත ප්‍රතිඵල රඳා පවතී. UCO හි සියලුම නිකුත් කරන්නන් විභේදනය මත ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීමේ වෙනසක් ඇති නොවේ.",
        "'CCC' හි නවීකරණ හඳුන්වාදීම: මෑතකදී ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද ස්වෛරී ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීමේ නිර්ණායකය 'CCC' කාණ්ඩයේ +/- විකරණයන් හඳුන්වා දෙයි. 'CCC' ලෙස ශ්‍රේණිගත කරන ලද ස්වෛරී පුද්ගලයන්ට 'CCC' සිට 'CCC-' හෝ 'CCC+' වෙත සංක්‍රමණය විය හැකි එක්-අතර ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීමේ වෙනසක් අත්විඳිය හැකිය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆිච් ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CCC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "RD",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දැක්ම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස හයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆිච් ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හොංකොං",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆිච් ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IDR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fitch Ratings ප්‍රකාශනය කරයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දැක්ම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස හයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්වෛරී ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීමේ නිර්ණායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் உள்ளூர் நாணய மதிப்பீடு கண்காணிப்பில் உள்ளது: ஃபிட்ச்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Fitch Ratings இலங்கையின் உள்ளூர் நாணய மதிப்பீட்டை ‘அண்டர் க்ரைடீரியா அவதானிப்பின்’ (UCO) கொள்கையில் மாற்றியதைத் தொடர்ந்து, ஏஜென்சியின் CCC தரவரிசைகளில் + மற்றும் - மாற்றியமைப்பாளர்களைப் பயன்படுத்துகிறது.",
        "இலங்கையின் நீண்ட கால வெளிநாட்டு நாணய மதிப்பீடு RD க்கு குறைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது ஆனால் அதன் நீண்ட கால ரூபாய் மதிப்பீடு ‘CCC’ இல் உள்ளது.",
        "\"இறுதி அளவுகோலின் நேரடி விளைவாக மதிப்பீடுகள் மாறக்கூடும் என்பதை UCO ஒதுக்கீடு குறிக்கிறது\" என்று ஃபிட்ச் கூறினார்.",
        "\"இது அடிப்படை கடன் சுயவிவரத்தில் மாற்றத்தைக் குறிக்கவில்லை அல்லது ஏற்கனவே இருக்கும் அவுட்லுக்கைப் பாதிக்காது.",
        "\"நாங்கள் ஆறு மாதங்களுக்குள் UCO நிலையைத் தீர்ப்போம். முடிவுகள் புதிய அளவுகோல்களின் அடிப்படையில் பொருத்தமான குறிப்பைப் பற்றிய ஃபிட்ச் மதிப்பீட்டைப் பொறுத்தது.",
        "இறுதி இறையாண்மை மதிப்பீட்டு அளவுகோல்களை வெளியிட்ட பிறகு Fitch இலங்கை UCO ஐ வைக்கிறது",
        "ஃபிட்ச் மதிப்பீடுகள் – ஹாங்காங் – 14 ஜூலை 2022: ஏஜென்சியின் எக்ஸ்போஷர் டிராஃப்ட்: ஸோவரேரியாவை மாற்றியதைத் தொடர்ந்து, ஃபிட்ச் ரேட்டிங்ஸ், இலங்கையின் நீண்ட கால உள்ளூர்-நாணய வழங்குபவர் இயல்புநிலை மதிப்பீடு (IDR) மற்றும் அதனுடன் தொடர்புடைய கருவிகளை அளவுகோல் கண்காணிப்பின் கீழ் (UCO) வைத்துள்ளது. இறுதி அளவுகோல்கள்.",
        "புதிய அளவுகோல்களால் அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்ட மாற்றங்களின் சுருக்கம் இங்கே கிடைக்கிறது: ஃபிட்ச் மதிப்பீடுகள் இறுதி இறையாண்மை மதிப்பீட்டு அளவுகோலை வெளியிடுகிறது",
        "இறுதி அளவுகோலின் நேரடி விளைவாக மதிப்பீடுகள் மாறக்கூடும் என்று UCO ஒதுக்கீடு குறிப்பிடுகிறது. இது அடிப்படைக் கிரெடிட் சுயவிவரத்தில் மாற்றத்தைக் குறிக்கவில்லை அல்லது ஏற்கனவே இருக்கும் அவுட்லுக்கைப் பாதிக்காது.",
        "ஆறு மாதங்களுக்குள் UCO நிலையைத் தீர்ப்போம். முடிவுகள் புதிய அளவுகோல்களின் அடிப்படையில் பொருத்தமான குறிப்பை ஃபிட்ச் மதிப்பீட்டைப் பொறுத்தது. UCO இல் உள்ள அனைத்து வழங்குநர்களும் தீர்மானத்தின் மீது மதிப்பீட்டில் மாற்றத்தைக் கொண்டிருக்க மாட்டார்கள்.",
        "'CCC' இல் மாற்றியமைப்பாளர்களின் அறிமுகம்: சமீபத்தில் வெளியிடப்பட்ட இறையாண்மை மதிப்பீட்டு அளவுகோல், 'CCC' பிரிவில் +/- மாற்றிகளை அறிமுகப்படுத்துகிறது. 'சிசிசி' என மதிப்பிடப்பட்ட இறையாண்மைகள், 'சிசிசி' இலிருந்து 'சிசிசி-' அல்லது 'சிசிசி+' க்கு மாறக்கூடிய ஒரு தர மதிப்பீட்டில் மாற்றத்தை அனுபவிக்கலாம்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃபிட்ச் மதிப்பீடுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CCC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "RD",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அவுட்லுக்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃபிட்ச் மதிப்பீடுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹாங்காங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபிட்ச் மதிப்பீடுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐடிஆர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃபிட்ச் மதிப்பீடுகள் வெளியிடுகின்றன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அவுட்லுக்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இறையாண்மை மதிப்பீடு அளவுகோல்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}