{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Recent-75-electricity-tariff-is-a-farce-CEB-Trade-Union-Alliance/108-243033",
  "time_ut": 1660514840,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Recent 75% electricity tariff is a farce: CEB Trade Union Alliance",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Recent 75% electricity tariff is a farce: CEB Trade Union Alliance",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The recent 75% increase in the electricity tariff is incorrect; it is a 100% increase when considering higher unit rates, the Ceylon Electricity Board (CEB) United Trade Union Alliance said.",
        "Trade Union Alliance Convener Ranjan Jayalal said the Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka (PUCSL) granted permission to increase the electricity tariff by 75% from August 8.",
        "Addressing the media, he said the category with consumption less than 30 units will be charged 42% of the cost.",
        "The units between 30 and 60 had been increased by 178.07%. All electricity usage units up to 200 will get a 100% tariff increase. Small-scale industries face serious issues with this increase.",
        "As a result, the price of all essential goods and services relating to electricity has gone up to where people cannot afford it.",
        "Therefore, the Trade Union Alliance raised their opposition to this recent electricity tariff increase.",
        "Jayalal claimed that CEB trade unions have not called for any discussions regarding the electricity tariff increase.",
        "We can show the minister how we can change the CEB into a profitable institute without privatising it. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "75%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "CEB Trade Union Alliance",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "75%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "100%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "United Trade Union Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Trade Union Alliance Convener",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Jayalal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "75%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 8",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "less than 30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "42%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "between 30 and 60",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "178.07%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Trade Union Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මෑත කාලීන 75% විදුලි ගාස්තුව විහිළුවක්: ලංවිම වෘත්තීය සමිති සන්ධානය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මෑතක දී විදුලි බිල 75% වැඩි කිරීම වැරදියි; ඉහළ ඒකක ගාස්තු සලකා බැලීමේදී එය 100% ක වැඩිවීමක් බව ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය (ලංවිම) ඒකාබද්ධ වෘත්තීය සමිති සන්ධානය පවසයි.",
        "වෘත්තීය සමිති එකමුතුවේ කැඳවුම්කරු රන්ජන් ජයලාල් මහතා පැවසුවේ, අගෝස්තු 8 වැනිදා සිට විදුලි බිල 75% කින් වැඩි කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව (PUCSL) අවසර ලබා දුන් බව ය.",
        "මාධ්‍ය වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් ඔහු කියා සිටියේ ඒකක 30 ට අඩු පරිභෝජනයක් ඇති කාණ්ඩයට පිරිවැයෙන් 42% ක් අය කරන බවයි.",
        "30 ත් 60 ත් අතර ඒකක 178.07% කින් වැඩි වී ඇත. 200 දක්වා වූ සියලුම විදුලි භාවිත ඒකක සඳහා 100%ක ගාස්තු වැඩිවීමක් ලැබේ. මෙම වැඩිවීමත් සමඟ කුඩා පරිමාණ කර්මාන්ත බරපතළ ගැටලුවලට මුහුණ දෙයි.",
        "එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස විදුලිය සම්බන්ධ සියලුම අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය භාණ්ඩ සහ සේවා වල මිල මිනිසුන්ට දරාගත නොහැකි තැන දක්වා ඉහළ ගොස් ඇත.",
        "එබැවින් මෙම මෑතක දී විදුලි බිල වැඩි කිරීමට වෘත්තීය සමිති සන්ධානය සිය විරෝධය මතු කළේය.",
        "ජයලාල් කියා සිටියේ විදුලි බිල වැඩි කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් කිසිදු සාකච්ඡාවක් සඳහා ලංවිම වෘත්තීය සමිති කැඳවා නොමැති බවයි.",
        "විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය පෞද්ගලීකරණය නොකර ලාභ ලබන ආයතනයක් බවට පත් කරන්නේ කොහොමද කියලා ඇමැතිතුමාට පෙන්වන්න පුළුවන්. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "75%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "ලංවිම වෘත්තීය සමිති සන්ධානය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "75%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "100%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් වෘත්තීය සමිති සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෘත්තීය සමිති සන්ධානයේ කැඳවුම්කරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් ජයලාල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "75%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 8",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30 ට අඩු",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "42%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30 සහ 60 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "178.07%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෘත්තීය සමිති සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சமீபத்திய 75% மின்சார கட்டணம் ஒரு கேலிக்கூத்து: CEB தொழிற்சங்க கூட்டணி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சமீபத்தில் 75% மின் கட்டணம் உயர்த்தப்பட்டது தவறானது; அதிக அலகு கட்டணங்களைக் கருத்தில் கொள்ளும்போது இது 100% அதிகரிப்பு என்று இலங்கை மின்சார சபை (இ.இ.பி.) ஐக்கிய தொழிற்சங்கக் கூட்டமைப்பு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழு (PUCSL) ஆகஸ்ட் 8 ஆம் திகதி முதல் 75% மின்சார கட்டணத்தை அதிகரிக்க அனுமதி வழங்கியுள்ளதாக தொழிற்சங்க கூட்டமைப்பு அழைப்பாளர் ரஞ்சன் ஜெயலால் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "செய்தியாளர்களிடம் பேசிய அவர், 30 யூனிட்டுகளுக்கு குறைவான நுகர்வு கொண்ட பிரிவினருக்கு செலவில் 42% வசூலிக்கப்படும் என்றார்.",
        "30 முதல் 60 வரையிலான அலகுகள் 178.07% அதிகரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன. 200 வரையிலான அனைத்து மின் பயன்பாட்டு அலகுகளுக்கும் 100% கட்டணம் உயர்த்தப்படும். இந்த அதிகரிப்பால் சிறுதொழில் நிறுவனங்கள் கடுமையான பிரச்சினைகளை எதிர்கொள்கின்றன.",
        "இதன் விளைவாக, மின்சாரம் தொடர்பான அனைத்து அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்கள் மற்றும் சேவைகளின் விலையும் மக்களால் வாங்க முடியாத அளவுக்கு உயர்ந்துள்ளது.",
        "எனவே, இந்த மின்கட்டண உயர்வுக்கு தொழிற்சங்க கூட்டமைப்பினர் எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "மின்சாரக் கட்டண அதிகரிப்பு தொடர்பில் எந்தவொரு கலந்துரையாடலுக்கும் மின்சார சபை தொழிற்சங்கங்கள் அழைப்பு விடுக்கவில்லை என ஜயலால் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மின்சார சபையை தனியார் மயமாக்காமல் இலாபம் ஈட்டும் நிறுவனமாக மாற்றுவது எப்படி என்பதை அமைச்சருக்கு காட்ட முடியும். (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "75%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "CEB தொழிற்சங்க கூட்டணி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "75%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "100%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தொழிற்சங்கக் கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தொழிற்சங்கக் கூட்டமைப்பு அழைப்பாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ஜெயலால்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "75%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 8",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30 க்கும் குறைவாக",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "42%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30 மற்றும் 60 க்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "178.07%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "தொழிற்சங்க கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}