{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/03/woman-dead-after-swept-away-by-strong-current/",
  "time_ut": 1656835020,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Woman dead after swept away by strong current",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Woman dead after swept away by strong current",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); A woman was swept away by strong currents in Uswatakeiyawa, Pamunuwa and later died upon admission to hospital.",
        "Police stated that the deceased had attended an event held at a hotel in Uswatakeiyawa with a group, and had gone down to the beach before being taken away by strong currents.",
        "The woman was swept into the sea by the strong waves and was washed back ashore, however, she later died on admission to Pamunwa Hospital.",
        "The deceased was identified as a 30-year-old resident of Biyanwila, Kadawata.",
        "Meanwhile, three youth who were swimming in Seethagalla Natural Seawater Pool in Gandara, Talalla were also swept into the sea.",
        "Police said that the two men who were rescued, are currently being treated at the Matara General Hospital.",
        "The incident took place when 17 students studying at Kumburupitiya Gamudava Technology College belonging to the Ruhuna University were swimming in Talalla.",
        "The missing was identified as a 22-year-old man, and a search and Rescue Operation is underway."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Uswatakeiyawa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pamunuwa",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Uswatakeiyawa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pamunwa Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Biyanwila",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kadawata",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seethagalla Natural Seawater Pool",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gandara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Talalla",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Matara General Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumburupitiya Gamudava Technology College",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ruhuna University",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Talalla",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ප්‍රබල දිය පහරකින් ගසාගෙන ගිය කාන්තාවක් මියයයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); පමුණුව, උස්‌වටකෙයියාව ප්‍රදේශයේදී කාන්තාවක් දැඩි දිය පහරකට හසුව ගසාගෙන ගොස් රෝහල් ගත කිරීමෙන් පසු මියගොස් තිබේ.",
        "පොලීසිය සඳහන් කළේ, මියගිය පුද්ගලයා පිරිසක් සමඟ උස්වටකෙයියාව ප්‍රදේශයේ හෝටලයක පැවති උත්සවයකට සහභාගී වී ඇති අතර, පසුව දැඩි දිය පහරකට හසුව මුහුදු වෙරළට බැස ඇති බවයි.",
        "මෙම කාන්තාව ප්‍රබල රළ පහරට හසුව මුහුදට ගසාගෙන ගොස් නැවත ගොඩට ගසාගෙන ගොස් ඇතත් පසුව ඇය පමුන්ව රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කිරීමේදී මියගොස් තිබේ.",
        "මියගොස් ඇත්තේ 30 හැවිරිදි කඩවත බියන්විල ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිකරුවෙකි.",
        "මේ අතර, තලල්ල, ගන්දර, සීතගල්ල ස්වභාවික මුහුදු ජල තටාකයේ දියනෑමට ගිය තරුණයින් තිදෙනෙකු ද මුහුදට ගසාගෙන ගොස් තිබෙනවා.",
        "බේරාගත් පුද්ගලයින් දෙදෙනා මේ වන විට මාතර මහ රෝහලේ ප්‍රතිකාර ලබන බවයි පොලිසිය පැවසුවේ.",
        "රුහුණු විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයට අයත් කුඹුරුපිටිය ගමුදව තාක්ෂණ විද්‍යාලයේ ඉගෙනුම ලබන සිසුන් 17 දෙනෙකු තලල්ල ප්‍රදේශයේ දියනෑමට යමින් සිටියදීයි මෙම සිද්ධිය සිදුව ඇත්තේ.",
        "අතුරුදන් වූ පුද්ගලයා 22 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයෙකු බවට හඳුනාගෙන ඇති අතර, සෝදිසි කිරීම් සහ මුදාගැනීමේ මෙහෙයුම් ක්‍රියාත්මකයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Uswatakeiyawa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පමුණුව",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Uswatakeiyawa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පමුන්ව රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බියන්විල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කඩවත",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීතගල්ල ස්වභාවික මුහුදු ජල තටාකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගන්දර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර මහ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුඹුරුපිටිය ගමුදව තාක්ෂණ විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුහුණු විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பலத்த நீரோட்டத்தில் அடித்துச் செல்லப்பட்ட பெண் உயிரிழந்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பமுனுவ, உஸ்வதகேயாவ பகுதியில் பெண் ஒருவர் பலத்த நீரோட்டத்தில் அடித்துச் செல்லப்பட்டு வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்ட பின்னர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "உயிரிழந்தவர் உஸ்வதகேயாவ ஹோட்டல் ஒன்றில் இடம்பெற்ற நிகழ்வொன்றில் குழுவொன்றுடன் கலந்து கொண்டதாகவும், பலத்த நீரோட்டத்தினால் கடற்கொள்ளைக்கு முன்னர் கடற்கரைக்கு சென்றுள்ளதாகவும் பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "பலத்த அலைகளால் கடலில் அடித்துச் செல்லப்பட்ட பெண், மீண்டும் கரைக்குக் கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்ட போதிலும், பமுன்வா வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்ட பின்னர் அவர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "உயிரிழந்தவர் 30 வயதுடைய கடவத்தை பியன்வில பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்தவர் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, தலல்ல, கந்தர பிரதேசத்தில் உள்ள சீதகல்ல இயற்கை கடல் நீர் குளத்தில் நீராடச் சென்ற மூன்று இளைஞர்களும் கடலில் அடித்துச் செல்லப்பட்டனர்.",
        "மீட்கப்பட்ட இருவரும் தற்போது மாத்தறை பொது வைத்தியசாலையில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வருவதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "ருஹுணு பல்கலைக்கழகத்திற்குட்பட்ட கும்புருபிட்டிய கமுதவ தொழிநுட்பக் கல்லூரியில் கல்வி கற்கும் 17 மாணவர்கள் தலல்லயில் நீராடிக் கொண்டிருந்த போதே இந்தச் சம்பவம் இடம்பெற்றுள்ளது.",
        "காணாமல் போனவர் 22 வயதுடையவர் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளதுடன், தேடுதல் மற்றும் மீட்பு நடவடிக்கைகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டு வருகின்றன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Uswatakeiyawa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பமுனுவ",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Uswatakeiyawa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பமுன்வா மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பியன்வில",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடவட",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீதகல்ல இயற்கை கடல் நீர் குளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காந்தார",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலல்லா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை பொது வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கும்புறுபிட்டிய கமுதவ தொழில்நுட்பக் கல்லூரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ருஹுணு பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலல்லா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}