{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/showers-strong-winds-rough-seas-forecast-for-sri-lanka-as-monsoon-begins-98091/",
  "time_ut": 1659348000,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Showers, strong winds, rough seas forecast for Sri Lanka as monsoon begins",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Showers, strong winds, rough seas forecast for Sri Lanka as monsoon begins",
      "author": "Mahadiya Hamza",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s fishing community has been advised to take precautionary measures as the monsoon rains begin on the island.",
        "The meteorology department issued a red warning on Monday August 01 for strong winds and rough seas in several areas.",
        "“Southwest monsoon flow is likely to strengthen from today onwards. Showery and windy conditions are likely to enhance in the western and southern sea areas during the next few days,” a statement from the meteorology department said.",
        "“Strong winds up to 60-70kph and very rough seas can be expected in the sea areas off the coast extending from Puttalam to Pottuvil via Colombo, Galle and Hambantota from today onwards.”",
        "Fishermen and the naval community are advised not to venture out to the seas off the coast extending from Puttalam to Pottuvil via Galle and Hambantota until further notice.",
        "Wind speed is also expected to increase up to 50-60 kmph in the sea areas off the coast extending from Kankasanturai to Puttalam via Mannar.",
        "These sea areas will also be rough at times, the Met Department said.",
        "Swell waves of about 2.5-3.5 meters in height are also expected in the sea areas off the coast extending from Puttalam to Pottuvil via Galle and Hambantota.",
        "Naval and multi-day fishing communities are advised not to venture out for fishing and naval activities in the sea areas off the coast extending from Puttalam to Pottuvil via Galle and Hambantota until further notice.",
        "They also requested to be attentive regarding future forecasts issued in this regard.",
        "Rainfall amount (mm): Light: 00-12.5, Light to moderate: 12.5-25, moderate: 25-50, Fairly Heavy rain: 50 -100,",
        "Heavy rain: 100 – 150, Very heavy rain: 150 or more. (Colombo/Aug01/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday August 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Southwest",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next few days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60-70kph",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50-60 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kankasanturai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Met Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Swell",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 2.5-3.5 meters",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "multi-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "mm",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "00-12.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12.5-25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "25-50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fairly Heavy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 -100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මෝසම් වර්ෂාව ආරම්භ වීමත් සමග ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට වැසි, තද සුළං, රළු මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ පිළිබඳ අනාවැකි",
      "author": "මහදිය හම්සා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - දිවයිනේ මෝසම් වර්ෂාව ආරම්භ වන බැවින් පූර්වාරක්ෂාව ගන්නා ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ධීවර ප්‍රජාවට උපදෙස් දී ඇත.",
        "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව අගෝස්තු 01 සඳුදා ප්‍රදේශ කිහිපයක තද සුළං සහ රළු මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ පිළිබඳ රතු අනතුරු ඇඟවීමක් නිකුත් කළේය.",
        "“නිරිතදිග මෝසම් ප්‍රවාහය අද සිට ශක්තිමත් වීමට ඉඩ තිබෙනවා. ඉදිරි දින කිහිපයේදී බස්නාහිර සහ දකුණු මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල වැසි සහ සුළං තත්ත්වය වැඩි විය හැකි බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව නිකුත් කළ නිවේදනයක දැක්වෙයි.",
        "පුත්තලම සිට කොළඹ, ගාල්ල සහ හම්බන්තොට හරහා පොතුවිල් දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල අද සිට පැයට කිලෝමීටර් 60-70 දක්වා තද සුළං බලාපොරොත්තු විය හැක.",
        "නැවත දැනුම් දෙන තුරු පුත්තලම සිට ගාල්ල සහ හම්බන්තොට හරහා පොතුවිල් දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල ධීවරයින්ට සහ නාවික ප්‍රජාවට නොයන ලෙස උපදෙස් දෙනු ලැබේ.",
        "කන්කසන්තුරේ සිට මන්නාරම හරහා පුත්තලම දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල සුළගේ වේගය පැ.කි.මී.50-60 දක්වා වැඩිවිය හැකි බවද අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "එම මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ විටින් විට රළු විය හැකි බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "පුත්තලම සිට ගාල්ල සහ හම්බන්තොට හරහා පොතුවිල් දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල ද මීටර් 2.5-3.5 පමණ උස රළ ඇති විය හැක.",
        "නැවත දැනුම් දෙන තුරු පුත්තලම සිට ගාල්ල සහ හම්බන්තොට හරහා පොතුවිල් දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල ධීවර හා නාවික කටයුතු සඳහා පිටත්ව නොයන ලෙස නාවික සහ බහුදින ධීවර ප්‍රජාවන්ට උපදෙස් දෙනු ලැබේ.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් නිකුත් කරන ඉදිරි අනාවැකි සම්බන්ධයෙන් අවධානයෙන් පසුවන ලෙසද ඔවුන් ඉල්ලා සිටියා.",
        "වර්ෂාපතන ප්රමාණය (මි.මී.): ආලෝකය: 00-12.5, සැහැල්ලු සිට මධ්යස්ථ: 12.5-25, මධ්යස්ථ: 25-50, තරමක් තද වැසි: 50 -100,",
        "අධික වර්ෂාව: 100 - 150, ඉතා අධික වර්ෂාව: 150 හෝ ඊට වැඩි. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 01/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 01 සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිරිතදිග",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60-70kph",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50-60 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කන්කසන්තුරේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉදිමීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීටර් 2.5-3.5 පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බහු දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මි.මී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "00-12.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12.5-25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "25-50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තරමක් බරයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 -100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையில் பருவமழை தொடங்கும் போது மழை, பலத்த காற்று, கடல் சீற்றத்துடன் இருக்கும் என கணிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "மஹதியா ஹம்சா",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையின் மீனவ சமூகம் தீவில் பருவமழை தொடங்குவதால் முன்னெச்சரிக்கை நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுக்க அறிவுறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 01 திங்கட்கிழமை பல பகுதிகளில் பலத்த காற்று மற்றும் கடல் கொந்தளிப்பாக இருக்கும் என வானிலை ஆய்வு மையம் சிவப்பு எச்சரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "தென்மேற்கு பருவமழை இன்று முதல் வலுப்பெற வாய்ப்புள்ளது. அடுத்த சில நாட்களில் மேற்கு மற்றும் தெற்கு கடற்பரப்புகளில் மழை மற்றும் காற்றுடன் கூடிய காலநிலை அதிகரிக்கும் என வானிலை ஆய்வு மையம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "புத்தளத்திலிருந்து கொழும்பு, காலி மற்றும் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை ஊடாக பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளில் இன்று முதல் மணித்தியாலத்துக்கு 60-70 கிலோ மீற்றர் வேகத்தில் பலத்த காற்று வீசுவதுடன் கடல் கொந்தளிப்பாகவும் காணப்படும்.",
        "புத்தளத்திலிருந்து காலி மற்றும் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை ஊடாக பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளுக்கு மறு அறிவித்தல் வரும் வரை மீனவர்கள் மற்றும் கடற்படை சமூகம் மீன்பிடிக்கச் செல்ல வேண்டாம் என அறிவுறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "காங்கேசன்துறையிலிருந்து மன்னார் ஊடாக புத்தளம் வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளில் காற்றின் வேகமானது மணித்தியாலத்துக்கு 50-60 கிலோ மீற்றர் வரை அதிகரித்து வீசக்கூடுமென எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகின்றது.",
        "இந்த கடல் பகுதிகள் சில சமயங்களில் கொந்தளிப்பாகவும் காணப்படும் என்றும் வானிலை ஆய்வு மையம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "புத்தளத்திலிருந்து காலி மற்றும் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை ஊடாக பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளில் சுமார் 2.5-3.5 மீற்றர் உயரம் கொண்ட கடல் அலைகள் எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகின்றன.",
        "புத்தளத்திலிருந்து காலி மற்றும் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை ஊடாக பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளுக்கு மறு அறிவித்தல் வரும் வரை கடற்றொழில் மற்றும் கடற்படை நடவடிக்கைகளுக்கு செல்ல வேண்டாம் என கடற்படை மற்றும் பல நாள் மீனவ சமூகங்கள் அறிவுறுத்தப்படுகின்றனர்.",
        "இது தொடர்பில் வெளியிடப்படும் எதிர்கால முன்னறிவிப்புகள் தொடர்பில் அவதானமாக இருக்குமாறும் அவர்கள் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "மழை அளவு (மிமீ): ஒளி: 00-12.5, லேசானது முதல் மிதமானது: 12.5-25, மிதமானது: 25-50, ஓரளவு கனமழை: 50 -100,",
        "கனமழை: 100 - 150, மிக அதிக மழை: 150 அல்லது அதற்கு மேல். (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்01/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 01 திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தென்மேற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த சில நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 60-70 கி.மீ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 50-60 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "காங்கசந்துறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வானிலை துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீங்குங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 2.5-3.5 மீட்டர்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பல நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மிமீ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "00-12.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12.5-25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "25-50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓரளவு கனமானது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 -100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}