{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/‘‘පොහොට්ටුව-ජනපති---අගමැති-දෙකම-ගන්න-හදනවා‘‘/1-616464",
  "time_ut": 1657874589,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "‘‘පොහොට්ටුව ජනපති - අගමැති දෙකම ගන්න හදනවා‘‘",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "\"Pohottuwa is trying to get both the President and the Prime Minister\"",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The chief organizer of the opposition, Member of Parliament Mr. Lakshman Kiriella said in Colombo today (15) that the government is working to lead the country by kicking the aspirations of the people and appointing a president and a prime minister.",
        "Mr. Kiriella also mentioned that although Samagi Jana Balawega worked to win the aspirations of the people by forming an all-party government with all the parties in the parliament on the advice of religious leaders including Trinitarian prelates, a serious situation has arisen due to the government not agreeing to it.",
        "He said this in a press conference called at the opposition leader's office in Marx Fernando Mawatha, Colombo, that yesterday's agreement with the political parties to build the country by sharing the positions of the president and prime minister and the government and the opposition has broken down.",
        "Mr. Kiriella also mentioned that the opposition parties had reached an agreement on this matter in the last few days and had planned to inform the Speaker of this decision today, but at the last moment the position of some people changed and this confused situation has arisen."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakshman Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trinitarian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Marx Fernando Mawatha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last few days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘‘පොහොට්ටුව ජනපති - අගමැති දෙකම ගන්න හදනවා‘‘",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනතා අභිලාෂයන්වලට පයින් ගසා පොහොට්ටුවෙන් ජනාධිපතිවරයකු සහ අගමැතිවරයකු පත්කර රට ගෙන යාමට ආණ්ඩුව කටයුතු කරමින් සිටින බව විපක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල මහතා කොළඹදී අද(15)පැවසීය.",
        "ත්‍රෛනිකායික මහ නාහිමියන් ඇතුළු ආගමික නායකයින්ගේ උපදෙස් මත පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සියලුම පක්ෂ හා එක්ව සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවා ජනතා අභිලාෂයන් ජයගැනීමට සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ කටයුතු කළත් ආණ්ඩුව එයට එකඟ නොවීම හේතුවෙන් බරපතළ තත්ත්වයක් පැන නැගී ඇතැයි ද කිරිඇල්ල මහතා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ජනාධිපති සහ අගමැති ධුර ආණ්ඩුව සහ විපක්ෂය බෙදාගෙන රට ගොඩනැගීමට දේශපාලන පක්ෂ සමඟ ඊයේ තිබූ සම්මුතිය අද වන විට බිඳ වැටී ඇතැයි ද කොළඹ මාක්ස් ප්‍රනාන්දු මාවතේ විපක්ෂ නායක කාර්යාලයේ කැඳවූ මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී ඔහු මේ බව පැවසීය.",
        "පසුගිය දින කිහිපය තුළ විපක්ෂයේ පක්ෂ මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් එකඟතාවයකට පැමිණ මෙම තීරණය අද දින කතානායක වරයාට දැනුම් දීමට සැලසුම් කර තිබුනත් අවසන් අවස්ථාවේදී කිහිපදෙනෙකුගේ ස්ථාවරය වෙනස් වීමෙන් මෙම ව්‍යාකූල තත්වය හටගෙන ඇතැයිද කිරිඇල්ල මහතා සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිත්වවාදී",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාක්ස් ප්‍රනාන්දු මාවත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය දින කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமர் இருவரையும் பெற பொஹொட்டுவ முயற்சி செய்கிறார்\"",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மக்களின் அபிலாஷைகளை எட்டி உதைத்து ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமரை நியமித்து நாட்டை வழிநடத்த அரசாங்கம் செயற்பட்டு வருவதாக எதிர்க்கட்சியின் பிரதம அமைப்பாளரும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருமான திரு.லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல இன்று (15) கொழும்பில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "திரித்துவ பீடாதிபதிகள் உள்ளிட்ட சமயத் தலைவர்களின் ஆலோசனையின் பேரில் அனைத்துக் கட்சிகளையும் ஒன்றிணைத்து பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைத்து மக்களின் அபிலாஷைகளை வென்றெடுப்பதற்காக சமகி ஜன பலவேக செயற்பட்ட போதிலும் பாரிய நிலைமை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் திரு.கிரியெல்ல குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். அரசு அதை ஏற்கவில்லை.",
        "கொழும்பு, மார்க்ஸ் பெர்னாண்டோ மாவத்தையில் உள்ள எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் அலுவலகத்தில் நடைபெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் அவர் இதனைத் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். ஜனாதிபதி, பிரதமர் பதவிகளைப் பகிர்ந்துகொண்டு நாட்டைக் கட்டியெழுப்பும் அரசியல் கட்சிகளுடன் நேற்றைய தினம் அரசாங்கம், எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் செய்துகொண்ட ஒப்பந்தம் முறிவடைந்துள்ளது. .",
        "இந்த விடயம் தொடர்பில் கடந்த சில தினங்களுக்கு முன்னர் எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் இணக்கப்பாட்டுக்கு வந்து இந்த தீர்மானத்தை சபாநாயகரிடம் தெரிவிக்க இன்று திட்டமிட்டிருந்த போதிலும் கடைசி நேரத்தில் சிலரது நிலைப்பாடு மாறி இந்த குழப்ப நிலை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் கிரியெல்ல குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திரித்துவவாதி",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மார்க்ஸ் பெர்னாண்டோ மாவத்தை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த சில நாட்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}