{
  "newspaper_id": "b-b-c-com-sinhala",
  "url": "https://www.bbc.com/sinhala/sri-lanka-62048045",
  "time_ut": 1656985408,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "#GOTAGOHOME ; පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණි ජනපතිට 'ගෝඨා ගෝ හෝම්' කියයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "#GOTAGOHOME ; The President who came to the Parliament is told 'Go Home'",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "As stated by Anura Kumara Dissanayake, Prime Minister Ranil Wickramasinghe today (July 05) stated in Parliament that he is ready to give up his position to give him the post of Prime Minister if the country can be restored within six months.",
        "The Prime Minister made a special statement about the current economic situation of the country and said that if a country with a negative economy can be turned into a country with a rich economic growth rate in a very short time, he deserves the Nobel Prize.",
        "It was special that President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa was also present in Parliament today.",
        "The opposition MPs protested by shouting 'Gotha Go Home'."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "six months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Nobel Prize",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "#GOTAGOHOME ; පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණි ජනපතිට 'ගෝඨා ගෝ හෝම්' කියයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇති පරිදි මාස හයක් තුළ රට යථා තත්ත්වයට පත්කළ හැකි නම් ඔහුට අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධූරය ලබා දීමට තමන් තනතුර අත්හැරීමට සුදානම් බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ අද (ජූලි 05) පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "සෘන ආර්ථිකයක් පවතින රටක් ඉතා කෙටි කලකින් ධන ආර්ථික වර්ධන වේගයක් සහිත රටක් බවට පත් කළ හැකි නම් ඔහු නොබෙල් ත්‍යාගය ලැබීමට ද සුදුසු බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසුවේ රටේ වත්මන් ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය ගැන විශේෂ ප්‍රකාශයක් කරමිනි.",
        "අද පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ ද පැමිණ සිටීම විශේෂත්වයක් විය.",
        "විපක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරු 'ගෝඨා ගෝ හෝම්' යනුවෙන් කෑ ගසමින් විරෝධතාවය පළ කළහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස හයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නොබෙල් ත්‍යාගය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "#GOTAGOHOME ; பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு வந்த ஜனாதிபதிக்கு 'வீட்டிற்கு செல்லுங்கள்'",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அநுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க தெரிவித்தது போல், ஆறு மாதங்களுக்குள் நாட்டை மீட்டெடுக்க முடியுமானால் பிரதமர் பதவியை தமக்கு வழங்குவதற்காக தனது பதவியை துறக்க தயார் என பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இன்று (ஜூலை 05) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நாட்டின் தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நிலை குறித்து சிறப்பு அறிக்கை வெளியிட்ட பிரதமர், எதிர்மறையான பொருளாதாரம் உள்ள ஒரு நாட்டை மிகக் குறுகிய காலத்தில் வளமான பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சி கொண்ட நாடாக மாற்ற முடியுமானால், அவர் நோபல் பரிசுக்கு தகுதியானவர் என்றார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவும் இன்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பிரசன்னமாகியிருந்தமை விசேட அம்சமாகும்.",
        "இதற்கு எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவித்து எதிர்க்கட்சி எம்.பி.க்கள் ‘கோதா வீட்டுக்கு செல்லுங்கள்’ என முழக்கமிட்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நோபல் பரிசு",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}