{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-customs-seizes-rs-16-mln-worth-illegal-cigarettes-five-arrested-99084/",
  "time_ut": 1661613000,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka Customs seizes Rs.16 mln worth illegal cigarettes; five arrested",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka Customs seizes Rs.16 mln worth illegal cigarettes; five arrested",
      "author": "Neshella Perera",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka Customs has seized 16 million rupees worth 810 cartons of cigarettes and arrested five individuals for attempting to smuggle the illegal consignment from Oman, it said in a statement..",
        "The five arrested had traveled to Sri Lanka through Oman Airlines via Dubai. The suspects are residents of Chilaw, Moratuwa and Maligawatta, Sri Lanka Customs said in a statement.",
        "The suspects were nabbed when they tried to use Green Channel, which is reserved for passengers who do not have to declare anything to the customs at the airport.. The suspects have failed to declare the cigarettes and pretended as they were their personal belongings, the Customs said.",
        "The cigarette stock contained 810 cartons of cigarettes and its market value is estimated to be around 16 million rupees.",
        "Airport Division of Sri Lanka Customs will impose fine on the confiscated cigarettes and will conduct further investigations. (Colombo/Aug 27/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka Customs",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Rs.16 mln",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "five",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "16 million",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "810",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oman",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oman Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chilaw, Moratuwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maligawatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Customs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Green Channel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Customs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "810",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "16 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Airport Division of Sri Lanka Customs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රුපියල් මිලියන 16ක් වටිනා නීතිවිරෝධී දුම්වැටි තොගයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකා රේගුව අත්අඩංගුවට පස් දෙනෙක් අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නෙෂෙල්ලා පෙරේරා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකා රේගුව විසින් දුම්වැටි කාටූන් 810 ක් වටිනා රුපියල් මිලියන 16 ක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති අතර ඕමානයේ සිට නීතිවිරෝධී භාණ්ඩ තොගය රැගෙන යාමට උත්සාහ කළ පුද්ගලයින් පස් දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් පස්දෙනා ඕමාන් ගුවන් සේවය හරහා ඩුබායි හරහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණ ඇත. සැකකරුවන් හලාවත, මොරටුව සහ මාලිගාවත්ත ප්‍රදේශවල පදිංචිකරුවන් බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා රේගුව නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටී.",
        "ගුවන් තොටුපළේ රේගුවට කිසිවක් ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය නොවන මගීන් සඳහා වෙන් කර ඇති ග්‍රීන් චැනල් භාවිතා කිරීමට උත්සාහ කිරීමේදී සැකකරුවන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත. රේගුව පැවසීය.",
        "දුම්වැටි තොගයේ දුම්වැටි කාටූන් 810ක් තිබී ඇති අතර එහි වෙළෙඳපොළ වටිනාකම රුපියල් මිලියන 16ක් පමණ වෙතැයි ගණන් බලා තිබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රේගුවේ ගුවන් තොටුපළ අංශය රාජසන්තක කරන ලද දුම්වැටි සඳහා දඩ නියම කරන අතර වැඩිදුර විමර්ශන සිදු කරනු ඇත. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 27/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රේගුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "රුපියල් මිලියන 16ක්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "පහ",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 16 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "810",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමාන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හලාවත, මොරටුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලිගාවත්ත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රේගුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හරිත නාලිකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රේගුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "810",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 16 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රේගුවේ ගුවන් තොටුපල අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "16 மில்லியன் ரூபா பெறுமதியான சட்டவிரோத சிகரெட்டுகளை இலங்கை சுங்கம் கைப்பற்றியுள்ளது. ஐந்து பேர் கைது",
      "author": "நெஷெல்லா பெரேரா",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – இலங்கை சுங்கப் பிரிவினர் 16 மில்லியன் ரூபா பெறுமதியான 810 அட்டைப்பெட்டி சிகரெட்டுகளை கைப்பற்றியுள்ளதுடன், ஓமானில் இருந்து சட்டவிரோதமான பொருட்களை கடத்திச் செல்ல முயன்ற ஐந்து நபர்களை கைது செய்துள்ளதாகவும் அது அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட ஐவரும் டுபாய் ஊடாக ஓமன் எயார்லைன்ஸ் ஊடாக இலங்கைக்கு பயணித்துள்ளனர். சந்தேகநபர்கள் சிலாபம், மொரட்டுவ மற்றும் மாளிகாவத்தை ஆகிய பகுதிகளைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள் என இலங்கை சுங்கப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "விமான நிலையத்தில் உள்ள சுங்கப் பிரிவினருக்கு அறிவிக்க வேண்டிய தேவையில்லாத பயணிகளுக்காக ஒதுக்கப்பட்ட கிரீன் சேனலை பயன்படுத்த முற்பட்ட போதே சந்தேகநபர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர். சுங்கத்துறை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "சிகரெட் கையிருப்பில் 810 அட்டைப்பெட்டிகள் சிகரெட்டுகள் இருந்ததாகவும் அதன் சந்தைப் பெறுமதி சுமார் 16 மில்லியன் ரூபா என மதிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை சுங்கப் பிரிவின் விமான நிலையப் பிரிவு, பறிமுதல் செய்யப்பட்ட சிகரெட்டுகளுக்கு அபராதம் விதிப்பதுடன், மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொள்ளும். (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட் 27/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை சுங்கம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரூ.16 மில்லியன்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஐந்து",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "16 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "810",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிலாபம், மொரட்டுவை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாளிகாவத்தை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பசுமை சேனல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "810",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "16 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுங்கத்தின் விமான நிலைய பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}