{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/02/portrait-of-sir-d-b-jayatilaka-at-sri-lankan-hc-in-delhi/",
  "time_ut": 1662092940,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Portrait of Sir D.B. Jayatilaka at Sri Lankan HC in Delhi",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Portrait of Sir D.B. Jayatilaka at Sri Lankan HC in Delhi",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Speaker of the Sri Lanka Parliament Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena unveiled a portrait of Sir D.B. Jayatilaka, Sri Lanka's first representative to India at the High Commission of Sri Lanka in New Delhi, coinciding with the 80th anniversary of the establishment of modern Indo-Lanka relations.",
        "This year marks the 80th anniversary of Sri Lanka (then Ceylon) sending Sir D.B. Jayatilaka as its first Representative to India in 1942. Unveiling the portrait of Sir D.B. Jayatilaka at the Chancery Building comes as one of a series of activities organized by the High Commission of Sri Lanka in New Delhi this year to mark the important anniversary.",
        "Earlier, in February, the High Commission named its Chancery Building after Sir D.B. Jayatilaka.",
        "Parliamentarians C.B. Rathnayake, Rohini Kumari Wijeratne, and Secretary General of Parliament Dhammika Dasanayake also attended the simple ceremony organized to unveil the portrait.",
        "The Sri Lankan Parliamentary delegation led by the Speaker was in transit in Delhi on their way back to Sri Lanka from an international conference.",
        "High Commissioner of Sri Lanka to India Milinda Moragoda and the staff of the High Commission were present on this occasion.",
        "Sir Don Baron Jayatilaka, Statesman, Buddhist Educationalist, Barrister, a pioneering literary figure of his era and one time Home Minister of Ceylon, had graduated from the Universities of Calcutta and Oxford.",
        "Sir Baron had first come to India to negotiate food shipments to Ceylon by the Government of India and was later appointed as the first Representative of the Government of Ceylon to New Delhi.",
        "The appointment of Sir D.B. Jayatilaka as Ceylon's Representative to India, which pre-dates the establishment of formal diplomatic relations between independent India and Sri Lanka in 1948, stands testimony to the very special bond and close relationship that the two countries have been enjoying since time immemorial.",
        "New Delhi can explore developing Trincomalee as an energy hub – Moragoda"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "D.B. Jayatilaka",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan HC",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "Delhi",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "D.B. Jayatilaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the High Commission of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "80th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "80th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "D.B. Jayatilaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Representative",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1942",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "D.B. Jayatilaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Chancery Building",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the High Commission of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "February",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chancery Building",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "D.B. Jayatilaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "C.B. Rathnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rohini Kumari Wijeratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Don",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayatilaka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Statesman",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Educationalist",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Barrister",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Universities of Calcutta",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oxford",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Baron",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "D.B. Jayatilaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රීමත් ඩී.බී.ගේ රුව ජයතිලක දිල්ලියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහාධිකරණයේදී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා විසින් ශ්‍රීමත් ඩී.බී. නවීන ඉන්දු-ලංකා සබඳතා ස්ථාපිත කිරීමේ 80 වැනි සංවත්සරයට සමගාමීව නවදිල්ලි නුවර ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රථම ඉන්දීය නියෝජිත ජයතිලක.",
        "මේ වසරේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව (එවකට ලංකාව) ශ්‍රීමත් ඩී.බී. ජයතිලක 1942 දී එහි ප්‍රථම නියෝජිතයා ලෙස ඉන්දියාවට පැමිණියේය. ශ්‍රීමත් ඩී.බී.ගේ රුව නිරාවරණය කරමින්. චාන්සරි ගොඩනැගිල්ලේ ජයතිලක මෙම වසරේ වැදගත් සංවත්සරය නිමිත්තෙන් නවදිල්ලියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය විසින් සංවිධානය කරන ලද ක්‍රියාකාරකම් මාලාවක් ලෙස පැමිණේ.",
        "මීට පෙර, පෙබරවාරි මාසයේදී මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය එහි චාන්සරි ගොඩනැගිල්ල නම් කළේ ශ්‍රීමත් ඩී.බී. ජයතිලකය.",
        "ආලේඛ්‍ය චිත්‍රය නිරාවරණය කිරීම වෙනුවෙන් සංවිධානය කර තිබූ චාම් උත්සවයට පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන සීබී රත්නායක, රෝහිණී කුමාරි විජේරත්න සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම් ධම්මික දසනායක ද එක්ව සිටියා.",
        "කථානායකවරයා ප්‍රමුඛ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තු දූත පිරිස ජාත්‍යන්තර සම්මන්ත්‍රණයකට සහභාගි වී ආපසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට එන අතරවාරයේදී දිල්ලි නුවරට ගමන් කරමින් සිටියහ.",
        "මෙම අවස්ථාවට ඉන්දියාවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් මිලින්ද මොරගොඩ මහතා ඇතුළු මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලයේ කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය එක්ව සිටියහ.",
        "ශ්‍රීමත් දොන් බාරොන් ජයතිලක, රාජ්‍ය පාලක, බෞද්ධ අධ්‍යාපනඥ, බැරිස්ටර්, ඔහුගේ යුගයේ පුරෝගාමී සාහිත්‍යවේදියෙකු සහ වරෙක ලංකාවේ ස්වදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යවරයා, කල්කටා සහ ඔක්ස්ෆර්ඩ් විශ්ව විද්‍යාලවලින් උපාධිය ලබා ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රීමත් බාරොන් ප්‍රථමයෙන් ඉන්දියාවට පැමිණ ඇත්තේ ඉන්දීය රජය විසින් ලංකාවට ආහාර නැව්ගත කිරීම පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා වන අතර පසුව ඔහුව නවදිල්ලියේ ලංකා රජයේ පළමු නියෝජිතයා ලෙස පත් කරන ලදී.",
        "ශ්‍රීමත් ඩී.බී. 1948 දී නිදහස් ඉන්දියාව සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර විධිමත් රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික සබඳතා පිහිටුවීමට පෙරාතුව ඉන්දියාවේ ලංකා නියෝජිතයා ලෙස ජයතිලක මහතා, දෙරට අනාදිමත් කාලයක සිට භුක්ති විඳින ඉතා සුවිශේෂී බැඳීම සහ සමීප සබඳතාවයට සාක්ෂි දරයි.",
        "නව දිල්ලියට ත්‍රිකුණාමලය බලශක්ති කේන්ද්‍රස්ථානයක් ලෙස සංවර්ධනය කිරීම ගවේෂණය කළ හැකිය - මොරගොඩ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩී.බී. ජයතිලකය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා එච්.සී",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "දිල්ලිය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.බී. ජයතිලකය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "80 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "80 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.බී. ජයතිලකය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නියෝජිතයා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1942",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.බී. ජයතිලකය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චාන්සරි ගොඩනැගිල්ල",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෙබරවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ කොමසාරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චාන්සරි ගොඩනැගිල්ල",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.බී. ජයතිලකය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සී බී රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෝහිණී කුමාරි විජේරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිල්ලිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දොන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයතිලකය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය පාලකයා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්‍යාපනඥයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැරිස්ටර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කල්කටා විශ්ව විද්‍යාල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔක්ස්ෆර්ඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බාරොන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩී.බී. ජයතිලකය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சர் டி.பி.யின் உருவப்படம். டெல்லியில் உள்ள இலங்கை உயர்நீதிமன்றத்தில் ஜெயதிலகா",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் சபாநாயகர் மகிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன சேர் டி.பி.யின் உருவப்படத்தை திறந்து வைத்தார். ஜயதிலக, புதுடெல்லியில் உள்ள இலங்கை உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயத்தில் இந்தியாவுக்கான இலங்கையின் முதல் பிரதிநிதி, நவீன இந்திய-இலங்கை உறவுகள் ஸ்தாபிக்கப்பட்ட 80 வது ஆண்டு நிறைவை ஒட்டி.",
        "இந்த ஆண்டு இலங்கையின் (அப்போதைய சிலோன்) 80வது ஆண்டு நிறைவைக் குறிக்கிறது. ஜயதிலக 1942 இல் இந்தியாவுக்கான அதன் முதல் பிரதிநிதியாக. சர் டி.பி.யின் உருவப்படத்தை திறந்து வைத்தார். இந்த ஆண்டு புதுடெல்லியில் உள்ள இலங்கை உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயத்தால் ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்ட முக்கியமான ஆண்டு நிறைவைக் குறிக்கும் வகையில், சான்சரி கட்டிடத்தில் உள்ள ஜயதிலக்க ஒரு தொடர் நடவடிக்கைகளில் ஒன்றாகும்.",
        "முன்னதாக, பிப்ரவரியில், உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம் அதன் சான்சரி கட்டிடத்திற்கு சர் டி.பி. ஜயதிலக.",
        "சிபி ரத்நாயக்க, ரோஹினி குமாரி விஜேரத்ன மற்றும் பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க ஆகியோரும் இந்த உருவப்படத்தை திறந்து வைக்கும் நிகழ்வில் கலந்து கொண்டனர்.",
        "சபாநாயகர் தலைமையிலான இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்றக் குழு சர்வதேச மாநாட்டில் கலந்து கொண்டு இலங்கை திரும்பும் வழியில் டெல்லியில் பயணித்துக் கொண்டிருந்தது.",
        "இந்தியாவுக்கான இலங்கை உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் மிலிந்த மொரகொட மற்றும் உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலய ஊழியர்கள் இந்த நிகழ்வில் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "சர் டான் பரோன் ஜயதிலக, ஸ்டேட்ஸ்மேன், பௌத்த கல்வியாளர், பாரிஸ்டர், அவரது சகாப்தத்தின் முன்னோடி இலக்கியவாதி மற்றும் ஒரு காலத்தில் இலங்கையின் உள்துறை அமைச்சராக இருந்தவர், கல்கத்தா மற்றும் ஆக்ஸ்போர்டு பல்கலைக்கழகங்களில் பட்டம் பெற்றவர்.",
        "சர் பரோன் முதன்முதலில் இந்திய அரசாங்கத்தால் இலங்கைக்கான உணவுப் பொருட்களைப் பற்றி பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்துவதற்காக இந்தியாவிற்கு வந்திருந்தார், பின்னர் புதுதில்லிக்கான இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தின் முதல் பிரதிநிதியாக நியமிக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "சர் டி.பி.யின் நியமனம். 1948 ஆம் ஆண்டு சுதந்திர இந்தியாவிற்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையில் முறையான இராஜதந்திர உறவுகளை ஸ்தாபிப்பதற்கு முற்பட்ட இந்தியாவிற்கான இலங்கையின் பிரதிநிதியாக ஜயதிலக்க, இரு நாடுகளும் காலங்காலமாக அனுபவித்து வரும் மிகவும் சிறப்பான பிணைப்பு மற்றும் நெருக்கமான உறவுக்கு சாட்சியாக நிற்கிறார்.",
        "திருகோணமலையை ஆற்றல் மையமாக - மொரகொடவாக அபிவிருத்தி செய்வதை புது தில்லி ஆராய முடியும்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டி.பி. ஜயதிலக",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை உயர் நீதிமன்றம்",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "டெல்லி",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.பி. ஜயதிலக",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "80வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "80வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.பி. ஜயதிலக",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரதிநிதி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1942",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.பி. ஜயதிலக",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சான்சரி கட்டிடம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிப்ரவரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உயர் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சான்சரி கட்டிடம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.பி. ஜயதிலக",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.பி.ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோஹினி குமாரி விஜேரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டெல்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தாதா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜயதிலக",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்டேட்ஸ்மேன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்வியாளர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ்டர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிலோன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்கத்தா பல்கலைக்கழகங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆக்ஸ்போர்டு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பரோன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டி.பி. ஜயதிலக",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிலோன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}