{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/කෝටි-24-කොකේන්-සමග-පෝලන්ත-ජාතිකයා-මාට්ටු/1-618241",
  "time_ut": 1660702052,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කෝටි 24 කොකේන් සමග පෝලන්ත ජාතිකයා මාට්ටු",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Polish man caught with 24 crores of cocaine",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Sudatta Silva, Customs Media Spokesman, Deputy Director of Customs (Legal Affairs) said that a Polish national has been arrested with a cocaine drug stock with a street value of 24 crores and 50 lakh rupees.",
        "He had come from Colombia to Doha, Qatar and from there he had arrived at Katunayake Airport by Qatar Airways flight.",
        "But because he could not find the suitcase he had brought at that time, when he came back to Katunayake Airport to take the suitcase, the officials of the Customs Drug Control Division, who were suspicious about the suitcase, found a used fax machine inside. In several rolls of paper, this cocaine drug stock weighing 05 kg was found while being hidden.",
        "At present, after arresting this stock of drugs and the Polish national who illegally brought them to Sri Lanka, the officers of the Customs Narcotics Control Division have handed them over to the officers of the Police Narcotics Division for further investigations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Polish",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "24",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sudatta Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Customs (Legal Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polish",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Doha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar Airways",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Katunayake Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Customs Drug Control Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "05 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Polish",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Customs Narcotics Control Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Police Narcotics Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කෝටි 24 කොකේන් සමග පෝලන්ත ජාතිකයා මාට්ටු",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රුපියල් විසි හතර කෝටි පනස් ලක්ෂයක් පමණ වීදි වටිනා කමක් ඇති කොකේන් මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය තොගයක් සමග පෝලන්ත ජාතිකයකු  අත් අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති බව රේගු මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක , නියෝජ්‍ය රේගු අධ්‍යක්ෂ ( නීති කටයුතු ) සුදත්ත සිල්වා මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය .",
        "කොලොම්බියාවේ සිට කටාර් රාජ්‍යයේ දෝහා වෙත පැමිණ එතැන් සිට කටාර් ගුවන් සේවයේ ගුවන් යානයෙන් කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ වෙත පැමිණ තිබුණි .",
        "එහෙත් මොහු රැගෙන ආ ගමන් මල්ල එම අවස්ථාවේ ඔහුට සොයා ගැනීමට නොහැකි වූ නිසා , එම ගමන් මල්ල රැගෙන යාම සදහා  යළිත් කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ වෙත පැමිණි අවස්ථාවේ මෙම ගමන් මල්ල පිළිබඳව සැක සිතූ රේගු මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය පාලන අංශයේ නිලධාරීන් එය පරීක්ෂාවට ලක් කිරීමේදී ,  පාවිච්චි කළ ෆැක්ස් යන්ත්‍රයක් තුළ වූ කඩදාසි රෝල් කීපයක , මෙම කිලෝ ග්රැම් 05 ක් බරැති කොකේන් මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය තොගය සගවා තිබියදී සොයා ගැනීමට සමත් වී තිබුණි .",
        "මේ වනවිට මෙම මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය තොගය සහ ඒවා නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස මෙරටට ගෙන ආ පෝලන්ත ජාතිකයා ද අත් අඩංගුවට ගැනීමෙන් අනතුරුව වැඩිදුර විමර්ශන කටයුතු සදහා රේගු මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය පාලන අංශයේ නිලධාරීන් විසින් පොලිස් මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය නාශක අංශයේ නිලධාරීන් වෙත භාර දී තිබේ ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පෝලන්ත",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "24",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සුදත්ත සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රේගු (නීති කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොලොම්බියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෝහා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර් එයාර්වේස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රේගු ඖෂධ පාලන අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 05 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රේගු මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය පාලන අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය නාශක අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "24 கோடி கொக்கைன் போதைப்பொருளுடன் போலந்து நாட்டைச் சேர்ந்தவர் பிடிபட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "24 கோடியே 50 இலட்சம் ரூபா பெறுமதியான கொக்கெய்ன் போதைப்பொருளுடன் போலந்து பிரஜை ஒருவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக சுங்க ஊடகப் பேச்சாளரான சுங்க ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர் (சட்ட விவகாரங்கள்) பிரதிப் பணிப்பாளர் திரு.சுதத்த சில்வா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கொலம்பியாவில் இருந்து கத்தாரின் தோஹாவுக்கு வந்திருந்த அவர், அங்கிருந்து கட்டார் ஏர்வேஸ் விமானம் மூலம் கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையத்தை வந்தடைந்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஆனால் அப்போது அவர் கொண்டு வந்த சூட்கேஸை காணாததால் மீண்டும் கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையத்திற்கு சூட்கேஸை எடுத்துச் செல்ல வந்த போது, ​​சூட்கேஸ் மீது சந்தேகம் அடைந்த சுங்க போதைப்பொருள் கட்டுப்பாட்டு பிரிவு அதிகாரிகள், உள்ளே பயன்படுத்தப்பட்ட தொலைநகல் இயந்திரம் இருப்பதை கண்டனர். பல காகிதச் சுருள்களில், 05 கிலோ எடையுள்ள இந்த கொக்கெய்ன் போதைப்பொருள் மறைத்து வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த போது கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "தற்போது, ​​இந்த போதைப்பொருளையும் சட்டவிரோதமாக இலங்கைக்கு கொண்டு வந்த போலந்து பிரஜையையும் கைது செய்த சுங்க போதைப்பொருள் கட்டுப்பாட்டு பிரிவின் அதிகாரிகள், மேலதிக விசாரணைகளுக்காக பொலிஸ் போதைப்பொருள் தடுப்பு பிரிவின் அதிகாரிகளிடம் ஒப்படைத்துள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "போலிஷ்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "24",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சுதத்த சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுங்கம் (சட்ட விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "போலிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொலம்பியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தோஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் ஏர்வேஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுங்க மருந்து கட்டுப்பாட்டு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "05 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "போலிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுங்க போதைப்பொருள் கட்டுப்பாட்டு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலிஸ் போதைப்பொருள் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}