{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/දිසා-කීපයකට-ගංවතුර-අවදානමක්/101-619076",
  "time_ut": 1661942049,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "දිසා කීපයකට ගංවතුර අවදානමක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "There is a risk of flooding in several areas",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Irrigation Department says that there is a risk of flooding in many low-lying areas of Ratnapura district as the downstream areas of the Kalu Ganga basin have received high rainfall.",
        "Director of Irrigation (Hydrology and Disaster Management) Engineer S.P. said that there may be a risk of flood today (31) or tomorrow (1) in the lowlands belonging to the Kalu Ganga plain in the divisional secretaries of Pelmadulla, Nivitigala, Ratnapura, Kuruvita, Ayagama and Alapatha in that district. Mr. C. Sugeeshwara said.",
        "The District Disaster Management Center says that the heavy rain in Kalutara district is flooding the main road and side roads.",
        "Ms. Sarangi Dhiraratne, Palindanuwara Divisional Secretary, said that many roads have been submerged due to the overflowing of the Maguru River."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Irrigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalu Ganga",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Irrigation (Hydrology and Disaster Management",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalu Ganga",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pelmadulla",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nivitigala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kuruvita",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ayagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alapatha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "C. Sugeeshwara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The District Disaster Management Center",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalutara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sarangi Dhiraratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Maguru River",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දිසා කීපයකට ගංවතුර අවදානමක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කළු ගඟ ද්‍රෝණියේ ධාරා ප්‍රදේශවලට ඉහළ වර්ෂාපතනයක් ලැබී ඇති බැවින් රත්නපුර දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ පහත් බිම් ගණනාවකට ගං වතුර අවදානමක් පවතින බව වාරිමාර්ග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "එම දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ පැල්මඩුල්ල, නිවිතිගල, රත්නපුර, කුරුවිට, අයගම සහ ඇලපාත යන ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කොට්ඨාශයන්හි කළු ගඟ තැන්නට අයත් පහත්බිම්වල අද (31) හෝ හෙට (1) ගං වතුර අවදානමක් මතුවිය හැකි බව වාරිමාර්ග අධ්‍යක්‍ෂ (ජල විද්‍යා හා ආපදා කළමනාකරණ) ඉංජිනේරු එස්.පී.සී සුගීෂ්වර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "කළුතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කයට ද පවතින අධික වර්ෂාව  ප්‍රධාන මාර්ගය සහ අතුරු මාර්ග ජලයෙන් යටවෙමින් පවතින බව දිස්ත්‍රික් ආපදා කළමනාකරණ මධ්‍යස්ථානය කියයි.",
        "මගුරු ගඟ පිටාර ගැලීම නිසා මාර්ග රැසක් යටවී ඇති බව පාලින්දනුවර ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් සාරංගී ධීරරත්න මහත්මිය පැවසුවාය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වාරිමාර්ග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළු ගඟ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වාරිමාර්ග (ජල විද්‍යාව සහ ආපදා කළමනාකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළු ගඟ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැල්මඩුල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවිතිගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුවිට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලපාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සී සුගීෂ්වර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිස්ත්‍රික් ආපදා කළමනාකරණ මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සාරංගි ධිරරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Maguru River",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பல பகுதிகளில் வெள்ள அபாயம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இரத்தினபுரி மாவட்டத்தின் களுகங்கைப் படுகையின் கீழ்பகுதிகளில் அதிக மழைவீழ்ச்சி பதிவாகியுள்ளதால் பல தாழ்நிலப் பிரதேசங்கள் வெள்ளத்தில் மூழ்கும் அபாயம் உள்ளதாக நீர்ப்பாசனத் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "பெல்மடுல்ல, நிவித்திகல, இரத்தினபுரி, குருவிட்ட ஆகிய பிரதேச செயலாளர்களுக்கு உட்பட்ட களுகங்கை சமவெளிக்கு உட்பட்ட தாழ்நிலங்களில் இன்று (31) அல்லது நாளை (1) வெள்ள அபாயம் ஏற்படக்கூடும் என நீர்ப்பாசன பணிப்பாளர் (நீரியல் மற்றும் அனர்த்த முகாமைத்துவ) பொறியியலாளர் எஸ்.பி. , அயகம மற்றும் அலபத அந்த மாவட்டத்தில் திரு.சி.சுகீஸ்வர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "களுத்துறை மாவட்டத்தில் பெய்து வரும் கடும் மழை காரணமாக பிரதான வீதி மற்றும் பக்க வீதிகள் வெள்ளத்தில் மூழ்கியுள்ளதாக மாவட்ட அனர்த்த முகாமைத்துவ நிலையம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மகுரு ஆறு பெருக்கெடுத்து ஓடுவதால் பல வீதிகள் நீரில் மூழ்கியுள்ளதாக பாலிந்தநுவர பிரதேச செயலாளர் திருமதி சாரங்கி திரரத்ன தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நீர்ப்பாசன திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "களு கங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நீர்ப்பாசனம் (நீரியல் மற்றும் பேரிடர் மேலாண்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "களு கங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெல்மதுல்லா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிவிதிகல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருவிட",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அயகம",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலபத",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.சுகீஸ்வரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாவட்ட பேரிடர் மேலாண்மை மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாரங்கி திரரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Maguru River",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}