{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/indian-shipment-of-rice-milk-powder-medicines-worth-3bn-arrive-in-sri-lanka-96403/",
  "time_ut": 1656055680,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Indian shipment of rice, milk powder, medicines worth 3bn arrive in Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Indian shipment of rice, milk powder, medicines worth 3bn arrive in Sri Lanka",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – A 15,000-metric ton shipment of rice, milk powder and essential medicines worth over three billion Sri Lankan rupees arrived in Colombo as part of a Indian humanitarian aid package to cash-strapped Sri Lanka as the island nation goes through its worst ever forex crisis.",
        "The Indian High Commission in Sri Lanka tweeted Friday June 24 afternoon that more aid will follow.",
        "From the people of #India to the people of #SriLanka!!! High Commissioner,Hon'ble Ministers @Keheliya_R, Nalin Fernando, MPs, various dignitaries and officials welcomed a large humanitarian consignment worth more than SLR 3 billion from #Tuticorn today. (1/2) pic.twitter.com/pMOF8kJppx",
        "This is the second such shipment to arrive from Tamil Nadu, India, since Sri Lanka defaulted on foreign debt as the country’s foreign reserves depleted making it difficult to pay for imports including essentials.",
        "Indian shipment of rice, milk powder, medicines worth 2bn arrive in Sri Lanka",
        "Friday’s donation, worth over 8.3 million US dollars, was ceremoniously handed over to Health Minister Keheliya Rambukwella, Minister of Trade, Commerce and Food Security Nalin Fernando and other officials.",
        "Indian media reported that the shipment had set off from Tuticorin on Wednesday June 22.",
        "The Tamil Nadu state assembly passed a resolution on April 29 to provide assistance to Sri Lanka. The Times of India reported that the Tamil Nadu government has promised total aid worth over 15.7 million US dollars. (Colombo/Jun24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "3bn",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "15,000-metric ton",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "over three billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Indian High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday June 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hon'ble Ministers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuticorn",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1/2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2bn",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.3 million US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Keheliya Rambukwella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commerce",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Food Security",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuticorin",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday June 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "April 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Times of India",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15.7 million US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jun24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බිලියන 3ක් වටිනා සහල්, කිරිපිටි, ඖෂධ ඉන්දියාවෙන් ලංකාවට එයි",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - දිවයිනේ ජාතිය එහි නරකම විදේශ විනිමය හරහා ගමන් කරන විට මුදල් හිඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඉන්දියානු මානුෂීය ආධාර පැකේජයක කොටසක් ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා රුපියල් බිලියන තුනකට වඩා වටිනා සහල්, කිරිපිටි සහ අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ඖෂධ මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 15,000ක නැව්ගත කිරීමක් කොළඹට පැමිණියේය. අර්බුදය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය ජුනි 24 සිකුරාදා සවස ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ තවත් ආධාර ලැබෙන බවයි.",
        "#ඉන්දියාවේ මිනිසුන්ගෙන් #ශ්‍රීලංකාවේ මිනිසුන්ට!!! මහ කොමසාරිස්,ගරු අමාත්‍යවරුන් වන @කෙහෙළිය_ආර්, නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු, මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්, විවිධ සම්භාවනීය අමුත්තන් සහ නිලධාරීන් විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා රුපියල් බිලියන 3 කට වැඩි වටිනාකමකින් යුත් විශාල මානුෂීය තොගයක් අද #Tuticorn වෙතින් පිළිගනු ලැබීය. (1/2) pic.twitter.com/pMOF8kJppx",
        "අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය ඇතුළු ආනයන සඳහා ගෙවීමට අපහසු වන පරිදි රටේ විදේශ සංචිත ක්‍ෂය වීම නිසා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව විදේශ ණය පැහැර හැරීම නිසා ඉන්දියාවේ තමිල්නාඩුවෙන් පැමිණෙන එවැනි දෙවන නැව්ගත කිරීම මෙයයි.",
        "බිලියන 2ක් වටිනා සහල්, කිරිපිටි, ඖෂධ ඉන්දියාවෙන් ලංකාවට එයි",
        "ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 8.3 කට අධික වටිනාකමකින් යුත් සිකුරාදා පරිත්‍යාගය සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය කෙහෙළිය රඹුක්වැල්ල, වෙළඳ, වාණිජ හා ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතා අමාත්‍ය නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු ඇතුළු නිලධාරීන් වෙත උත්සවාකාරයෙන් භාර දෙන ලදී.",
        "ජුනි 22 බදාදා තූත්තුකුඩියෙන් නැව්ගත කර ඇති බව ඉන්දීය මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "තමිල්නාඩු ප්‍රාන්ත සභාව අප්‍රේල් 29 දා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ආධාර ලබාදීමේ යෝජනාවක් සම්මත කළේය. ටයිම්ස් ඔෆ් ඉන්දියා වාර්තා කළේ තමිල්නාඩු රජය ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 15.7 කට වැඩි සම්පූර්ණ ආධාරයක් ලබා දෙන බවට පොරොන්දු වී ඇති බවයි. (කොළඹ/ජුනි24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "බිලියන 3ක්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙට්රික් ටොන් 15,000",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන තුනකට වඩා",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 24 සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගරු ඇමතිතුමනි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuticorn",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1/2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 2ක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 8.3 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්යය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙහෙළිය රඹුක්වැල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාණිජ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "තූත්තුකුඩිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 22 බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටයිම්ස් ඔෆ් ඉන්දියා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 15.7 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජුනි24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "3 பில்லியன் பெறுமதியான அரிசி, பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் மருந்துப் பொருட்கள் இலங்கைக்கு இந்திய ஏற்றுமதி",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - தீவு நாடு அதன் மோசமான அந்நிய செலாவணியை கடந்து செல்லும் போது பண நெருக்கடியில் உள்ள இலங்கைக்கான இந்திய மனிதாபிமான உதவிப் பொதியின் ஒரு பகுதியாக மூன்று பில்லியன் இலங்கை ரூபாய் மதிப்புள்ள அரிசி, பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் அத்தியாவசிய மருந்துகளின் 15,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் ஏற்றுமதி கொழும்பு வந்தடைந்தது. நெருக்கடி.",
        "இலங்கையில் உள்ள இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயம் ஜூன் 24 வெள்ளிக்கிழமை பிற்பகல் ட்வீட் செய்தது, மேலும் உதவிகள் தொடரும்.",
        "#இந்திய மக்களிடம் இருந்து #இலங்கை மக்கள் வரை!!! உயர்ஸ்தானிகர், மாண்புமிகு அமைச்சர்கள் @கெஹலிய_ஆர், நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ, பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள், பல்வேறு பிரமுகர்கள் மற்றும் அதிகாரிகள் இன்று தூத்துக்குடியிலிருந்து SLR 3 பில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான பெறுமதியான மனிதாபிமானப் பொருட்களை வரவேற்றனர். (1/2) pic.twitter.com/pMOF8kJppx",
        "இலங்கை வெளிநாட்டுக் கடனைத் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தாததால், நாட்டின் வெளிநாட்டு கையிருப்பு குறைந்து, அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்கள் உள்ளிட்ட இறக்குமதிகளுக்குச் செலுத்துவதில் சிரமம் ஏற்பட்டதால், இந்தியாவின் தமிழ்நாட்டிலிருந்து வரும் இதுபோன்ற இரண்டாவது ஏற்றுமதி இதுவாகும்.",
        "2 பில்லியன் பெறுமதியான அரிசி, பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் மருந்துகள் இலங்கைக்கு இந்திய ஏற்றுமதி",
        "8.3 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர் பெறுமதியான வெள்ளிக்கிழமை நன்கொடை சுகாதார அமைச்சர் கெஹலிய ரம்புக்வெல்ல, வர்த்தக, வர்த்தக மற்றும் உணவு பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சர் நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ மற்றும் ஏனைய அதிகாரிகளிடம் சம்பிரதாயபூர்வமாக கையளிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "ஜூன் 22 புதன்கிழமை தூத்துக்குடியில் இருந்து கப்பல் புறப்பட்டதாக இந்திய ஊடகங்கள் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளன.",
        "இலங்கைக்கு உதவி வழங்குவது தொடர்பாக தமிழ்நாடு மாநில சட்டசபையில் கடந்த ஏப்ரல் 29ம் தேதி தீர்மானம் நிறைவேற்றப்பட்டது. 15.7 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர் மதிப்பிலான மொத்த உதவியை தமிழக அரசு உறுதியளித்துள்ளதாக டைம்ஸ் ஆஃப் இந்தியா செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூன்24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "3 பில்லியன்",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "15,000-மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று பில்லியன்களுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 24 வெள்ளிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாண்புமிகு அமைச்சர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தூத்துக்குடி",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1/2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.3 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆரோக்கியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெஹலிய ரம்புக்வெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வர்த்தகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உணவு பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தூத்துக்குடி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 22 புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டைம்ஸ் ஆஃப் இந்தியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15.7 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூன்24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Indian shipment of rice, milk powder, medicines worth 3bn arrive in Sri Lanka",
  "body_lines": [
    "ECONOMYNEXT – A 15,000-metric ton shipment of rice, milk powder and essential medicines worth over three billion Sri Lankan rupees arrived in Colombo as part of a Indian humanitarian aid package to cash-strapped Sri Lanka as the island nation goes through its worst ever forex crisis.",
    "The Indian High Commission in Sri Lanka tweeted Friday June 24 afternoon that more aid will follow.",
    "From the people of #India to the people of #SriLanka!!! High Commissioner,Hon'ble Ministers @Keheliya_R, Nalin Fernando, MPs, various dignitaries and officials welcomed a large humanitarian consignment worth more than SLR 3 billion from #Tuticorn today. (1/2) pic.twitter.com/pMOF8kJppx",
    "This is the second such shipment to arrive from Tamil Nadu, India, since Sri Lanka defaulted on foreign debt as the country’s foreign reserves depleted making it difficult to pay for imports including essentials.",
    "Indian shipment of rice, milk powder, medicines worth 2bn arrive in Sri Lanka",
    "Friday’s donation, worth over 8.3 million US dollars, was ceremoniously handed over to Health Minister Keheliya Rambukwella, Minister of Trade, Commerce and Food Security Nalin Fernando and other officials.",
    "Indian media reported that the shipment had set off from Tuticorin on Wednesday June 22.",
    "The Tamil Nadu state assembly passed a resolution on April 29 to provide assistance to Sri Lanka. The Times of India reported that the Tamil Nadu government has promised total aid worth over 15.7 million US dollars. (Colombo/Jun24/2022)"
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Indian shipment of rice, milk powder, medicines worth 3bn arrive in Sri Lanka",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – A 15,000-metric ton shipment of rice, milk powder and essential medicines worth over three billion Sri Lankan rupees arrived in Colombo as part of a Indian humanitarian aid package to cash-strapped Sri Lanka as the island nation goes through its worst ever forex crisis.",
        "The Indian High Commission in Sri Lanka tweeted Friday June 24 afternoon that more aid will follow.",
        "From the people of #India to the people of #SriLanka!!! High Commissioner,Hon'ble Ministers @Keheliya_R, Nalin Fernando, MPs, various dignitaries and officials welcomed a large humanitarian consignment worth more than SLR 3 billion from #Tuticorn today. (1/2) pic.twitter.com/pMOF8kJppx",
        "This is the second such shipment to arrive from Tamil Nadu, India, since Sri Lanka defaulted on foreign debt as the country’s foreign reserves depleted making it difficult to pay for imports including essentials.",
        "Indian shipment of rice, milk powder, medicines worth 2bn arrive in Sri Lanka",
        "Friday’s donation, worth over 8.3 million US dollars, was ceremoniously handed over to Health Minister Keheliya Rambukwella, Minister of Trade, Commerce and Food Security Nalin Fernando and other officials.",
        "Indian media reported that the shipment had set off from Tuticorin on Wednesday June 22.",
        "The Tamil Nadu state assembly passed a resolution on April 29 to provide assistance to Sri Lanka. The Times of India reported that the Tamil Nadu government has promised total aid worth over 15.7 million US dollars. (Colombo/Jun24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "3bn",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "15,000-metric ton",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "over three billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Indian High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday June 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hon'ble Ministers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuticorn",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1/2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2bn",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.3 million US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Keheliya Rambukwella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commerce",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Food Security",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuticorin",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday June 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "April 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Times of India",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15.7 million US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jun24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බිලියන 3ක් වටිනා සහල්, කිරිපිටි, ඖෂධ ඉන්දියාවෙන් ලංකාවට එයි",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - දිවයිනේ ජාතිය එහි නරකම විදේශ විනිමය හරහා ගමන් කරන විට මුදල් හිඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඉන්දියානු මානුෂීය ආධාර පැකේජයක කොටසක් ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා රුපියල් බිලියන තුනකට වඩා වටිනා සහල්, කිරිපිටි සහ අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ඖෂධ මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 15,000ක නැව්ගත කිරීමක් කොළඹට පැමිණියේය. අර්බුදය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය ජුනි 24 සිකුරාදා සවස ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ තවත් ආධාර ලැබෙන බවයි.",
        "#ඉන්දියාවේ මිනිසුන්ගෙන් #ශ්‍රීලංකාවේ මිනිසුන්ට!!! මහ කොමසාරිස්,ගරු අමාත්‍යවරුන් වන @කෙහෙළිය_ආර්, නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු, මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්, විවිධ සම්භාවනීය අමුත්තන් සහ නිලධාරීන් විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා රුපියල් බිලියන 3 කට වැඩි වටිනාකමකින් යුත් විශාල මානුෂීය තොගයක් අද #Tuticorn වෙතින් පිළිගනු ලැබීය. (1/2) pic.twitter.com/pMOF8kJppx",
        "අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය ඇතුළු ආනයන සඳහා ගෙවීමට අපහසු වන පරිදි රටේ විදේශ සංචිත ක්‍ෂය වීම නිසා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව විදේශ ණය පැහැර හැරීම නිසා ඉන්දියාවේ තමිල්නාඩුවෙන් පැමිණෙන එවැනි දෙවන නැව්ගත කිරීම මෙයයි.",
        "බිලියන 2ක් වටිනා සහල්, කිරිපිටි, ඖෂධ ඉන්දියාවෙන් ලංකාවට එයි",
        "ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 8.3 කට අධික වටිනාකමකින් යුත් සිකුරාදා පරිත්‍යාගය සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය කෙහෙළිය රඹුක්වැල්ල, වෙළඳ, වාණිජ හා ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතා අමාත්‍ය නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු ඇතුළු නිලධාරීන් වෙත උත්සවාකාරයෙන් භාර දෙන ලදී.",
        "ජුනි 22 බදාදා තූත්තුකුඩියෙන් නැව්ගත කර ඇති බව ඉන්දීය මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "තමිල්නාඩු ප්‍රාන්ත සභාව අප්‍රේල් 29 දා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ආධාර ලබාදීමේ යෝජනාවක් සම්මත කළේය. ටයිම්ස් ඔෆ් ඉන්දියා වාර්තා කළේ තමිල්නාඩු රජය ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 15.7 කට වැඩි සම්පූර්ණ ආධාරයක් ලබා දෙන බවට පොරොන්දු වී ඇති බවයි. (කොළඹ/ජුනි24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "බිලියන 3ක්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙට්රික් ටොන් 15,000",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන තුනකට වඩා",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 24 සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගරු ඇමතිතුමනි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuticorn",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1/2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 2ක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 8.3 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්යය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙහෙළිය රඹුක්වැල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාණිජ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "තූත්තුකුඩිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 22 බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටයිම්ස් ඔෆ් ඉන්දියා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 15.7 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජුනි24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "3 பில்லியன் பெறுமதியான அரிசி, பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் மருந்துப் பொருட்கள் இலங்கைக்கு இந்திய ஏற்றுமதி",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - தீவு நாடு அதன் மோசமான அந்நிய செலாவணியை கடந்து செல்லும் போது பண நெருக்கடியில் உள்ள இலங்கைக்கான இந்திய மனிதாபிமான உதவிப் பொதியின் ஒரு பகுதியாக மூன்று பில்லியன் இலங்கை ரூபாய் மதிப்புள்ள அரிசி, பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் அத்தியாவசிய மருந்துகளின் 15,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் ஏற்றுமதி கொழும்பு வந்தடைந்தது. நெருக்கடி.",
        "இலங்கையில் உள்ள இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயம் ஜூன் 24 வெள்ளிக்கிழமை பிற்பகல் ட்வீட் செய்தது, மேலும் உதவிகள் தொடரும்.",
        "#இந்திய மக்களிடம் இருந்து #இலங்கை மக்கள் வரை!!! உயர்ஸ்தானிகர், மாண்புமிகு அமைச்சர்கள் @கெஹலிய_ஆர், நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ, பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள், பல்வேறு பிரமுகர்கள் மற்றும் அதிகாரிகள் இன்று தூத்துக்குடியிலிருந்து SLR 3 பில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான பெறுமதியான மனிதாபிமானப் பொருட்களை வரவேற்றனர். (1/2) pic.twitter.com/pMOF8kJppx",
        "இலங்கை வெளிநாட்டுக் கடனைத் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தாததால், நாட்டின் வெளிநாட்டு கையிருப்பு குறைந்து, அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்கள் உள்ளிட்ட இறக்குமதிகளுக்குச் செலுத்துவதில் சிரமம் ஏற்பட்டதால், இந்தியாவின் தமிழ்நாட்டிலிருந்து வரும் இதுபோன்ற இரண்டாவது ஏற்றுமதி இதுவாகும்.",
        "2 பில்லியன் பெறுமதியான அரிசி, பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் மருந்துகள் இலங்கைக்கு இந்திய ஏற்றுமதி",
        "8.3 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர் பெறுமதியான வெள்ளிக்கிழமை நன்கொடை சுகாதார அமைச்சர் கெஹலிய ரம்புக்வெல்ல, வர்த்தக, வர்த்தக மற்றும் உணவு பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சர் நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ மற்றும் ஏனைய அதிகாரிகளிடம் சம்பிரதாயபூர்வமாக கையளிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "ஜூன் 22 புதன்கிழமை தூத்துக்குடியில் இருந்து கப்பல் புறப்பட்டதாக இந்திய ஊடகங்கள் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளன.",
        "இலங்கைக்கு உதவி வழங்குவது தொடர்பாக தமிழ்நாடு மாநில சட்டசபையில் கடந்த ஏப்ரல் 29ம் தேதி தீர்மானம் நிறைவேற்றப்பட்டது. 15.7 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர் மதிப்பிலான மொத்த உதவியை தமிழக அரசு உறுதியளித்துள்ளதாக டைம்ஸ் ஆஃப் இந்தியா செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூன்24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "3 பில்லியன்",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "15,000-மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று பில்லியன்களுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 24 வெள்ளிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாண்புமிகு அமைச்சர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தூத்துக்குடி",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1/2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.3 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆரோக்கியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெஹலிய ரம்புக்வெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வர்த்தகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உணவு பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தூத்துக்குடி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 22 புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டைம்ஸ் ஆஃப் இந்தியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15.7 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூன்24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}