{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/peoples-bank-commemorates-its-61st-anniversary/",
  "time_ut": 1656843600,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "People’s Bank commemorates its 61st anniversary",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "People’s Bank commemorates its 61st anniversary",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "People’s Bank, held a modest ceremony to on 1st July to commemorate their 61st anniversary at the bank’s Head Office in Colombo 02. Chairman of the People’s Bank Sujeewa Rajapakse and CEO/General Manager Ranjith Kodituwakku addressed the staff at this event.",
        "In addition, Religious programs were organized by the Buddhist Association, Hindu Association, Muslim Majlis and the Christians Guild of the People’s Bank to invoke blessings on the country, the people, the customers and the pioneering leaders who have contributed to establish the People’s Bank.",
        "Accordingly, a Pirith chanting was held at the Head Office which was followed by an alms giving at Sambodhi Viharaya in Fort with the patronage of Chief Incumbent Most Ven. Professor Iththademaliye Indhasara Thero. Hindu pooja was conducted by Sri Nivasa Kurukkal, Bambalapitiya, Islamic Service conducted by Deshabandu Al Haj Faisal Hassan mowlavi at Dawatagaha Jumma mosque in Colombo and the holy mass was conducted by Rev. Father Anton Rohitha at St. Philip Mary’s church in Pettah.People’s Bank Corporate and Executive Management, bank staffs and retired employees were also present at the occasion.",
        "Iroshini Wijenayaka of Ideal Group represents Sri Lanka at World Women Leadership Congress",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "People’s Bank",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "61st anniversary",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "People’s Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1st July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "61st",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the People’s Bank Sujeewa Rajapakse",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Kodituwakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Buddhist Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muslim",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Christians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the People’s Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the People’s Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Head Office",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sambodhi Viharaya",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fort",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Iththademaliye Indhasara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Nivasa Kurukkal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bambalapitiya, Islamic Service",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Deshabandu Al Haj Faisal Hassan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dawatagaha Jumma",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anton Rohitha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "St. Philip Mary’s",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pettah",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "People’s Bank Corporate and Executive Management",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Iroshini Wijenayaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ideal Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "World Women Leadership Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මහජන බැංකුව සිය 61 වැනි සංවත්සරය සමරයි",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "මහජන බැංකුව, ඔවුන්ගේ 61 වැනි සංවත්සරය නිමිත්තෙන් ජුලි 01 වැනි දින දක්වා කොළඹ 02 පිහිටි බැංකු ප්‍රධාන කාර්යාලයේදී චාම් උත්සවයක් පැවැත්විණි. මෙම අවස්ථාවට මහජන බැංකුවේ සභාපති සුජීව රාජපක්ෂ සහ ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී/සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරී රංජිත් කොඩිතුවක්කු යන මහත්වරු කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය ඇමතූහ.",
        "මීට අමතරව, මහජන බැංකුව පිහිටුවීමට දායක වූ රටට, ජනතාවට, ගනුදෙනුකරුවන්ට සහ පුරෝගාමී නායකයින්ට ආශිර්වාද කිරීම සඳහා බෞද්ධ සංගමය, හින්දු සංගමය, මුස්ලිම් මජ්ලිස් සහ මහජන බැංකුවේ කිතුනු සංසදය විසින් ආගමික වැඩසටහන් සංවිධානය කරන ලදී.",
        "ඒ අනුව විහාරාධිපති අතිපූජ්‍ය නාහිමියන්ගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් කොටුව සම්බෝධි විහාරස්ථානයේ දී දානමය පිංකමක් ද ඉන් අනතුරුව ප්‍රධාන කාර්යාලයේ දී පිරිත් සජ්ඣායනයක් ද පැවැත්විණි. මහාචාර්ය ඉත්තදෙමලියේ ඉන්දසාර හිමි. කොළඹ දවටගහ ජුම්මා පල්ලියේ දී දේශබන්දු අල් හජ් ෆයිසාල් හසන් මවුලවි මහතා විසින් මෙහෙයවන ලද ඉස්ලාමීය දේව මෙහෙය බම්බලපිටිය ශ්‍රී නිවාස කුරුක්කල් විසින් හින්දු පූජාව පවත්වනු ලැබූ අතර පූජ්‍ය ඇන්ටන් රෝහිත පියතුමා විසින් පිටකොටුව ශාන්ත පිලිප් මරියා දේවස්ථානයේ දී දිව්‍ය පූජාව පවත්වන ලදී. ආයතනික හා විධායක කළමනාකාරීත්වය, බැංකු කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය සහ විශ්‍රාමික සේවකයින් ද මෙම අවස්ථාවට එක්ව සිටියහ.",
        "Ideal Group හි Iroshini Wijenayaka ලෝක කාන්තා නායකත්ව සම්මේලනයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව නියෝජනය කරයි",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මහජන බැංකුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "61 වැනි සංවත්සරය",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහජන බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "61 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන බැංකුව සුජීව රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Kodituwakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුස්ලිම්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිතුනුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්රධාන කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සම්බෝධි විහාරය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලකොටුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉත්තදෙමලියේ ඉන්දසර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී නිවාස කුරුක්කල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බම්බලපිටිය, ඉස්ලාමීය සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දේශබන්දු අල් හජ් ෆයිසාල් හසන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවටගහ ජුම්මා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇන්ටන් රෝහිත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශාන්ත පිලිප් මරියා",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිටකොටුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන බැංකුවේ ආයතනික සහ විධායක කළමනාකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉරෝෂිනී විජේනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයිඩියල් සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක කාන්තා නායකත්ව සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மக்கள் வங்கி தனது 61வது ஆண்டு நிறைவைக் கொண்டாடுகிறது",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "மக்கள் வங்கி, கொழும்பு 02 இல் உள்ள வங்கியின் தலைமையகத்தில் தமது 61வது ஆண்டு நிறைவை முன்னிட்டு ஜூலை 1ஆம் திகதி வரை சாதாரணமான விழாவை நடத்தியது. இந்த நிகழ்வில் மக்கள் வங்கியின் தலைவர் சுஜீவ ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் பிரதம நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரி/பொது முகாமையாளர் ரஞ்சித் கொடிதுவாக்கு ஆகியோர் ஊழியர்களிடம் உரையாற்றினர்.",
        "மேலும், பௌத்த சங்கம், இந்து சங்கம், முஸ்லிம் மஜ்லிஸ் மற்றும் மக்கள் வங்கியின் கிறிஸ்தவர்களின் கில்ட் ஆகியன இணைந்து நாடு, மக்கள், வாடிக்கையாளர்கள் மற்றும் மக்கள் வங்கியை ஸ்தாபிக்க பங்களித்த முன்னோடித் தலைவர்களுக்கு ஆசிர்வாதம் வழங்கும் வகையில் சமய நிகழ்ச்சிகள் ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்டிருந்தன.",
        "அதன்படி, தலைமைக் காரியாலயத்தில் பிரித் ஓதுதல் இடம்பெற்றதுடன், அதனைத் தொடர்ந்து கோட்டை சம்போதி விகாரையில் அன்னதானம் பிரதம அதிதியாக அதிபரின் அனுசரணையுடன் இடம்பெற்றது. பேராசிரியர் இத்ததெமாலியே இந்தசர தேரர். கொழும்பு தவதகஹா ஜும்மா பள்ளிவாசலில் தேசபந்து அல் ஹாஜ் பைசல் ஹசன் மௌலவி அவர்களால் நடாத்தப்பட்ட இஸ்லாமிய சேவை பம்பலப்பிட்டி ஸ்ரீ நிவாச குருக்கள் அவர்களினால் இந்து பூஜையும், பீப்பிள்ஸ் பேங்க் புனித பிலிப் மேரிஸ் தேவாலயத்தில் ஆன்டன் ரோஹிதா அவர்களால் புனித வழிபாடும் இடம்பெற்றது. இந்நிகழ்ச்சியில் கார்ப்பரேட் மற்றும் நிர்வாக நிர்வாகம், வங்கி ஊழியர்கள் மற்றும் ஓய்வு பெற்ற பணியாளர்கள் கலந்து கொண்டனர்.",
        "ஐடியல் குழுமத்தின் இரோஷினி விஜேநாயக்க உலக மகளிர் தலைமைத்துவ காங்கிரஸில் இலங்கையை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்துகிறார்",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மக்கள் வங்கி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "61வது ஆண்டுவிழா",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "61வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் வங்கி சுஜீவ ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Kodituwakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புத்த சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முஸ்லிம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிறிஸ்தவர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தலைமை அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸம்போதி விஹாராய",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இத்ததேமலியே இந்தசர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ நிவாச குருக்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பம்பலப்பிட்டி, இஸ்லாமிய சேவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசபந்து அல் ஹாஜ் பைசல் ஹசன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தவதகஹா ஜும்மா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அன்டன் ரோஹிதா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செயின்ட் பிலிப் மேரிஸ்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்டா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் வங்கி கார்ப்பரேட் மற்றும் நிர்வாக மேலாண்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரோஷினி விஜேநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐடியல் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக மகளிர் தலைமைத்துவ காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}