{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/28/fuel-crisis-public-transport-severely-affected/",
  "time_ut": 1658982600,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Fuel Crisis: Public Transport Severely Affected",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Fuel Crisis: Public Transport Severely Affected",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The shortage of fuel in the country has negatively affected public passenger transport services.",
        "The Chairman of the Lanka Private Bus Owners' Association Gamunu Wijeratna said that Private Buses are now receiving fuel from SLTB Depots, and thus there is a possibility of increasing operations, however, the situation at present is not positive.",
        "Also, Sri Lanka Transport Board (SLTB) says that buses will be operating today (28) as usual. Sri Lanka Railways also said that trains will operate today (28) as usual."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Lanka Private Bus Owners' Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gamunu Wijeratna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Transport Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Railways",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය: පොදු ප්‍රවාහනය දැඩි ලෙස බලපායි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); රටේ පවතින ඉන්ධන හිඟය පොදු මගී ප්‍රවාහන සේවාවන්ට අහිතකර ලෙස බලපා ඇත.",
        "ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් රථ හිමියන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති ගැමුණු විජේරත්න කියා සිටියේ ලංගම ඩිපෝවලින් මේ වන විට පෞද්ගලික බස් රථ සඳහා ඉන්ධන ලැබෙන බවත්, ඒ අනුව මෙහෙයුම් වැඩි කිරීමේ හැකියාවක් පවතින නමුත් මේ වන විට තත්ත්වය යහපත් නොවන බවත්ය.",
        "එමෙන්ම අද (28) දිනයේ ද සාමාන්‍ය පරිදි බස් රථ ධාවනය කෙරෙන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය පවසයි. අද (28) දිනයේ ද සාමාන්‍ය පරිදි දුම්රිය ධාවනය කෙරෙන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා දුම්රිය සේවය පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගැමුණු විජේරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දුම්රිය සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடி: பொது போக்குவரத்து கடுமையாக பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); நாட்டில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள எரிபொருள் தட்டுப்பாடு பொது பயணிகள் போக்குவரத்து சேவைகளை எதிர்மறையாக பாதித்துள்ளது.",
        "தனியார் பேருந்துகள் தற்போது இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை டிப்போக்களில் இருந்து எரிபொருளைப் பெற்று வருவதாகவும், இதனால் சேவைகள் அதிகரிக்க வாய்ப்பு இருப்பதாகவும் எனினும் தற்போது நிலைமை சாதகமாக இல்லை எனவும் இலங்கை தனியார் பேருந்து உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் கமுனு விஜேரத்ன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மேலும், இன்று (28) பஸ்கள் வழமை போன்று இயங்கும் என இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை தெரிவித்துள்ளது. இன்று (28) வழமை போன்று புகையிரத சேவைகள் இடம்பெறும் எனவும் இலங்கை ரயில்வே தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கமுனு விஜேரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ரயில்வே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}