{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/16/sri-lanka-police-oic-hailed-a-hero-for-foiling-criminal-attack-and-arresting-suspects/",
  "time_ut": 1660644840,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka: Police OIC hailed a hero for foiling criminal attack and arresting suspects",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka: Police OIC hailed a hero for foiling criminal attack and arresting suspects",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The OIC of the Kaduwela Police has been hailed a hero after he managed to arrest three suspects who attempted to escape in an SUV.",
        "Police Spokesperson SSP Attorney-at-Law Nihal Thalduwa told News 1st that the OIC for Kaduwela was returning to his Police Station at around 11 PM on Monday (15) after attending the Perahera of the Kaduwela Rankadu Devalaya.",
        "At that moment, the OIC had come across a group armed with swords and machetes at the Kaduwela Town Center.",
        "The Police Spokesperson said that when the OIC was stopping his cruiser at the location, the suspects attempted to flee by getting into an SUV.",
        "The OIC had taken out his pistol and opened fire at the SUV.",
        "The suspects had driven ahead and then dumped the SUV in a bid to escape by foot, and during the getaway, the OIC managed to arrest three of them while one suspect got away.",
        "Investigations revealed that the suspects had arrived to carry out an attack on a drug peddler identified as Roshan, living down school lane in Kothelawala.",
        "Sri Lanka: Police OIC hailed a hero for foiling criminal attack and arresting suspects"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The OIC of the Kaduwela Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Spokesperson SSP",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "OIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kaduwela",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "around 11 PM",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "OIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kaduwela Town Center",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "OIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "OIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "OIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Roshan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kothelawala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව: සාපරාධී ප්‍රහාරයක් වැලැක්වීම සහ සැකකරුවන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් පොලිස් ස්ථානාධිපති වීරයෙකුට ප්‍රශංසා කළේය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); SUV රථයකින් පැන යාමට තැත්කළ සැකකරුවන් තිදෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට සමත්වීමත් සමඟ කඩුවෙල පොලිසියේ ස්ථානාධිපතිවරයා වීරයෙකු බවට පත්වී තිබෙනවා.",
        "පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නීතීඥ නිහාල් තල්දූව News 1st වෙත පැවසුවේ කඩුවෙල ප්‍රදේශයේ ස්ථානාධිපතිවරයා කඩුවෙල රන්කඩු දේවාලයේ පෙරහැරට ගොස් සඳුදා (15) රාත්‍රී 11 ට පමණ සිය පොලිස් ස්ථානයට පැමිණෙමින් සිටි බවයි.",
        "එම අවස්ථාවේදී කඩුවෙල නගර මධ්‍යයේ කඩු, මුගටිවලින් සන්නද්ධ පිරිසක් සිටි ස්ථානාධිපතිවරයාට හමුවී ඇත.",
        "පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශකවරයා සඳහන් කළේ, පොලිස් ස්ථානාධිපතිවරයා සිය නෞකාව එම ස්ථානයේ නවත්වන අවස්ථාවේදී සැකකරුවන් SUV රථයක නැගී පළා යාමට උත්සාහ කළ බවයි.",
        "පොලිස් ස්ථානාධිපතිවරයා පිස්තෝලය එළියට ගෙන SUV රථයට වෙඩි තබා ඇත.",
        "සැකකරුවන් ඉදිරියෙන් ධාවනය කර පසුව පයින් පැන යාමේ අරමුණින් SUV රථය දමා ගොස් ඇති අතර, පලා යාමේදී එක් සැකකරුවෙකු පලා යද්දී ඔවුන්ගෙන් තිදෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට ස්ථානාධිපතිවරයා සමත් විය.",
        "කොතලාවල ප්‍රදේශයේ පාසල් මංතීරුවේ පදිංචි රොෂාන් නමැති මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය ජාවාරම්කරුවෙකුට ප්‍රහාරයක් එල්ල කිරීමට සැකකරුවන් පැමිණ ඇති බවයි විමර්ශනවලදී අනාවරණ වුණේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව: සාපරාධී ප්‍රහාරයක් වැලැක්වීම සහ සැකකරුවන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් පොලිස් ස්ථානාධිපති වීරයෙකුට ප්‍රශංසා කළේය"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කඩුවෙල පොලිසියේ ස්ථානාධිපති එස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රකාශක ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්ථානාධිපති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කඩුවෙල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප.ව. 11ට පමණ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්ථානාධිපති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කඩුවෙල නගර මධ්‍යයේ",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්ථානාධිපති",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්ථානාධිපති",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්ථානාධිපති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොෂාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොතලාවල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை: கிரிமினல் தாக்குதலை முறியடித்து, சந்தேக நபர்களை கைது செய்ததற்காக போலீஸ் ஓ.ஐ.சி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); SUV ரக வாகனத்தில் தப்பிச் செல்ல முயன்ற மூன்று சந்தேக நபர்களை கைது செய்ததன் மூலம் கடுவெல பொலிஸ் நிலையப் பொறுப்பதிகாரி மாவீரராகப் புகழப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "கடுவெல ரன்காடு தேவாலயத்தின் பெரஹெராவில் கலந்து கொண்டு திங்கட்கிழமை (15) இரவு 11 மணியளவில் தனது பொலிஸ் நிலையத்திற்குத் திரும்பிக் கொண்டிருந்ததாக பொலிஸ் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர் சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் சட்டத்தரணி நிஹால் தல்துவ News 1st க்கு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அந்த நேரத்தில், கடுவலை நகர மையத்தில் வாள்கள் மற்றும் கத்திகளுடன் ஆயுதம் ஏந்திய ஒரு குழுவை OIC கண்டது.",
        "OIC தனது பயணக் கப்பலை அந்த இடத்தில் நிறுத்திய போது, ​​சந்தேகநபர்கள் SUV வாகனத்தில் ஏறி தப்பிச் செல்ல முற்பட்டதாக பொலிஸ் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "OIC தனது கைத்துப்பாக்கியை எடுத்து SUV மீது துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தினார்.",
        "சந்தேக நபர்கள் முன்னோக்கி ஓட்டிச் சென்று பின்னர் SUV யை காலால் தப்பிக்கும் முயற்சியில் வீசிவிட்டுச் சென்றுள்ளனர், மேலும் தப்பிச் செல்லும் போது OIC அவர்களில் மூவரைக் கைது செய்தார், ஒரு சந்தேக நபர் தப்பிச் சென்றார்.",
        "கொத்தலாவல பிரதேசத்தில் பாடசாலை வீதியில் வசிக்கும் ரொஷான் என்ற போதைப்பொருள் வியாபாரி மீது தாக்குதல் நடத்துவதற்காக சந்தேகநபர்கள் வருகை தந்துள்ளதாக விசாரணைகளில் தெரியவந்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை: கிரிமினல் தாக்குதலை முறியடித்து, சந்தேக நபர்களை கைது செய்ததற்காக போலீஸ் ஓ.ஐ.சி"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடுவெல காவல்துறையின் ஓ.ஐ.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செய்தி தொடர்பாளர் எஸ்.எஸ்.பி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "OIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடுவெல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 11 PM",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "OIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடுவெல நகர மையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "OIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "OIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "OIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரோஷன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொத்தலாவல",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}