{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Sysco-LABS-ranked-amongst-LMD-s-Most-Respected-Entities-for-2022/34-738854",
  "time_ut": 1660846937,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sysco LABS ranked amongst LMD’s Most Respected Entities for 2022",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sysco LABS ranked amongst LMD’s Most Respected Entities for 2022",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sysco LABS was recently recognised by LMD Magazine as one of Sri Lanka’s Most Respected Entities for 2022. This year marks the first time that Sysco LABS has been ranked in the top 100.",
        "Sysco LABS is the captive innovation centre of Sysco, a Fortune 500 company and the world’s leader in foodservice. Sysco LABS specialises in delivering technology that powers Sysco’s global systems – from enterprise-grade technology to solutions that revolutionise the way Sysco connects with its customers, impacting millions of people around the globe.",
        "Speaking about the ranking, Sysco LABS Sri Lanka Managing Director Shanil Fernando said: “We are honoured to be ranked amongst the top 100 for the first time, especially since we are one of the younger brands on the list. Our story is built on the ingenuity and innovation of Sri Lankan engineering talent, and we will continue to deliver technology that impacts the future of the global foodservice industry. Despite different challenges during the past year, we have successfully continued to grow our operation and contribute to Sri Lanka’s IT export offering.”",
        "Sysco LABS is focused on cultivating a mindset of continuous improvement across the organisation and fostering an innovation-based engineering culture. Sysco LABS’ precision-driven technology enables Sysco to fulfil its purpose of “connecting the world to share food and care for one another.”",
        "With more than 71,000 associates, Sysco LABS operates 333 distribution facilities worldwide and serves more than 700,000 customer locations. Sysco LABS’s engineering teams based out of Colombo, Sri Lanka and Austin and Houston, TX, innovate across the entire food service journey – from the enterprise-grade technology that enables Sysco’s business, to the technology that revolutionises the way that Sysco connects with restaurants and the technology that shapes the way those restaurants connect with customers."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "LMD Magazine",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "This year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sysco",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sysco",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "millions",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sysco LABS Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shanil Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sysco",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "more than 71,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "333",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 700,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Austin",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Houston",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "TX",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Sysco LABS 2022 සඳහා LMD හි වඩාත්ම ගෞරවනීය ආයතන අතරට ශ්‍රේණිගත කර ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sysco LABS 2022 සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වඩාත්ම ගෞරවනීය ආයතනවලින් එකක් ලෙස LMD සඟරාව විසින් මෑතකදී පිළිගනු ලැබීය. Sysco LABS හොඳම 100 අතරට ශ්‍රේණිගත කළ පළමු අවස්ථාව මෙය වේ.",
        "Sysco LABS යනු Fortune 500 සමාගමක් වන Sysco හි වහල් නවෝත්පාදන මධ්‍යස්ථානය වන අතර ආහාර සේවයේ ලොව ප්‍රමුඛයා වේ. Sysco LABS විසින් Sysco හි ගෝලීය පද්ධති බලගන්වන තාක්‍ෂණය බෙදා හැරීම සඳහා විශේෂීකරණය කරයි - ව්‍යවසාය-ශ්‍රේණියේ තාක්‍ෂණයේ සිට Sysco සිය ගනුදෙනුකරුවන් සමඟ සම්බන්ධ වන ආකාරය විප්ලවීය කරන විසඳුම් දක්වා, ලොව පුරා මිලියන සංඛ්‍යාත පුද්ගලයින්ට බලපෑම් කරයි.",
        "ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම පිළිබඳව අදහස් දක්වමින් Sysco LABS ශ්‍රී ලංකා කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ ශනිල් ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා මෙසේ පැවසීය: “පළමු වරට හොඳම 100 අතරට ශ්‍රේණිගත වීමට ලැබීම ගැන අපි ගෞරවයට පාත්‍ර වෙමු, විශේෂයෙන් අපි ලැයිස්තුවේ සිටින ලාබාල සන්නාමවලින් එකක් වන බැවිනි. අපගේ කතාව ගොඩනැගී ඇත්තේ ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය ඉංජිනේරු කුසලතාවන්ගේ දක්ෂතාවය සහ නවෝත්පාදනය මත වන අතර ගෝලීය ආහාර සේවා කර්මාන්තයේ අනාගතයට බලපාන තාක්‍ෂණය අපි දිගටම ලබා දෙන්නෙමු. පසුගිය වසර තුළ විවිධ අභියෝග මධ්‍යයේ වුවද, අපි අපගේ ක්‍රියාකාරිත්වය සාර්ථකව අඛණ්ඩව වර්ධනය කර ගනිමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තොරතුරු තාක්ෂණ අපනයන පිරිනැමීමට දායක වී ඇත්තෙමු.",
        "Sysco LABS ආයතනය පුරා අඛණ්ඩව වැඩිදියුණු කිරීමේ මානසිකත්වයක් වර්ධනය කිරීම සහ නවෝත්පාදන මත පදනම් වූ ඉංජිනේරු සංස්කෘතියක් පෝෂණය කිරීම කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු කරයි. Sysco LABS හි නිරවද්‍ය-ධාවන තාක්‍ෂණය, \"ආහාර බෙදා ගැනීමට සහ එකිනෙකාට සැලකිල්ල දැක්වීමට ලෝකය සම්බන්ධ කිරීමේ\" එහි අරමුණ ඉටු කිරීමට Sysco හට හැකියාව ලබා දෙයි.",
        "ආශ්‍රිතයන් 71,000කට අධික සංඛ්‍යාවක් සමඟින්, Sysco LABS ලොව පුරා බෙදාහැරීමේ පහසුකම් 333ක් ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන අතර පාරිභෝගික ස්ථාන 700,000කට වඩා සේවා සපයයි. Sysco LABS හි ඉංජිනේරු කණ්ඩායම්, කොළඹ, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ Austin සහ Houston, TX, Sysco හි ව්‍යාපාරය සක්‍රීය කරන ව්‍යවසාය ශ්‍රේණියේ තාක්‍ෂණයේ සිට ආපනශාලා සමඟ සම්බන්ධ වන ආකාරය විප්ලවීය වෙනසක් ඇති කරන තාක්‍ෂණය දක්වා සමස්ත ආහාර සේවා ගමන පුරා නව්‍යකරණය කරයි. එම අවන්හල් පාරිභෝගිකයින් සමඟ සම්බන්ධ වන ආකාරය හැඩගස්වන තාක්ෂණය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "LMD සඟරාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිස්කෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිස්කෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sysco LABS Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශනිල් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිස්කෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "71,000 කට වඩා වැඩිය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "333",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "700,000 කට වඩා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔස්ටින්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හූස්ටන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "TX",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டிற்கான எல்எம்டியின் மிகவும் மதிக்கப்படும் நிறுவனங்களில் சிஸ்கோ லேப்ஸ் இடம் பெற்றுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டிற்கான இலங்கையின் மிகவும் மதிக்கப்படும் நிறுவனங்களில் ஒன்றாக LMD சஞ்சிகையால் Sysco LABS அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்டது. இந்த வருடம் முதல் 100 இடங்களுக்குள் Sysco LABS இடம்பிடித்துள்ளது.",
        "சிஸ்கோ லேப்ஸ் என்பது ஃபார்ச்சூன் 500 நிறுவனமான சிஸ்கோவின் கேப்டிவ் இன்னோவேஷன் சென்டர் மற்றும் உணவு சேவையில் உலகின் முன்னணி நிறுவனமாகும். Sysco LABS ஆனது, Syscoவின் உலகளாவிய அமைப்புகளுக்கு சக்தி அளிக்கும் தொழில்நுட்பத்தை வழங்குவதில் நிபுணத்துவம் பெற்றது - நிறுவன தர தொழில்நுட்பம் முதல் Sysco தனது வாடிக்கையாளர்களுடன் இணைக்கும் விதத்தில் புரட்சியை ஏற்படுத்தும் தீர்வுகள் வரை, உலகெங்கிலும் உள்ள மில்லியன் கணக்கான மக்களை பாதிக்கிறது.",
        "தரவரிசை பற்றி பேசிய Sysco LABS இலங்கையின் முகாமைத்துவப் பணிப்பாளர் ஷனில் பெர்னாண்டோ, “முதன்முறையாக முதல் 100 இடங்களுக்குள் இடம்பிடித்ததில் நாங்கள் பெருமையடைகிறோம், குறிப்பாக நாங்கள் பட்டியலில் உள்ள இளைய பிராண்ட்களில் ஒன்றாக இருப்பதால். எங்கள் கதை இலங்கையின் பொறியியல் திறமைகளின் புத்தி கூர்மை மற்றும் புதுமையின் அடிப்படையில் கட்டமைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது, மேலும் உலகளாவிய உணவு சேவைத் துறையின் எதிர்காலத்தை பாதிக்கும் தொழில்நுட்பத்தை நாங்கள் தொடர்ந்து வழங்குவோம். கடந்த வருடத்தில் பல்வேறு சவால்கள் இருந்த போதிலும், நாங்கள் வெற்றிகரமாக தொடர்ந்து எமது செயற்பாடுகளை மேம்படுத்தி இலங்கையின் தகவல் தொழில்நுட்ப ஏற்றுமதி வழங்கலுக்கு பங்களித்துள்ளோம்.",
        "Sysco LABS ஆனது நிறுவனம் முழுவதும் தொடர்ச்சியான முன்னேற்றத்தின் மனநிலையை வளர்ப்பதிலும் புதுமை அடிப்படையிலான பொறியியல் கலாச்சாரத்தை வளர்ப்பதிலும் கவனம் செலுத்துகிறது. சிஸ்கோ லேப்ஸின் துல்லியமான உந்துதல் தொழில்நுட்பம், \"உணவைப் பகிர்ந்துகொள்வதற்கும் ஒருவரையொருவர் கவனித்துக்கொள்வதற்கும் உலகை இணைக்கும்\" அதன் நோக்கத்தை நிறைவேற்ற சிஸ்கோவிற்கு உதவுகிறது.",
        "71,000 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட கூட்டாளிகளுடன், Sysco LABS உலகளவில் 333 விநியோக வசதிகளை இயக்குகிறது மற்றும் 700,000 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட வாடிக்கையாளர் இருப்பிடங்களுக்கு சேவை செய்கிறது. கொழும்பு, இலங்கை மற்றும் ஆஸ்டின் மற்றும் ஹூஸ்டன், TX ஆகிய இடங்களில் உள்ள சிஸ்கோ LABS இன் பொறியியல் குழுக்கள், சிஸ்கோவின் வணிகத்தை செயல்படுத்தும் நிறுவன தர தொழில்நுட்பம் முதல், உணவகங்களுடன் சிஸ்கோ இணைக்கும் விதத்தில் புரட்சியை ஏற்படுத்தும் தொழில்நுட்பம் வரை முழு உணவு சேவை பயணத்திலும் புதுமைகளை உருவாக்குகின்றன. அந்த உணவகங்கள் வாடிக்கையாளர்களுடன் இணைக்கும் விதத்தை வடிவமைக்கும் தொழில்நுட்பம்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "LMD இதழ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிஸ்கோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஸ்கோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மில்லியன்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிஸ்கோ லேப்ஸ் இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷனில் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிஸ்கோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "71,000க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "333",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "700,000க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்டின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹூஸ்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "TX",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}