{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/’’රනිල්-වැඩ්ඩෙක්-නොවෙයි’’/1-618252",
  "time_ut": 1660712139,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "’’රනිල් වැඩ්ඩෙක් නොවෙයි’’",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "\"Ranil is not a fool\"",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Sajith Premadasa, the opposition leader, questioned how Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe, who went home after being defeated in Colombo, could become a leader.",
        "The opposition leader said that some people say that Ranil Wickremesinghe is a crook and went home after losing from the Colombo district.",
        "However, Mr. Premadasa said that he does not question the method by which Ranil Wickremesinghe became the President and that the appointment was done constitutionally.",
        "He further said that if he had promised to protect Rajapaksa's band of thieves, he would be the president of the country today."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "’’රනිල් වැඩ්ඩෙක් නොවෙයි’’",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොළඹින් පරාද වී ගෙදර ගිය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වැඩ්ඩකු වන්නේ කෙසේදැයි විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ප්‍රශ්න කළේය.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ වැඩ්ඩෙකු  යැයි  සමහරුන් පවසන බව  පැවසූ විපක්ෂනායකවරයා   කොළඹ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයෙන් පැරදී ගෙදර ගිය ඔහු  ජනාධිපතිවරයා බවට පත්වීම නිසා එසේ පවසන්නේ යැයිද   ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් රනිල් වික‍්‍රමසිංහ ජනාධිපති ධුරයට  පත්වූ  ක්‍රමවේදය ප්‍රශ්න නොකරන බවත් එම පත්වීම සිදු වූයේ  ව්‍යවස්ථානුකූලව බවත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පැවසුවේය.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ හොරු රැල රකින බවට තමන්ද පොරොන්දු වූයේ නම් අද තමා මෙරට ජනාධිපති බව ඔහු තවදුරටත් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"ரணில் ஒரு முட்டாள் அல்ல\"",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பில் தோற்கடிக்கப்பட்டு வீட்டுக்குச் சென்ற திரு.ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க எவ்வாறு தலைவராக முடியும் என எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் திரு.சஜித் பிரேமதாச கேள்வி எழுப்பினார்.",
        "ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவை ஒரு மோசடிக்காரன் என்று சிலர் கூறுவதாகவும், கொழும்பு மாவட்டத்தில் தோற்று வீட்டுக்குச் சென்றதாகவும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியேற்ற முறை தொடர்பில் தாம் கேள்வி எழுப்பவில்லை எனவும், அரசியலமைப்புச் சட்டத்திற்கு அமையவே இந்த நியமனம் இடம்பெற்றுள்ளதாகவும் திரு.பிரேமதாச தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மேலும், ராஜபக்சேவின் திருடர் கூட்டத்தை பாதுகாப்பதாக உறுதியளித்திருந்தால், அவர்தான் இன்று நாட்டின் அதிபராக இருப்பார் என்று கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}