{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Australia-working-with-India-to-provide-fuel-for-SL-navy-and-air-force/108-243489",
  "time_ut": 1661147954,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Australia working with India to provide fuel for SL navy and air force",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Australia working with India to provide fuel for SL navy and air force",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Australia is working with India to provide fuel to Sri Lanka’s navy and air force, Australia's High Commissioner to Sri Lanka Paul Stephens said.",
        "\"Australia is pleased to be working with India to provide fuel to Sri Lanka’s navy and air force. It will help our longstanding cooperation against transnational crime to continue. As Indian Ocean neighbours, all three counties share a commitment to preserving regional security,\" the Australian High Commission in Colombo tweeted."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Australia",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "air force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paul Stephens",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian Ocean",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Australian High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාවට සහ ගුවන් හමුදාවට ඉන්ධන සැපයීම සඳහා ඉන්දියාව සමඟ එක්ව කටයුතු කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නාවික හමුදාවට සහ ගුවන් හමුදාවට ඉන්ධන සැපයීම සඳහා ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාව ඉන්දියාව සමඟ එක්ව කටයුතු කරන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඔස්ට්‍රේලියානු මහ කොමසාරිස් පෝල් ස්ටීවන්ස් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "\"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නාවික හමුදාවට සහ ගුවන් හමුදාවට ඉන්ධන සැපයීම සඳහා ඉන්දියාව සමඟ කටයුතු කිරීමට ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව සතුටු වෙනවා. එය ජාත්‍යන්තර අපරාධවලට එරෙහි අපගේ දිගුකාලීන සහයෝගීතාව දිගටම කරගෙන යාමට උපකාරී වනු ඇත. ඉන්දියානු සාගර අසල්වැසියන් ලෙස, කලාප තුනම කලාපීය ආරක්ෂාව ආරක්ෂා කිරීමට කැපවී සිටිති,\" කොළඹ ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝල් ස්ටීවන්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියන් සාගරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை கடற்படை மற்றும் விமானப்படைக்கு எரிபொருளை வழங்க ஆஸ்திரேலியா இந்தியாவுடன் இணைந்து செயல்படுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் கடற்படை மற்றும் விமானப்படைக்கு எரிபொருள் வழங்குவதற்கு அவுஸ்திரேலியா இந்தியாவுடன் இணைந்து செயற்படுவதாக இலங்கைக்கான அவுஸ்திரேலியாவின் உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் பால் ஸ்டீபன்ஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"இலங்கையின் கடற்படை மற்றும் விமானப்படைக்கு எரிபொருளை வழங்குவதற்கு இந்தியாவுடன் இணைந்து பணியாற்றுவதில் அவுஸ்திரேலியா மகிழ்ச்சியடைகிறது. இது நாடுகடந்த குற்றங்களுக்கு எதிரான நமது நீண்டகால ஒத்துழைப்பு தொடர உதவும். இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல் அண்டை நாடுகளாக, பிராந்திய பாதுகாப்பைப் பாதுகாப்பதில் மூன்று மாவட்டங்களும் உறுதிப்பாட்டை பகிர்ந்து கொள்கின்றன,\" கொழும்பில் உள்ள அவுஸ்திரேலிய உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயம் ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பால் ஸ்டீபன்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய பெருங்கடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலிய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}