{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/හිටපු-අගමැති-ෂෙන්සෝ-අබේට-වෙඩි-තියලා/1-616036",
  "time_ut": 1657252421,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "හිටපු අගමැති ෂෙන්සෝ අබේට වෙඩි තියලා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Former Prime Minister Shinzo Abe was shot",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Foreign media reports that Shinzo Abe, a former Prime Minister of Japan, was shot and his condition is serious.",
        "The former Prime Minister was shot while attending a public meeting and addressing the gathering. It is reported that the shooting was done by an Irishman who was among the crowd and the security personnel immediately arrested him.",
        "Japan's NHK news service reports that the gunshots pierced the abbot's chest and his heart had stopped as he fell unconscious.",
        "Shinzo Abe is the longest serving Prime Minister of Japan. Abe, who held the position of Prime Minister from 2012 to September 2020, resigned from the post of Prime Minister, saying that he was unable to provide maximum service to the people due to his poor health."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Shinzo Abe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Irishman",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හිටපු අගමැති ෂෙන්සෝ අබේට වෙඩි තියලා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජපානයේ හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයකු වන ෂෙන්සෝ අබේ, වෙඩි ප්‍රහාරයකට ලක් වුණු බවත් ඔහුගේ තත්ත්වය බරපතල බවත් විදෙස් මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා වෙඩි ප්‍රහාරයට ලක්වූයේ ජන හමුවකට සහභාගී වී, රැස්ව සිටි පිරිස අමතමින් කතා කරමින් සිටින අවස්ථාවේදීය. වෙඩි තැබීම කළේ පිරිස අතර සිටි අයර්ලන්ත ජාතිකයකු බවත් ආරක්ෂක නිලධාරීන් වහා ඔහු අත්අඩංගුවට ගැණුනු බවත් වාර්තා වේ.",
        "වෙඩි ප්‍රහාරය අග්‍රාමාතවරයාගේ පපුව පසාරු කළ බවත්, සිහිසුන්ව ඇද වැටුණු ඔහුගේ හදවත නැවැතී තිබුණු බවත් වෛද්‍ය ආධාරකරුවන් ඔහුට ප්‍රථමාධාර ලබා දෙන්න වූ බවත් ජපානයේ එන්.එච්.කේ පුවත් සේවය වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "ජපානයේ වැඩිම කාලයක් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරය හෙබවූ තැනැත්තා වන්නේ ෂෙන්සෝ අබේය. 2012 සිට 2020 සැප්තැම්බරය තෙක් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරය හෙබවූ අබේ, අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වූයේ අයහපත් සෞඛ්‍ය තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් ජනතාවට උපරිම සේවයක් ලබා දීමට නොහැකි බව පවසමිනි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Shinzo Abe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අයර්ලන්ත ජාතිකයා",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முன்னாள் பிரதமர் ஷின்சோ அபே சுடப்பட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜப்பானின் முன்னாள் பிரதமர் ஷின்சோ அபே சுடப்பட்டதாகவும், அவரது உடல்நிலை கவலைக்கிடமாக இருப்பதாகவும் வெளிநாட்டு ஊடகங்கள் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளன.",
        "பொதுக்கூட்டத்தில் கலந்து கொண்டு உரையாற்றும் போதே முன்னாள் பிரதமர் சுடப்பட்டார். கூட்டத்தினரிடையே இருந்த அயர்லாந்தைச் சேர்ந்த ஒருவரே துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தியதாகவும், பாதுகாப்புப் படையினர் உடனடியாக அவரைக் கைது செய்ததாகவும் கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "துப்பாக்கிக் குண்டுகள் மடாதிபதியின் மார்பைத் துளைத்ததாகவும், அவர் மயங்கி விழுந்ததால் அவரது இதயம் நின்றுவிட்டதாகவும் ஜப்பானின் NHK செய்திச் சேவை தெரிவிக்கிறது.",
        "ஷின்சோ அபே ஜப்பானின் பிரதமராக நீண்ட காலம் பதவி வகித்தவர். 2012ஆம் ஆண்டு முதல் 2020ஆம் ஆண்டு செப்டம்பர் மாதம் வரை பிரதமராக பதவி வகித்த அபே, தனது உடல்நலக் குறைவால் மக்களுக்கு அதிகபட்ச சேவையை வழங்க முடியவில்லை என்று கூறி பிரதமர் பதவியை ராஜினாமா செய்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Shinzo Abe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐரிஷ்காரன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}