{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83878/30-year-old-shot-dead-in-balapitiya",
  "time_ut": 1658821620,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "30-year-old shot dead in Balapitiya",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "30-year-old shot dead in Balapitiya",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A man was gunned down and killed in a shooting that took place in Balapitiya area of Ambalangoda this afternoon (26).",
        "The victim, who suffered critical gunshot wounds, succumbed to injuries after being admitted to the Balapitiya Base Hospital.",
        "The deceased was a 30-year-old father of three residing in Ponaduwa area of Madampagama in Ambalangoda.",
        "He was reportedly a suspect of a murder case, and was shot while returning from the Balapitiya Magistrate’s court."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "30-year-old",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Balapitiya",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "this afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Balapitiya Base Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Madampagama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Balapitiya Magistrate’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බලපිටියේදී වෙඩි තබා ඝාතනය කර ඇත්තේ 30 හැවිරිදි අයෙකි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අම්බලන්ගොඩ, බලපිටිය ප්‍රදේශයේ අද (26) පස්වරුවේ සිදුවූ වෙඩි තැබීමකින් පුද්ගලයෙකු වෙඩි තබා ඝාතනය කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "වෙඩි වැදීමෙන් බරපතළ තුවාල ලැබූ පුද්ගලයා බලපිටිය මූලික රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කිරීමෙන් පසු මියගොස් තිබේ.",
        "මෙලෙස මියගොස් ඇත්තේ අම්බලන්ගොඩ, මාදම්පාගම, පොනදූව ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිව සිටි 30 හැවිරිදි තිදරු පියෙක්.",
        "ඔහු මිනීමැරුම් නඩුවක සැකකරුවෙකු බවත්, බලපිටිය මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයට ගොස් ආපසු එමින් සිටියදී වෙඩි තබා ඇති බවත් වාර්තා වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "30 හැවිරිදිය",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "බලපිටිය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බලපිටිය මූලික රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාදම්පාගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බලපිටිය මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பலபிட்டியவில் 30 வயதுடைய நபர் சுட்டுக்கொல்லப்பட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அம்பலாங்கொட பலபிட்டிய பிரதேசத்தில் இன்று (26) பிற்பகல் இடம்பெற்ற துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டில் ஒருவர் சுட்டுக் கொல்லப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "படுகாயமடைந்த நபர் பலப்பிட்டிய ஆதார வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டதன் பின்னர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "அம்பலாங்கொடை, மாதம்பகம, பொனடுவ பிரதேசத்தில் வசிக்கும் 30 வயதுடைய மூன்று பிள்ளைகளின் தந்தையே உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "அவர் கொலை வழக்கு ஒன்றில் சந்தேக நபர் எனவும், பலப்பிட்டிய நீதவான் நீதிமன்றில் இருந்து திரும்பும் போது சுடப்பட்டதாகவும் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "30 வயது",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "பலபிட்டிய",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பலபிட்டிய ஆதார வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மடம்பகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பலபிட்டிய நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}