{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/SL-to-request-Japan-to-initiate-dialogue-with-creditors/342-243329",
  "time_ut": 1660876327,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SL to request Japan to initiate dialogue with creditors",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SL to request Japan to initiate dialogue with creditors",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka is likely to request Japan to initiate a dialogue with Sri Lanka’s creditors including China and India, foreign media reported yesterday.",
        "The report quoted President Ranil Wickremesinghe of making such a remark.",
        "It was also reported that President Wickremesinghe was scheduled to travel to Tokyo next month to hold talks with Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida but a spokesman from the President’s office told Daily Mirror that he will fly to Japan to attend the funeral of former Prime Minister Shinzo Abe.",
        "Meanwhile Mr.Wickremesnghe earlier on Tuesday made a somewhat similar remark when he said Sri Lanka will have to talk to Japan on how Sri Lanka could come out of woods. He stressed the need for having a dialogue with top donors including India and China. He also said talks will go on with the IMF in order to finalize a staff level agreement. In addition the President revealed that LAZARD one of the advisors on Sri Lanka’s debt resettlement had prepared a distress sustainability plan. (Yohan Perera)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tokyo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fumio Kishida",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesnghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LAZARD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yohan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ණය හිමියන් සමඟ සංවාදයක් ආරම්භ කරන ලෙස ජපානයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "චීනය සහ ඉන්දියාව ඇතුළු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණයහිමියන් සමඟ සංවාදයක් ආරම්භ කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජපානයෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කිරීමට ඉඩ ඇති බව විදෙස් මාධ්‍ය ඊයේ වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "එවැනි ප්‍රකාශයක් කළ බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා උපුටා දක්වමින් වාර්තාවේ.",
        "ජපාන අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ෆුමියෝ කිෂිඩා සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ ලබන මාසයේ ටෝකියෝ නුවරට යාමට නියමිත බව ද වාර්තා වූ නමුත් හිටපු අගමැති ෂින්සෝ අබේගේ අවමංගල්‍ය උත්සවයට සහභාගී වීම සඳහා ඔහු ජපානයට පියාසර කරන බව ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙකු ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත පැවසීය. .",
        "මේ අතර වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මීට පෙර අඟහරුවාදා ද ඊට සමාන ප්‍රකාශයක් කළේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වනයෙන් ගොඩ එන්නේ කෙසේද යන්න පිළිබඳව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ජපානය සමඟ කතා කිරීමට සිදුවන බව ප්‍රකාශ කරමිනි. ඉන්දියාව සහ චීනය ඇතුළු ඉහළම පරිත්‍යාගශීලීන් සමඟ සංවාදයක අවශ්‍යතාවය ඔහු අවධාරණය කළේය. කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමක් අවසන් කිරීම සඳහා IMF සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කරන බව ද ඔහු පැවසීය. මීට අමතරව, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය නැවත පියවීම පිළිබඳ උපදේශකයෙකු වන LAZARD විසින් ආපදා තිරසාර සැලැස්මක් සකස් කර ඇති බව ජනාධිපතිවරයා අනාවරණය කළේය. (යොහාන් පෙරේරා)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටෝකියෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fumio Kishida",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලාසාඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යොහාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கடனாளர்களுடன் உரையாடலைத் தொடங்க ஜப்பானைக் கோருவதற்கு SL",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சீனா மற்றும் இந்தியா உள்ளிட்ட இலங்கையின் கடனாளிகளுடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தையை ஆரம்பிக்குமாறு ஜப்பானிடம் இலங்கை கோரிக்கை விடுக்க வாய்ப்புள்ளதாக வெளிநாட்டு ஊடகங்கள் நேற்று செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளன.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவே இவ்வாறான கருத்தை வெளியிட்டதாக அந்த அறிக்கையில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க அடுத்த மாதம் டோக்கியோவுக்குச் சென்று ஜப்பானியப் பிரதமர் ஃபுமியோ கிஷிடாவுடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்துவார் என்றும், ஆனால் முன்னாள் பிரதமர் ஷின்சோ அபேயின் இறுதிச் சடங்கில் கலந்துகொள்வதற்காக அவர் ஜப்பானுக்குச் செல்லவுள்ளதாக ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகப் பேச்சாளர் டெய்லி மிரருக்குத் தெரிவித்தார். .",
        "இதற்கிடையில், திரு.விக்கிரமசிங்கே செவ்வாய்கிழமை சற்று முன்னர் இதே கருத்தை வெளியிட்டார். இலங்கை காடுகளில் இருந்து வெளிவருவது குறித்து இலங்கை ஜப்பானுடன் பேச வேண்டும் என்றார். இந்தியா, சீனா உள்ளிட்ட உயர்மட்ட நன்கொடையாளர்களுடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்த வேண்டியதன் அவசியத்தை அவர் வலியுறுத்தினார். ஊழியர் நிலை ஒப்பந்தத்தை இறுதி செய்ய சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தப்படும் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார். மேலும், இலங்கையின் கடன் மீள்குடியேற்றம் தொடர்பான ஆலோசகர்களில் ஒருவரான LAZARD, துன்ப நிலைத்தன்மைத் திட்டத்தை தயாரித்துள்ளதாக ஜனாதிபதி வெளிப்படுத்தினார். (யோஹான் பெரேரா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோக்கியோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fumio Kishida",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்கே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லாசர்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோஹான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}