{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ඇප්-එකට-ඉන්ධන-21-සිට/101-616612",
  "time_ut": 1658130768,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඇප් එකට ඉන්ධන 21 සිට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "App fuel from 21",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Kumara Rajapaksa, President of the Petrol Station Owners Association, said today (18) morning that fuel will be released from next Thursday (21st) according to the 'National Fuel Licence' and Cipetco will not mind queuing up at petrol stations.",
        "From Thursday, Q.R. Mr. Kumara Rajapaksa said that fuel will be issued only according to the symbol and the registration number of the vehicle and also mentioned that the people who are currently in the queue should leave.",
        "Accordingly, Mr. Rajapaksa further said that only vehicle owners with the last digit of the vehicle registration number 0, 1 and 2 should come to get fuel on the 21st."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "21",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kumara Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Petrol Station Owners Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18) morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "next Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21st",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cipetco",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Q.R.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "0",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 21st",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඇප් එකට ඉන්ධන 21 සිට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "‘ජාතික ඉල්ධන බලපත්‍රය’ අනුව ලබන බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (21 වැනිදා) සිට ඉන්ධන නිකුත් කිරීම ආරම්භ කරන බවත් සිපෙට්කෝ ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල්වල පෝලිමේ සිටීමෙන් පළක් නොවන බවත් ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති කුමාර රාජපක්‍ෂ මහතා අද (18) පෙරවරුවේ පැවසීය.",
        "බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා සිට කිව්.ආර්. සංකේතය සහ වාහනයේ ලියාපදිංචි අංකය අනුව පමණක් ඉන්ධන නිකුත් කරන බව කී කුමාර රාජපක්‍ෂ මහතා දැනට පෝලිම්වල සිටින ජනතාව ඉවත්විය යුතු බව ද සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ඒ අනුව වාහනයේ ලියාපදිංචි අංකයේ අවසන් ඉලක්කම 0, 1 සහ 2 වන වාහන හිමියන් පමණක් ලබන 21 වැනිදා ඉන්ධන ලබාගැනීමට පැමිණිය යුතු බව ද රාජපක්‍ෂ මහතා වැඩි දුරටත් කීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "21",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කුමාර රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18) උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිපෙට්කෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Q.R.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "0",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பயன்பாட்டு எரிபொருள் 21 முதல்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தேசிய எரிபொருள் உரிமத்தின்படி எதிர்வரும் வியாழன் (21ஆம் திகதி) முதல் எரிபொருள் வெளியிடப்படும் எனவும், எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையங்களில் வரிசையில் நிற்பதை சிபெட்கோ பொருட்படுத்தாது எனவும் பெற்றோல் நிலைய உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் திரு.குமார ராஜபக்ஷ இன்று (18) காலை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "வியாழன் முதல், கே.ஆர். வாகனத்தின் சின்னம் மற்றும் பதிவு இலக்கத்தின் அடிப்படையில் மாத்திரமே எரிபொருள் வழங்கப்படும் எனத் தெரிவித்த திரு.குமார ராஜபக்ஷ, தற்போது வரிசையில் நிற்கும் மக்கள் வெளியேறுமாறும் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இதன்படி, வாகனப் பதிவு இலக்கமான 0, 1 மற்றும் 2 ஆகிய கடைசி இலக்கங்களைக் கொண்ட வாகன உரிமையாளர்கள் மாத்திரம் எதிர்வரும் 21ஆம் திகதி எரிபொருளைப் பெற்றுக்கொள்ள வருமாறு திரு.ராஜபக்ஷ மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "21",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "குமார ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோல் நிலைய உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18) காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிபெட்கோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கே.ஆர்.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "0",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}