{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83429/praveen-jayawickrama-tests-positive-for-covid-19",
  "time_ut": 1656953280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Praveen Jayawickrama tests positive for Covid-19",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Praveen Jayawickrama tests positive for Covid-19",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lankan cricketer Praveen Jayawickrama has tested positive for Covid-19 and has isolated immediately for five days, Sri Lanka Cricket (SLC) said.",
        "However, the rest of the national team members have tested negative for the virus, according to the SLC statement.",
        "Jayawickrama was one of the spinners named in the 18-member Sri Lanka squad for the Test series against Australia.",
        "Another Sri Lankan cricketer, Angelo Mathews, was recently ruled out of the first Test against Australia in Galle following a mid-game positive COVID-19 case.",
        "Mathews had returned a positive rapid antigen test on Thursday after feeling unwell. Sri Lanka Cricket had said he has since been isolated from other team members.",
        "A dominants Australia had thrashed Sri Lanka by 10 wickets in the first Test at Galle to go 1-0 up in the two-match series."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Praveen Jayawickrama",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Praveen Jayawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "five days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Cricket",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayawickrama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Angelo Mathews",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "COVID-19",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Cricket",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ප්‍රවීන් ජයවික්‍රම Covid-19 සඳහා ධනාත්මක බව පරීක්‍ෂා කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් ක්‍රීඩක ප්‍රවීන් ජයවික්‍රම Covid-19 සඳහා ධනාත්මක බව පරීක්‍ෂා කර ඇති අතර දින පහක් වහාම හුදෙකලා වී ඇති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් (SLC) පවසයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් නිවේදනයට අනුව ජාතික කණ්ඩායමේ සෙසු සාමාජිකයින් වෛරසය සඳහා සෘණාත්මක පරීක්‍ෂණයක් කර ඇත.",
        "ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාවට එරෙහි ටෙස්ට් තරඟාවලිය සඳහා නම් කර ඇති ක්‍රීඩකයින් 18 දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචිතයේ දඟ පන්දු යවන්නෙකු ලෙස ජයවික්‍රම නම් කර තිබුණා.",
        "තවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් ක්‍රීඩකයෙකු වන ඇන්ජලෝ මැතිව්ස් ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවට එරෙහිව ගාල්ලේ පැවති පළමු ටෙස්ට් තරඟයෙන් ඉවත් කරන ලද්දේ තරඟයේ මැද භාගයේ ධනාත්මක COVID-19 නඩුවක් හේතුවෙන්.",
        "මැතිව්ස් බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා ධනාත්මක වේගවත් ප්‍රතිදේහජනක පරීක්‍ෂණයක් නැවත ලබා දී තිබුණේ අසනීපයෙන් පසුවය. ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබුණේ එතැන් සිට ඔහු සෙසු කණ්ඩායම් සාමාජිකයන්ගෙන් හුදෙකලා වී ඇති බවයි.",
        "ගාල්ලේදී පැවැති පළමු ටෙස්ට් තරගයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කඩුලු 10කින් පරාජයට පත්කළ ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාව තරග දෙකකින් සමන්විත තරගාවලිය 1-0ක් ලෙස ඉදිරියට පැමිණ තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ප්‍රවීන් ජයවික්‍රම",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රවීන් ජයවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින පහක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයවික්‍රම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇන්ජලෝ මැතිව්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "COVID-19",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரவீன் ஜெயவிக்கிரமவுக்கு கோவிட்-19 தொற்று உறுதி செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை கிரிக்கெட் வீரர் பிரவீன் ஜெயவிக்ரம கோவிட்-19 க்கு சாதகமாக சோதனை செய்து ஐந்து நாட்களுக்கு உடனடியாக தனிமைப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாக இலங்கை கிரிக்கெட் (எஸ்எல்சி) தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், மீதமுள்ள தேசிய அணி உறுப்பினர்கள் வைரஸுக்கு எதிர்மறையான சோதனை செய்துள்ளதாக SLC அறிக்கை தெரிவிக்கிறது.",
        "அவுஸ்திரேலியாவுக்கு எதிரான டெஸ்ட் தொடருக்கான 18 பேர் கொண்ட இலங்கை அணியில் இடம் பெற்ற சுழற்பந்து வீச்சாளர்களில் ஜெயவிக்ரமாவும் ஒருவர்.",
        "மற்றொரு இலங்கை கிரிக்கெட் வீரரான ஏஞ்சலோ மேத்யூஸ், சமீபத்தில் ஆஸ்திரேலிய அணிக்கு எதிரான காலியில் நடந்த முதல் டெஸ்ட் போட்டியின் நடுப்பகுதியில் கோவிட்-19 தொற்றுக்கு உள்ளானதைத் தொடர்ந்து ஆட்டமிழந்தார்.",
        "மேத்யூஸ் வியாழன் அன்று உடல்நிலை சரியில்லாமல் இருந்ததால் பாசிட்டிவ் ரேபிட் ஆன்டிஜென் சோதனைக்கு திரும்பினார். அதன் பின்னர் அவர் மற்ற அணி உறுப்பினர்களிடமிருந்து தனிமைப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாக இலங்கை கிரிக்கெட் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "காலேயில் நடந்த முதல் டெஸ்டில் இலங்கையை 10 விக்கெட் வித்தியாசத்தில் வீழ்த்தி இரண்டு போட்டிகள் கொண்ட தொடரில் ஆதிக்கம் செலுத்திய ஆஸ்திரேலியா 1-0 என முன்னிலை பெற்றது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பிரவீன் ஜெயவிக்ரம",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரவீன் ஜெயவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கிரிக்கெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெயவிக்ரம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏஞ்சலோ மேத்யூஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "COVID-19",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கிரிக்கெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}