{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/26/sjb-wants-to-appoint-ranjan-to-national-list/",
  "time_ut": 1661505240,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SJB wants to appoint Ranjan to National List",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SJB wants to appoint Ranjan to National List",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Leader of the Opposition Sajith Premadasa says that the Samagi Jana Balawegaya will pledge to appoint former MP Ranjan Ramanayake to the Parliament in the first instance of an occurrence of a vacancy in the National List.",
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe granted a conditional Presidential Pardon to Ranjan Ramanayake on Friday (26) morning.",
        "A statement from the President's Media Division noted that the Pardon will be subject to the conditions that Ranjan Ramanayake no longer makes any statement that is in contempt of court and does not act in such a manner.",
        "On the 12th of January 2021, Ranjan Ramanayake was sentenced to jail for contempt of court.",
        "Ramanayake was sentenced to four years of Rigorous Imprisonment by the Supreme Court of Sri Lanka.",
        "Ramanayake was accused of contempt of court for allegedly making a controversial statement regarding the composition of the Supreme Court judge bench hearing the petitions filed against the President’s dissolution of Parliament in 2018.",
        "In January 2020, Ramanayake was arrested for committing a crime in terms of Article 111C (2) of the Constitution by interfering with the functions of judges. He was later granted bail, and following the conclusion of the trial, he was sentenced.",
        "On the 7th of April 2021, Sri Lankan Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardene informed Parliament that the Parliamentary seat of Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) MP Ranjan Ramanayake has been declared vacant.",
        "He said the Parliament Secretary General has informed the Elections Commission that MP Ranjan Ramanayake ceases to be an MP as per Parliamentary Act.",
        "Ranjan Ramanayake released from Colombo prison on ‘Conditional Presidential Pardon’",
        "U.S. Donates 3,000 metric tons of food to feed Sri Lankan school children"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SJB",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranjan to National List",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Opposition Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National List",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Presidential Pardon",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26) morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pardon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 12th of January 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "January 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 111C (2",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 7th of April 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Elections Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "per Parliamentary Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SJB එකට රන්ජන් ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවට පත් කරන්න ඕන",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවේ පුරප්පාඩුවක් ඇති වූ විට පළමු අවස්ථාවේදීම හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පත් කිරීමට සමගි ජන බලවේගය ප්‍රතිඥා දෙන බව විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් සිකුරාදා (26) පෙරවරුවේ රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතාට කොන්දේසි සහිත ජනාධිපති සමාවක් ප්‍රදානය කළේය.",
        "ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය නිකුත් කළ නිවේදනයක දැක්වෙන්නේ රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා අධිකරණයට අපහාස වන ආකාරයේ කිසිදු ප්‍රකාශයක් සිදු නොකරන සහ එලෙස ක්‍රියා නොකිරීමේ කොන්දේසිවලට යටත්ව මෙම සමාව හිමිවන බවයි.",
        "2021 ජනවාරි 12 වැනිදා රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමේ චෝදනාවට සිර දඬුවම් නියම විය.",
        "රාමනායක මහතාට ශ්‍රී ලංකා ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය විසින් වසර හතරක බරපතල වැඩ සහිත සිරදඬුවමක් නියම කරන ලදී.",
        "2018 වසරේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසුරුවා හැරීමට එරෙහිව ගොනු කර ඇති පෙත්සම් විභාග කරන ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ විනිසුරු මඩුල්ලේ සංයුතිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ආන්දෝලනාත්මක ප්‍රකාශයක් සිදු කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් රාමනායක මහතාට අධිකරණයට අපහාස කළ බවට චෝදනා එල්ල විය.",
        "2020 ජනවාරි මාසයේදී රාමනායක මහතා ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 111 සී (2) වගන්තිය ප්‍රකාරව විනිසුරුවරුන්ගේ කාර්යයන්ට බාධා කරමින් අපරාධයක් සිදු කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා ලදී. පසුව ඔහුට ඇප නියම වූ අතර, නඩු විභාගය අවසන් වීමෙන් පසු ඔහුට දඬුවම් නියම විය.",
        "සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ (SJB) පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතාගේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධුරය පුරප්පාඩු වී ඇති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා 2021 අප්‍රේල් 7 වන දින පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට දැනුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු පනතට අනුව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක මන්ත්‍රී ධූරයෙන් ඉවත් වන බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම්වරයා මැතිවරණ කොමිසමට දැනුම් දී ඇති බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "‘කොන්දේසි සහිත ජනාධිපති සමාව’ මත රන්ජන් රාමනායක කොළඹ බන්ධනාගාරයෙන් නිදහස්",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පාසල් දරුවන් පෝෂණය කිරීම සඳහා එක්සත් ජනපදය ආහාර මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 3000ක් පරිත්‍යාග කරයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "රන්ජන් ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවට",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂය සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති සමාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26) උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාවෙන්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021 ජනවාරි 12 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020 ජනවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වගන්තිය 111C (2",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021 අප්‍රේල් 7 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැතිවරණ කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු පනත අනුව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 3,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரஞ்சனை தேசியப்பட்டியலுக்கு நியமிக்க SJB விரும்புகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); தேசியப் பட்டியலில் வெற்றிடமொன்று ஏற்பட்டால் முதல் தடவையாக முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவை நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக நியமிக்க சமகி ஜன பலவேகய கட்சி உறுதியளிக்கும் என எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு நிபந்தனையுடன் கூடிய ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பை வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (26) காலை வழங்கினார்.",
        "நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதிக்கும் வகையிலான எந்தவொரு கருத்தையும் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க வெளியிடமாட்டார் என்ற நிபந்தனைகளுக்கு உட்பட்டு மன்னிப்பு வழங்கப்படுமென ஜனாதிபதி ஊடகப் பிரிவு விடுத்துள்ள அறிக்கையில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "2021 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜனவரி மாதம் 12 ஆம் திகதி, நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதித்த குற்றத்திற்காக ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு சிறைத்தண்டனை விதிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு இலங்கை உச்சநீதிமன்றம் நான்கு ஆண்டுகள் கடுங்காவல் சிறைத்தண்டனை விதித்தது.",
        "2018 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜனாதிபதியால் பாராளுமன்றம் கலைக்கப்பட்டமைக்கு எதிராக தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட மனுக்களை விசாரிக்கும் உச்ச நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதி பெஞ்ச் அமைப்பு தொடர்பில் சர்ச்சைக்குரிய கருத்தை வெளியிட்டதாக நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதித்ததாக ராமநாயக்க மீது குற்றம் சுமத்தப்பட்டிருந்தது.",
        "ஜனவரி 2020 இல், நீதிபதிகளின் செயல்பாடுகளில் தலையிடுவதன் மூலம் அரசியலமைப்பின் 111 சி (2) பிரிவுகளின்படி குற்றம் செய்ததற்காக ராமநாயக்க கைது செய்யப்பட்டார். பின்னர் அவருக்கு ஜாமீன் வழங்கப்பட்டு, வழக்கு விசாரணை முடிவடைந்ததை தொடர்ந்து அவருக்கு தண்டனை விதிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "2021 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஏப்ரல் மாதம் 7 ஆம் திகதி, இலங்கை சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன, சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவின் பாராளுமன்ற ஆசனம் வெற்றிடமாக இருப்பதாக அறிவிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற சட்டத்தின் பிரகாரம் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க எம்பி பதவியில் இருந்து விலகுவதாக பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் தேர்தல்கள் ஆணைக்குழுவிற்கு அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கொழும்பு சிறையிலிருந்து ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க ‘நிபந்தனைக்குட்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பில்’ விடுதலை",
        "இலங்கையின் பாடசாலை மாணவர்களுக்கு உணவளிக்க அமெரிக்கா 3,000 மெட்ரிக் தொன் உணவை வழங்குகிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரஞ்சன் தேசியப்பட்டியலுக்கு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்க்கட்சியான சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பட்டியல்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26) காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னிக்கவும்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 12, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு வருடங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிவு 111C (2",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 7, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேர்தல் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற சட்டத்தின்படி",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}