{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Basils-exit-from-country-foiled-after-protests-by-passengers/342-240901",
  "time_ut": 1657595898,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Basil’s exit from country foiled after protests by passengers",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Basil’s exit from country foiled after protests by passengers",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "An attempt by former Minister Basil Rajapaksa to leave the country through the Silk Route Passenger Clearance Terminal was foiled due to airport immigration officials refusing to let him leave the country following the protests by passengers.",
        "According to the immigration office sources, the former Minister arrived at the Badaranaike International Airport (BIA) at 12.00 midnight last night to leave for Dubai.",
        "The reserved fight for Basil Rajapaksa was scheduled to leave for Dubai at 3.15 am today.",
        "However, the immigration officers refused to approve Basil Rajapaksa's departure. Later, the Sri Lanka Immigration and Emigration Officers' Association (SLIEOA) decided to withdraw from functioning at the Silk Route Passenger Clearance Terminal from last night.",
        "However, it was reported that Basil Rajapaksa had to return without being able to proceed. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Basil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Silk Route Passenger Clearance Terminal",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Badaranaike International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "12.00 midnight last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.15 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Immigration",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLIEOA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Silk Route Passenger Clearance Terminal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මගීන්ගේ විරෝධයෙන් බැසිල් රටින් පිටවීම අසාර්ථක විය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සේද මාර්ග මගී නිෂ්කාශන පර්යන්තය හරහා හිටපු අමාත්‍ය බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතා රටින් පිටවීමට ගත් උත්සාහය මගීන්ගේ විරෝධය හමුවේ ඔහුට රටින් පිටවීමට ගුවන් තොටුපළ ආගමන විගමන නිලධාරීන් අවසර නොදීම හේතුවෙන් ව්‍යර්ථ විය.",
        "ආගමන විගමන කාර්යාල ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කළේ, හිටපු අමාත්‍යවරයා ඩුබායි බලා පිටත්ව යාම සඳහා ඊයේ මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රී 12.00 ට බදනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළට (BIA) පැමිණි බවයි.",
        "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ වෙනුවෙන් වෙන්වූ සටන අද අලුයම 3.15ට ඩුබායි බලා පිටත්වීමට නියමිතව තිබුණි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ නික්මයාම අනුමත කිරීම ආගමන විගමන නිලධාරීන් ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය. පසුව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආගමන හා විගමන නිලධාරීන්ගේ සංගමය (SLIEOA) සේද මාර්ග මගී නිෂ්කාශන පර්යන්තයේ ක්‍රියාකාරීත්වයෙන් ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ සිට ඉවත් වීමට තීරණය කළේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් ඉදිරියට යාමට නොහැකිව බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂට ආපසු යාමට සිදුවූ බවයි වාර්තා වුණේ. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බැසිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සේද මාර්ගයේ මගී නිෂ්කාශන පර්යන්තය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රී 12.00",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.15 පෙ.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආගමන",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLIEOA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සේද මාර්ගයේ මගී නිෂ්කාශන පර්යන්තය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பயணிகளின் எதிர்ப்பை அடுத்து பசிலின் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறுவது தோல்வியடைந்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் பசில் ராஜபக்ச பட்டுப்பாதை பயணிகள் அனுமதி முனையத்தின் ஊடாக நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேற மேற்கொண்ட முயற்சி, பயணிகளின் எதிர்ப்பை அடுத்து விமான நிலைய குடிவரவு அதிகாரிகள் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேற அனுமதிக்க மறுத்ததால் முறியடிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "டுபாய் செல்வதற்காக முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் நேற்று நள்ளிரவு 12.00 மணியளவில் பதராநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தை (BIA) வந்தடைந்ததாக குடிவரவு குடியகழ்வு அலுவலக வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "பசில் ராஜபக்சவுக்கான ஒதுக்கப்பட்ட போராட்டம் இன்று அதிகாலை 3.15 மணிக்கு டுபாய்க்கு செல்லவிருந்தது.",
        "எனினும், பசில் ராஜபக்ச வெளியேறுவதற்கு குடிவரவு அதிகாரிகள் அனுமதி மறுத்துள்ளனர். பின்னர், இலங்கை குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு அதிகாரிகள் சங்கம் (SLIEOA) நேற்று இரவு முதல் பட்டுப்பாதை பயணிகள் அனுமதி முனையத்தில் செயற்படுவதிலிருந்து விலக தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "எனினும் அதனை தொடர முடியாமல் பசில் ராஜபக்ச திரும்ப வேண்டிய நிலை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "துளசி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பட்டு பாதை பயணிகள் அனுமதி முனையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பதராநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று நள்ளிரவு 12.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 3.15 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்சவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை குடிவரவு",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLIEOA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பட்டு பாதை பயணிகள் அனுமதி முனையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}