{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/2100-businesses-installed-their-own-fuel-storage-tanks-many-without-permission-Minister/342-243739",
  "time_ut": 1661429662,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "2100+ businesses installed their own fuel storage tanks, many without permission: Minister",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "2100+ businesses installed their own fuel storage tanks, many without permission: Minister",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Power and Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekera said that the Ministry has observed that 2100 plus businesses have installed their own fuel storage tanks as consumer points, many without approval.",
        "Accordingly, he said that the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC) will not distribute to businesses that have no approvals and do not comply with guidelines.",
        "However, distribution to the 1250 plus fuel stations will be prioritized.",
        "Meanwhile, he said that upon evaluating consumer points, the CPC will continue distribution of essential consumer points.",
        "\"Export businesses will be required to pay in US$. Businesses can also make arrangements to fulfil their requirements from bunker suppliers,\" the Minister said.",
        "Nevertheless, petrol will not be delivered to businesses, he  reiterated. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1250",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US$",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "2100+ ව්‍යාපාරිකයන් තමන්ගේම ඉන්ධන ගබඩා ටැංකි සවිකර ඇති අතර බොහෝ ඒවා අවසරයකින් තොරව: ඇමති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර මහතා පැවසුවේ, ව්‍යාපාර 2100 කට වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් ඔවුන්ගේම ඉන්ධන ගබඩා ටැංකි පාරිභෝගික ස්ථාන ලෙස ස්ථාපිත කර ඇති බවත්, බොහෝ ඒවා අනුමැතියකින් තොරව බවත් අමාත්‍යාංශය නිරීක්ෂණය කර ඇති බවයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව කිසිදු අනුමැතියක් නොමැති සහ මාර්ගෝපදේශවලට අනුකූල නොවන ව්‍යාපාර සඳහා බෙදා හැරීම සිදු නොකරන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, 1250 ට වැඩි ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් වෙත බෙදා හැරීමට ප්‍රමුඛත්වය දෙනු ලැබේ.",
        "මේ අතර පාරිභෝගික ලකුණු ඇගයීමෙන් පසු ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව අත්‍යවශ්‍ය පාරිභෝගික ලකුණු බෙදා හැරීම අඛණ්ඩව සිදු කරන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "\"අපනයන ව්‍යාපාර සඳහා ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් වලින් ගෙවීමට සිදුවනු ඇත. ව්‍යාපාරවලටද බංකර් සැපයුම්කරුවන්ගෙන් තම අවශ්‍යතා ඉටුකර ගැනීමට කටයුතු කළ හැක,\" අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "එසේ වුවද, ව්‍යාපාරවලට පෙට්‍රල් ලබා නොදෙන බව ඔහු නැවත අවධාරණය කළේය. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1250",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US$",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "2100+ வணிகங்கள் தங்கள் சொந்த எரிபொருள் சேமிப்பு தொட்டிகளை நிறுவியுள்ளன, பல அனுமதியின்றி: அமைச்சர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர, 2100க்கும் மேற்பட்ட வர்த்தக நிறுவனங்கள் தமது சொந்த எரிபொருள் சேமிப்பு தாங்கிகளை நுகர்வோர் புள்ளிகளாக நிறுவியுள்ளதை அமைச்சு அவதானித்துள்ளதாக தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இதன்படி, இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் (CPC) அனுமதி பெறாத மற்றும் வழிகாட்டுதல்களுக்கு இணங்காத வணிகங்களுக்கு விநியோகிக்காது என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், 1250 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட எரிபொருள் நிலையங்களுக்கு விநியோகம் முன்னுரிமை அளிக்கப்படும்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், நுகர்வோர் புள்ளிகளை மதிப்பிடும்போது, ​​அத்தியாவசிய நுகர்வோர் புள்ளிகளை CPC தொடர்ந்து விநியோகிக்கும் என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"ஏற்றுமதி வணிகங்கள் அமெரிக்க டாலரில் செலுத்த வேண்டும். வணிகங்கள் பதுங்கு குழி சப்ளையர்களிடமிருந்து தங்கள் தேவைகளை பூர்த்தி செய்ய ஏற்பாடு செய்யலாம்,\" என்று அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "இருந்தபோதிலும், வணிக நிறுவனங்களுக்கு பெட்ரோல் வழங்கப்படாது என்று அவர் மீண்டும் வலியுறுத்தினார். (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1250",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க டாலர்$",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}