{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/litro-says-hopeful-of-ending-sri-lankas-cooking-gas-queues-end-july-97240/",
  "time_ut": 1657603320,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Litro says hopeful of ending Sri Lanka’s cooking gas queues end-July",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Litro says hopeful of ending Sri Lanka’s cooking gas queues end-July",
      "author": "Dulya de Silva",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s state owned Litro Gas Lanka Ltd hopes to eliminate the country’s cooking gas queues by July 31 and to maintain adequate stocks in the country till the end of October, Chairman Muditha Pieris said.",
        "The company commenced distribution on Monday July 11 after a period of interruption due to Sri Lanka’s inability to import stocks.",
        "“From [Tuesday July 12] morning we will be distributing 120,000 cylinders,” Peiris said.",
        "While prices on the 12.5 kg cylinders have been hiked, Pieris urged the public not to buy from the black market as Litro had made arrangements to procure 33,000 MT of gas till the end of July, and 100,000 MT to last till the end of October this year.",
        "“We have already paid for the initial ships, and signed agreements with the World Bank. People will not have to wait a long time in lines because we have bought necessary stocks to fulfil the needs.”",
        "Pieris said a shipment of 3,200 MT was due July 16 night, and a ship carrying 20,000 MT was currently nearing the Maldives sea.",
        "Litro is also expecting to release gas to the Keravalapitiya Gas Terminal from four ships, starting July 20.",
        "Sri Lanka’s gas shortage has forced many people to turn to firewood or kerosene stoves. Sri Lankans are also unable to deal with the rising costs of gas cylinders.",
        "Litro officials had urged the public back in June to not queue up due to lack of supply.",
        "At present, officials have instructed the public to produce their electricity bill for the month of May when buying gas, in a bid to reduce hoarding.",
        "The country’s lack of dollars and downgraded ratings have made it difficult to ensure a steady supply of cooking gas and fuel. So far at least 15 people have died in the queues that have formed since March.",
        "The gas shortage left many families unable to cook meals to feed themselves. In this situation, added to a food shortage, high inflation, power cuts and standstill of public transport, the majority of the country is currently dragging their way through daily life. (Colombo/Jul11/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Litro",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "end-July",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas Lanka Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of October",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muditha Pieris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday July 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12] morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "120,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12.5 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pieris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "33,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of October this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pieris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 16 night",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Keravalapitiya Gas Terminal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the month of May",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "at least 15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "March",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉවුම් පිහුම් ගෑස් පෝලිම් ජූලි අගදී අවසන් කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව Litro පවසයි",
      "author": "දුල්යා ද සිල්වා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රජයට අයත් Litro Gas Lanka Ltd ජූලි 31 වනදා වන විට රටේ ඉවුම් පිහුම් ගෑස් පෝලිම් ඉවත් කර ඔක්තෝබර් අවසානය දක්වා ප්‍රමාණවත් තොග රට තුළ පවත්වා ගැනීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව සභාපති මුදිත පීරිස් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට කොටස් ආනයනය කිරීමට නොහැකි වීම හේතුවෙන් බාධාවකින් පසු සමාගම ජූලි 11 සඳුදා බෙදා හැරීම ආරම්භ කළේය.",
        "“[ජුලි 12 අඟහරුවාදා] උදෑසන සිට අපි සිලින්ඩර 120,000ක් බෙදාහරිනවා,” පීරිස් පැවසීය.",
        "කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 12.5 සිලින්ඩරවල මිල ඉහළ නංවා ඇති අතර, ජූලි මස අවසන් වන තෙක් ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 33,000ක් ලබා ගැනීමටත්, මේ ඔක්තෝම්බර් මස අවසන් වනතුරු මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 100,000ක් ලබා ගැනීමටත් කටයුතු කර ඇති බැවින් කළු කඩයෙන් මිලදී නොගන්නා ලෙස පීරිස් ජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. වර්ෂය.",
        "“අපි දැනටමත් මූලික නැව් සඳහා මුදල් ගෙවා ඇති අතර ලෝක බැංකුව සමඟ ගිවිසුම් අත්සන් කර ඇත. අවශ්‍යතා සපුරාලීම සඳහා අවශ්‍ය තොග අප විසින් මිලදී ගෙන ඇති නිසා මිනිසුන්ට දිගු වේලාවක් පෝලිම්වල රැඳී සිටීමට සිදු නොවනු ඇත.",
        "පීරිස් පැවසුවේ ජූලි 16 රාත්‍රියේ මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 3,200 ක නැව්ගත කිරීමක් සිදු කළ යුතු බවත්, මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 20,000 ක් රැගත් නෞකාවක් මේ වන විට මාලදිවයින් මුහුද ආසන්නයේ පවතින බවත් ය.",
        "ලිට්‍රෝ සමාගම ජූලි 20 වැනිදා සිට කෙරවලපිටිය ගෑස් පර්යන්තයට නැව් හතරකින් ගෑස් මුදා හැරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ගෑස් හිඟය බොහෝ දෙනෙකුට දර හෝ භූමිතෙල් ලිප වෙත යොමු වීමට සිදු වී ඇත. ගෑස් සිලින්ඩර් මිල ඉහළ යාමත් සමඟ ගනුදෙනු කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ට ද නොහැකි වී තිබේ.",
        "සැපයුම නොමැතිකම හේතුවෙන් පෝලිම්වලට නොයන ලෙස ලිට්‍රෝ නිලධාරීන් ජුනි මාසයේදී මහජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "මේ වන විට ගෑස් මිළදී ගැනීමේදී මැයි මාසය සඳහා වන විදුලි බිල්පත් ගොඩගැසීම අවම කිරීමේ අරමුණින් මහජනතාවට තම විදුලි බිල ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලෙස නිලධාරීන් දැනුම් දී ඇත.",
        "රටේ ඩොලර් හිඟකම සහ ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම් පහත හෙලීම නිසා ඉවුම් පිහුම් ගෑස් සහ ඉන්ධන ස්ථාවර සැපයුමක් සහතික කිරීම දුෂ්කර වී ඇත. මාර්තු මාසයේ සිට ඇති වූ පෝලිම් වලින් මේ වන විට අවම වශයෙන් පුද්ගලයින් 15 දෙනෙකු මිය ගොස් ඇත.",
        "ගෑස් හිඟය නිසා බොහෝ පවුල්වලට ආහාර පිසීමට නොහැකි විය. මේ තත්ත්වය තුළ ආහාර හිඟයකට, අධික උද්ධමනයකට, විදුලි කප්පාදුවට සහ පොදු ප්‍රවාහනය ඇනහිටීමට එක් වූ රටේ බහුතරයක් මේ වන විට දෛනික ජීවිතය ඇද දමමින් සිටිති. (කොළඹ/ජූලි11/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "අවසානය-ජූලි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔක්තෝබර් අවසානය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදිත පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 11 සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12] උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "120,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 12.5 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "33,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි අග",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ ඔක්තෝබර් අවසානයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,200 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 16 රෑ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙරවලපිටිය ගෑස් පර්යන්තය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැයි මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් 15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் சமையல் எரிவாயு வரிசைகள் ஜூலை மாத இறுதியில் முடிவுக்கு வரும் என லிட்ரோ நம்பிக்கை தெரிவித்துள்ளது",
      "author": "துல்யா டி சில்வா",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - இலங்கையின் அரசுக்குச் சொந்தமான Litro Gas Lanka Ltd, ஜூலை 31ஆம் தேதிக்குள் நாட்டின் சமையல் எரிவாயு வரிசையை அகற்றி, அக்டோபர் இறுதி வரை நாட்டில் போதுமான அளவு இருப்புகளைப் பராமரிக்க நம்புகிறது என்று தலைவர் முதித பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பங்குகளை இறக்குமதி செய்ய இலங்கையின் இயலாமை காரணமாக ஒரு கால இடைவெளியின் பின்னர் நிறுவனம் ஜூலை 11 திங்கட்கிழமை விநியோகத்தை ஆரம்பித்தது.",
        "“[செவ்வாய் 12] காலை முதல் நாங்கள் 120,000 சிலிண்டர்களை விநியோகிப்போம்,” என்று பீரிஸ் கூறினார்.",
        "12.5 கிலோ எடையுள்ள சிலிண்டர்களின் விலை உயர்த்தப்பட்டுள்ள நிலையில், ஜூலை இறுதி வரை 33,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் எரிவாயுவையும், அக்டோபர் இறுதி வரை 100,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் எரிவாயுவையும் கொள்முதல் செய்ய லிட்ரோ ஏற்பாடு செய்திருப்பதால் கறுப்புச் சந்தையில் வாங்க வேண்டாம் என்று பீரிஸ் பொதுமக்களை கேட்டுக் கொண்டார். ஆண்டு.",
        "\"நாங்கள் ஏற்கனவே ஆரம்பக் கப்பல்களுக்கு பணம் செலுத்தியுள்ளோம், மேலும் உலக வங்கியுடன் ஒப்பந்தங்களில் கையெழுத்திட்டுள்ளோம். தேவைகளை பூர்த்தி செய்ய தேவையான பங்குகளை நாங்கள் வாங்கியிருப்பதால் மக்கள் நீண்ட நேரம் வரிசையில் காத்திருக்க வேண்டியதில்லை.",
        "ஜூலை 16 இரவு 3,200 மெட்ரிக் டன் ஏற்றுமதி செய்ய வேண்டும் என்றும், 20,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்களை ஏற்றிச் செல்லும் கப்பல் தற்போது மாலத்தீவு கடலை நெருங்கி வருவதாகவும் பீரிஸ் கூறினார்.",
        "ஜூலை 20 முதல் நான்கு கப்பல்களில் இருந்து கெரவலப்பிட்டி எரிவாயு முனையத்திற்கு எரிவாயுவை வெளியிட Litro எதிர்பார்க்கிறது.",
        "இலங்கையில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள எரிவாயு தட்டுப்பாடு பலரை விறகு அல்லது மண்ணெண்ணெய் அடுப்புகளை நாட வேண்டிய கட்டாயத்தில் உள்ளது. அதிகரித்து வரும் எரிவாயு சிலிண்டர்களின் விலையை சமாளிக்க முடியாமல் இலங்கையர்களும் உள்ளனர்.",
        "சப்ளை இல்லாததால் வரிசையில் நிற்க வேண்டாம் என்று லிட்ரோ அதிகாரிகள் ஜூன் மாதத்தில் பொதுமக்களை வலியுறுத்தினர்.",
        "தற்போது, ​​காஸ் வாங்கும் போது, ​​பதுக்கல்லை குறைக்கும் வகையில், மே மாதத்துக்கான மின் கட்டணத்தை பொதுமக்கள் தாக்கல் செய்ய அதிகாரிகள் அறிவுறுத்தியுள்ளனர்.",
        "நாட்டின் டாலர்கள் பற்றாக்குறை மற்றும் தரமிறக்கப்பட்ட மதிப்பீடுகள் ஆகியவை சமையல் எரிவாயு மற்றும் எரிபொருளின் நிலையான விநியோகத்தை உறுதி செய்வதை கடினமாக்கியுள்ளன. மார்ச் மாதத்தில் இருந்து உருவான வரிசைகளில் இதுவரை குறைந்தது 15 பேர் இறந்துள்ளனர்.",
        "எரிவாயு தட்டுப்பாடு காரணமாக பல குடும்பங்கள் உணவு சமைக்க முடியாமல் தவித்தனர். இந்த சூழ்நிலையில், உணவுப் பற்றாக்குறை, உயர் பணவீக்கம், மின்வெட்டு மற்றும் பொது போக்குவரத்து ஸ்தம்பிதம் ஆகியவற்றுடன், நாட்டின் பெரும்பான்மையான மக்கள் தற்போது அன்றாட வாழ்க்கையை இழுத்துச் செல்கின்றனர். (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை11/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "லிட்ரோ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இறுதியில்-ஜூலை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் லங்கா லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அக்டோபர் இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதிதா பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 11 திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12] காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "120,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12.5 கி.கி",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "33,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு அக்டோபர் இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 16 இரவு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெரவலப்பிட்டி எரிவாயு முனையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மே மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}