{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/29/gl-meets-commonwealth-foreign-ministers/",
  "time_ut": 1656476640,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "GL meets Commonwealth Foreign Ministers",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "GL meets Commonwealth Foreign Ministers",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); In a series of bilateral meetings held on the sidelines of the Commonwealth Heads of Government Meeting 2022 (CHOGM) in Kigali, Rwanda from 24–25 June 2022, Minister of Foreign Affairs Prof. G.L. Peiris met with the Foreign Ministers and Heads of delegations of Commonwealth Member States to discuss a range of issues of political and economic significance, overcoming the current economic crisis faced by Sri Lanka, and enhancing cooperation through multilateral fora including through the Commonwealth.",
        "In a meeting with Minister of Foreign Affairs, International Business and Diaspora Relations of Dominica Kenneth Melchoir Darroux , Foreign Minister Peiris discussed developments related to tourism which is critical to the economies of both nations. The two Ministers shared experiences of increasing resilience in the tourism industry to cope with COVID-19 pandemic and ongoing global crises.",
        "Minister Peiris met with Minister for Foreign Affairs and Tourism of the Republic of Seychelles Sylvestre Radegonde and discussed the status of several promising ventures such as medical tourism and enhancing cooperation in ocean related issues. Minister Peiris stated that Sri Lanka was focused on Seychelles as a gateway to enhancing trade and bilateral relations with the African Continent. Minister Radegonde thanked Sri Lanka for the donation of 2 patrol boats for maritime surveillance, following a request made by Seychelles.",
        "In a bilateral meeting with Minister for Foreign Affairs of the People’s Republic of Bangladesh A.K. Abdul Momen, the Bangladesh side briefed Minister Peiris on steps being taken by Bangladesh to assist Sri Lanka during the current economic crisis including through provision of food, medical assistance and the extension of a credit line. Minister Peiris thanked Minister Momen for the assistance at this critical stage. The two Ministers also discussed avenues of increasing bilateral trade. Minister Momen noted Sri Lanka’s successful hosting of the Fifth Summit of Heads of State/ Government of the Bay of Bengal Initiative for Multi-Sectoral Technical and Economic Cooperation (BIMSTEC) in March 2022 in virtual format.",
        "Minister Peiris briefed Cabinet Secretary for Foreign Affairs of the Republic of Kenya Raychelle Omamo on the several steps taken by Sri Lanka to address reconciliation related issues and added that Sri Lanka was keen to learn from African countries regarding their reconciliation experiences. Cabinet Secretary Omano shared the experiences related to reconciliation efforts in Kenya and added that each country has to devise a template that promotes healing. Noting that several Sri Lankan companies had invested in the garment sector in Kenya, Cabinet Secretary Omano encouraged Sri Lanka to explore joint ventures with Kenyan companies in other industries.",
        "In a bilateral meeting with Minister for Foreign Affairs, Regional Integration and International Trade of the Republic of Mauritius Alan Ganoo, Minister Peiris encouraged greater cooperation between the two countries in ocean affairs issues, including in regional and international fora. The two Ministers also discussed the effect of climate change on island nations, cooperation in tourism industry and addressing the impact of soaring food prices in the world market.",
        "Minister Peiris’s bilateral meeting with Minister for Foreign Affairs of the Republic of Cyprus Ioannis Kasoulides, focused on employment opportunities and consular assistance to the Sri Lankan workers in Cyprus. Minister Peiris appreciated the employment opportunities provided by Cyprus and added that Sri Lanka was keen to increase foreign employment opportunities. Minister Kasoulides briefed Minister Peiris on steps that the Cyprus government was taking to enhance welfare measures to Sri Lankan workers. Sharing their experiences in dealing with the IMF to address economic challenges, Minister Kasoulides said that Cyprus experienced an economic turnaround after implementing critical economic reforms on an expeditious basis.",
        "Several issues related to enhancing multi-faceted bilateral relations was discussed in a bilateral meeting between Minister Peiris and Minister for Foreign Affairs of Malaysia Saifuddin Abdullah. Minister Abdullah stated that many Sri Lankan origin Malaysians have contributed to the growth of Malaysia. Noting that the Malaysian government was focused on developing a digital economy, Minister Abdullah suggested that Sri Lanka explore the job market for IT workers in Malaysia. The also Ministers discussed close cooperation between the two countries on ocean related issues at multilateral fora.",
        "Minister Peiris concluded his visit to Rwanda with a meeting between Minister for Foreign Affairs and International Cooperation of the Republic of Rwanda Vincent Biruta. Minister Peiris congratulated Minister Biruta for the Rwandan government’s successful hosting of the CHOGM meeting adding that the meeting strengthened the Commonwealth at a critical time. Noting that Rwanda has made impressive progress in recent times, particularly on economic and reconciliation spheres, Minister Peiris encouraged closer relations between the two countries.",
        "Minister Biruta thanked Minister Peiris and observed that African countries are gaining confidence to forge their own paths towards economic and political resilience. Minister Biruta also expressed a desire to explore potential areas to strengthen political and trade relations with Sri Lanka.",
        "Previously, Minister Peiris held bilateral discussions with India’s External Affairs Minister Dr. S. Jaishankar and Minister for Foreign Affairs and Local Government of New Zealand Nanaia Mahuta, on the sidelines of CHOGM."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Commonwealth Foreign Ministers",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Commonwealth Heads of Government Meeting 2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CHOGM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kigali",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rwanda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24–25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Foreign Ministers and Heads",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commonwealth",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "fora",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commonwealth",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "International Business",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Diaspora Relations",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seychelles",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the African Continent",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Radegonde",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seychelles",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abdul Momen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Momen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Momen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Fifth Summit of Heads of State/ Government of the Bay of Bengal Initiative for Multi-Sectoral Technical and Economic Cooperation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BIMSTEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "March 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Foreign Affairs of the Republic of Kenya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Omamo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "African",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Omano",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kenya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kenya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Omano",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kenyan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Alan Ganoo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kasoulides",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kasoulides",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Foreign Affairs of",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saifuddin Abdullah",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abdullah",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malaysians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malaysia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malaysian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abdullah",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malaysia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rwanda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Republic of Rwanda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vincent Biruta",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Biruta",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rwandan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "CHOGM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commonwealth",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rwanda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Biruta",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "African",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Biruta",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "External Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Foreign Affairs and Local Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CHOGM",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජීඑල් පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරුන් හමුවෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය රාජ්‍ය නායක සමුළුව 2022 (CHOGM) ට සමගාමීව 2022 ජුනි 24 සිට 25 දක්වා රුවන්ඩාවේ කිගාලි හි පැවති ද්විපාර්ශ්වික රැස්වීම් මාලාවකදී විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්. පීරිස් මහතා විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරුන් සහ නියෝජිත කණ්ඩායම් ප්‍රධානීන් හමුවිය පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය සාමාජික රටවල් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුහුණ දී සිටින වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් මිදීම සහ පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලය ඇතුළු බහුපාර්ශ්වික සංසද හරහා සහයෝගීතාව වැඩි දියුණු කිරීම සඳහා දේශපාලන හා ආර්ථික වැදගත්කමක් ඇති කරුණු රාශියක් සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට.",
        "ඩොමිනිකාගේ විදේශ කටයුතු, ජාත්‍යන්තර ව්‍යාපාර සහ ඩයස්පෝරා සබඳතා අමාත්‍ය Kenneth Melchoir Darroux සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවකදී විදේශ අමාත්‍ය පීරිස් දෙරටේම ආර්ථිකයට තීරණාත්මක වන සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරයට අදාළ වර්ධනයන් පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කළේය. COVID-19 වසංගතයට සහ දැනට පවතින ගෝලීය අර්බුදවලට මුහුණ දීම සඳහා සංචාරක කර්මාන්තයේ ඔරොත්තු දීමේ හැකියාව ඉහළ නැංවීමේ අත්දැකීම් අමාත්‍යවරුන් දෙදෙනා බෙදා ගත්හ.",
        "පීරිස් අමාත්‍යවරයා සීෂෙල්ස් ජනරජයේ විදේශ කටයුතු සහ සංචාරක අමාත්‍ය සිල්වෙස්ට්‍රේ රඩෙගොන්ඩේ මහතා හමුවී වෛද්‍ය සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරය සහ සාගර ආශ්‍රිත ගැටළු සම්බන්ධයෙන් සහයෝගීතාව ඉහළ නැංවීම වැනි පොරොන්දු වූ ව්‍යාපාර කිහිපයක තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කළේය. අමාත්‍ය පීරිස් ප්‍රකාශ කළේ අප්‍රිකානු මහාද්වීපය සමඟ වෙළෙඳ සහ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතා වැඩිදියුණු කර ගැනීමේ දොරටුවක් ලෙස සීෂෙල්ස් රාජ්‍යය කෙරෙහි ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අවධානය යොමු කර ඇති බවයි. සීෂෙල්ස් විසින් කරන ලද ඉල්ලීමකට අනුව සමුද්‍ර නිරීක්ෂණ කටයුතු සඳහා මුර සංචාර යාත්‍රා 2ක් පරිත්‍යාග කිරීම පිළිබඳව අමාත්‍ය රදේගොන්ඬේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ස්තුතිය පුද කළේය.",
        "බංග්ලාදේශ මහජන සමූහාණ්ඩුවේ විදේශ කටයුතු පිළිබඳ අමාත්‍ය ඒ.කේ. අබ්දුල් මොමන්, බංගලිදේශය පාර්ශවයෙන් අමාත්‍ය පීරිස්ට ආහාර සැපයීම, වෛද්‍ය ආධාර සැපයීම සහ ණය මාර්ගය දීර්ඝ කිරීම ඇතුළු වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහය වීමට බංග්ලාදේශය ගෙන ඇති පියවර පිළිබඳව දැනුවත් කරන ලදී. මෙම තීරණාත්මක අවස්ථාවේදී ලබාදුන් සහය පිළිබඳව අමාත්‍ය පීරිස් මහතා අමාත්‍ය මොමන් මහතාට ස්තූතිය පුද කළේය. ද්විපාර්ශ්වික වෙළෙඳාම ඉහළ නැංවීමේ මාර්ග පිළිබඳව ද අමාත්‍යවරුන් දෙදෙනා සාකච්ඡා කළහ. 2022 මාර්තු මාසයේදී බහු ආංශික තාක්ෂණික සහ ආර්ථික සහයෝගීතාව සඳහා වන බෙංගාල බොක්කෙහි රාජ්‍ය නායකයන්ගේ/ රජයේ පස්වන සමුළුව (BIMSTEC) අතථ්‍ය ආකෘතියෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව විසින් සාර්ථකව පැවැත්වීම පිළිබඳව අමාත්‍ය Momen සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "සංහිඳියාව සම්බන්ධ ගැටළු විසඳීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ගෙන ඇති පියවර කිහිපයක් පිළිබඳව කෙන්යානු ජනරජයේ විදේශ කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කැබිනට් ලේකම් Raychelle Omamo වෙත කරුණු දැක්වූ අමාත්‍ය පීරිස්, අප්‍රිකානු රටවල ඔවුන්ගේ සංහිඳියා අත්දැකීම් පිළිබඳව ඉගෙන ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව උනන්දු වන බවද පැවසීය. කැබිනට් ලේකම් ඔමානෝ, කෙන්යාවේ ප්‍රතිසන්ධාන ප්‍රයත්නයන් සම්බන්ධ අත්දැකීම් බෙදාගත් අතර, සෑම රටක්ම සුවය ප්‍රවර්ධනය කරන අච්චුවක් සකස් කළ යුතු බව පැවසීය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සමාගම් කිහිපයක් කෙන්යාවේ ඇඟලුම් ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ ආයෝජනය කර ඇති බව සඳහන් කළ කැබිනට් ලේකම් ඔමානෝ, වෙනත් කර්මාන්තවල කෙන්යානු සමාගම් සමඟ හවුල් ව්‍යාපාර ගවේෂණය කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දිරිමත් කළේය.",
        "මොරිෂස් ජනරජයේ විදේශ කටයුතු, කලාපීය ඒකාබද්ධතා සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර වෙළෙඳ කටයුතු පිළිබඳ අමාත්‍ය ඇලන් ගනූ මහතා සමඟ පැවති ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සාකච්ඡාවකදී අමාත්‍ය පීරිස් මහතා කලාපීය සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර සංසද ඇතුළුව සාගර කටයුතු සම්බන්ධයෙන් දෙරට අතර වැඩි සහයෝගිතාවක් දිරිමත් කළේය. දේශගුණික විපර්යාස හේතුවෙන් දූපත් රාජ්‍යයන්ට ඇති කරන බලපෑම, සංචාරක කර්මාන්තයේ සහයෝගිතාව සහ ලෝක වෙළෙඳපොළේ ආහාර මිල ඉහළ යාමේ බලපෑම පිළිබඳව ද අමාත්‍යවරුන් දෙදෙනා සාකච්ඡා කළහ.",
        "සයිප්‍රස් ජනරජයේ විදේශ කටයුතු පිළිබඳ අමාත්‍ය Ioannis Kasoulides සමඟ අමාත්‍ය පීරිස්ගේ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සාකච්ඡාවේදී සයිප්‍රසයේ ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ශ්‍රමිකයින්ට රැකියා අවස්ථා සහ කොන්සියුලර් ආධාර පිළිබඳව අවධානය යොමු විය. සයිප්‍රසය විසින් සපයනු ලබන රැකියා අවස්ථා පිළිබඳව අමාත්‍ය පීරිස් මහතා අගය කළ අතර විදේශ රැකියා අවස්ථා ඉහළ නැංවීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව උනන්දු වන බවද පැවසීය. සයිප්‍රස් රජය ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ශ්‍රමිකයන්ගේ සුබසාධන ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ඉහළ නැංවීම සඳහා ගෙන යන පියවර පිළිබඳව අමාත්‍ය Kasoulides අමාත්‍ය පීරිස් මහතාට දැනුම් දුන්නේය. ආර්ථික අභියෝගවලට මුහුණ දීම සඳහා ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ ගනුදෙනු කිරීමේදී ඔවුන්ගේ අත්දැකීම් බෙදාගත් අමාත්‍ය Kasoulides කියා සිටියේ කඩිනම් පදනමක් මත තීරණාත්මක ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමෙන් පසු සයිප්‍රසය ආර්ථික පෙරළියක් අත්විඳින බවයි.",
        "පීරිස් අමාත්‍යවරයා සහ මැලේසියාවේ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය සයිෆුදීන් අබ්දුල්ලා අතර පැවති ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සාකච්ඡාවකදී බහුවිධ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතා වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් කරුණු කිහිපයක් සාකච්ඡා කර තිබේ. ශ්‍රී ලාංකික සම්භවයක් ඇති මැලේසියානුවන් රැසක් මැලේසියාවේ වර්ධනයට දායක වී ඇති බව අමාත්‍ය අබ්දුල්ලා ප්‍රකාශ කළා. මැලේසියානු රජය ඩිජිටල් ආර්ථිකයක් සංවර්ධනය කිරීම කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු කර ඇති බව සඳහන් කළ අමාත්‍ය අබ්දුල්ලා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මැලේසියාවේ තොරතුරු තාක්ෂණ සේවකයින් සඳහා රැකියා වෙළඳපොළ ගවේෂණය කරන ලෙස යෝජනා කළේය. බහුපාර්ශ්වික සංසදවලදී සාගර ආශ්‍රිත ගැටළු සම්බන්ධයෙන් දෙරට අතර සමීප සහයෝගීතාව පිළිබඳව ද අමාත්‍යවරු සාකච්ඡා කළහ.",
        "රුවන්ඩා ජනරජයේ විදේශ කටයුතු සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර සහයෝගිතා අමාත්‍ය වින්සන්ට් බිරූටා මහතා අතර හමුවකින් අමාත්‍ය පීරිස් සිය රුවන්ඩා සංචාරය අවසන් කළේය. රුවන්ඩා රජය CHOGM රැස්වීම සාර්ථකව පැවැත්වීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අමාත්‍ය Biruta වෙත සුබ පැතූ අමාත්‍ය පීරිස්, තීරණාත්මක අවස්ථාවකදී මෙම රැස්වීම පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලය ශක්තිමත් කළ බව පැවසීය. රුවන්ඩාව මෑත කාලීනව විශේෂයෙන් ආර්ථික හා සංහිඳියා ක්ෂේත්‍රවල කැපී පෙනෙන ප්‍රගතියක් ලබා ඇති බව සඳහන් කළ අමාත්‍ය පීරිස් දෙරට අතර සමීප සබඳතා දිරිමත් කළේය.",
        "අමාත්‍ය Biruta අමාත්‍යවරයාට ස්තූතිය පුද කළ අතර, අප්‍රිකානු රටවල් ආර්ථික හා දේශපාලනික ඔරොත්තු දීමේ හැකියාව සඳහා තමන්ගේම මාවතක් සකස් කර ගැනීමට විශ්වාසයක් ඇති කරගෙන සිටින බව නිරීක්ෂණය කළේය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ දේශපාලන සහ වෙළඳ සබඳතා ශක්තිමත් කර ගැනීමට විභව ක්ෂේත්‍ර ගවේෂණය කිරීමට ද අමාත්‍ය Biruta කැමැත්ත පළ කළේය.",
        "මීට පෙර, CHOGM එකට සමගාමීව, අමාත්‍ය පීරිස්, ඉන්දියාවේ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය ආචාර්ය S. Jaishankar සහ විදේශ කටයුතු සහ නවසීලන්ත පළාත් පාලන අමාත්‍ය Nanaia Mahuta සමඟ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරු",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය රාජ්‍ය නායක සමුළුව 2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චෝගම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිගාලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුවන්ඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24-25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ ඇමතිවරුන් සහ ප්රධානීන්",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු රාජ්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳහා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු රාජ්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්යන්තර ව්යාපාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩයස්පෝරා සබඳතා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීෂෙල්ස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රිකානු මහාද්වීපය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රදේගොන්ඩේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීෂෙල්ස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබ්දුල් මොමන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොහොත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොහොත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බහු-ආංශික තාක්ෂණික සහ ආර්ථික සහයෝගීතාව සඳහා වන බෙංගාල බොක්කෙහි රාජ්‍ය/ආණ්ඩුවේ ප්‍රධානීන්ගේ පස්වන සමුළුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිම්ස්ටෙක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 මාර්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙන්යා ජනරජයේ විදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔමාමෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමානෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙන්යාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙන්යාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමානෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙන්යානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇලන් ගනූ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කසූලිඩ්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කසූලිඩ්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සයිෆුදීන් අබ්දුල්ලා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබ්දුල්ලා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැලේසියන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැලේසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැලේසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබ්දුල්ලා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැලේසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුවන්ඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුවන්ඩා ජනරජය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වින්සන්ට් බිරූටා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිරුටා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුවන්ඩාව",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චෝගම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු රාජ්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුවන්ඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බිරුටා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිරුටා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්. ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු සහ පළාත් පාලන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චෝගම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பொதுநலவாய வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர்களை சந்தித்தார் ஜி.எல்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 2022 ஜூன் 24-25 வரை ருவாண்டாவின் கிகாலியில் நடைபெற்ற காமன்வெல்த் தலைவர்கள் மாநாடு 2022 (CHOGM) ஐ ஒட்டி நடைபெற்ற இருதரப்பு சந்திப்புகளின் தொடரில், வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல். பீரிஸ் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர்கள் மற்றும் பிரதிநிதிகளின் தலைவர்களை சந்தித்தார். பொதுநலவாய உறுப்பு நாடுகள் அரசியல் மற்றும் பொருளாதார முக்கியத்துவம் வாய்ந்த பல்வேறு விடயங்களைப் பற்றி விவாதிக்க, இலங்கை எதிர்கொள்ளும் தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை சமாளித்தல் மற்றும் பொதுநலவாய நாடுகள் உட்பட பலதரப்பு மன்றங்கள் மூலம் ஒத்துழைப்பை மேம்படுத்துதல்.",
        "டொமினிகா கென்னத் மெல்கொயர் டாரோக்ஸின் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர், சர்வதேச வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் புலம்பெயர் உறவுகள் அமைச்சர் பீரிஸ், இரு நாடுகளினதும் பொருளாதாரத்திற்கு முக்கியமான சுற்றுலாத்துறை தொடர்பான அபிவிருத்திகள் குறித்து கலந்துரையாடினார். கோவிட்-19 தொற்றுநோய் மற்றும் நிலவும் உலகளாவிய நெருக்கடிகளைச் சமாளிக்க சுற்றுலாத் துறையில் அதிகரித்த பின்னடைவு பற்றிய அனுபவங்களை இரு அமைச்சர்களும் பகிர்ந்து கொண்டனர்.",
        "அமைச்சர் பீரிஸ், சீஷெல்ஸ் குடியரசின் வெளிவிவகார மற்றும் சுற்றுலாத்துறை அமைச்சர் சில்வெஸ்டர் ராடெகோண்டேவைச் சந்தித்து, மருத்துவச் சுற்றுலா மற்றும் கடல் தொடர்பான பிரச்சினைகளில் ஒத்துழைப்பை மேம்படுத்துதல் போன்ற பல நம்பிக்கைக்குரிய முயற்சிகளின் நிலை குறித்து கலந்துரையாடினார். ஆபிரிக்க கண்டத்துடன் வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் இருதரப்பு உறவுகளை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கான நுழைவாயிலாக சீசெல்ஸ் மீது இலங்கை கவனம் செலுத்துவதாக அமைச்சர் பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்தார். சீஷெல்ஸ் விடுத்த கோரிக்கையை அடுத்து, கடல் கண்காணிப்புக்காக 2 ரோந்துப் படகுகளை இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கியதற்கு அமைச்சர் ராதேகொண்டே நன்றி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பங்களாதேஷ் மக்கள் குடியரசின் வெளியுறவுத்துறை அமைச்சர் ஏ.கே உடனான இருதரப்பு சந்திப்பில். அப்துல் மொமன், பங்களாதேஷ் தரப்பு, தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியின் போது இலங்கைக்கு உணவு வழங்குதல், மருத்துவ உதவி வழங்குதல் மற்றும் கடன் வரியை நீடித்தல் உட்பட பங்களாதேஷ் எடுத்து வரும் நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்து அமைச்சர் பீரிஸுக்கு விளக்கமளித்தது. இந்த நெருக்கடியான கட்டத்தில் உதவியமைக்காக அமைச்சர் மொமனுக்கு அமைச்சர் பீரிஸ் நன்றி தெரிவித்தார். இருதரப்பு வர்த்தகத்தை அதிகரிப்பதற்கான வழிகள் குறித்தும் இரு அமைச்சர்களும் விவாதித்தனர். பல துறை தொழில்நுட்ப மற்றும் பொருளாதார ஒத்துழைப்புக்கான (பிம்ஸ்டெக்) வங்காள விரிகுடாவின் அரச தலைவர்களின்/அரசாங்கத்தின் ஐந்தாவது உச்சிமாநாட்டை மார்ச் 2022 இல் மெய்நிகர் வடிவத்தில் இலங்கை வெற்றிகரமாக நடத்தியதை அமைச்சர் மொமன் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "நல்லிணக்கம் தொடர்பான பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு தீர்வு காண்பதற்கு இலங்கை எடுத்த பல நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்து கென்யா குடியரசின் வெளிவிவகாரங்களுக்கான அமைச்சரவை செயலாளர் ரேசெல் ஒமாமோவிடம் அமைச்சர் பீரிஸ் விளக்கமளித்தார். கென்யாவில் நல்லிணக்க முயற்சிகள் தொடர்பான அனுபவங்களைப் பகிர்ந்துகொண்ட கேபினட் செயலர் ஓமனோ, ஒவ்வொரு நாடும் குணப்படுத்துவதை ஊக்குவிக்கும் டெம்ப்ளேட்டை உருவாக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் கூறினார். கென்யாவில் ஆடைத் துறையில் பல இலங்கை நிறுவனங்கள் முதலீடு செய்திருப்பதைக் குறிப்பிட்ட கேபினட் செயலாளர் ஓமனோ, கென்ய நிறுவனங்களுடன் மற்ற தொழில்களில் கூட்டு முயற்சிகளை ஆராய இலங்கையை ஊக்குவித்தார்.",
        "மொரீஷியஸ் குடியரசின் வெளிவிவகார, பிராந்திய ஒருங்கிணைப்பு மற்றும் சர்வதேச வர்த்தக அமைச்சர் அலன் கானூவுடனான இருதரப்பு சந்திப்பில், பிராந்திய மற்றும் சர்வதேச அரங்குகள் உட்பட கடல் விவகாரங்களில் இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையில் அதிக ஒத்துழைப்பை அமைச்சர் பீரிஸ் ஊக்குவித்தார். தீவு நாடுகளில் பருவநிலை மாற்றத்தால் ஏற்படும் பாதிப்புகள், சுற்றுலாத் துறையில் ஒத்துழைப்பு மற்றும் உலக சந்தையில் உணவுப் பொருட்களின் விலை உயர்வால் ஏற்படும் பாதிப்புகள் குறித்தும் இரு அமைச்சர்களும் விவாதித்தனர்.",
        "சைப்ரஸ் குடியரசின் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் Ioannis Kasoulides உடனான அமைச்சர் பீரிஸின் இருதரப்பு சந்திப்பு, சைப்ரஸில் உள்ள இலங்கைத் தொழிலாளர்களுக்கு வேலை வாய்ப்புகள் மற்றும் தூதரக உதவிகள் குறித்து கவனம் செலுத்தியது. சைப்ரஸ் வழங்கிய தொழில் வாய்ப்புகளை பாராட்டிய அமைச்சர் பீரிஸ், வெளிநாட்டு வேலை வாய்ப்புகளை அதிகரிக்க இலங்கை ஆர்வமாக இருப்பதாகவும் தெரிவித்தார். இலங்கைத் தொழிலாளர்களுக்கான நலன்புரி நடவடிக்கைகளை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கு சைப்ரஸ் அரசாங்கம் எடுத்து வரும் நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்து அமைச்சர் கசோலிட்ஸ் அமைச்சர் பீரிஸிடம் விளக்கினார். பொருளாதார சவால்களை எதிர்கொள்வதற்காக IMF உடன் தங்கள் அனுபவங்களைப் பகிர்ந்து கொண்ட அமைச்சர் Kasoulides, விரைவான அடிப்படையில் முக்கியமான பொருளாதார சீர்திருத்தங்களை செயல்படுத்திய பின்னர் சைப்ரஸ் ஒரு பொருளாதார மாற்றத்தை சந்தித்ததாக கூறினார்.",
        "அமைச்சர் பீரிஸ் மற்றும் மலேசிய வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் சைபுதீன் அப்துல்லா ஆகியோருக்கு இடையில் இடம்பெற்ற இருதரப்பு சந்திப்பில் பலதரப்பு இருதரப்பு உறவுகளை மேம்படுத்துவது தொடர்பான பல விடயங்கள் கலந்துரையாடப்பட்டன. இலங்கையை பூர்வீகமாகக் கொண்ட பல மலேசியர்கள் மலேசியாவின் வளர்ச்சிக்கு பங்களித்துள்ளதாக அமைச்சர் அப்துல்லா தெரிவித்தார். மலேசிய அரசாங்கம் டிஜிட்டல் பொருளாதாரத்தை அபிவிருத்தி செய்வதில் கவனம் செலுத்துவதாக குறிப்பிட்ட அமைச்சர் அப்துல்லா, மலேசியாவில் உள்ள தகவல் தொழில்நுட்ப ஊழியர்களுக்கான வேலை சந்தையை இலங்கை ஆராய வேண்டும் என்று பரிந்துரைத்தார். பலதரப்பு மன்றங்களில் கடல் தொடர்பான பிரச்சனைகளில் இரு நாடுகளுக்கு இடையே உள்ள நெருக்கமான ஒத்துழைப்பு குறித்தும் அமைச்சர்கள் விவாதித்தனர்.",
        "ருவாண்டா குடியரசின் வெளிவிவகார மற்றும் சர்வதேச ஒத்துழைப்புக்கான அமைச்சர் வின்சென்ட் பிருட்டாவிற்கு இடையிலான சந்திப்புடன் அமைச்சர் பீரிஸ் தனது ருவாண்டா விஜயத்தை நிறைவு செய்தார். பொதுநலவாய மாநாட்டை ருவாண்டா அரசாங்கம் வெற்றிகரமாக நடத்தியமைக்காக அமைச்சர் பீரிஸ் அமைச்சர் பிருட்டாவுக்கு வாழ்த்து தெரிவித்தார். குறிப்பாக பொருளாதார மற்றும் நல்லிணக்கத் துறைகளில் அண்மைக் காலங்களில் ருவாண்டா குறிப்பிடத்தக்க முன்னேற்றம் கண்டுள்ளதாகக் குறிப்பிட்ட அமைச்சர் பீரிஸ், இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையிலான நெருக்கமான உறவுகளை ஊக்குவித்தார்.",
        "அமைச்சர் பிருதா அமைச்சர் பீரிஸுக்கு நன்றி தெரிவித்ததுடன், பொருளாதார மற்றும் அரசியல் பின்னடைவை நோக்கி ஆபிரிக்க நாடுகள் தமது சொந்த பாதைகளை உருவாக்குவதற்கான நம்பிக்கையை பெற்றுவருவதை அவதானித்தார். இலங்கையுடனான அரசியல் மற்றும் வர்த்தக உறவுகளை வலுப்படுத்துவதற்கான சாத்தியமான பகுதிகளை ஆராயவும் அமைச்சர் பிருதா விருப்பம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "முன்னதாக, அமைச்சர் பீரிஸ், இந்திய வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் டாக்டர். எஸ். ஜெய்சங்கர் மற்றும் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் நனையா மஹுதா மற்றும் நியூசிலாந்தின் உள்ளூராட்சி அமைச்சர் நனையா மஹுதா ஆகியோருடன் CHOGM ஐ ஒட்டி இருதரப்பு கலந்துரையாடல்களை நடத்தினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "காமன்வெல்த் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர்கள்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "காமன்வெல்த் அரசாங்கத் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டம் 2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CHOGM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிகாலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ருவாண்டா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24-25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளிநாட்டு விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர்கள் மற்றும் தலைவர்கள்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமன்வெல்த்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்றங்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமன்வெல்த்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளிநாட்டு விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலகளாவிய வர்த்தகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புலம்பெயர் உறவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீஷெல்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்பிரிக்க கண்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராடேகோண்டே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீஷெல்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அப்துல் மொமன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொமன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொமன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வங்காள விரிகுடாவின் மாநிலத் தலைவர்களின் ஐந்தாவது உச்சி மாநாடு, பல துறைகளின் தொழில்நுட்ப மற்றும் பொருளாதார ஒத்துழைப்புக்கான முன்முயற்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிம்ஸ்டெக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கென்யா குடியரசின் வெளியுறவு விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமமோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்பிரிக்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமனோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கென்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கென்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமனோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கென்யா",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆலன் கணூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
