{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/හොරුන්ගේ-ආරක්ෂාවට-ජනාධිපතිවරයෙක්-පත්-කරලා/11-395626",
  "time_ut": 1658398539,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "හොරුන්ගේ ආරක්ෂාවට ජනාධිපතිවරයෙක් පත් කරලා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A president has been appointed to protect thieves",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Samagi Jana Balawegaya Secretary General Parliament Member Ranjith Maddumabandara said that the people of the country tried to send the thieves in power home by struggling and marching.",
        "He said this while attending a press conference held at the office of the opposition leader in Colombo.",
        "Further, Member of Parliament Mr. Ranjith Maddumabandara expressed his views.",
        "A new president for this country was elected yesterday in parliament. First of all, I wish him well. I pray that he will get the strength to rebuild this country. We have to ask that the country's referendum was also represented in Parliament yesterday. The MPs in the Parliament today are the MPs who came forward in the 2020 elections under the prevailing atmosphere and according to the opinion of the people at that time. That opinion has changed today. Then we say that the opinion of the country is not reflected here. According to the opinion of the people of the country, the president who was appointed then fled this country. Most of this was done by the people who worked to appoint that president. Most of the MPs appointed with the President are in the Parliament.",
        "So we ask that the people of this country struggled, marched and protested to drive out the thieves. Now today the thieves have joined together and appointed one person. The people of this country expected a clean politics. That's why we prepared to go on a journey together with Mr. Sajith Premadasa, who has clean both hands, and Mr. Dallas Alahapperuma, who has clean hands. Our party did not spend even five cents on this. We need a president who acts according to the opinion of the people. What is the reason for these members of parliament to vote? Recovering the country from the flood? Or establish democracy in the country? According to what we heard, they have to fix the fire in their house. We are not against it. For their own safety. Get your vehicle permit. The MPs here have voted to stay in power."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Maddumabandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Maddumabandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "First",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "five cents",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හොරුන්ගේ ආරක්ෂාවට ජනාධිපතිවරයෙක් පත් කරලා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රටේ ජනතාව අරගල කරමින්, පෙළපාලි යමින් උත්සහ කළේ බලයේ සිටින හොරුන් ගෙදර යැවීමට බවත්, කෙසේ වෙතත් එම හොරු එක්ව සිය ආරක්ෂාවට ජනාධිපතිවරයෙක් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව හරහා පත් කර ගැනීම සිදුවූ බවත් සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ මහලේකම් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රංජිත් මද්දුමබණ්ඩාර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "කොළඹ විපක්ෂනායක කාර්යාලයේ පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකට එක්වෙමින් හෙතෙම මේ බව සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "එහිදී වැඩිදුරටත් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රංජිත් මද්දුමබණ්ඩාර මහතා මෙලෙස අදහස් පළ කර සිටියේය.",
        "මේ රටට අලුත් ජනාධිපතිවරයෙක් ඊයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී තෝරා පත්කර ගත්තා. මම පළමුවෙන් එතුමාට සුබ ප්‍රාර්ථනා කරනවා. එතුමාට මේ රට ගොඩ ගන්න ශක්තිය ලැබේවා කියලා ප්‍රාර්ථනා කරනවා. අපිට අහන්න වෙනවා ඊයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ රටේ ජනමතයද නියෝජනය වුනේ කියලා. අද පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ඉන්න මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 2020 මැතිවරණ වල එදා තිබුණු වාතාවරණය යටතේ, එදා තිබුණු ජනතාවගේ අදහස අනුව ඉදිරිපත් වූ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්. ඒ මතය අද වෙනස් වෙලා තිබෙනවා. එහෙනම් අපි කියනවා රටේ මතය මෙතන පිළිඹිබු වෙලා නෑ කියලා. රටේ ජනතාව සිය මතය අනුව එදා පත් කරපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා මේ රටෙන් පැන්නුවා. ඒ ජනාධිපතිවරයා පත් කරන්න කටයුතු කරපු අය තමයි මේක වැඩි හරියක් කළේ. ඒ ජනාධිපතිවරයා සමග පත්කරපු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වැඩි හරියක් තමයි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ඉන්නේ.",
        "එහෙනම් අපි අහන්නේ මේ රටේ ජනතාව අරගල කළේ, පෙළපාලි ගියේ විරෝධතා දැක්වූයේ හොරු ටික පන්නන්න කියලා. දැන් අද හොරු ටික එකතුවෙලා එක් පුද්ගලයෙක් පත් කරගෙන සිටිනවා. මේ රටේ ජනතාව බලාපොරොත්තු වුණේ පිරිසිදු දේශපාලනයක්. අපි ඒ නිසා තමයි අත් දෙකම පිරිසුදු සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහත්මයාත් අත්දෙක පිරිසිදු ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාත් එකතුවෙලා එක ගමනක් යන්න ලෑස්ති වුණේ. අපේ පක්ෂය නම් මේකට සත පහක්වත් වියදම් කළේ නෑ. අපිට ඔ්නි ජනතාවගේ මතය අනුව කටයුතු කරන ජනාධිපතිවරයෙක්. මොකක්ද මේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ඡන්දය දෙන්න හේතුව? රට ආගාදයෙන් ගොඩ ගැනීමද? නැතිනම් රටේ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය ස්ථාපිත කරන්නද? අපිට ආරංචි විදියට තිබෙන්නේ තමන්ගේ ගේ පිච්චුන එක හදාගන්න. අපි ඒකට විරුද්ධ නෑ. තමන්ගේ ආරක්ෂාවට. තමන්ගේ වාහන පර්මිට් එක ගන්න. තමන් බලයේ ඉන්න තමයි මෙතන ඉන්න මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ඡන්දය දීලා තිබෙන්නේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් මද්දුමබණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් මද්දුමබණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශත පහක්",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "திருடர்களைப் பாதுகாக்க ஜனாதிபதி நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஆட்சியில் இருக்கும் திருடர்களை போராடி ஊர்வலம் நடத்தி வீட்டுக்கு அனுப்பவே நாட்டு மக்கள் முயன்றனர் என சமகி ஜன பலவேகயவின் செயலாளர் நாயகம் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சித் மத்துமபண்டார தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கொழும்பில் உள்ள எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் அலுவலகத்தில் நடைபெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் கலந்துகொண்டு கருத்து தெரிவிக்கும் போதே அவர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மேலும், நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் திரு.ரஞ்சித் மத்துமபண்டார கருத்துத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த நாட்டுக்கான புதிய ஜனாதிபதி நேற்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டார். முதலில் நான் அவருக்கு நல்வாழ்த்துக்கள். இந்த நாட்டை மீண்டும் கட்டியெழுப்ப அவர் பலம் பெற பிரார்த்திக்கிறேன். நாட்டின் பொது வாக்கெடுப்பு பாராளுமன்றத்திலும் நேற்று பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தப்பட்டது என்பதை நாம் கேட்க வேண்டும். 2020ஆம் ஆண்டு தேர்தலில் நிலவும் சூழலின் கீழ் அன்றைய மக்களின் கருத்துப்படி முன்வந்த எம்.பி.க்களே இன்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் உள்ள எம்.பி.க்கள். அந்தக் கருத்து இன்று மாறிவிட்டது. அப்போது நாட்டின் கருத்து இங்கு பிரதிபலிக்கவில்லை என்று கூறுகிறோம். நாட்டு மக்களின் கருத்துப்படி அப்போது நியமிக்கப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி இந்த நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறினார். இதில் பெரும்பாலானவை அந்த ஜனாதிபதியை நியமிக்க உழைத்தவர்களால் செய்யப்பட்டவை. ஜனாதிபதியுடன் நியமிக்கப்படும் பெரும்பாலான எம்.பி.க்கள் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் உள்ளனர்.",
        "எனவே திருடர்களை விரட்டியடிக்க இந்த நாட்டு மக்கள் போராடி, ஊர்வலம், போராட்டம் நடத்த வேண்டும் என்று கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறோம். இப்போது இன்று திருடர்கள் ஒன்று சேர்ந்து ஒருவரை நியமித்துள்ளனர். இந்த நாட்டு மக்கள் சுத்தமான அரசியலை எதிர்பார்த்தனர். அதனால்தான் இரு கைகளையும் சுத்தமாக வைத்திருக்கும் திரு.சஜித் பிரேமதாச அவர்களுடன், சுத்தமான கைகளையுடைய திரு.டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும அவர்களுடன் இணைந்து ஒரு பயணத்தை மேற்கொள்ளத் தயாரானோம். இதற்கு எங்கள் கட்சி ஐந்து காசு கூட செலவு செய்யவில்லை. மக்களின் கருத்துக்கு அமைய செயற்படும் ஜனாதிபதியே எமக்கு தேவை. இந்த நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் வாக்களிக்க காரணம் என்ன? வெள்ளத்தில் இருந்து நாட்டை மீட்பதா? அல்லது நாட்டில் ஜனநாயகத்தை நிலைநாட்டவா? நாங்கள் கேள்விப்பட்டபடி, அவர்கள் வீட்டில் தீயை சரிசெய்ய வேண்டும். நாங்கள் அதற்கு எதிரானவர்கள் அல்ல. தங்கள் பாதுகாப்பிற்காக. உங்கள் வாகன அனுமதியைப் பெறுங்கள். இங்குள்ள எம்.பி.க்கள் ஆட்சியை தக்கவைக்க வாக்களித்துள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சித் மத்துமபண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சித் மத்துமபண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து சென்ட்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}