{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83681/diesel-shipment-reaches-colombo-another-expected-later-today",
  "time_ut": 1657945080,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Diesel shipment reaches Colombo, another expected later today",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Diesel shipment reaches Colombo, another expected later today",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A shipment of diesel arrived in Colombo this morning (July 16) and sample checking is currently underway, Minister of Power and Energy Kanchana Wijesekara said in a tweet.",
        "Another vessel carrying a diesel consignment is expected to reach Colombo later today.",
        "Meanwhile, Sri Lanka is also expecting a petrol shipment either on the 18th or 19th of July.",
        "According to Minister Wijesekara, the payments for all three fuel shipments have already been settled."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Colombo",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "later today",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 18th or 19th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඩීසල් නැව්ගත කිරීම අදින් පසුව බලාපොරොත්තු වන තවත් එකක් කොළඹට ළඟා වේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අද (ජූලි 16) උදෑසන ඩීසල් තොගයක් කොළඹට පැමිණි අතර සාම්පල පරීක්ෂා කිරීම මේ වන විට සිදුවෙමින් පවතින බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "ඩීසල් තොගයක් රැගත් තවත් යාත්‍රාවක් අද පස්වරුවේ කොළඹට ළඟා වීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "මේ අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ද ජූලි 18 හෝ 19 යන දෙදින තුළ පෙට්‍රල් නැව්ගත කිරීමක් අපේක්ෂා කරයි.",
        "විජේසේකර ඇමතිවරයාට අනුව ඉන්ධන තොග තුනේම ගෙවීම් දැනටමත් පියවා අවසන්ය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කොළඹ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද පසුව",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 18 හෝ 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டீசல் ஏற்றுமதி கொழும்பை வந்தடைகிறது, மற்றொன்று இன்று பிற்பகுதியில் எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இன்று (ஜூலை 16) காலை கொழும்பிற்கு டீசல் ஏற்றுமதி வந்துள்ளது, தற்போது மாதிரி சோதனை நடைபெற்று வருவதாக மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர டுவிட்டரில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "டீசல் சரக்குகளை ஏற்றிச் செல்லும் மற்றுமொரு கப்பல் இன்று பிற்பகல் கொழும்பு வந்தடையும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், ஜூலை 18 அல்லது 19 ஆம் தேதிகளில் பெட்ரோல் ஏற்றுமதியை இலங்கை எதிர்பார்க்கிறது.",
        "அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகரவின் கூற்றுப்படி, மூன்று எரிபொருள் ஏற்றுமதிக்கான கொடுப்பனவுகள் ஏற்கனவே தீர்க்கப்பட்டுள்ளன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கொழும்பு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பின்னர் இன்று",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 18 அல்லது 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}