{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Sri-Lanka-add-Theekshana-Wellalage-and-Manasinghe-to-Test-squad/342-240362",
  "time_ut": 1656992060,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka add Theekshana, Wellalage and Manasinghe to Test squad",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka add Theekshana, Wellalage and Manasinghe to Test squad",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka have bolstered their spin bowling options ahead of the second Test against Australia in Galle on Friday, calling up uncapped spinners Maheesh Theekshana, Dunith Wellalage and Lakshitha Manasinghe.",
        "The additions come after left arm spinner Praveen Jayawickrama tested positve for Covid-19 last morning, with a Rapid Antigen Test administered after the player reported that he was feeling unwell.",
        "Further tests on the rest of the squad and support staff members returned no other Covid-19 positive cases.",
        "Theekshana and Wellalage were part of Sri Lanka's ODI squad that beat Australia thrice in the five match series, while Manasinghe was the leading wicket-taker in Sri Lanka A's two unofficial Tests against Australia A last month.",
        "Of the three, right-arm off-spinner Manasinghe has the more polished First Class record, with 73 wickets in 17 matches at an average of 26.38, most recently turning out for the Sinhalese Sports Club.",
        "In constrast, Theekshana has played just three First Class matches, though that is largely due to his continuous involvement with Sri Lanka's limited over teams.",
        "Wellalage, who now plays for Colts CC, has featured in 11 First Class matches, though his contributions with the Under 19 and Sri Lanka ODI teams this year have been particularly noteworthy."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Theekshana, Wellalage and",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Manasinghe",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Theekshana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakshitha Manasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Praveen Jayawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "73",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "26.38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sinhalese Sports Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Theekshana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colts CC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ටෙස්ට් සංචිතයට තීක්ෂණ, වෙල්ලාලගේ සහ මනසිංහ එක් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාවට එරෙහිව සිකුරාදා ගාල්ලේදී පැවැත්වෙන දෙවැනි ටෙස්ට් තරගයට පෙර ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඔවුන්ගේ දඟ පන්දු යැවීමේ විකල්පය ශක්තිමත් කර ඇති අතර, මහේෂ් තීක්ෂණ, දුනිත් වෙල්ලාලගේ සහ ලක්ෂිත මානසිංහ යන දඟ පන්දු යවන්නන් කැඳවා ඇත.",
        "වම් අත දඟ පන්දු යවන ක්‍රීඩක ප්‍රවීන් ජයවික්‍රම කොවිඩ්-19 සඳහා ධනාත්මක බව පරීක්‍ෂා කිරීමෙන් පසුව මෙම එකතු කිරීම් සිදු කර ඇති අතර, ක්‍රීඩකයා ඔහුට අසනීප වූ බව වාර්තා කිරීමෙන් පසු වේගවත් ප්‍රතිදේහජනක පරීක්ෂණයක් සිදු කරන ලදී.",
        "සෙසු සංචිතයේ සහ සහායක කාර්ය මණ්ඩල සාමාජිකයින්ගේ වැඩිදුර පරීක්ෂණ මගින් වෙනත් කොවිඩ් -19 ධනාත්මක රෝගීන් කිසිවක් වාර්තා නොවීය.",
        "තීක්ෂණ සහ වෙල්ලාලගේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා එක්දින සංචිතයේ කොටසක් වූ අතර තරග පහකින් සමන්විත තරගාවලියේදී ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාව තෙවරක් පරාජය කළ අතර, පසුගිය මාසයේ ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු A කණ්ඩායමට එරෙහිව ශ්‍රී ලංකා A පිලේ නිල නොවන ටෙස්ට් තරග දෙකේදී මනසිංහ ප්‍රමුඛතම කඩුලු ලාභියා විය.",
        "මේ තිදෙනාගෙන්, දකුණත් පිට දඟ පන්දු යවන මනසිංහ වඩාත් ඔප දැමූ පළමු පෙළ වාර්තාවට හිමිකම් කියන අතර, තරග 17කදී කඩුලු 73ක් දවා ගැනීමේ සාමාන්‍ය 26.38ක් වන අතර, ඉතා මෑතක දී සිංහල ක්‍රීඩා සමාජය වෙත හැරී ගියේය.",
        "ඊට වෙනස්ව, තීක්ෂණ ක්‍රීඩා කර ඇත්තේ පළමු පෙළ තරග තුනකට පමණි, නමුත් එයට බොහෝ දුරට හේතු වී ඇත්තේ ඔහු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සීමිත ඕවර කණ්ඩායම් සමඟ අඛණ්ඩව සම්බන්ධ වීමයි.",
        "මේ වන විට කෝල්ට්ස් සීසී පිලට ක්‍රීඩා කරන වෙල්ලාලගේ මේ වසරේ අවුරුදු 19න් පහළ සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා එක්දින කණ්ඩායම් සමඟින් ඔහුගේ දායකත්වය විශේෂයෙන් කැපී පෙනුනද පළමු පෙළ තරග 11කට ක්‍රීඩා කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "තීක්ෂණ, වෙල්ලාලගේ සහ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "මානසිංහ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තීක්ෂණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂිත මානසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රවීන් ජයවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මානසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මානසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "73",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "26.38 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල ක්‍රීඩා සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තීක්ෂණ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෝල්ට්ස් සීසී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை டெஸ்ட் அணியில் தீக்ஷனா, வெல்லலகே மற்றும் மானசிங்க ஆகியோர் சேர்க்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வெள்ளியன்று காலியில் ஆஸ்திரேலியாவுக்கு எதிரான இரண்டாவது டெஸ்ட் போட்டிக்கு முன்னதாக, இலங்கை அணி சுழற்பந்து வீச்சு விருப்பங்களை வலுப்படுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "இடது கை சுழற்பந்து வீச்சாளர் பிரவீன் ஜெயவிக்ரம நேற்று காலை கோவிட் -19 க்கு நேர்மறை சோதனை செய்ததை அடுத்து, அவர் உடல்நிலை சரியில்லாமல் இருப்பதாக வீரர் தெரிவித்ததை அடுத்து, ரேபிட் ஆன்டிஜென் சோதனை நடத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "மற்ற குழு மற்றும் துணைப் பணியாளர்கள் மீதான கூடுதல் சோதனைகள் வேறு எந்த கோவிட்-19 நேர்மறை வழக்குகளும் இல்லை.",
        "ஐந்து போட்டிகள் கொண்ட தொடரில் ஆஸ்திரேலியாவை மூன்று முறை தோற்கடித்த இலங்கையின் ODI அணியில் தீக்ஷனா மற்றும் வெல்லலகே ஆகியோர் அங்கம் வகித்தனர், அதே நேரத்தில் கடந்த மாதம் ஆஸ்திரேலியா A க்கு எதிரான இலங்கை A இன் இரண்டு அதிகாரப்பூர்வமற்ற டெஸ்ட் போட்டிகளில் மானசிங்க முன்னணி விக்கெட்டுகளை வீழ்த்தினார்.",
        "மூவரில், வலது கை சுழற்பந்து வீச்சாளர் மனசிங்க, 17 போட்டிகளில் 26.38 சராசரியில் 73 விக்கெட்டுகளுடன், மிகவும் மெருகூட்டப்பட்ட முதல் தர சாதனையைப் பெற்றுள்ளார்.",
        "இதற்கு நேர்மாறாக, தீக்ஷனா மூன்று முதல் தர போட்டிகளில் மட்டுமே விளையாடியுள்ளார்.",
        "தற்போது கோல்ட்ஸ் CCக்காக விளையாடும் வெல்லலகே, 11 முதல் தர போட்டிகளில் பங்கேற்றுள்ளார், இருப்பினும் இந்த ஆண்டு 19 வயதுக்குட்பட்ட மற்றும் இலங்கை ODI அணிகளில் அவரது பங்களிப்புகள் குறிப்பாக குறிப்பிடத்தக்கவை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "தீக்ஷன, வெல்லலகே மற்றும்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "மானசிங்க",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தீக்ஷனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்சித மனசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரவீன் ஜெயவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடைசி காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மானசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மானசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "73",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "26.38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கள விளையாட்டுக் கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தீக்ஷனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோல்ட்ஸ் சிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}