{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Man-transporting-over-5-tonnes-of-stale-fish-in-lorry-arrested-in-Negombo/342-244102",
  "time_ut": 1662001789,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Man transporting over 5 tonnes of stale fish in lorry arrested in Negombo",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Man transporting over 5 tonnes of stale fish in lorry arrested in Negombo",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "One person was taken into the custody with a lorry while transporting 5,670 kg of stale fish which are unfit for human consumption in Kochchikade, Negombo yesterday.",
        "The police when checked the lorry found the lorry was transporting malodorous fish from Chilaw towards Negombo at Toppuwa Bridge.",
        "They found the fish worth over Rs.3.4 million which is unfit for human consumption. The police arrested the driver of the lorry, a 53-year-old resident of Pitipana, Negombo, would be produced in Negombo Magistrate's Court. (Darshana Sanjeewa Balasuriya)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Negombo",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,670 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kochchikade",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Negombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chilaw",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Toppuwa Bridge",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "lorry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "53-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pitipana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Negombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Negombo Magistrate's Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Darshana Sanjeewa Balasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ටොන් 5කට අධික පරණ මාළු තොගයක් ලොරි රථයකින් ප්‍රවාහනය කළ පුද්ගලයෙකු මීගමුවේදී අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මීගමුව - කොච්චිකඩේ ප්‍රදේශයේදී මිනිස් පරිභෝජනයට නුසුදුසු මාළු කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 5670ක් ප්‍රවාහනය කරමින් සිටි පුද්ගලයෙකු ලොරි රථයක් සමඟ ඊයේ අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "ලොරි රථය පරීක්ෂා කිරීමේදී හලාවත සිට මීගමුව දෙසට තොප්පුව පාලම අසලදී දුගඳ හමන මාළු ප්‍රවාහනය කරමින් තිබූ ලොරි රථය පොලිසිය විසින් සොයා ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "රුපියල් ලක්ෂ 34කට අධික වටිනාකමකින් යුත් මිනිස් පරිභෝජනයට නුසුදුසු මෙම මත්ස්‍ය තොගය ඔවුන් සොයා ගෙන තිබෙනවා. ලොරි රථයේ රියදුරු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති අතර ඔහු මීගමුව පිටිපන ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 53 හැවිරිදි අයෙකු වන අතර ඔහු මීගමුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිතයි. (දර්ශන සංජීව බාලසූරිය)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මීගමුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 5,670 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොච්චිකඩේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "භලාවත",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "තොප්පුව පාලම",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලොරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "53 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිටිපන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීගමුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දර්ශන සංජීව බාලසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நீர்கொழும்பில் 5 தொன் பழமையான மீன்களை லொறியில் ஏற்றிச் சென்ற நபர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நீர்கொழும்பு கொச்சிக்கடையில் மனித பாவனைக்கு தகுதியற்ற 5,670 கிலோ பழமையான மீன்களை ஏற்றிச் சென்ற போது லொறியுடன் ஒருவர் நேற்று கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "லொறியை பொலிஸார் சோதனையிட்ட போது, ​​சிலாபத்தில் இருந்து நீர்கொழும்பு நோக்கி துர்நாற்றம் கொண்ட மீன்களை ஏற்றிச் சென்ற லொறி தோப்புவ பாலத்தில் வைத்து கண்டெடுக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "3.4 மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான பெறுமதியான மீன்கள் மனித பாவனைக்கு தகுதியற்றதாக காணப்பட்டது. லொறியின் சாரதி நீர்கொழும்பு, பிடிபனை பிரதேசத்தை சேர்ந்த 53 வயதுடைய நபரை கைது செய்த பொலிஸார், நீர்கொழும்பு நீதவான் நீதிமன்றில் ஆஜர்படுத்தப்படவுள்ளனர். (தர்ஷன சஞ்சீவ பாலசூரிய)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நீர்கொழும்பு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,670 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொச்சிக்கடை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீர்கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிலாபம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தோப்புவா பாலம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சரக்குந்து",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "53 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிடிபனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீர்கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீர்கொழும்பு நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தர்ஷன சஞ்சீவ பாலசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}