{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84525/private-bus-owners-lodge-complaint-with-intl-organizations",
  "time_ut": 1661401740,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Private bus owners lodge complaint with int’l organizations",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Private bus owners lodge complaint with int’l organizations",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Private Bus Owners’ Association has filed a complaint with the European Union’s office and the OHCHR’s office in Colombo, with regard to the buses torched on the 09th of May amidst nationwide unrest that broke out following the attacks on anti-government protest sites in Colombo.",
        "The president of the association, Gemunu Wijeratne said the owners of these buses are facing severe financial difficulties after their vehicles were set on fire.",
        "The association has appealed to the international organizations to conduct an impartial investigation into the matter and to do them justice.",
        "According to Wijeratne, at least 50 buses were torched and destroyed that day."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the European Union’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "OHCHR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "09th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gemunu Wijeratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijeratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "at least 50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "that day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන් ජාත්‍යන්තර සංවිධානවලට පැමිණිලි කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොළඹ රාජ්‍ය විරෝධී උද්ඝෝෂණ ස්ථානවලට ප්‍රහාර එල්ල කිරීමත් සමඟ රටපුරා ඇති වූ නොසන්සුන්තා මධ්‍යයේ මැයි 09 වනදා බස් රථ ගිනි තැබීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය කොළඹ යුරෝපා සංගමයේ කාර්යාලයට සහ OHCHR කාර්යාලයට පැමිණිල්ලක් ගොනු කර තිබේ.",
        "එම සංගමයේ සභාපති ගැමුණු විජේරත්න කියා සිටියේ මෙම බස් රථවලට ගිනි තැබීමෙන් පසු එම බස් රථ හිමියන් දැඩි මූල්‍ය දුෂ්කරතාවලට මුහුණ පා සිටින බවයි.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් අපක්ෂපාතී පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වා තමන්ට සාධාරණයක් ඉටු කරන ලෙස එම සංගමය ජාත්‍යන්තර සංවිධානවලින් ඉල්ලා සිටියි.",
        "විජේරත්නට අනුව එදින බස් රථ 50ක් ගිනි තබා විනාශ කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපීය සංගමයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "OHCHR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "09 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගැමුණු විජේරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේරත්න ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් 50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சர்வதேச அமைப்புகளிடம் புகார் அளித்தனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பில் அரசாங்க எதிர்ப்புப் போராட்டத் தளங்கள் மீதான தாக்குதலைத் தொடர்ந்து நாடு தழுவிய அமைதியின்மைக்கு மத்தியில் மே மாதம் 09 ஆம் திகதி பஸ்கள் எரிக்கப்பட்டமை தொடர்பில் தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம் கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றிய அலுவலகம் மற்றும் OHCHR அலுவலகத்தில் முறைப்பாடு செய்துள்ளது.",
        "வாகனங்கள் தீக்கிரையாக்கப்பட்டதையடுத்து இந்த பஸ்களின் உரிமையாளர்கள் கடும் நிதி நெருக்கடிகளை எதிர்நோக்கி வருவதாக சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் கெமுனு விஜேரத்ன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இவ்விவகாரம் குறித்து பாரபட்சமற்ற விசாரணை நடத்தி தமக்கு நீதி வழங்குமாறு சர்வதேச அமைப்புகளிடம் சங்கம் வேண்டுகோள் விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "விஜேரத்னவின் கூற்றுப்படி, அன்றைய தினம் குறைந்தது 50 பேருந்துகள் தீவைத்து அழிக்கப்பட்டன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியத்தின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "OHCHR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "09 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கெமுனு விஜேரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}