{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/un-to-host-over-190-world-leaders-and-delegates-despite-threats-from-deadly-new-covid-19-variant/",
  "time_ut": 1658574540,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "UN to host over 190 world leaders and delegates — Despite threats from deadly new Covid-19 variant",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "UN to host over 190 world leaders and delegates — Despite threats from deadly new Covid-19 variant",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "UNITED NATIONS, Jul 22 2022 (IPS) – The United Nations is planning to host a high-level “in-person” General Assembly session, September 20-26, with over 190 world leaders and delegates listed to speak, including heads of state, heads of government, high-ranking ministers and senior officials.The world body is apparently on a risky path, with hundreds of delegates due in New York for the opening of the 77th session—and, most worryingly, at a time when a new Covid-19 variant BA.5 is sweeping across the United States, including New York.",
        "In a letter addressed to the President of the General Assembly, E. Courtenay Rattray Chef de Cabinet, says “while there is strong support for the return to a pre-pandemic General Debate, as reflected by the level of inscriptions by Member States in the provisional list of speakers– and an improvement in the environment as compared to the last two years– we also recognize that we are not free from the Coronavirus and its impact.”",
        "“As such, there is a need to be prudent in our facilitation of the General Debate and High-level Week.”",
        "Under a business-as-usual scenario, occupancy at UN Headquarters will increase significantly this September, particularly in meeting rooms and in the General Assembly and Conference buildings.",
        "“With a view to mitigating this impact, our planning assumptions reflect an emphasis on basic protective measures and a decrease in the number of attendees, as much as reasonably possible”, the letter said. On July 21, White House Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre formally announced that US President Joe Biden, who is scheduled to address the General Assembly on September 20, tested positive for COVID-19. “He is fully vaccinated and twice boosted and experiencing very mild symptoms. He has begun taking Paxlovid. Consistent with CDC guidelines, he will isolate at the White House and will continue to carry out all of his duties fully during that time,” she added.",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "UN",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "190",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "UNITED NATIONS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jul",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IPS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "The United Nations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "General Assembly",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "September",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "190",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "hundreds",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "New York",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "77th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "New York",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the General Assembly",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "E. Courtenay Rattray Chef de Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Debate",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last two years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Coronavirus",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this September",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the General Assembly",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "White House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karine Jean-Pierre",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the General Assembly",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CDC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the White House",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලෝක නායකයින් සහ නියෝජිතයින් 190 කට වැඩි පිරිසකට සත්කාරකත්වය සැපයීමට එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවිධානය - මාරාන්තික නව Covid-19 ප්‍රභේදයෙන් තර්ජන තිබියදීත්",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "එක්සත් ජාතීන්, ජූලි 22 2022 (IPS) - එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවිධානය විසින් සැප්තැම්බර් 20-26 දක්වා ඉහළ මට්ටමේ \"පුද්ගලික\" මහා සභා සැසියක් පැවැත්වීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති අතර, රාජ්‍ය නායකයින් ඇතුළුව ලෝක නායකයින් සහ නියෝජිතයින් 190 කට අධික සංඛ්‍යාවක් කථා කිරීමට ලැයිස්තුගත කර ඇත. , රජයේ ප්‍රධානීන්, ඉහළ පෙළේ අමාත්‍යවරුන් සහ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරීන්. ලෝක ආයතනය පෙනෙන පරිදි අවදානම් මාවතක ගමන් කරමින් සිටින අතර, 77 වැනි සැසිවාරය විවෘත කිරීම සඳහා නියෝජිතයන් සිය ගණනක් නිව්යෝර්ක් නුවරට පැමිණීමට නියමිතව ඇත-සහ, වඩාත්ම කනස්සල්ලට කරුණ නම්, නව Covid-19 ප්‍රභේදය BA.5 නිව් යෝර්ක් ඇතුළු එක්සත් ජනපදය පුරා පැතිරෙමින් පවතී.",
        "මහා මණ්ඩලයේ සභාපති E. Courtenay Rattray Chef de Cabinet වෙත ලිපියක් යවමින් පවසන්නේ, “පූර්ව වසංගත පොදු විවාදයකට නැවත පැමිණීම සඳහා දැඩි සහයෝගයක් පවතින අතර, සාමාජික රටවල ශිලාලේඛන මට්ටමෙන් පිළිබිඹු වේ. කථිකයන්ගේ තාවකාලික ලැයිස්තුව - සහ පසුගිය වසර දෙකට සාපේක්ෂව පරිසරයේ දියුණුවක් - අපි කොරෝනා වයිරසයෙන් සහ එහි බලපෑමෙන් නිදහස් නොවන බව ද හඳුනා ගනිමු.",
        "\"එබැවින්, පොදු විවාදය සහ ඉහළ මට්ටමේ සතිය සඳහා අපගේ පහසුකම් සැලසීමේදී විචක්ෂණශීලී විය යුතුය.\"",
        "ව්‍යාපාරික-සාමාන්‍ය තත්වයක් යටතේ, මෙම සැප්තැම්බර් මාසයේදී එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මූලස්ථානයේ පදිංචිය සැලකිය යුතු ලෙස වැඩි වනු ඇත, විශේෂයෙන් රැස්වීම් කාමරවල සහ මහා සභා රැස්වීම් සහ සම්මන්ත්‍රණ ගොඩනැගිලිවල.",
        "\"මෙම බලපෑම අවම කිරීමේ අරමුණින්, අපගේ සැලසුම් උපකල්පන මගින් මූලික ආරක්ෂක පියවරයන් කෙරෙහි අවධාරණයක් සහ සාධාරණ ලෙස හැකිතාක් සහභාගිවන්නන්ගේ සංඛ්‍යාව අඩුවීමක් පිළිබිඹු කරයි\", ලිපියේ සඳහන් වේ. සැප්තැම්බර් 20 වැනි දින මහා සභාව ඇමතීමට නියමිත එක්සත් ජනපද ජනාධිපති ජෝ බයිඩෙන් COVID-19 සඳහා ධනාත්මක බව පරීක්‍ෂා කළ බව ජූලි 21 වන දින ධවල මන්දිර මාධ්‍ය ලේකම් Karine Jean-Pierre නිල වශයෙන් නිවේදනය කළේය. “ඔහු සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම එන්නත් කර ඇති අතර දෙවරක් වැඩි දියුණු කර ඇති අතර ඉතා මෘදු රෝග ලක්ෂණ අත්විඳියි. ඔහු Paxlovid ගැනීම ආරම්භ කර ඇත. සීඩීසී මාර්ගෝපදේශයන්ට අනුකූලව, ඔහු ධවල මන්දිරයේ හුදෙකලා වන අතර එම කාලය තුළ ඔහුගේ සියලු රාජකාරි සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම ඉටු කරනු ඇත, ”ඇය වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එ.ජා",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "190",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IPS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු රැස්වීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "190",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිය ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිව්යෝක්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "77 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිව්යෝක්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහා සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "E. Courtenay Rattray Chef de කැබිනට්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විවාදය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසර දෙක",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරෝනාවයිරසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එ.ජා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහා සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධවල මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karine Jean-Pierre",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහා සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CDC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධවල මන්දිරය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "190 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட உலகத் தலைவர்கள் மற்றும் பிரதிநிதிகளுக்கு ஐ.நா.",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "யுனைடெட் நேஷன்ஸ், ஜூலை 22 2022 (IPS) - 190 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட உலகத் தலைவர்கள் மற்றும் பிரதிநிதிகள் பேசுவதற்கு பட்டியலிடப்பட்டுள்ள நாடுகளின் தலைவர்கள் உட்பட, செப்டம்பர் 20-26 ஆம் தேதிகளில் ஒரு உயர்மட்ட \"நேரில்\" பொதுச் சபை அமர்வை நடத்த ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் திட்டமிட்டுள்ளது. , அரசாங்கத் தலைவர்கள், உயர் அமைச்சர்கள் மற்றும் மூத்த அதிகாரிகள் கோவிட்-19 மாறுபாடு BA.5 நியூயார்க் உட்பட அமெரிக்கா முழுவதும் பரவி வருகிறது.",
        "பொதுச் சபையின் தலைவரான ஈ. கோர்டனே ராட்ரே செஃப் டி கேபினட்க்கு எழுதிய கடிதத்தில், \"தொற்றுநோய்க்கு முந்தைய பொது விவாதத்திற்கு திரும்புவதற்கு வலுவான ஆதரவு உள்ளது, இது உறுப்பு நாடுகளின் கல்வெட்டுகளின் அளவைப் பிரதிபலிக்கிறது. பேச்சாளர்களின் தற்காலிக பட்டியல் - மற்றும் கடந்த இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளுடன் ஒப்பிடுகையில் சுற்றுச்சூழலில் ஏற்பட்ட முன்னேற்றம் - கொரோனா வைரஸ் மற்றும் அதன் தாக்கத்திலிருந்து நாம் விடுபடவில்லை என்பதையும் நாங்கள் அங்கீகரிக்கிறோம்.",
        "\"எனவே, பொது விவாதம் மற்றும் உயர்மட்ட வாரத்தை எளிதாக்குவதில் கவனமாக இருக்க வேண்டிய அவசியம் உள்ளது.\"",
        "வணிக-வழக்கமான சூழ்நிலையில், இந்த செப்டம்பரில் ஐ.நா தலைமையகத்தில், குறிப்பாக சந்திப்பு அறைகள் மற்றும் பொதுச் சபை மற்றும் மாநாட்டு கட்டிடங்களில் ஆக்கிரமிப்பு கணிசமாக அதிகரிக்கும்.",
        "\"இந்த பாதிப்பைக் குறைக்கும் நோக்கில், எங்கள் திட்டமிடல் அனுமானங்கள் அடிப்படை பாதுகாப்பு நடவடிக்கைகளுக்கு முக்கியத்துவம் கொடுக்கின்றன மற்றும் பங்கேற்பாளர்களின் எண்ணிக்கையில் குறைவு, நியாயமான முறையில் முடிந்தவரை\", கடிதம் கூறியது. ஜூலை 21 அன்று, வெள்ளை மாளிகையின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் கரீன் ஜீன்-பியர், செப்டம்பர் 20 அன்று பொதுச் சபையில் உரையாற்றத் திட்டமிடப்பட்ட அமெரிக்க ஜனாதிபதி ஜோ பிடனுக்கு COVID-19 க்கு நேர்மறை சோதனை செய்ததாக அதிகாரப்பூர்வமாக அறிவித்தார். \"அவர் முழுமையாக தடுப்பூசி போடப்பட்டு இரண்டு முறை ஊக்கம் பெற்றவர் மற்றும் மிக லேசான அறிகுறிகளை அனுபவித்து வருகிறார். அவர் பாக்ஸ்லோவிட் எடுக்கத் தொடங்கினார். CDC வழிகாட்டுதல்களுக்கு இணங்க, அவர் வெள்ளை மாளிகையில் தனிமைப்படுத்தப்படுவார், மேலும் அந்த நேரத்தில் தனது அனைத்து கடமைகளையும் முழுமையாக நிறைவேற்றுவார், ”என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஐ.நா",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "190",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.பி.எஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "190",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நூற்றுக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நியூயார்க்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "77வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நியூயார்க்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொதுச் சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈ. கோர்ட்டனே ராட்ரே செஃப் டி கேபினட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விவாதம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த இரண்டு வருடங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரோனா வைரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுச் சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளை மாளிகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கரீன் ஜீன்-பியர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுச் சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CDC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளை மாளிகை",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}