{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ජනපති-රටින්-යයි/1-616321",
  "time_ut": 1657677388,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ජනපති රටින් යයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The President leaves the country",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Katunayake airport sources said that President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa has left for Maldives this morning.",
        "The President, his wife and one of their security officers have left.",
        "It is reported that a group of Sri Lankan Air Force officers took and approved the passports and other essential documents of the four persons to the immigration department officials at the Katunayake airport departure terminal.",
        "They left the Katunayake Air Force Base at around 01.45 this morning in a Antonov-32 (AN-32) type aircraft belonging to the Sri Lanka Air Force.",
        "The BBC reported that Sri Lankan President Gotabaya Rajapaksa left the country in a military jet.",
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa arrived in Malé, the capital of the Maldives, at around 3 am today, BBC News reported."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Katunayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the immigration department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Katunayake Air Force Base",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BBC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malé",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "BBC News",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපති රටින් යයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා අද අලුයම මාලදිවයින බලා නික්ම ගොස් ඇති බව කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ ආරංචි මාර්ග සදහන් කළේය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා,ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ සහ ඔවුන්ගේ ආරක්ෂක නිලධාරීවරයකු මෙසේ පිටත්ව ගොස් තිබේ.",
        "මොවුන් සිව් දෙනාගේ ගුවන් ගමන් බලපත්‍ර ඇතුළු අනෙකුත් අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ලියකියවිලි , කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ පිටත්වීමේ පර්යන්තයේ ආගමන විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තු නිලධාරීන් වෙත , ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදා නිලධාරීන් පිරිසක් විසින් රැගෙන විත් අනුමත කර ගෙන ගොස් ඇතැයි වාර්තා වෙයි.",
        "ඔවුන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාවට අයත් ඇන්ටොනෝව් - 32 ( ඒ.එන්.- 32 ) වර්ගයේ විශේෂ ගුවන් යානයකින් අද අලුයම 01.45 ට පමණ බලා කටුනායක ගුවන් හමුදා කදවුරෙන් පිටත්ව ගොස් තිබේ .",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා හමුදා ජෙට් යානයකින් රටින් පිටව ගිය බව බී.බී.සී පුවත් සේවය වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා අද අලුයම 3 ට පමණ මාලදිවයිනේ මලේ අගනුවරට පැමිණි බව බී.බී.සී පුවත් සේවය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක ගුවන් හමුදා කඳවුර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බීබීසී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාන්දර 3",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීබීසී පුවත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறுகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ இன்று காலை மாலைதீவுக்கு சென்றுள்ளதாக கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலைய தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி, அவரது மனைவி மற்றும் அவர்களது பாதுகாப்பு அதிகாரி ஒருவர் வெளியேறியுள்ளனர்.",
        "இலங்கை விமானப்படை அதிகாரிகள் குழுவொன்று கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலைய புறப்படும் முனையத்தில் குடிவரவு திணைக்கள அதிகாரிகளிடம் நான்கு பேரின் கடவுச்சீட்டு மற்றும் ஏனைய அத்தியாவசிய ஆவணங்களை எடுத்துச் சென்று அங்கீகரித்ததாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இலங்கை விமானப்படைக்கு சொந்தமான Antonov-32 (AN-32) ரக விமானத்தில் அவர்கள் இன்று அதிகாலை 01.45 மணியளவில் கட்டுநாயக்க விமானப்படை தளத்தில் இருந்து புறப்பட்டனர்.",
        "இலங்கை அதிபர் கோத்தபய ராஜபக்ச ராணுவ ஜெட் விமானத்தில் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறியதாக பிபிசி செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ இன்று அதிகாலை 3 மணியளவில் மாலைதீவின் தலைநகரான மாலேயை சென்றடைந்ததாக பிபிசி செய்திகள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க விமானப்படை தளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிபிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 3 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிபிசி செய்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}