{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84508/ven-balangoda-kashyapa-thero-under-arrest",
  "time_ut": 1661333220,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ven. Balangoda Kashyapa Thero under arrest",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ven. Balangoda Kashyapa Thero under arrest",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Criminal Investigation Department (CID) arrested Venerable Balangoda Kashyapa Thero today (August 24).",
        "Kashyapa Thero was placed under arrest when he arrived at the CID premises this morning to provide a statement with regard to his alleged forcible entry to the Temple Trees.",
        "In the meantime, Sri Lanka Police said it is seeking the assistance of the general public to identify 24 people who forcibly entered the Temple Trees and damaged its properties on July 09.",
        "Information on these individuals can be submitted to the following contact numbers:"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Balangoda Kashyapa Thero",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kashyapa Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kashyapa Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Temple Trees",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හාමුදුරුවෝ. බලංගොඩ කාශ්‍යප හිමි අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව (CID) විසින් අද (අගෝස්තු 24) පූජ්‍ය බලංගොඩ කාශ්‍යප හිමියන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "අරලියගහ මන්දිරයට බලහත්කාරයෙන් ඇතුළු වූ බව කියන සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ප්‍රකාශයක් ලබාදීම සඳහා අද පෙරවරුවේ අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තු පරිශ්‍රයට පැමිණි අවස්ථාවේදී කාශ්‍යප හිමියන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "මේ අතර, ජූලි 09 වැනිදා අරලියගහ මන්දිරයට බලහත්කාරයෙන් ඇතුළු වී එහි දේපළවලට හානි කළ පුද්ගලයන් 24 දෙනෙකු හඳුනා ගැනීමට සාමාන්‍ය ජනතාවගේ සහය අපේක්ෂා කරන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "මෙම පුද්ගලයින් පිළිබඳ තොරතුරු පහත සම්බන්ධතා අංක වෙත ඉදිරිපත් කළ හැක."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බලංගොඩ කාශ්‍යප හිමි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාශ්‍යප හාමුදුරුවෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාශ්‍යප හාමුදුරුවෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරලියගහ මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வண. பலாங்கொட காஷ்யப தேரர் கைது!",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வணக்கத்திற்குரிய பலாங்கொட காஷ்யப தேரரை குற்றப் புலனாய்வு திணைக்களம் (CID) இன்று (ஆகஸ்ட் 24) கைது செய்துள்ளது.",
        "அலரிமாளிகைக்குள் பலவந்தமாக பிரவேசித்ததாக கூறப்படும் குற்றச்சாட்டு தொடர்பில் வாக்குமூலம் வழங்குவதற்காக இன்று காலை சிஐடி வளாகத்திற்கு வந்த போதே காஷ்யப தேரர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், ஜூலை 09 அன்று அலரிமாளிகைக்குள் பலவந்தமாக நுழைந்து அதன் சொத்துக்களை சேதப்படுத்திய 24 பேரை அடையாளம் காண பொது மக்களின் உதவியை நாடவுள்ளதாக இலங்கை பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இந்த நபர்கள் பற்றிய தகவல்களை பின்வரும் தொடர்பு எண்களுக்கு சமர்ப்பிக்கலாம்:"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பலாங்கொட காஷ்யப தேரர்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஷ்யப தேரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காஷ்யப தேரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவில் மரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}