{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132173",
  "time_ut": 1658675114,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "மைத்திரியின் வீடு ரணிலுக்கு !",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Maithri's house for Ranil!",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "It has been decided to give the current President Ranil Wickremesinghe a house located in Paget Road, Colombo, which was used as his official residence by the former President and Member of Parliament Maithripala Sirisena during his presidency.",
        "It is said that the Presidential Palace and Alari Palace have been damaged in the background where lakhs of people visited after they were captured by the protesters.",
        "In this situation, while legal actions and rectification work are being carried out in relation to these houses, it has become impossible for the President or the Prime Minister to visit them.",
        "In this situation, President Ranil Wickremesinghe's personal residence has also been damaged by fire, and he is currently being kept in a safe place under the full protection of the security forces.",
        "In this situation, temporarily, the government has decided to give the Beget Street house to President Ranil.",
        "On March 29th, the High Court issued an interim injunction against the decision taken by the cabinet to allow Maithripala Sirisena to own the house located on Paget Road, Colombo, which was used as his official residence during the presidency of Maithripala Sirisena, after his retirement from office and continuing.",
        "Following this, former President Maithripala Sirisena came out of his house located on Paget Road, Colombo.",
        "The interim injunction was issued by a bench of judges headed by Justice Preethi Padman Surasena and comprising Justices Yasanda Gotakoda and Mahinda Samayawardana.",
        "This interim injunction was issued with effect from four weeks from the date of issue, March 29.",
        "As the former president was unable to continue staying at the Paget Road house, he has announced that he will leave the house after the New Year.",
        "Former President Maithripala Sirisena has moved out of his Paget Street house and is staying in a new house even as the government has given him another house in Colombo.",
        "This fundamental rights violation petition has been filed by the Center for Alternative Policies and its Executive Director Pakhyasothi Saravanamuthu, demanding that the decision taken by the Cabinet to make the house located on Paget Road, the property of the former President Maithripala Sirisena, after his retirement from the presidency, is a violation of basic human rights.",
        "Former President Maithripala Sirisena and current cabinet members have been named as respondents to the petition.",
        "It is noteworthy that the Presidents' Rights Act No. 4 of 1986 provides housing for retiring presidents."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Maithri",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paget Road, Colombo",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Palace",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Beget Street",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "March 29th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paget Road, Colombo",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paget Road, Colombo",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Preethi Padman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yasanda Gotakoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Samayawardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "March 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the New Year",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paget Street",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Center for Alternative Policies",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Executive",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakhyasothi Saravanamuthu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paget Road",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රනිල්ට මෛත්‍රීගේ ගෙදර!",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා ජනාධිපතිව සිටි සමයේ ඔහුගේ නිල නිවස ලෙස භාවිත කළ කොළඹ පැජට් පාරේ පිහිටි නිවසක් වත්මන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට ලබාදීමට තීරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "විරෝධතාකරුවන්ගේ ග්‍රහණයට ලක්වීමෙන් පසු ලක්ෂ සංඛ්‍යාත ජනතාවක් පැමිණි පසුබිමක ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට සහ ඇලරි මැදුරට හානි සිදුව ඇති බව සඳහන්.",
        "මේ තත්ත්වය තුළ මෙම නිවාසවලට අදාළව නීතිමය කටයුතු සහ නිවැරදි කිරීමේ කටයුතු සිදුකෙරෙන අතරවාරයේදී ජනාධිපතිවරයාට හෝ අගමැතිවරයාට ඒවා නැරඹීමට යාමට නොහැකි තත්ත්වයක් උද්ගතව ඇත.",
        "මෙම තත්ත්වය තුළ ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසටද ගින්නෙන් හානි සිදුව ඇති අතර, ඔහු මේ වන විට ආරක්‍ෂක අංශවල පූර්ණ ආරක්‍ෂාව යටතේ ආරක්‍ෂිත ස්ථානයක රඳවා ඇත.",
        "මේ තත්ත්වය තුළ තාවකාලිකව බෙගෙට් වීදියේ නිවස ජනාධිපති රනිල්ට ලබාදීමට රජය තීරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "මෛත‍්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා ජනාධිපති ධුරය දැරූ සමයේ මෛත‍්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතාගේ නිල නිවස ලෙස භාවිත කළ කොළඹ පැජට් පාරේ පිහිටි නිවස ඔහු විශ‍්‍රාම යාමෙන් පසු මෛත‍්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතාට හිමිකර ගැනීමට කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය ගත් තීරණයට එරෙහිව මහාධිකරණය මාර්තු 29 වැනිදා අතුරු තහනම් නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කළේය. කාර්යාලයෙන් සහ දිගටම.",
        "ඉන් අනතුරුව හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා කොළඹ පැජට් පාරේ පිහිටි සිය නිවසින් පිටතට පැමිණියේය.",
        "අභියාචනාධිකරණ විනිසුරු ප්‍රීති පද්මන් සූරසේන මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් යුත් විනිසුරු යසඳ ගොටකොඩ සහ මහින්ද සමයවර්ධන යන මහත්වරුන් ගෙන් සමන්විත විනිසුරු මඩුල්ලක් විසින් මෙම අතුරු තහනම් නියෝගය නිකුත් කර ඇත.",
        "මෙම අතුරු තහනම් නියෝගය නිකුත් කරන ලද්දේ මාර්තු 29 නිකුත් කළ දින සිට සති හතරක සිට බලපැවැත්වෙන පරිදි ය.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයාට පැජට් පාරේ නිවසේ තවදුරටත් රැඳී සිටීමට නොහැකි වූ නිසා අලුත් අවුරුද්දෙන් පසු නිවසින් පිටව යන බව ඔහු ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබේ.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතාට රජය විසින් කොළඹින් තවත් නිවසක් ලබාදී තිබියදී පැජට් වීදියේ නිවසින් ඉවත්ව නව නිවසක ලැගුම්ගෙන සිටියි.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා විශ්‍රාම ගැනීමෙන් පසු පැජට් පාරේ පිහිටි නිවස ඔහුගේ දේපළ බවට පත් කිරීමට අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය ගත් තීරණයට අනුව විකල්ප ප්‍රතිපත්ති කේන්ද්‍රය සහ එහි විධායක අධ්‍යක්ෂ පාක්‍යසෝති සරවනමුත්තු විසින් මෙම මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් උල්ලංඝනය කිරීමේ පෙත්සම ගොනු කර තිබේ. ජනාධිපති ධූරයේ සිට, මූලික මානව හිමිකම් උල්ලංඝනය කිරීමකි.",
        "මෙම පෙත්සමේ වගඋත්තරකරුවන් ලෙස හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා සහ වත්මන් කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයේ සාමාජිකයින් නම් කර තිබේ.",
        "1986 අංක 4 දරන ජනාධිපති අයිතිවාසිකම් පනත මගින් විශ්‍රාම යන ජනාධිපතිවරුන් සඳහා නිවාස ලබා දීම විශේෂත්වයකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මෛත්‍රී",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැජට් පාර, කොළඹ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Beget Street",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැජට් පාර, කොළඹ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැජට් පාර, කොළඹ",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රීති පද්මන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යසඳ ගොටකොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද සමයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සති හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අලුත් අවුරුද්ද",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැජට් වීදිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විකල්ප ප්‍රතිපත්ති සඳහා මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විධායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාඛ්‍යසෝති සරවනමුත්තු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැජට් පාර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மைத்திரியின் வீடு ரணிலுக்கு !",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியும் தர்போதைய பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருமான மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன ஜனாதிபதியாக  இருந்த காலப்பகுதியில், அவரது உத்தியோகபூர்வ வாசஸ்தலமாக பயன்படுத்திய  கொழும்பு , பெஜட் வீதியில் அமைந்துள்ள வீட்டை, தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவுக்கு வழங்க தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை, அலரி மாளிகை ஆகியன போராட்டக்காரர்களால் கைப்பற்றப்பட்ட பின்னர் அங்கு  இலட்சக்கணக்கான மக்கள் சென்றுவந்த பின்னணியில் அவை சேதமடைந்துள்ளதாக கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "இந் நிலையில்  அம்மாளிகைகள் தொடர்பில் சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளும்  திருத்த வேலைகலும்  முன்னெடுக்கப்பட்டு வரும் நிலையில்,  அவற்றுக்கு ஜனாதிபதியோ பிரதமரோ வதிவதற்கு செல்ல முடியாத நிலை உருவாகியுள்ளது.",
        "இந் நிலையில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லமும் தீ வைத்து சேதப்பட்டுத்தப்பட்டுள்ள பின்னணியில் அவர் தற்போது பாதுகாப்புப் பிரிவினரின் பூரண பாதுகாப்பில், பாதுகாப்பான இடமொன்றில் தங்க வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இவ்வாறான நிலையிலேயே தற்காலிகமாக,   ஜனாதிபதி ரணிலுக்கு பெஜட் வீதி வீட்டை வழங்க அரசாங்கம் தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "முன்னதாக மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன ஜனாதிபதியாக  இருந்த காலப்பகுதியில், அவரது உத்தியோகபூர்வ வாசஸ்தலமாக பயன்படுத்திய  கொழும்பு , பெஜட் வீதியில் அமைந்துள்ள  வீட்டை,  ஜனாதிபதி பதவியிலிருந்து ஓய்வுபெற்ற பின்னரும் தொடர்ந்தும் அவருக்கு சொந்தமாக்கிக்கொள்ளும் வகையில் அமைச்சரவை ஊடாக முன்னெடுக்கப்பட்ட தீர்மானத்துக்கு உயர் நீதிமன்றம்  கடந்த மார்ச் 29 ஆம் திகதி  இடைக்கால தடை உத்தரவு பிறப்பித்தது.",
        "இதனையடுத்து முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன கொழும்பு பெஜட் வீதியில் அமைந்துள்ள  வீட்டிலிருந்து வெளியறினார்.",
        "நீதியரசர் ப்ரீத்தி பத்மன் சுரசேன தலைமையிலான யசந்த கோதாகொட, மஹிந்த சமயவர்தன ஆகிய நீதியரசர்களை உள்ளடக்கிய  நீதியரசர்கள் குழாமே இந்த இடைக்கால தடை உத்தரவைப் பிறப்பித்தது.",
        "இந்த இடைக்கால தடை உத்தரவானது,  பிறப்பிக்கப்பட்ட தினமான  மார்ச் 29  ஆம் திகதியிலிருந்து நான்கு வாரங்களின் பின்னர் அமுலகும் வண்ணம் பிறப்பிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "அதனால் பெஜட் வீதி வீட்டில் தொடர்ந்து முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியால் தங்கியிருக்க முடியாத நிலை ஏற்பட்ட நிலையில், புத்தாண்டின் பின்னர் அவர் அவ்வீட்டிலிருந்து வெளியேறுவதாக  அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேனவுக்கு கொழும்பில் மற்றொரு வீட்டினை அரசாங்கம் வழங்கியுள்ள நிலையிலேயே, பெஜட் வீதி வீட்டை விட்டு அவர் வெளியேறி, புதிய வீட்டில் தங்கியுள்ளார்..",
        "பெஜட் வீதியில் அமைந்துள்ள  வீட்டை,  ஜனாதிபதி பதவியிலிருந்து ஓய்வுபெற்ற பின்னரும் தொடர்ந்தும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேனவுக்கு  சொந்தமாக்கிக்கொள்ளும் வகையில்  அமைச்சரவை ஊடாக முன்னெடுக்கப்பட்ட தீர்மானம்  அடிப்படை மனித உரிமைகளை மீறுவதாக  தீர்ப்பளிக்குமாறு கோரி மாற்றுக் கொள்கைகளுக்கான மத்திய நிலையம் மற்றும் அதன் நிறைவேற்றுப் பணிப்பாளர்  பாக்கியசோதி சரவணமுத்துவினால் இந்த அடிப்படை உரிமை மீறல் மனு  தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மனுவின் பிரதிவாதிகளாக முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன, தற்போதைய அமைச்சரவை உறுப்பினர்கள் உள்ளிட்டோர் பெயரிடப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "1986 ஆம் ஆண்டின் 4 ஆம் இலக்க ஜனாதிபதிகளின் உரிமைகள் சட்டம் பிரகாரம் ஓய்வுபெறும் ஜனாதிபதிகளுக்கு வீடுகள் வழங்கப்படுவது குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மைத்திரி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேஜெட் வீதி, கொழும்பு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெகெட் தெரு",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேஜெட் வீதி, கொழும்பு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேஜெட் வீதி, கொழும்பு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ப்ரீத்தி பத்மன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யசந்த கோடகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த சமயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புத்தாண்டு",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேஜெட் தெரு",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாற்றுக் கொள்கைகளுக்கான மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிர்வாகி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாக்கியசோதி சரவணமுத்து",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேஜெட் சாலை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}