{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/FactCheck-lk-by-Verité-Research-first-Lankan-platform-to-receive-IFCN-accreditation/56-737941",
  "time_ut": 1658875088,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "FactCheck.lk by Verité Research first Lankan platform to receive IFCN accreditation",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "FactCheck.lk by Verité Research first Lankan platform to receive IFCN accreditation",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "FactCheck.lk by Verité Research joins a prestigious list of global fact checking organisations and platforms that are recognised for maintaining an international standard of fact checking practices by adhering to a code of principles laid down by the International Fact Checking Network (IFCN).",
        "FactCheck.lk by Verité Research is the first Sri Lankan platform to become a verified signatory of the IFCN’s code of principles.",
        "FactCheck.lk is among 88 active IFCN signatories from around the world, and one of the 16 South Asian fact checking organisations/platforms listed as an active signatory.",
        "The IFCN by the Poynter Institute in the USA is a global alliance of fact checkers. It was launched in 2015 to bring together the growing community of fact checkers around the world, and promote excellence in fact checking."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Verité Research",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Lankan",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "IFCN",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Verité Research",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Fact Checking Network",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IFCN",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Verité Research",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "IFCN",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FactCheck.lk",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "88",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IFCN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IFCN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Poynter Institute",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "USA",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "FactCheck.lk by Verité Research IFCN ප්‍රතීතනය ලැබූ පළමු ලංකා වේදිකාව",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "FactCheck.lk by Verité Research, ජාත්‍යන්තර කරුණු පිරික්සීමේ ජාලය (IFCN) විසින් පනවා ඇති ප්‍රතිපත්ති සංග්‍රහයකට අනුගත වෙමින් ජාත්‍යන්තර සත්‍ය පරීක්‍ෂණ පිළිවෙත් පවත්වාගෙන යාම සඳහා පිළිගත් ගෝලීය කරුණු පරීක්‍ෂණ සංවිධාන සහ වේදිකාවල කීර්තිමත් ලැයිස්තුවකට එක් වේ.",
        "Verité Research විසින් FactCheck.lk යනු IFCN හි මූලධර්ම සංග්‍රහයේ සත්‍යාපිත අත්සන්කරුවෙකු බවට පත් වූ පළමු ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය වේදිකාව වේ.",
        "FactCheck.lk ලොව පුරා සිටින සක්‍රීය IFCN අත්සන්කරුවන් 88 අතර වන අතර, සක්‍රීය අත්සන් කරුවෙකු ලෙස ලැයිස්තුගත කර ඇති දකුණු ආසියානු කරුණු පරීක්ෂා කිරීමේ සංවිධාන/වේදිකා 16න් එකකි.",
        "ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදයේ Poynter ආයතනය විසින් IFCN යනු කරුණු පරීක්ෂකයන්ගේ ගෝලීය සන්ධානයකි. එය 2015 දී දියත් කරන ලද්දේ ලොව පුරා වර්ධනය වන කරුණු පරීක්‍ෂක ප්‍රජාව එක් කිරීමට සහ සත්‍ය පරීක්‍ෂණයේ විශිෂ්ටත්වය ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමට ය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "වෙරිටේ පර්යේෂණ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ලාංකික",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "IFCN",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වෙරිටේ පර්යේෂණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර කරුණු පිරික්සුම් ජාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IFCN",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෙරිටේ පර්යේෂණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "IFCN",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FactCheck.lk",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "88",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IFCN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IFCN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොයින්ටර් ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇඑජ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "FactCheck.lk by Verité Research IFCN அங்கீகாரத்தைப் பெற்ற முதல் இலங்கைத் தளம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வெரிடே ரிசர்ச் மூலம் FactCheck.lk ஆனது, சர்வதேச உண்மைச் சரிபார்ப்பு வலையமைப்பால் (IFCN) வகுத்துள்ள கொள்கைகளின் நெறிமுறையைப் பின்பற்றி, சர்வதேச தரநிலை உண்மைச் சரிபார்ப்பு நடைமுறைகளைப் பராமரிப்பதற்காக அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்ட உலகளாவிய உண்மைச் சரிபார்ப்பு நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் தளங்களின் மதிப்புமிக்க பட்டியலில் இணைகிறது.",
        "Verité Research வழங்கும் FactCheck.lk ஆனது IFCN இன் கொள்கைகளின் கையொப்பமிடப்பட்ட முதல் இலங்கைத் தளமாகும்.",
        "FactCheck.lk ஆனது உலகெங்கிலும் உள்ள 88 செயலில் உள்ள IFCN கையொப்பமிட்ட நிறுவனங்களில் ஒன்றாகும், மேலும் செயலில் கையெழுத்திட்டதாக பட்டியலிடப்பட்டுள்ள 16 தெற்காசிய உண்மைச் சரிபார்ப்பு நிறுவனங்கள்/தளங்களில் ஒன்றாகும்.",
        "அமெரிக்காவில் உள்ள Poynter இன்ஸ்டிட்யூட் மூலம் IFCN ஆனது உண்மை சரிபார்ப்பவர்களின் உலகளாவிய கூட்டணியாகும். உலகெங்கிலும் வளர்ந்து வரும் உண்மைச் சரிபார்ப்பவர்களின் சமூகத்தை ஒன்றிணைப்பதற்கும், உண்மைச் சரிபார்ப்பில் சிறந்து விளங்குவதற்கும் இது 2015 இல் தொடங்கப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வெரிடே ஆராய்ச்சி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஐ.எஃப்.சி.என்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வெரிடே ஆராய்ச்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச உண்மைச் சரிபார்ப்பு நெட்வொர்க்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.எஃப்.சி.என்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெரிடே ஆராய்ச்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.எஃப்.சி.என்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FactCheck.lk",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "88",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.எஃப்.சி.என்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.எஃப்.சி.என்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poynter நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}