{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/பாராளுமன்றத்துக்கு-முன்பாக-போராட்டம்-ரணிலிம்-கேம்/175-300378",
  "time_ut": 1657726807,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "பாராளுமன்றத்துக்கு முன்பாக போராட்டம்; ’ரணிலிம் கேம்’",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Protest before Parliament; 'Ranilim Game'",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Ratindu Senaratne alias Ratta, one of the empty face protestors, has requested not to participate in the protest in front of the Parliament.",
        "We have been patiently fighting for more than 90 days. That patience should continue for another day or two.",
        "We have captured the President's House, the President's Secretariat and the Alary House. There is no need for us to touch on anything beyond this. Therefore, those who are protesting in front of the Parliament should return to empty-handed without causing further damage to public property.",
        "Those who struggle before Parliament should not fall into Ranil's game. He also said that this is Ranil's game."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranilim Game'",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ratindu Senaratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratta",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "more than 90 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "another day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Secretariat",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Alary House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ඉදිරිපිට විරෝධතා; 'රනිලිම් ගේම්'",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ඉදිරිපිට පැවැත්වෙන විරෝධතාවයට සහභාගි නොවන ලෙස හිස් මුහුණු විරෝධතාවයේ නිරතව සිටි රතිඳු සේනාරත්න හෙවත් රත්තා ඉල්ලීමක් කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "අපි දින 90කට වැඩි කාලයක් ඉවසීමෙන් සටන් කළා. ඒ ඉවසීම තවත් දිනක් දෙකක් පැවතිය යුතුය.",
        "අපි ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය, ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය, ඇලරි හවුස් අල්ලාගෙන තිබෙනවා. මෙතනින් එහාට අපිට අත තියන්න අවශ්‍ය නැහැ. ඒ නිසා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ඉදිරිපිට උද්ඝෝෂණ කරන අය තවදුරටත් පොදු දේපළවලට හානි නොකර හිස් අතින් ආපසු යා යුතුයි.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ඉස්සරහා දඟලන අය රනිල්ගේ ගේමට වැටෙන්න එපා. මේක රනිල්ගේ ගේමක් බවද ඔහු කීවේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිලිම් ගේම්'",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රතිඳු සේනාරත්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රට්ටා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින 90 කට වඩා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තවත් දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇලරි නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாராளுமன்றத்துக்கு முன்பாக போராட்டம்; ’ரணிலிம் கேம்’",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாராளுமன்றத்துக்கு முன்பாக போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட வேண்டாம் என காலி முகத்திடல் போராட்டக்காரர்களில் ஒருவரான செயற்பாட்டாளரான ரட்டா (Ratta) என்கிற ரதிந்து சேனாரத்ன கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "கடந்த 90 நாட்களுக்கு மேலாக பொறுமையாக போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டு வருகிறோம். இன்னும் ஓரிரு நாட்களுக்கும் அந்தப் பொறுமை தொடர வேண்டும்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை, ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம், அலரி மாளிகை என்பனவற்றை நாம் கைப்பற்றி இருக்கிறோம். இதற்கு மேலாக எதையும் நாம் கைபற்ற வேண்டிய அவசியம் இல்லை. எனவே, மேலும் பொதுமக்களின் சொத்துக்களுக்கு சேதம் விளைவிக்காது பாராளுமன்றதுக்கு முன்பாக போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபடுபவர்கள் காலி முகத்துடலுக்கு மீள திரும்பி வரவேண்டும் எனவும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்துக்கு முன்பாக போராடுபவர்கள் ரணிலின் கேம்க்குள் சிக்க வேண்டாம். இது ரணிலின் கேம் எனவும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணிலிம் கேம்'",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரதிந்து சேனாரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரட்டா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "90 நாட்களுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மற்றொரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செயலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலரி மாளிகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}