{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78925",
  "time_ut": 1659899700,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ceylon Teachers’ Union (CTU) General Secretary Joseph Stalin released on One Million Rupee  bail after being remanded for allegedly violating a court order  Attends  immediately after his release  the Protest demanding his release  by  teachers and principals near the Lipton Circus Roundabout in Colombo",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ceylon Teachers’ Union (CTU) General Secretary Joseph Stalin released on One Million Rupee  bail after being remanded for allegedly violating a court order  Attends  immediately after his release  the Protest demanding his release  by  teachers and principals near the Lipton Circus Roundabout in Colombo",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Ceylon Teachers’ Union (CTU) General Secretary Joseph Stalin, who was released on bail after being remanded for allegedly violating a court order, was received by a large group of teachers and principals near the Lipton Circus Roundabout in Colombo yesterday (8).",
        "Stalin, a well known trade unionist, was produced before the Colombo Fort Magistrate’s Court yesterday (8). At that time, Colombo Fort Chief Magistrate Thilina Gamage ordered that he be released on two personal sureties of Rs. 500,000 each.",
        "Meanwhile, before he was released on bail, a group of teachers and principals had organised a protest near the Lipton Circus Roundabout in Colombo, demanding his release. Stalin, who was subsequently released on bail, also arrived at the venue last evening and was welcomed by the assembled teachers and principals.",
        "He proceeded to join the demonstration being staged there, where those gathered then protested against President Ranil Wickremesinghe and the current Government. They expressed their strong opposition to the President, especially regarding the arrest of activists involved in the ongoing people’s struggle, known as the “aragalaya”.",
        "Stalin, who has been at the forefront of the protests which earlier demanded the resignation of former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, and are now demanding the resignation of Wickremesinghe, was arrested by the Police on 3 August for allegedly violating a court order during a protest march at Bank of Ceylon Mawatha on 28 May. His arrest has since seen much opposition from several parties including the teachers’ and principals’ trade unions, other trade unions, the main Parliamentary Opposition (the Samagi Jana Balawegaya), and the United Nations Special Rapporteur on Human Rights Defenders.",
        "Earlier, the All-Ceylon United Teachers’ Union (CTU) had said that all associations affiliated with the education sector had organised a protest movement yesterday (8), demanding the release of Stalin."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ceylon Teachers’ Union",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Joseph Stalin",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "One Million Rupee",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Protest",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "the Lipton Circus Roundabout",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Colombo",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Teachers’ Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joseph Stalin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Lipton Circus Roundabout",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8)",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Stalin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Fort Magistrate’s",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8)",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Fort",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Lipton Circus Roundabout",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Stalin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Stalin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bank of Ceylon Mawatha",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliamentary Opposition",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations Special Rapporteur on Human Rights Defenders",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the All-Ceylon United Teachers’ Union",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8)",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Stalin",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලංකා ගුරු සංගමයේ (CTU) ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් ජෝසප් ස්ටාලින් අධිකරණ නියෝගයක් කඩ කිරීමේ චෝදනාව මත රිමාන්ඩ් භාරයේ සිට රුපියල් මිලියනයක ඇප මත මුදා හැරියේ ඔහු නිදහස් කළ වහාම ඔහු නිදහස් කරන ලෙස බලකරමින් කොළඹ ලිප්ටන් වටරවුම වටරවුම අසලදී ගුරුවරුන් සහ විදුහල්පතිවරුන් විසින් පවත්වන ලද විරෝධතාවයට සහභාගී වේ.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "අධිකරණ නියෝගයක් කඩ කිරීමේ චෝදනාව මත රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාරගතව සිට ඇප මත මුදාහැර සිටින ලංකා ගුරු සංගමයේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් ජෝසප් ස්ටාලින් මහතා ඊයේ (8) කොළඹ ලිප්ටන් වටරවුම අසලදී ගුරුවරුන් සහ විදුහල්පතිවරුන් විශාල පිරිසක් විසින් පිළිගනු ලැබීය.",
        "සුප්‍රසිද්ධ වෘත්තීය සමිති ක්‍රියාකාරිකයෙකු වන ස්ටාලින් ඊයේ (8) කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කෙරුණා. එම අවස්ථාවේදී කොළඹ කොටුව ප්‍රධාන මහේස්ත්‍රාත් තිළිණ ගමගේ නියෝග කළේ රුපියල් ලක්ෂයක ශරීර ඇප දෙකක් මත ඔහු මුදා හැරීමටයි. 500,000 බැගින්.",
        "මේ අතර ඔහු ඇප මත මුදා හැරීමට පෙර ඔහු නිදහස් කරන ලෙස බලකරමින් ගුරුවරුන් සහ විදුහල්පතිවරුන් පිරිසක් කොළඹ ලිප්ටන් වටරවුම අසල විරෝධතාවයක් සංවිධානය කර තිබුණා. පසුව ඇප මත නිදහස් වූ ස්ටාලින් ද ඊයේ සවස එම ස්ථානයට පැමිණි අතර රැස්ව සිටි ගුරුවරුන් සහ විදුහල්පතිවරුන් විසින් ඔහු පිළිගනු ලැබීය.",
        "ඔහු එහි පැවැත්වෙමින් තිබූ පෙළපාලියට එක්වීමට ගිය අතර එහිදී රැස්ව සිටි පිරිස ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සහ වත්මන් රජයට විරෝධය පළ කළහ. විශේෂයෙන්ම \"අරගලය\" නමින් හැඳින්වෙන අඛණ්ඩ ජනතා අරගලයට සම්බන්ධ ක්‍රියාකාරීන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඔවුන් ජනාධිපතිවරයාට දැඩි විරෝධය පළ කළා.",
        "මීට පෙර හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටි විරෝධතාවල ඉදිරියෙන්ම සිටි සහ දැන් වික්‍රමසිංහට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටින ස්ටාලින් අගෝස්තු 03 වනදා විරෝධතා පාගමනකදී අධිකරණ නියෝගයක් කඩ කිරීමේ චෝදනාව මත පොලිසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගනු ලැබීය. මැයි 28 වෙනිදා ලංකා බැංකු මාවතේ. ඔහු අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමෙන් පසුව ගුරුවරුන්ගේ සහ විදුහල්පතිවරුන්ගේ වෘත්තීය සමිති, අනෙකුත් වෘත්තීය සමිති, ප්‍රධාන පාර්ලිමේන්තු විපක්ෂය (සමගි ජන බලවේගය) සහ මානව හිමිකම් ආරක්‍ෂකයින් පිළිබඳ එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ විශේෂ වාර්තාකරු ඇතුළු පාර්ශව කිහිපයකින් විශාල විරෝධයක් එල්ල විය.",
        "ස්ටාලින් නිදහස් කරන ලෙස බලකරමින් අධ්‍යාපන ක්ෂේත්‍රයට සම්බන්ධ සියලුම සංගම් ඊයේ (8) විරෝධතා ව්‍යාපාරයක් සංවිධානය කළ බව සමස්ත ලංකා එක්සත් ගුරු සංගමය (CTU) මීට පෙර ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබුණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලංකා ගුරු සංගමය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජෝසප් ස්ටාලින්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රුපියල් මිලියනයක්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "විරෝධතාව",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "ලිප්ටන් වටරවුම වටරවුම",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "කොළඹ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ගුරු සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝසප් ස්ටාලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිප්ටන් වටරවුම වටරවුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8)",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්ටාලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8)",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිප්ටන් වටරවුම වටරවුම",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්ටාලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්ටාලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා බැංකු මාවත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු විපක්ෂය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මානව හිමිකම් ආරක්ෂකයින් පිළිබඳ එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ විශේෂ වාර්තාකරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමස්ත ලංකා එක්සත් ගුරු සංගමය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8)",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්ටාලින්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நீதிமன்ற உத்தரவை மீறிய குற்றச்சாட்டின் பேரில் இலங்கை ஆசிரியர் சங்கத்தின் (CTU) பொதுச் செயலாளர் ஜோசப் ஸ்டாலின் ஒரு மில்லியன் ரூபா பிணையில் விடுதலை செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "நீதிமன்ற உத்தரவை மீறிய குற்றச்சாட்டில் விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டு பிணையில் விடுவிக்கப்பட்ட இலங்கை ஆசிரியர் சங்கத்தின் (CTU) பொதுச் செயலாளர் ஜோசப் ஸ்டாலினை, நேற்று (8) கொழும்பு லிப்டன் சர்க்கஸ் சுற்றுவட்டத்திற்கு அருகில் ஆசிரியர்கள் மற்றும் அதிபர்கள் திரளாக வரவேற்றனர்.",
        "பிரபல தொழிற்சங்கவாதியான ஸ்டாலின் நேற்று (8) கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றத்தில் ஆஜர்படுத்தப்பட்டார். இதன்போது, ​​இரண்டு ரூபா பெறுமதியான இரண்டு சரீரப் பிணைகளில் அவரை விடுவிக்குமாறு கொழும்பு கோட்டை பிரதான நீதவான் திலின கமகே உத்தரவிட்டார். தலா 500,000.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், அவர் பிணையில் விடுவிக்கப்படுவதற்கு முன்னர், அவரை விடுவிக்கக் கோரி, கொழும்பு லிப்டன் சுற்றுவட்டச் சுற்றுவட்டத்திற்கு அருகில் ஆசிரியர்கள் மற்றும் அதிபர்கள் குழுவொன்று போராட்டம் ஒன்றை ஏற்பாடு செய்திருந்தது. இதையடுத்து ஜாமீனில் வெளியே வந்த ஸ்டாலினும் நேற்று மாலை நிகழ்ச்சி நடைபெறும் இடத்துக்கு வந்து திரண்டிருந்த ஆசிரியர்கள் மற்றும் தலைமையாசிரியர்கள் அவரை வரவேற்றனர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கும் தற்போதைய அரசாங்கத்துக்கும் எதிராக அங்கு கூடியிருந்தவர்கள் ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டனர். குறிப்பாக “அறகலய” எனப்படும் மக்கள் போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டமை தொடர்பில் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு தமது கடும் எதிர்ப்பை வெளிப்படுத்தினர்.",
        "முன்னதாக முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவை பதவி விலகக் கோரியும், தற்போது விக்ரமசிங்கேவை பதவி விலகக் கோரியும் நடைபெற்ற போராட்டங்களில் முன்னணியில் இருந்த ஸ்டாலின், கடந்த ஆகஸ்ட் 3ஆம் தேதி நீதிமன்ற உத்தரவை மீறி நடந்த போராட்டத்தின் போது காவல்துறையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டார். மே 28 அன்று இலங்கை வங்கி மாவத்தை. அவரது கைதுக்குப் பின்னர் ஆசிரியர்கள் மற்றும் அதிபர்களின் தொழிற்சங்கங்கள், பிற தொழிற்சங்கங்கள், பிரதான பாராளுமன்ற எதிர்க்கட்சி (சமகி ஜன பலவேகய) மற்றும் ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் மனித உரிமைகள் பாதுகாவலர்களுக்கான சிறப்பு அறிக்கையாளர் உட்பட பல தரப்பினரிடமிருந்து அதிக எதிர்ப்பைக் கண்டது.",
        "ஸ்டாலினை விடுவிக்கக் கோரி கல்வித்துறையுடன் இணைந்த அனைத்து சங்கங்களும் நேற்று (8) கண்டனப் போராட்டத்தை நடத்தியதாக அகில இலங்கை ஐக்கிய ஆசிரியர் சங்கம் (CTU) முன்னதாக தெரிவித்திருந்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை ஆசிரியர் சங்கம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜோசப் ஸ்டாலின்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஒரு மில்லியன் ரூபாய்",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆர்ப்பாட்டம்",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "லிப்டன் சர்க்கஸ் ரவுண்டானா",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "கொழும்பு",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ஆசிரியர் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜோசப் ஸ்டாலின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிப்டன் சர்க்கஸ் ரவுண்டானா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8)",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்டாலின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8)",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிப்டன் சர்க்கஸ் ரவுண்டானா",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்டாலின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்டாலின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை வங்கி மாவத்தை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற எதிர்க்கட்சி",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனித உரிமைகள் பாதுகாவலர்களுக்கான ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் சிறப்பு அறிக்கையாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அகில இலங்கை ஐக்கிய ஆசிரியர் சங்கம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8)",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்டாலின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}