{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84610/protest-in-front-of-un-office-in-colombo-hearing-of-case-postponed",
  "time_ut": 1661766120,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Protest in front of UN Office in Colombo: hearing of case postponed",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Protest in front of UN Office in Colombo: hearing of case postponed",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Colombo Magistrate’s Court today ordered that the case filed against a group including former Minister Wimal Weerawansa will be called for hearing on December 12.",
        "The case was filed on the charges of causing public inconvenience by blocking the roads around the United Nations (UN) Office in Thummulla, Colombo when the then UN Human Rights Commissioner, Prince Zeid Al Hussain visited Sri Lanka in the year 2016.",
        "The case was called before Colombo Chief Magistrate Nandana Amarasinghe today (29).",
        "Wimal Weerawansa, Weerakumara Dissanayake, Piyasiri Dissanayake and Mohammed Muzammil who were named as suspects of the case, had appeared before the court today, while MP Jayantha Samaraweera and Rojer Senevirathne had not appeared before the court.",
        "The Attorney who appeared on behalf of MP Jayantha Samaraweera and Rojer Senevirathne, informed the court that his clients are unwell and that the relevant medical reports are submitted to the court.",
        "Then the Magistrate, who ordered to postpone the hearing of the case to December 12, further advised the witnesses appeared before the court on that date."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "UN Office",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Colombo",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Colombo Magistrate’s Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "December 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the United Nations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thummulla",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year 2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandana Amarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerakumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Piyasiri Dissanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mohammed Muzammil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "December 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කොළඹ එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ කාර්යාලය ඉදිරිපිට විරෝධතාවක්: නඩු විභාගය කල් යයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු අමාත්‍ය විමල් වීරවංශ ඇතුළු පිරිසකට එරෙහිව පවරා ඇති නඩුව දෙසැම්බර් මස 12 වනදා විභාගයට ගැනීමට කොළඹ මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය අද නියෝග කළා.",
        "2016 වසරේ එවකට එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කොමසාරිස් සෙයිද් අල් හුසේන් කුමරු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණි අවස්ථාවේ කොළඹ තුම්මුල්ලේ පිහිටි එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවිධානයේ කාර්යාලය අවට මාර්ග අවහිර කරමින් මහජන අපහසුතාවට පත් කිරීමේ චෝදනාව යටතේ මෙම නඩුව පවරා තිබුණා.",
        "මෙම නඩුව අද (29) කොළඹ ප්‍රධාන මහේස්ත්‍රාත් නන්දන අමරසිංහ මහතා ඉදිරියේ කැඳවනු ලැබීය.",
        "මෙම නඩුවේ විත්තිකරුවන් ලෙස නම් කර සිටින විමල් වීරවංශ, වීරකුමාර දිසානායක, පියසිරි දිසානායක සහ මොහොමඩ් මුසම්මිල් යන මහත්වරුන් අද අධිකරණය හමුවේ පෙනී සිටි අතර පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ජයන්ත සමරවීර සහ රොජර් සෙනෙවිරත්න අධිකරණය හමුවේ පෙනී සිටියේ නැත.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ජයන්ත සමරවීර සහ රොජර් සෙනෙවිරත්න වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි නීතීඥවරයා අධිකරණයට දන්වා සිටියේ තම සේවාදායකයන් අසනීප තත්ත්වයෙන් පසුවන බවත් අදාළ වෛද්‍ය වාර්තා අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කරන බවත්ය.",
        "අනතුරුව නඩුව දෙසැම්බර් 12 වැනිදාට කල් තැබීමට නියෝග කළ මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා එදිනට සාක්ෂිකරුවන්ට අධිකරණය හමුවේ පෙනී සිටින ලෙස වැඩිදුරටත් අවවාද කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ කාර්යාලය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "කොළඹ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙසැම්බර් 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එ.ජා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුම්මුල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එ.ජා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016 වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දන අමරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරකුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පියසිරි දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොහොමඩ් මුසම්මිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙසැම්බර් 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கொழும்பில் ஐ.நா அலுவலகம் முன்பாக போராட்டம்: வழக்கு விசாரணை ஒத்திவைப்பு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் விமல் வீரவன்ச உள்ளிட்ட குழுவினருக்கு எதிராக தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ள வழக்கை எதிர்வரும் டிசம்பர் மாதம் 12ஆம் திகதி விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக் கொள்ளுமாறு கொழும்பு நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம் இன்று உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "கடந்த 2016ஆம் ஆண்டு ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபையின் மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணையாளர் இளவரசர் செயிட் அல் ஹுசைன் இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்த போது, ​​கொழும்பு, தும்முல்லையில் உள்ள ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபையின் அலுவலகத்தை சுற்றி வீதிகளை மறித்து பொதுமக்களுக்கு அசௌகரியத்தை ஏற்படுத்திய குற்றச்சாட்டின் பேரில் இந்த வழக்கு தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டது.",
        "இந்த வழக்கு இன்று (29) கொழும்பு பிரதான நீதவான் நந்தன அமரசிங்க முன்னிலையில் விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக்கொள்ளப்பட்டது.",
        "இந்த வழக்கின் சந்தேக நபர்களாக குறிப்பிடப்பட்டிருந்த விமல் வீரவன்ச, வீரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க, பியசிறி திஸாநாயக்க மற்றும் மொஹமட் முஸம்மில் ஆகியோர் இன்று நீதிமன்றில் ஆஜராகியிருந்ததுடன், பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஜயந்த சமரவீர மற்றும் ரொஜர் செனவிரத்ன ஆகியோர் நீதிமன்றில் ஆஜராகவில்லை.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஜயந்த சமரவீர மற்றும் ரொஜர் செனவிரத்ன ஆகியோர் சார்பில் ஆஜரான சட்டத்தரணி, தனது வாடிக்கையாளர்கள் சுகயீனமடைந்துள்ளதாகவும், அது தொடர்பான மருத்துவ அறிக்கைகள் நீதிமன்றில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் நீதிமன்றில் அறிவித்தார்.",
        "வழக்கின் விசாரணையை டிசம்பர் 12ஆம் தேதிக்கு ஒத்திவைத்து உத்தரவிட்ட மாஜிஸ்திரேட், அன்றைய தினம் சாட்சிகள் நீதிமன்றத்தில் ஆஜராகுமாறு அறிவுறுத்தினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஐ.நா அலுவலகம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "கொழும்பு",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு மாஜிஸ்திரேட் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிசம்பர் 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தும்முல்லை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016 ஆம் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தன அமரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பியசிறி திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முகம்மது முஸம்மில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிசம்பர் 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}