{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/27/sri-lanka-to-drop-fish-chicken-prices-soon/",
  "time_ut": 1661587740,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka to drop fish & chicken prices soon",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka to drop fish & chicken prices soon",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Minister of Trade, Commerce, and Food Security, Nalin Fernando says a final decision on reducing the prices of Chicken and Fish will be taken next week.",
        "Despite the reduction in prices of essential goods such as Dhal and Sugar last month, the prices of Chicken, Eggs, and Fish skyrocketed.",
        "The Government recently introduced a control price on Eggs, to bring down the market price from Rs. 65 to Rs. 43 – 45.",
        "Minister Nalin Fernando says the Consumer Affairs Authority (CAA) is now exploring the possibility of reducing the prices of Fish, which skyrocketed amidst the fuel crisis.",
        "He noted that the CAA has also collected data on the production costs for Chicken and the prices in the market, adding that steps will be taken to set affordable prices for the benefit of the consumers."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Food Security",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chicken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "next week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chicken",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Eggs",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "43",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nalin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Consumer Affairs Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CAA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chicken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මාළු සහ කුකුල් මස් මිල ළඟදීම පහත හෙළයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); කුකුළු මස් සහ මාළු මිල අඩු කිරීම පිළිබඳ අවසන් තීරණය ලබන සතියේදී ගන්නා බව වෙළෙඳ, වාණිජ හා ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතා අමාත්‍ය නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා පවසයි.",
        "පසුගිය මාසයේ පරිප්පු, සීනි වැනි අත්‍යවශ්‍ය භාණ්ඩවල මිල අඩු කළත් කුකුල් මස්, බිත්තර, මාළු මිල අහස උසට නැඟුණා.",
        "රජය පසුගියදා බිත්තර සඳහා පාලන මිලක් හඳුන්වා දුන්නේ වෙළෙඳපොළ මිල රු. 65 සිට රු. 43 - 45.",
        "ඉන්ධන අර්බුදයත් සමඟ ඉහළ ගිය මාළු මිල අඩු කිරීමේ හැකියාව පාරිභෝගික කටයුතු අධිකාරිය (CAA) දැන් සොයා බලන බව අමාත්‍ය නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා පවසයි.",
        "කුකුළු මස් සඳහා වන නිෂ්පාදන පිරිවැය සහ වෙළඳපොලේ මිල ගණන් පිළිබඳව ද CAA විසින් දත්ත රැස් කර ඇති බව සඳහන් කළ ඔහු පාරිභෝගිකයින්ගේ යහපත සඳහා දැරිය හැකි මිලක් නියම කිරීමට පියවර ගන්නා බව පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුකුල් මස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුකුල් මස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බිත්තර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "43",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාරිභෝගික කටයුතු අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CAA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුකුල් මස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையில் மீன் மற்றும் கோழி விலை விரைவில் குறையும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); கோழிக்கறி மற்றும் மீன் விலைகளை குறைப்பது தொடர்பில் அடுத்த வாரம் இறுதி முடிவு எடுக்கப்படும் என வர்த்தக, வர்த்தக மற்றும் உணவு பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சர் நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கடந்த மாதம் பருப்பு, சர்க்கரை போன்ற அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களின் விலை குறைக்கப்பட்டாலும், கோழி, முட்டை, மீன் ஆகியவற்றின் விலை கிடுகிடுவென உயர்ந்தது.",
        "மார்க்கெட் விலையை ரூ.10 ஆக குறைக்கும் வகையில், சமீபத்தில் முட்டை மீதான கட்டுப்பாட்டு விலையை அரசு அறிமுகப்படுத்தியது. 65 முதல் ரூ. 43 - 45.",
        "எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடிக்கு மத்தியில் அதிகரித்துள்ள மீன்களின் விலையை குறைப்பதற்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகளை நுகர்வோர் விவகார அதிகார சபை (CAA) தற்போது ஆராய்ந்து வருவதாக அமைச்சர் நலின் பெர்னாண்டோ தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கோழியின் உற்பத்தி செலவுகள் மற்றும் சந்தையில் உள்ள விலைகள் பற்றிய தரவுகளையும் CAA சேகரித்துள்ளது என்று குறிப்பிட்ட அவர், நுகர்வோரின் நலனுக்காக மலிவு விலையை நிர்ணயம் செய்ய நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்படும் என்று கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உணவு பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோழி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோழி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முட்டைகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "43",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுகர்வோர் விவகார ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CAA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோழி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}