{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/22/unhrc-core-group-on-sl-express-dismay-over-gallefaceraid/",
  "time_ut": 1658503980,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "UNHRC core group on SL express dismay over #GalleFaceRaid",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "UNHRC core group on SL express dismay over #GalleFaceRaid",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The United Nations Human Rights Council (UNHRC) core group on Sri Lanka has expressed their dismay regarding the violence which took place at the Galle Face protest site early morning today (22).",
        "Accordingly, a statement issued by core group on Sri Lank, which includes Canada, Germany, Malawi, Montenegro, North Macedonia, the USA and UK, highlighted that peaceful protests is a fundamental part of any democracy.",
        "Moreover, the core group has called for full respect for human rights and the rule of law.",
        "Govt and Govt approved private schools to resume activities on 25th July"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The United Nations Human Rights Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Galle Face",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "early morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malawi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Montenegro",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "North Macedonia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USA",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Govt",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25th July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයේ මූලික කණ්ඩායම #GalleFaceRaid ගැන කණගාටුව ප්‍රකාශ කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); අද (22) අලුයම ගාලු මුවදොර විරෝධතා භූමියේ ඇති වූ ප්‍රචණ්ඩ ක්‍රියා සම්බන්ධයෙන් එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පිළිබඳ මූලික කණ්ඩායම සිය කණගාටුව ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබේ.",
        "ඒ අනුව, කැනඩාව, ජර්මනිය, මලාවි, මොන්ටිනිග්‍රෝ, උතුරු මැසිඩෝනියාව, ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය සහ එක්සත් රාජධානිය ඇතුළත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පිළිබඳ මූලික කණ්ඩායම විසින් නිකුත් කරන ලද නිවේදනයක සාමකාමී විරෝධතා ඕනෑම ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදයක මූලික අංගයක් බව අවධාරණය කර ඇත.",
        "එපමණක් නොව, මූලික කණ්ඩායම මානව හිමිකම් සහ නීතියේ ආධිපත්‍යයට පූර්ණ ගරු කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා තිබේ.",
        "රජයේ සහ රජයේ පෞද්ගලික පාසල් ජූලි 25 වැනි දින නැවත ක්‍රියාකාරකම් ආරම්භ කිරීමට අනුමැතිය ලබා දී ඇත"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිමිදිරි උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මලාවි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොන්ටිනිග්රෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු මැසිඩෝනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇඑජ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "#GalleFaceRaid குறித்து SL எக்ஸ்பிரஸ் அதிருப்தியில் UNHRC முக்கிய குழு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); காலி முகத்திடலில் இன்று (22) அதிகாலை இடம்பெற்ற வன்முறைச் சம்பவங்கள் தொடர்பில் இலங்கை தொடர்பான ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவையின் (UNHRC) முக்கிய குழு விசனம் வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அதன்படி, கனடா, ஜேர்மனி, மலாவி, மொண்டினீக்ரோ, வடக்கு மாசிடோனியா, அமெரிக்கா மற்றும் இங்கிலாந்து ஆகிய நாடுகளை உள்ளடக்கிய இலங்கை தொடர்பான முக்கிய குழுவினால் வெளியிடப்பட்ட அறிக்கையில், அமைதியான போராட்டங்கள் எந்தவொரு ஜனநாயகத்தின் அடிப்படை அங்கம் என்பதை எடுத்துக்காட்டுகிறது.",
        "மேலும், மனித உரிமைகள் மற்றும் சட்டத்தின் ஆட்சியை முழுமையாக மதிக்க வேண்டும் என்று கோர் குழு அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "தனியார் பள்ளிகள் ஜூலை 25 ஆம் தேதி மீண்டும் செயல்பட அரசு மற்றும் அரசு ஒப்புதல் அளித்துள்ளது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி முகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மனி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலாவி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாண்டினீக்ரோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு மாசிடோனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}