{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130359",
  "time_ut": 1656436345,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "22 ஆவது அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தம் விரைவில் பாராளுமன்றிற்கு அதன் பின் 21 ஆவது திருத்தம் என பெயர் மாற்றப்படும் - விஜேதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The 22nd Amendment to the Constitution will soon be renamed Parliament as the 21st Amendment - Wijetasa Rajapaksa",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "The 22nd Amendment to the Constitution will be published in the Gazette in a couple of days and will be tabled in Parliament shortly thereafter. Minister of Justice, Prisons Affairs and Constitutional Reforms Wijetasa Rajapaksa said the amendment would be renamed the 21st Amendment to the Constitution after it is tabled in Parliament.",
        "He was speaking at a press conference at the Government Information Department on Tuesday (28).",
        "The Cabinet approved the 22nd Amendment to the Constitution, a key condition for strengthening democracy and upholding the rule of law in the country, as expected by the people and the international community.",
        "The 22nd Amendment to the Constitution, approved by the Cabinet, will be published in the Gazette and will soon be tabled in Parliament. The bill will be published in the Gazette 7 days after it is included in the parliamentary agenda and the next steps will be taken thereafter.",
        "There is an ambiguous situation among the people regarding the number of constitutional amendments. The 21st Amendment is an amendment submitted by the United People's Power.",
        "A constitutional amendment has been submitted by the government due to difficulties in implementing it. That is why we consider this as the 22nd Amendment.",
        "As the 22nd Amendment to the Constitution was submitted by the Government, I withdrew the amendment I had proposed.",
        "However, the amendment, which is currently being approved by the Cabinet, will be renamed the 21st Amendment after it is tabled in Parliament. When the first debate on the 22nd Amendment begins, it will be referred to as the 21st Amendment.",
        "I believe that the 21st Amendment to the Constitution put forward by the United People's Power is unworkable.",
        "The minister also pointed out that the Supreme Court had ruled that a referendum was necessary to legislate every string in it."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "The 22nd Amendment",
          "label": "LAW"
        },
        {
          "text": "Constitution",
          "label": "LAW"
        },
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Amendment - Wijetasa Rajapaksa",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The 22nd Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gazette",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "a couple of days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijetasa Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 21st Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Government Information Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd Amendment to the Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The 22nd Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gazette",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Gazette 7 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The 21st Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United People's Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 22nd Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 22nd Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 21st Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 21st Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 21st Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United People's Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "22 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය ළඟදීම පාර්ලිමේන්තුව 21 වැනි සංශෝධනය ලෙස නම් කරනවා - විජේතාසා රාජපක්ෂ",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "22 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය තව දින දෙකකින් ගැසට් මගින් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කෙරෙන අතර ඉන් නොබෝ වේලාවකින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිතය. අධිකරණ, බන්ධනාගාර කටයුතු සහ ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ අමාත්‍ය විජේතාස රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පැවසුවේ එය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමෙන් පසු එය 21 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය ලෙස නම් කරන බවයි.",
        "ඒ මහතා මේ බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේ අඟහරුවාදා (28) රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ පැවැති ප්‍රවෘත්ති සාකච්ඡාවකදීය.",
        "ජනතාව සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාව අපේක්ෂා කළ පරිදි රටේ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය ශක්තිමත් කිරීම සහ නීතියේ ආධිපත්‍යය තහවුරු කිරීම සඳහා ප්‍රධාන කොන්දේසියක් වන 22 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනයට කැබිනට් අනුමැතිය හිමි විය.",
        "අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය විසින් අනුමත කරන ලද 22 වන ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය ගැසට් මගින් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර නුදුරේදීම පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිතයි. පනත් කෙටුම්පත පාර්ලිමේන්තු න්‍යාය පත්‍රයට ඇතුළත් කර දින 7කට පසු ගැසට් මගින් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කෙරෙන අතර ඉන් අනතුරුව ඉදිරි පියවර ගැනීමට නියමිතය.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධන සංඛ්‍යාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජනතාව අතර ඇත්තේ අපැහැදිලි තත්ත්වයක්. 21 වැනි සංශෝධනය එක්සත් ජනතා බලවේගය විසින් ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලද සංශෝධනයකි.",
        "එය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමේ දුෂ්කරතා හේතුවෙන් රජය විසින් ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනයක් ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇත. ඒකයි අපි මේක 22 වැනි සංශෝධනය ලෙස සලකන්නේ.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 22 වැනි සංශෝධනය රජය විසින් ඉදිරිපත් කළ නිසා මම යෝජනා කළ සංශෝධනය ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගත්තා.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, මේ වන විට අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලයේ අනුමැතියට ලක්ව ඇති එම සංශෝධනය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමෙන් පසු 21 වැනි සංශෝධනය ලෙස නම් කෙරෙනු ඇත. 22 වැනි සංශෝධනය පිළිබඳ පළමු විවාදය ආරම්භ වන විට එය 21 වැනි සංශෝධනය ලෙස හඳුන්වනු ලැබේ.",
        "එක්සත් ජනතා බලවේගය විසින් ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති 21 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය ක්‍රියාත්මක කළ නොහැකි බව මම විශ්වාස කරමි.",
        "එහි සෑම නූලක්ම නීතිගත කිරීමට ජනමත විචාරණයක් අවශ්‍ය බවට ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය තීන්දු කර ඇති බවද අමාත්‍යවරයා පෙන්වා දුන්නේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
          "label": "LAW"
        },
        {
          "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
          "label": "LAW"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "සංශෝධනය - විජේතාස රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගැසට්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජේතාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගැසට්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගැසට් පත්‍රය දින 7 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනතා බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනතා බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "22 ஆவது அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தம் விரைவில் பாராளுமன்றிற்கு அதன் பின் 21 ஆவது திருத்தம் என பெயர் மாற்றப்படும் - விஜேதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் 22 ஆவது திருத்தம் ஓரிரு தினங்களில் வர்த்தமானி அறிவித்தலில் வெளியிடப்பட்டு , அதனைத் தொடர்ந்து பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படும். பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பித்தன் பின்னர் இத் திருத்தமானது அரசியலமைப்பின் 21 ஆவது திருத்தமாக பெயர் மாற்றப்படும் என்று நீதி, சிறைச்சாலைகள் விவகாரங்கள் மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு மறுசீரமைப்பு அமைச்சர் விஜேதாச ராஜபக்ஷ தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களத்தில் 28 ஆம் திகதி செவ்வாய்கிழமை இடம்பெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் மாநாட்டில் இதனைத் தெரிவித்த அவர் மேலும் குறிப்பிடுகையில் ,",
        "மக்களும் சர்வதேச சமூகமும் எதிர்பார்த்ததைப்  போன்று நாட்டில் ஜனநாயகத்தை வலுப்படுத்துவதற்கும் சட்டத்தின் ஆட்சியை நிலைநிறுத்துவதற்கும் முக்கிய நிபந்தனையான அரசியலமைப்பின் 22 ஆவது திருத்தத்திற்கு அமைச்சரவை அங்கீகாரம் வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "அமைச்சரவை அனுமதி கிடைக்கப் பெற்றுள்ள 22 ஆவது அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தம் வர்த்தமானி அறிவித்தல் ஊடாக வெளியிடப்படுவதோடு, விரைவில் பாராளுமன்றத்திலும் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படும். குறித்த சட்ட மூலம் வர்த்தமானியில் வெளியிடப்பட்டு 7 நாட்களின் பின்னர் பாராளுமன்ற நிகழ்ச்சி நிரலுக்குள் உள்ளடக்கப்பட்டு அதன் பின்னர் அடுத்த கட்ட நடவடிக்கைகள் எடுக்கப்படும்.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தத்தின் இலக்கம் தொடர்பில் மக்கள் மத்தியில் தெளிவற்ற நிலைமையொன்று காணப்படுகிறது. ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தி சமர்ப்பித்துள்ள திருத்தமே 21 ஆவது திருத்தம் ஆகும்.",
        "அதனை நடைமுறைப்படுத்துவதில் சிக்கல் காணப்படுகின்றமையால் அரசாங்கத்தினால் அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தமொன்று சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. எனவே தான் இதனை 22 ஆவது திருத்தமாகக் கருதுகின்றோம்.",
        "அரசாங்கத்தினால் 22 ஆவது அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தம் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டமையினால் , என்னால் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட திருத்தத்தை வாபஸ் பெற்றுக் கொண்டேன்.",
        "எவ்வாறிருப்பினும் தற்போது அமைச்சரவை அனுமதி பெற்றுக் கொள்ளப்பட்ட திருத்தம் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டதன் பின்னர் 21 ஆவது திருத்தம் என்று பெயர் மாற்றப்படும். அதற்கமைய 22 ஆவது திருத்தம் தொடர்பான முதலாவது விவாதம் ஆரம்பிக்கும் போது , அது 21 ஆவது திருத்தமாகவே குறிப்பிடப்படும்.",
        "ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தியினால் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட அரசியலமைப்பின் 21 ஆவது திருத்தம் நடைமுறைப்படுத்த முடியாதது என நான் நம்புகின்றேன்.",
        "அதில் உள்ள ஒவ்வொரு சரத்தையும் சட்டமாக்குவதற்கு சர்வஜன வாக்கெடுப்பு அவசியம் என உச்ச நீதிமன்றம் தீர்ப்பளித்துள்ளதாகவும் அமைச்சர் சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22வது திருத்தம்",
          "label": "LAW"
        },
        {
          "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
          "label": "LAW"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "திருத்தம் - விஜேதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "22வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசிதழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓரிரு நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜேதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "21வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பின் 22வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசிதழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வர்த்தமானி 7 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "21வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}