{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/31/thundershowers-expected-today-31/",
  "time_ut": 1661917740,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Thundershowers expected today (31)",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Thundershowers expected today (31)",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Department of Meteorology says that there is a low-level atmospheric disturbance in the vicinity of Sri Lanka. Therefore, cloudy skies will prevail over the southern half of the island.",
        "Showers or thundershowers will occur at times over most parts of the island.",
        "Very heavy showers above 150mm may occur at some places in the Western, Southern, Sabaragamuwa, Central, and Uva provinces. Heavy showers of about 100mm can occur at some places elsewhere.",
        "The general public is kindly requested to take adequate precautions to minimize damages caused by temporary localized strong winds and lightning during thundershowers.",
        "On the apparent southward relative motion of the sun, it is going to be directly over the latitudes of Sri Lanka until the 07th of September in this year.",
        "The nearest towns of Sri Lanka over which the sun is overhead today (31) are Kappachchi (Vavuniya District), Tammannekulama (Anuradhapura District), and Uppuveli (Trincomalee District) about 12.10 noon.",
        "Distribution & Sales: CAA imposes strict conditions on series of goods"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "half",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "150mm",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 07th of September",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kappachchi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tammannekulama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura District",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uppuveli",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 12.10 noon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අද (31) ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ආසන්නයේ පහළ වායුගෝලයේ කැළඹීමක් පවතින බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි. එබැවින් දිවයිනේ දකුණු අර්ධය පුරා අහස වළාකුලින් බරව පවතිනු ඇත.",
        "දිවයිනේ බොහෝ ප්‍රදේශවල විටින් විට වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇති වේ.",
        "බස්නාහිර, දකුණ, සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම සහ ඌව පළාත්වල ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලිමීටර් 150 ට වැඩි ඉතා තද වැසි ඇති විය හැක. සෙසු ප්‍රදේශවල ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලිමීටර් 100ක පමණ තද වැසි ඇති විය හැක.",
        "ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇති වන විට එම ප්‍රදේශවල තාවකාලික තද සුළං සහ අකුණු මඟින් සිදුවන අනතුරු අවම කර ගැනීමට ප්‍රමාණවත් පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස සාමාන්‍ය ජනතාවගෙන් කාරුණිකව ඉල්ලා සිටියි.",
        "සූර්යයාගේ දෘශ්‍ය ලෙස දකුණට සාපේක්ෂ චලිතය මත, එය මේ වසරේ සැප්තැම්බර් 07 වැනිදා දක්වා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අක්ෂාංශවලට සෘජුවම ඉහළින් පවතී.",
        "අද (31) හිරු මුදුන්ව පවතින ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආසන්නතම නගර වන්නේ කප්පච්චි (වවුනියා දිස්ත්‍රික්කය), තම්මැන්නකුලම (අනුරාධපුර දිස්ත්‍රික්කය) සහ උප්පුවේලි (ත්‍රිකුණාමලය දිස්ත්‍රික්කය) දහවල් 12.10 ට පමණ ය.",
        "බෙදා හැරීම සහ විකුණුම්: CAA විසින් භාණ්ඩ මාලාවක් සඳහා දැඩි කොන්දේසි පනවයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඩක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "150 මි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 07 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කප්පච්චි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තම්මැන්නකුලම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උප්පුවේලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල් 12.10ට පමණ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இன்று (31) இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கையை அண்மித்த பகுதிகளில் குறைந்த வளிமண்டல குழப்பம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. எனவே, தீவின் தெற்குப் பகுதியில் வானம் மேகமூட்டத்துடன் காணப்படும்.",
        "தீவின் பெரும்பாலான பகுதிகளில் அவ்வப்போது மழை அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை பெய்யும்.",
        "மேல், தெற்கு, சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய மற்றும் ஊவா மாகாணங்களில் சில இடங்களில் 150 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான கடும் மழை பெய்யக்கூடும். மற்ற இடங்களில் சில இடங்களில் சுமார் 100மிமீ அளவில் கனமழை பெய்யலாம்.",
        "இடியுடன் கூடிய மழையின் போது தற்காலிகமாக பலத்த காற்று மற்றும் மின்னல் தாக்கங்களினால் ஏற்படக்கூடிய பாதிப்புகளை குறைத்துக்கொள்ள போதிய முன்னெச்சரிக்கை நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுக்குமாறு பொதுமக்கள் அன்புடன் கேட்டுக்கொள்ளப்படுகிறார்கள்.",
        "சூரியனின் தெற்கு நோக்கிய ஒப்பீட்டு இயக்கத்தில், அது இந்த ஆண்டு செப்டம்பர் 07 ஆம் தேதி வரை இலங்கையின் அட்சரேகைகளுக்கு நேராக இருக்கும்.",
        "இன்று (31) கப்பச்சி (வவுனியா மாவட்டம்), தம்மன்னேகுளம் (அநுராதபுரம் மாவட்டம்), உப்புவெளி (திருகோணமலை மாவட்டம்) ஆகியவை நண்பகல் 12.10 மணியளவில் சூரியன் மேல்நோக்கி நிற்கும் இலங்கையின் அருகிலுள்ள நகரங்களாகும்.",
        "விநியோகம் மற்றும் விற்பனை: தொடர் சரக்குகளுக்கு CAA கடுமையான நிபந்தனைகளை விதிக்கிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதி",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "150மிமீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 07 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கப்பாச்சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மன்னேகுலம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம் மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உப்புவெளி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 12.10 மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}