{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට-අලුත්-කමිටු-තුනක්/101-618682",
  "time_ut": 1661335755,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට අලුත් කමිටු තුනක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Three new committees for Parliament",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Speaker of the House Minister Susil Prema Jayanta informed the parliamentary party leaders today (24) that three more parliamentary standing committees are expected to be established based on the president's proposal.",
        "The leader of the House also stated that the sectoral monitoring committees to add amendments to the parliamentary standing orders will be set up promptly.",
        "The Committee on Parliamentary Affairs was held yesterday (24) morning at the Parliament complex under the chairmanship of Deputy Speaker Mr. Ajith Rajapakse.",
        "The President, as the Minister of Finance, has decided to present the opening speech (budget speech) of the second reading of the Appropriation (Amendment) Bill to Parliament on the 30th.",
        "Meanwhile, the adjournment debate on the electricity bill increase will be held on the 29th",
        "The Committee on Parliamentary Affairs also decided to hold the second reading debate on the Appropriation Bill on the 30th, 31st, 1st and 2nd of September.",
        "Also, three decrees under the Foreign Exchange Act, one resolution under the Customs Ordinance Act and two provisions under the Special Merchandise Tax Act are to be approved on the same day."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Susil Prema Jayanta",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Committee on Parliamentary Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24) morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Rajapakse",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Appropriation (Amendment) Bill",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 30th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Committee on Parliamentary Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Appropriation Bill",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 30th, 31st, 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2nd of September",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Foreign Exchange Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Customs Ordinance Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Special Merchandise Tax Act",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the same day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට අලුත් කමිටු තුනක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා ගේ යෝජනාවක් අනුව තවත් පාර්ලිමේන්තු ස්ථාවර කාරක සභා තුනක් පිහිටුවීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන බව සභානායක අමාත්‍ය සුසිල් ප්‍රේම ජයන්ත මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තු පක්ෂ නායකයන්ට අද (24)  දැනුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු ස්ථාවර නියෝග වලට සංශෝධන එක්කර ගැනීමේ ආංශික අධීක්ෂණ කාරක සභා කඩිනමින් පිහිටුවීමට කටයුතු කරගෙන යන බවද සභා නායකවරයා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව නියෝජ්‍ය කතානායක අජිත් රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණයේදී ඊයේ(24) පෙරවරුවේ පැවැත්විණ.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා, මුදල් අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස විසර්ජන (සංශෝධන) පනත් කෙටුම්පත දෙවනවර කියවීමේ සමාරම්භක කථාව ( අයවැය කතාව) පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ලබන 30 වෙනිදා  ඉදිරිපත්  කිරීමට තීරණය කර ඇත.",
        "මේ අතර විදුලි බිල වැඩි කිරීම පිළිබඳ  සභාව කල්තැබීමේ විවාදය ලබන 29 වෙනිදා පැවැත්වෙනු ඇත",
        "විසර්ජන පනත් කෙටුම්පත පිළිබඳ දෙවැනි වර කියවීමේ විවාදය ලබන30 වැනි දා,31 වැනි දා ,සැප්තැම්බර පළවෙනිදා සහ දෙවැනි දා පැවැත්වීමටද පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව තීරණය කළේය.",
        "තවද විදේශ විනිමය පනත යටතේ නියෝග තුනක්, රේගු ආඥා පනත යටතේ යෝජනා සම්මතයක් සහ ‍විශේෂ වෙළද භාණ්ඩ බදු පනත යටතේ නියමයන් දෙකක්ද එදින ම අනුමත කර ගැනීමට නියමිතය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුසිල් ප්‍රේම ජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24) උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විසර්ජන (සංශෝධන) පනත් කෙටුම්පත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විසර්ජන පනත් කෙටුම්පත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "30, 31, 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 2 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ විනිමය පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රේගු ආඥා පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශේෂ වෙළඳ භාණ්ඩ බදු පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එදිනම",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு மூன்று புதிய குழுக்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் பிரேரணையின் அடிப்படையில் மேலும் மூன்று நாடாளுமன்ற நிலைக்குழுக்கள் அமைக்கப்பட உள்ளதாக சபாநாயகர் அமைச்சர் சுசில் பிரேம ஜயந்த இன்று (24) பாராளுமன்ற கட்சித் தலைவர்களுக்கு அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "நாடாளுமன்ற நிலையியற் கட்டளைகளில் திருத்தங்களைச் சேர்ப்பதற்கான துறைசார் கண்காணிப்புக் குழுக்கள் உடனடியாக அமைக்கப்படும் என்றும் அவைத் தலைவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற விவகாரங்களுக்கான குழு நேற்று (24) காலை பாராளுமன்ற வளாகத்தில் பிரதி சபாநாயகர் திரு அஜித் ராஜபக்ஷ தலைமையில் நடைபெற்றது.",
        "நிதியமைச்சர் என்ற வகையில், ஒதுக்கீட்டு (திருத்தச்) சட்டமூலத்தின் இரண்டாம் வாசிப்பின் ஆரம்ப உரையை (பட்ஜெட் உரை) எதிர்வரும் 30ஆம் திகதி பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்க ஜனாதிபதி தீர்மானித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, மின் கட்டண அதிகரிப்பு தொடர்பான ஒத்திவைப்பு வேளை விவாதம் எதிர்வரும் 29ஆம் திகதி நடைபெறவுள்ளது",
        "ஒதுக்கீட்டுச் சட்டமூலம் மீதான இரண்டாம் வாசிப்பு விவாதத்தை எதிர்வரும் 30, 31, செப்டெம்பர் 1 மற்றும் 2ஆம் திகதிகளில் நடத்துவதற்கும் நாடாளுமன்ற விவகாரங்களுக்கான குழு தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "மேலும், அன்னியச் செலாவணிச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் மூன்று ஆணைகளும், சுங்கச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் ஒரு தீர்மானமும், சிறப்பு வணிக வரிச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் இரண்டு விதிகளும் ஒரே நாளில் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட உள்ளன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுசில் பிரேம ஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாடாளுமன்ற விவகாரங்களுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24) காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒதுக்கீடு (திருத்தம்) மசோதா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாடாளுமன்ற விவகாரங்களுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒதுக்கீட்டு மசோதா",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "30, 31, 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 2 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்நிய செலாவணி சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுங்க கட்டளை சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறப்பு வணிக வரி சட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதே நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}