{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83496/rakna-arakshaka-lanka-among-3-institutions-brought-under-investment-promotion-ministry",
  "time_ut": 1657213320,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Rakna Arakshaka Lanka among 3 institutions brought under Investment Promotion Ministry",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Rakna Arakshaka Lanka among 3 institutions brought under Investment Promotion Ministry",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has issued a Gazette Extraordinary bringing three institutions including Rakna Arakshaka Lanka Limited (RALL) under the purview of the Ministry of Investment Promotion.",
        "The other two institutions brought under the said ministry are Selendiva Investments Limited and Hotel Developers (Lanka) Pvt Limited.",
        "Rakna Arakshaka Lanka was previously under the purview of the Ministry of Defence while Selendiva Investments Ltd. and Hotel Developers (Lanka) Pvt Ltd. came under the Ministry of Urban Development and Housing.",
        "Newly-appointed Member of Parliament Dhammika Perera currently serves as the Minister of Investment Promotion."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Rakna Arakshaka Lanka",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Investment Promotion Ministry",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rakna Arakshaka Lanka Limited",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Investment Promotion",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Selendiva Investments Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rakna Arakshaka Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Defence while",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Selendiva Investments Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Urban Development and Housing",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන අමාත්‍යාංශය යටතට ගෙන එන ආයතන 3ක් අතරට රක්නා ආරක්ෂක ලංකා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රක්නා ආරක්ෂක ලංකා ලිමිටඩ් (RALL) ඇතුළු ආයතන තුනක් ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන අමාත්‍යාංශය යටතට පත් කරමින් ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා අතිවිශේෂ ගැසට් නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කර තිබේ.",
        "ඉහත අමාත්‍යාංශය යටතට ගෙන ඇති අනෙකුත් ආයතන දෙක වන්නේ Selendiva Investments Limited සහ Hotel Developers (Lanka) Pvt Limited ය.",
        "Rakna Arakshaka Lanka මීට පෙර ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය යටතේ පැවති අතර Selendiva Investments Ltd සහ Hotel Developers (Lanka) Pvt Ltd නාගරික සංවර්ධන හා නිවාස අමාත්‍යාංශය යටතට පත් විය.",
        "අලුතින් පත් වූ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධම්මික පෙරේරා මහතා දැනට ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රක්නා ආරක්ෂක ලංකා",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන අමාත්‍යාංශය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත රක්නා ආරක්ෂක ලංකා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Selendiva Investments Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රක්නා ආරක්ෂක ලංකා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ අතරතුර ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Selendiva Investments Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාගරික සංවර්ධන හා නිවාස අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு அமைச்சின் கீழ் கொண்டுவரப்பட்ட 3 நிறுவனங்களில் ரக்னா பாதுகாப்பு லங்கா",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "Rakna Arakshaka Lanka Limited (RALL) உட்பட மூன்று நிறுவனங்களை முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு அமைச்சின் கீழ் கொண்டுவருவதற்கான அதிவிசேட வர்த்தமானியை ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ வெளியிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "மேற்படி அமைச்சின் கீழ் கொண்டுவரப்பட்ட ஏனைய இரண்டு நிறுவனங்கள் Selendiva Investments Limited மற்றும் Hotel Developers (Lanka) Pvt Limited ஆகும்.",
        "Rakna Arakshaka Lanka முன்னர் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சின் கீழ் இருந்தது, Selendiva Investments Ltd மற்றும் Hotel Developers (Lanka) Pvt Ltd ஆகியவை நகர அபிவிருத்தி மற்றும் வீடமைப்பு அமைச்சின் கீழ் வந்தன.",
        "புதிதாக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் தம்மிக்க பெரேரா தற்போது முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு அமைச்சராக கடமையாற்றுகின்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரக்னா பாதுகாப்பு லங்கா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "முதலீட்டு மேம்பாட்டு அமைச்சகம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரக்னா பாதுகாப்பு லங்கா லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "செலண்டிவா இன்வெஸ்ட்மென்ட்ஸ் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரக்னா பாதுகாப்பு லங்கா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம் போது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செலண்டிவா இன்வெஸ்ட்மென்ட்ஸ் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நகர்ப்புற வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் வீட்டுவசதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}