{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84662/ice-worth-nearly-rs-150-million-seized-in-mannar",
  "time_ut": 1661933940,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "‘Ice’ worth nearly Rs. 150 million seized in Mannar",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "‘Ice’ worth nearly Rs. 150 million seized in Mannar",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Two persons who were transporting about 10kg and 400g of crystal methamphetamine (‘Ice’) in Mannar area have been apprehended by Sri Lanka Army today (Aug 31).",
        "The suspects and the contraband were taken into custody during a search at an army roadblock en route to Vankalai from Talaimannar.",
        "It is reported that the apprehended drugs are worth approximately Rs. 150 million.",
        "The suspects are found to be the residents of Mannar and Talaimannar areas, aged 32 and 34 years.",
        "The suspects and the seized items have been handed over to the Mannar police by SL Army.",
        "The police will seek detention orders on the arrestees after producing them before the Mannar Magistrate’s Court later today."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "150 million",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mannar",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10kg and",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "400",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "(‘Ice’",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vankalai",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Talaimannar",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "150 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Talaimannar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "32 and 34 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "SL Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Mannar Magistrate’s Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රුපියල් කෝටියකට ආසන්න වටිනාකමකින් යුත් ‘අයිස්’ මන්නාරමේදී කෝටි 15ක් අල්ලයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මන්නාරම ප්‍රදේශයේදී ක්‍රිස්ටල් මෙතම්ෆෙටමින් (‘අයිස්’) කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 10 යි ග්‍රෑම් 400 ක් පමණ ප්‍රවාහනය කරමින් සිටි පුද්ගලයින් දෙදෙනෙකු අද (අගෝස්තු 31) ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුධ හමුදාව විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "තලෙයිමන්නාරමේ සිට වන්කාලෙයි දක්වා ගමන් කරමින් තිබූ යුද හමුදා මාර්ග බාධකයක් පරීක්ෂා කිරීමේදී සැකකරුවන් සහ නීති විරෝධී භාණ්ඩ තොගය අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය තොගයේ වටිනාකම රුපියල් කෝටි 100කට ආසන්න බව වාර්තා වේ. මිලියන 150 කි.",
        "සැකකරුවන් මන්නාරම සහ තලෙයිමන්නාරම ප්‍රදේශවල පදිංචි අවුරුදු 32 සහ 34 යන වයස්වල පසුවන්නන් බව අනාවරණය වී ඇත.",
        "සැකකරුවන් සහ අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් භාණ්ඩ ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුධ හමුදාව විසින් මන්නාරම පොලිසිය වෙත භාරදී ඇත.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරුවන් මන්නාරම මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයට අද ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමෙන් පසු රැඳවුම් නියෝග ලබා ගැනීමට පොලිසිය කටයුතු කරනවා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මිලියන 150 කි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "මන්නාරම",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10kg සහ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "400",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "('අයිස්'",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුද හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වංකලයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලෙයිමන්නාරම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 150 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලෙයිමන්නාරම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 32 සහ 34",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුද හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "‘ஐஸ்’ கிட்டத்தட்ட ரூ. மன்னாரில் 150 மில்லியன் கைப்பற்றப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மன்னார் பகுதியில் சுமார் 10 கிலோ 400 கிராம் கிரிஸ்டல் மெத்தம்பெட்டமைன் (‘ஐஸ்’) கடத்திச் சென்ற இருவர் சிறிலங்கா இராணுவத்தினரால் இன்று (ஆகஸ்ட் 31) கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "தலைமன்னாரிலிருந்து வான்கலை நோக்கிச் செல்லும் இராணுவ வீதித் தடையொன்றில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட தேடுதலின் போதே சந்தேகநபர்களும் கடத்தப்பட்ட பொருட்களும் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட போதைப்பொருட்களின் பெறுமதி சுமார் ரூ. 150 மில்லியன்.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்கள் 32 மற்றும் 34 வயதுடைய மன்னார் மற்றும் தலைமன்னார் பிரதேசங்களை சேர்ந்தவர்கள் என தெரியவந்துள்ளது.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்களும் கைப்பற்றப்பட்ட பொருட்களும் இலங்கை இராணுவத்தினரால் மன்னார் பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர்களை இன்று பிற்பகல் மன்னார் நீதவான் நீதிமன்றில் ஆஜர்படுத்தியதன் பின்னர் அவர்களை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்குமாறு பொலிஸார் கோரவுள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "150 மில்லியன்",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "மன்னார்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 கிலோ மற்றும்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "400",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "(‘பனி’",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாங்கலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமன்னார்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "150 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமன்னார்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "32 மற்றும் 34 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "SL இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மன்னார் நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}