{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132313",
  "time_ut": 1658853068,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "உயிர்த்த ஞாயிறு தின தாக்குதல்கள் : ரணிலின் விடுபாட்டுரிமைக்கு மைத்திரி கடும் ஆட்சேபனை",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Resurrection Sunday attacks: Maithiri strongly objects to Ranil's right to leave",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former President Maithripala Sirisena's party has raised strong objections to remove President Ranil Wickremesinghe from the defendant list using his constitutional leave of absence in the 12 fundamental rights violation petitions filed claiming that his fundamental rights were violated by failing to prevent the 21/4 Resurrection Sunday terrorist attacks despite sufficient intelligence information. .",
        "These fundamental rights violation petitions were heard by Chief Justice Jayantha Jayasuriya, Justices Bhuvanega Aluvihara, L.T.P.Tehithenia, Murtu Fernando, S. Durairaja, A.H.M.D. Nawaz and Shiran Gunaratna were taken up for questioning today (26) before a seven-member panel of judges. At the same time, President's lawyer Faiser Mustapha, who appeared in the forum on behalf of former President Maithripala Sirisena, raised this objection.",
        "When the case came up for hearing today, a fundamental objection was raised by senior counsel Suren Fernando on behalf of one of the defendants, former Prime Minister and today's President Ranil Wickremesinghe. It was pointed out by lawyer Suresh Fernando that as the recipient of his service is currently sworn in as the President, no case can be filed against him as per Article 35 of the Constitution, which is his constitutional right to leave.",
        "Another defendant, former President Maithripala Sirisena's lawyer, President's lawyer Baisar Mustafa, and many other parties raised strong objections.",
        "In this situation, the hearings on the petitions were adjourned till tomorrow (27) to present the objections of other parties centered on the basic objection put forward on behalf of President Ranil Wickremesinghe. Tomorrow, the objections regarding President Ranil's right to leave will be placed before the council.",
        "12 parties including Nandana Sirimanna, a father who lost his two children in the 21/4 suicide bombing, Janaka Vidhanake, a tourism businessman, two Catholic priests, Mothitha Ekanayake, a lawyer caught in the bomb attack at Shangrilla Hotel, Catholic religious leaders, and the Lawyers Association of Sri Lanka have filed these fundamental rights violation petitions.",
        "The defendants are former President Maithripala Sirisena, former Prime Minister and current President Ranil Wickremesinghe, the then Cabinet, former Defense Secretary Hemasiri, Inspector General of Police Pujith, Senior Deputy Inspector General of Police Nilantha Jayawardena who was the Director of the National Intelligence Service, Sisira Mendis who was the Chief of the National Intelligence Service, and Legal It is noteworthy that the Chancellor and others have been named."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sunday",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "21/4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayantha Jayasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bhuvanega Aluvihara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "L.T.P.Tehithenia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Murtu Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. Durairaja",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shiran Gunaratna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Faiser Mustapha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suren Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suresh Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 35 of the Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Baisar Mustafa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandana Sirimanna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "21/4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janaka Vidhanake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Catholic",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mothitha Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shangrilla Hotel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Catholic",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Lawyers Association of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defense",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hemasiri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Inspector General of Police Pujith",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nilantha Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Intelligence Service",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sisira Mendis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Intelligence Service",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Resurrection Sunday attacks: රනිල්ට ඉවත්වීමට ඇති අයිතියට මෛත්‍රී දැඩි විරෝධය",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "21/4 උත්ථාන ඉරිදා ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැලැක්වීමට අපොහොසත් වීමෙන් ඔහුගේ මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් කඩ වූ බවට ගොනු කර ඇති මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් කඩවීම් පෙත්සම් 12 න් ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත නිවාඩු යොදා ගනිමින් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විත්තිකරු ලැයිස්තුවෙන් ඉවත් කිරීමට හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතාගේ පාර්ශ්වයෙන් දැඩි විරෝධයක් එල්ල වී තිබේ. ප්‍රමාණවත් බුද්ධි තොරතුරු තිබියදීත් ප්‍රහාර..",
        "මෙම මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් උල්ලංඝන පෙත්සම් අගවිනිසුරු ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය, විනිසුරුවරුන් වන බුවනේග අලුවිහාර, එල්.ටී.පී.තෙහිතේනියා, මුර්තු ප්‍රනාන්දු, එස්. දුරෙයිරාජා, ඒ.එච්.එම්.ඩී. නවාස් සහ ශිරාන් ගුණරත්න සත් පුද්ගල විනිසුරු මඩුල්ලක් හමුවේ අද (26) ප්‍රශ්න කිරීම සඳහා කැඳවනු ලැබුවා. ඒ සමගම හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා වෙනුවෙන් එම සංසදයේ පෙනී සිටි ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ ෆයිසර් මුස්තාපා මහතා මෙම විරෝධය මතු කළේය.",
        "මෙම නඩුව අද විභාගයට ගත් අවස්ථාවේදී විත්තිකරුවන්ගෙන් එක් අයෙකු වන හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය සහ වත්මන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ වෙනුවෙන් ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නීතීඥ සුරේන් ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා මූලික විරෝධතාවක් ඉදිරිපත් කළා. නීතීඥ සුරේෂ් ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා පෙන්වා දුන්නේ තම සේවයේ ලාභියා මේ වන විට ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දී ඇති බැවින් ඔහුට පිටව යාමට ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත අයිතිය වන ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 35 වැනි වගන්තිය ප්‍රකාරව ඔහුට එරෙහිව නඩු පැවරිය නොහැකි බවයි.",
        "තවත් විත්තිකරුවෙකු වන හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතාගේ නීතීඥ, ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ බයිසාර් මුස්තාෆා ඇතුළු පාර්ශව රැසක් ඊට දැඩි විරෝධය පළ කළා.",
        "මෙම තත්ත්වය තුළ ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වෙනුවෙන් ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති මූලික විරෝධතාවය කේන්ද්‍ර කර ගනිමින් සෙසු පාර්ශ්වවල විරෝධතා ඉදිරිපත් කිරීම සඳහා පෙත්සම් විභාගය හෙට (27) දක්වා කල් තැබිණි. ජනාධිපති රනිල්ට පිටව යාමට ඇති අයිතිය පිළිබඳ විරෝධතා හෙට සභාවට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "21/4 මරාගෙන මැරෙන බෝම්බ ප්‍රහාරයෙන් දරු දෙදෙනා අහිමි වූ පියකු වන නන්දන සිරිමාන්න, සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරික ජනක විදානක, කතෝලික පූජකවරුන් දෙදෙනකු, ෂැන්ග්‍රිල්ලා හෝටලයේ බෝම්බ ප්‍රහාරයට හසුවූ නීතිඥ මෝතිත ඒකනායක ඇතුළු පාර්ශව 12ක්, කතෝලික ආගමික නායකයන්, සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතීඥ සංගමය විසින් මෙම මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් කඩකිරීමේ පෙත්සම් ගොනු කර ඇත.",
        "විත්තිකරුවන් වන්නේ හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන, හිටපු අගමැති සහ වත්මන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, එවකට කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය, හිටපු ආරක්ෂක ලේකම් හේමසිරි, පොලිස්පති පූජිත්, ජාතික බුද්ධි සේවයේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ලෙස කටයුතු කළ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති නිලන්ත ජයවර්ධන, ජාතික බුද්ධි සේවයේ ප්‍රධානියා ලෙස කටයුතු කළ සිසිර මෙන්ඩිස් සහ නීති කුලපතිවරයා ඇතුළු පිරිසක් නම් කර තිබීම විශේෂත්වයකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉරිදා",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "21/4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුවනේග අලුවිහාරය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "L.T.P.Tehithenia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුර්තු ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.දුරෙයිරාජා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශිරාන් ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆයිසර් මුස්තාපා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුරේන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුරේෂ් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාවේ 35 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බයිසර් මුස්තාෆා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දන සිරිමාන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "21/4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජානක විදානක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කතෝලික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෝතිතා ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂැන්ග්‍රිල්ලා හෝටලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කතෝලික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හේමසිරි ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති පූජිත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිලන්ත ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික බුද්ධි සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිසිර මෙන්ඩිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික බුද්ධි සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "உயிர்த்த ஞாயிறு தின தாக்குதல்கள் : ரணிலின் விடுபாட்டுரிமைக்கு மைத்திரி கடும் ஆட்சேபனை",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "போதுமான உளவுத் தகவல்கள் இருந்தும் 21/4 உயிர்த்த ஞாயிறு தின பயங்கரவாத தாக்குதல்களை  தடுக்க   தவறியதன் ஊடாக, தமது அடிப்படை உரிமைகள் மீறப்பட்டுள்ளதாக  கூறி தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ள 12 அடிப்படை உரிமை மீறல் மனுக்களில், ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை அரசியலமைப்பூடாக அவருக்கு கிடைக்கப் பெற்றுள்ள விடுபாட்டுரிமையை பயன்படுத்தி  பிரதிவாதி பட்டியலிலிருந்து நீக்க, முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன தரப்பினர் கடும் ஆட்சேபனைகளை முன்வைத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்த அடிப்படை உரிமை மீறல் மனுக்கள்  பிரதம நீதியரசர் ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய,  நீதியரசர்களான புவனேக அலுவிஹார, எல்.டி.பி.தெஹிதெனிய,  முர்து பெர்ணான்டோ, எஸ். துரைராஜா, ஏ.எச்.எம்.டி. நவாஸ், ஷிரான் குணரத்ன  ஆகியோர் அடங்கிய ஏழு பேர் கொண்ட நீதியரசர்கள் குழாம் முன் இன்று ( 26) விசாரணைக்கு  எடுத்துக்கொள்ளப்பட்டது. இதன்போதே  முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன சார்பில் மன்றில் ஆஜரான ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி பைசர் முஸ்தபா இந்த ஆட்சேபனையை முன் வைத்தார்.",
        "இன்றைய தினம் இவ்வழக்கு விசாரணைக்கு வந்த போது,  பிரதிவாதிகளில் ஒருவரான முன்னாள் பிரதமரும் இந் நாள் ஜனாதிபதியுமான  ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க சார்பில் சிரேஷ்ட சட்டத்தரணி சுரேன் பெர்ணான்டோவினால் அடிப்படை ஆட்சேபனை ஒன்று முன் வைக்கப்பட்டது. தனது சேவை பெறுநர் தற்போது ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியேற்றுள்ள நிலையில், அரசியலமைப்பின் 35 ஆவது உறுப்புரை பிரகாரம் அவருக்கு எதிராக எந்த வழக்கினையும் முன்னெடுத்து செல்ல முடியாது எனவும் , அது அவருக்கு அரசியலமைப்பூடாக வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ள விடுபாட்டுரிமை எனவும்  சட்டத்தரணி சுரேஷ் பெர்ணான்டோவினால் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டது.",
        "இதற்கு மற்றொரு பிரதிவாதியான முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேனவின் சட்டத்தரணி  ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி பைசர் முஸ்தபா உள்ளிட்ட பலர்  தரப்பினர் கடும் ஆட்சேபனைகளை முன் வைத்தனர்.",
        "இந் நிலையில்  ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க சார்பில் முன் வைக்கப்பட்ட அடிப்படை ஆட்சேபனத்தை மையப்படுத்திய ஏனைய தரப்பினரின் ஆட்சேபனைகளை முன் வைக்க, மனுக்கள் மீதான விசாரணைகள் நாளை ( 27) வரை ஒத்தி வைக்கப்பட்டது.  நாளைய தினம்   ஜனாதிபதி ரணிலின் விடுபாட்டுரிமை தொடர்பிலான ஆட்சேபனைகளை மன்றில் முன் வைக்கப்படவுள்ளன.",
        "21/4 தற்கொலை குண்டுத்தாக்குதலில் தனது இரு பிள்ளைகளை இழந்த தந்தையான நந்தன சிறிமான்ன,  சுற்றுலா துறை வர்த்தகர் ஜனக விதானகே, இரு கத்தோலிக்க மதகுருமார்,  ஷெங்ரில்லா ஹோட்டலில் குண்டுத் தாக்குதலில் சிக்கிய சட்டத்தரணி  மோதித்த ஏக்கநாயக்க, கத்தோலிக்க மதத் தலைவர்கள், இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்  உள்ளிட்ட 12 தரப்பினரால்  இந்த அடிப்படை உரிமை மீறல் மனுக்களை தாக்கல் செய்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இதில் பிரதிவாதிகள்  தரப்பினராக முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன, முன்னாள் பிரதமரும் தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதியுமான  ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க, அப்போதைய அமைச்சரவை, முன்னாள்  பாதுகாப்பு செயலர் ஹேமசிறி, பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் பூஜித், தேசிய உளவுச் சேவையின் பணிப்பாளராக இருந்த சிரேஷ்ட பிரதிப் பொலிஸ்மா அதிபர் நிலந்த ஜயவர்தன,  தேசிய உளவுச் சேவை பிரதானியாக இருந்த சிசிர மெண்டிஸ்,  மற்றும் சட்ட மா அதிபர் உள்ளிட்டோர் பெயரிடப்பட்டுள்ளமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "21/4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புவனேகா அலுவிஹார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்.டி.பி.தெஹிதெனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முர்து பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.துரைராஜா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷிரான் குணரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பைசர் முஸ்தபா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுரேன் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுரேஷ் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பின் பிரிவு 35",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பைசர் முஸ்தபா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தன சிறிமான்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "21/4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனக விதானகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தோலிக்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மோதித ஏகநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷங்ரில்லா ஹோட்டல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தோலிக்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹேமசிறி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் பூஜித்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலந்த ஜயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய புலனாய்வு சேவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிசிர மெண்டிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய புலனாய்வு சேவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}