{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/27/moragoda-meets-indian-petroleum-minister-for-urgent-energy-cooperation/",
  "time_ut": 1656337500,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Moragoda meets Indian Petroleum Minister for urgent energy cooperation",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Moragoda meets Indian Petroleum Minister for urgent energy cooperation",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): High Commissioner of Sri Lanka to India Milinda Moragoda met with the Minister of Petroleum & Natural Gas and Housing and Urban Affairs of India Shri Hardeep Singh Puri, on Monday (27) to discuss urgent matters pertaining to bilateral energy cooperation. The meeting was held at the Ministry of Housing & Urban Affairs in New Delhi.",
        "At the outset, High Commissioner Moragoda briefed Minister Puri on the acute challenges that Sri Lanka is currently facing with regard to the supply and distribution of petroleum products and the severe hardships that the people are undergoing.",
        "While thanking India for the assistance that was extended in the form of lines of credit to import fuel, the High Commissioner of Sri Lanka discussed with Minister Puri the possibility of securing petrol and diesel supplies that are required by Sri Lanka at present on an urgent basis. Minister Puri responded positively in this regard and assured the High Commissioner of all possible support to Sri Lanka at this critical juncture.",
        "The High Commissioner and the Minister also discussed modalities through which India and Sri Lanka could further expand cooperation in the petroleum sector to help overcome the immediate crisis and to ensure the energy security in Sri Lanka. In this context, High Commissioner Moragoda and Minister Puri discussed ways and means through which Sri Lanka could establish long-term ties in the petroleum, oil, gas and related logistics sectors.",
        "BREAKING: Only essential services to operate from midnight (27); CPC will only issue fuel for essential services",
        "Unbeaten knock by Chamari Athapaththu guides Sri Lanka to easy win against India Women"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Petroleum & Natural Gas and Housing and Urban Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singh Puri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Housing & Urban Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Moragoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moragoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chamari Athapaththu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හදිසි බලශක්ති සහයෝගීතාවයක් සඳහා මොරගොඩ ඉන්දීය ඛනිජ තෙල් අමාත්‍යවරයා හමුවෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): ද්විපාර්ශ්වික බලශක්ති සහයෝගීතාවයට අදාළ හදිසි කරුණු සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා ඉන්දියාවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් මිලින්ද මොරගොඩ සඳුදා (27) ඉන්දියාවේ ඛනිජ තෙල් හා ස්වභාවික ගෑස් සහ නිවාස හා නාගරික කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය ශ්‍රී හර්දීප් සිං පූරි හමුවිය. . නවදිල්ලි නුවර නිවාස හා නාගරික කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේදී මෙම හමුව පැවැත්විණි.",
        "ආරම්භයේදීම, මහ කොමසාරිස් මොරගොඩ, ඛනිජ තෙල් නිෂ්පාදන සැපයීම සහ බෙදා හැරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දැනට මුහුණ දී සිටින උග්‍ර අභියෝග සහ ජනතාව මුහුණ දෙන දැඩි දුෂ්කරතා පිළිබඳව අමාත්‍ය පූරිට විස්තර කළේය.",
        "ඉන්ධන ආනයනය කිරීමට ණය වශයෙන් ලබාදුන් සහයට ඉන්දියාවට ස්තූතිය පළ කරන අතරම, ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයා, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට දැනට අවශ්‍ය පෙට්‍රල් සහ ඩීසල් සැපයුම් කඩිනමින් ලබා ගැනීමේ හැකියාව පිළිබඳව අමාත්‍ය පූරි සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කළේය. . අමාත්‍ය පූරි මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් ධනාත්මකව ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වූ අතර මෙම තීරණාත්මක අවස්ථාවේ දී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබා දිය හැකි සෑම සහයෝගයක්ම මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයාට සහතික කළේය.",
        "ක්ෂනික අර්බුදයෙන් මිදීමට සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බලශක්ති සුරක්‍ෂිතතාවය සහතික කිරීමට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා ඉන්දියාව සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඛනිජ තෙල් ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ සහයෝගීතාව තවදුරටත් පුළුල් කළ හැකි ක්‍රමවේද පිළිබඳව ද මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයා සහ අමාත්‍යවරයා සාකච්ඡා කළහ. මෙම සන්දර්භය තුළ, මහ කොමසාරිස් මොරගොඩ සහ අමාත්‍ය පූරි, ඛනිජ තෙල්, තෙල්, ගෑස් සහ ඒ ආශ්‍රිත සැපයුම් ක්ෂේත්‍රවල ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට දිගුකාලීන සබඳතා ඇති කර ගත හැකි ක්‍රම සහ විධි පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කළහ.",
        "BREAKING: මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ (27) සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වීමට අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සේවා පමණක්; තෙල් සංස්ථාව ඉන්ධන නිකුත් කරන්නේ අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය සේවා සඳහා පමණි",
        "චමරි අතපත්තුගේ අපරාජිත පහරක් ඉන්දීය කාන්තා පිලට එරෙහිව පහසු ජයක් කරා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මෙහෙයවයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "1 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඛනිජ තෙල් සහ ස්වභාවික ගෑස් සහ නිවාස හා නාගරික කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිං පූරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවාස හා නාගරික කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මොරගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පූරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පූරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පූරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොරගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පූරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චමරි අතපත්තු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அவசர எரிசக்தி ஒத்துழைப்புக்காக மொரகொட இந்திய பெட்ரோலிய அமைச்சரை சந்தித்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): இந்தியாவிற்கான இலங்கை உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் மிலிந்த மொரகொட, இந்தியாவின் பெற்றோலியம் மற்றும் இயற்கை எரிவாயு மற்றும் வீடமைப்பு மற்றும் நகர்ப்புற விவகார அமைச்சர் ஸ்ரீ ஹர்தீப் சிங் பூரியை திங்கட்கிழமை (27) சந்தித்து இருதரப்பு எரிசக்தி ஒத்துழைப்பு தொடர்பான அவசர விவகாரங்கள் குறித்து கலந்துரையாடினார். . புதுதில்லியில் உள்ள வீட்டுவசதி மற்றும் நகர்ப்புற விவகாரங்கள் அமைச்சகத்தில் இந்த சந்திப்பு நடைபெற்றது.",
        "ஆரம்பத்தில், உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் மொரகொட, பெட்ரோலியப் பொருட்களின் விநியோகம் மற்றும் விநியோகம் தொடர்பாக இலங்கை தற்போது எதிர்நோக்கும் கடுமையான சவால்கள் மற்றும் மக்கள் படும் கடுமையான இன்னல்கள் குறித்து அமைச்சர் பூரிக்கு விளக்கமளித்தார்.",
        "எரிபொருளை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்காக இந்தியாவுக்கு கடன் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ள உதவிக்கு நன்றி தெரிவித்த இலங்கை உயர்ஸ்தானிகர், தற்போது இலங்கைக்குத் தேவையான பெற்றோல் மற்றும் டீசல் விநியோகங்களை அவசரகால அடிப்படையில் பாதுகாப்பதற்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகள் குறித்து அமைச்சர் பூரியுடன் கலந்துரையாடினார். . அமைச்சர் பூரி இது தொடர்பாக சாதகமாக பதிலளித்ததுடன், இந்த நெருக்கடியான தருணத்தில் இலங்கைக்கு சாத்தியமான அனைத்து ஆதரவையும் உயர் ஸ்தானிகருக்கு உறுதியளித்தார்.",
        "உயர்ஸ்தானிகரும் அமைச்சரும் உடனடி நெருக்கடியை சமாளிக்க உதவுவதற்கும் இலங்கையின் எரிசக்தி பாதுகாப்பை உறுதி செய்வதற்கும் பெட்ரோலிய துறையில் இந்தியாவும் இலங்கையும் ஒத்துழைப்பை மேலும் விரிவுபடுத்துவதற்கான வழிமுறைகள் குறித்தும் கலந்துரையாடினர். இந்தச் சூழலில், பெட்ரோலியம், எண்ணெய், எரிவாயு மற்றும் தொடர்புடைய தளவாடத் துறைகளில் இலங்கை நீண்ட கால உறவுகளை ஏற்படுத்துவதற்கான வழிகள் மற்றும் வழிமுறைகள் குறித்து உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் மொரகொட மற்றும் அமைச்சர் பூரி ஆகியோர் கலந்துரையாடினர்.",
        "BREAKING: நள்ளிரவு (27) முதல் அத்தியாவசிய சேவைகள் மட்டும் செயல்படும்; அத்தியாவசிய சேவைகளுக்கு மட்டுமே CPC எரிபொருளை வழங்கும்",
        "சாமரி அதபத்துவின் ஆட்டமிழக்காமல், இந்தியப் பெண்களுக்கு எதிராக இலங்கையை எளிதாக வெற்றி பெற வழிவகுத்தது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "1வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோலியம் மற்றும் இயற்கை எரிவாயு மற்றும் வீட்டுவசதி மற்றும் நகர்ப்புற விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங் பூரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீட்டுவசதி மற்றும் நகர்ப்புற விவகாரங்கள் அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மொரகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொரகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாமரி அதபத்து",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}