{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83344/oil-seen-rising-past-us200-a-barrel-on-russian-crude-price-cap",
  "time_ut": 1656585720,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Oil seen rising past US$200 a barrel on Russian crude price cap",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Oil seen rising past US$200 a barrel on Russian crude price cap",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Oil prices are likely to rise past US$200 per barrel if the Group of Seven (G7) manages to cap the price of Russian crude oil.",
        "Citing Bjarne Schieldrop, the chief commodities analyst at Swedish bank SEB Group, on Wednesday (June 29), energy portal Oilprice.com said that the G7’s price capping proposal is a “recipe for disaster” given the current stress that the oil market is under.",
        "G7 leaders agreed on Tuesday to study ways to cap the price of Russian oil sold internationally and are seeking support among “like-minded” nations.",
        "It is one of the critical items being discussed in this week’s G7 meeting as the group tries to find creative ways to lower energy prices for themselves and maintain adequate crude supplies from Russia — while simultaneously punishing Russia in what many see as an impossible task.",
        "US Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen continued to put pressure on European countries to support a price cap.",
        "Oilprice.com said that according to Schieldrop, the plan seems “neat on paper, but it sounds like a recipe for disaster right now”, given the strong demand for crude oil and low supplies that have so far given Russia the upper hand in the market. Russia could choose not to sell the oil at a capped price — a decision that could lead to Russia’s production falling by as much as two million barrels per day.",
        "Russia’s crude and condensate production rose in June by 5% to 10.7 million bpd, according to Kommersant sources — a figure that included between 800,000 and 900,000 bpd of condensate, which is not included in the OPEC+ agreement.",
        "But Russia’s oil exports have slipped 3.3% in June with a rise in domestic refining demand.",
        "Reuters said oil prices edged higher on Thursday after dipping in early Asian trade as concerns about global supply tightness outweighed a build in US gasoline and distillate inventories.",
        "Brent crude futures for September, the more actively traded contract, rose 63 cents, or 0.6%, to US$113.08 a barrel. The less liquidly traded August contract expiring on Thursday was at US$116.08, down 18 cents, or 0.2%."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "200",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "Russian",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Group of Seven",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Citing Bjarne Schieldrop",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Swedish bank SEB Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oilprice.com",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "G7",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "G7",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janet Yellen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "European",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Oilprice.com",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Schieldrop",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "as much as two million barrels",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.7 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kommersant",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "between 800,000 and 900,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "OPEC+",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.3%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "September",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "63 cents",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "113.08",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "116.08",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 cents",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.2%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රුසියානු බොරතෙල් මිල සීමාව මත තෙල් බැරලයක් ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් 200 ඉක්මවන බව පෙනේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සෙවන් සමූහය (G7) රුසියානු බොරතෙල් මිල සීමා කිරීමට සමත් වුවහොත් තෙල් මිල බැරලයක ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් 200 ඉක්මවා යාමට ඉඩ ඇත.",
        "බදාදා (ජූනි 29) ස්වීඩන් බැංකුවේ SEB සමූහයේ ප්‍රධාන වෙළඳ භාණ්ඩ විශ්ලේෂක Bjarne Schieldrop උපුටා දක්වමින් Oilprice.com බලශක්ති ද්වාරය කියා සිටියේ G7 හි මිල සීමා කිරීමේ යෝජනාව තෙල් වෙළඳපොළ පවතින වත්මන් ආතතියට අනුව “ආපදා සඳහා වට්ටෝරුවක්” බවයි. .",
        "G7 නායකයින් අඟහරුවාදා ජාත්‍යන්තරව විකුණනු ලබන රුසියානු තෙල් මිල සීමා කිරීමේ ක්‍රම අධ්‍යයනය කිරීමට එකඟ වූ අතර “සමාන අදහස්” ඇති ජාතීන් අතර සහාය අපේක්ෂා කරති.",
        "මෙම සතියේ G7 රැස්වීමේදී සාකච්ඡා කෙරෙන තීරණාත්මක අයිතමයන්ගෙන් එකකි, සමූහය තමන් සඳහා බලශක්ති මිල අඩු කිරීමට සහ රුසියාවෙන් ප්‍රමාණවත් බොරතෙල් සැපයුම් පවත්වා ගැනීමට නිර්මාණාත්මක ක්‍රම සොයා ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කරන අතර - බොහෝ දෙනෙකුට කළ නොහැකි කාර්යයක් ලෙස රුසියාවට දඩුවම් කරන අතරම.",
        "එක්සත් ජනපද භාණ්ඩාගාර ලේකම් ජැනට් යෙලන් යුරෝපීය රටවලට මිල සීමාවකට සහාය දෙන ලෙස දිගින් දිගටම බලපෑම් කළේය.",
        "Oilprice.com පැවසුවේ Schieldrop ට අනුව, සැලැස්ම “කඩදාසි මත පිළිවෙලට පෙනෙන නමුත් එය දැන් ව්‍යසනය සඳහා වට්ටෝරුවක් සේ පෙනේ”, බොරතෙල් සඳහා ඇති දැඩි ඉල්ලුම සහ අඩු සැපයුම් සඳහා රුසියාවට මෙතෙක් ඉහළ අතක් ලබා දී ඇති බවයි. වෙලඳපොල. රුසියාවට සීමා කළ මිලකට තෙල් අලෙවි නොකිරීමට තීරණය කළ හැකිය - රුසියාවේ නිෂ්පාදනය දිනකට බැරල් මිලියන දෙකකින් පහත වැටීමට තුඩු දිය හැකි තීරණයකි.",
        "රුසියාවේ බොරතෙල් සහ ඝනීභවනය නිෂ්පාදනය ජුනි මාසයේදී 5% කින් Bpd මිලියන 10.7 දක්වා වැඩි විය, Kommersant මූලාශ්‍රවලට අනුව - OPEC + ගිවිසුමට ඇතුළත් නොවන ඝනීභවනය 800,000 ත් 900,000 ත් අතර ප්‍රමාණයක් ඇතුළත් විය.",
        "එහෙත් දේශීය පිරිපහදු ඉල්ලුම ඉහළ යාමත් සමඟ ජුනි මාසයේදී රුසියාවේ තෙල් අපනයන 3.3% කින් පහත වැටී ඇත.",
        "රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවය පැවසුවේ, ගෝලීය සැපයුම් තදබදය පිළිබඳ උත්සුකයන් එක්සත් ජනපදයේ පෙට්‍රල් සහ ආසවනය කරන බඩු තොගවල ගොඩනැගීමට වඩා වැඩි වීම නිසා මුල් ආසියානු වෙළඳාමේ පහත වැටීමෙන් පසු බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා තෙල් මිල ඉහළ ගිය බවයි.",
        "සැප්තැම්බර් සඳහා බ්‍රෙන්ට් බොරතෙල් අනාගතය, වඩාත් ක්‍රියාකාරීව වෙළඳාම් කරන ලද කොන්ත්‍රාත්තුවක්, බැරලයක් ඩොලර් 113.08 දක්වා ශත 63 කින් හෝ 0.6% කින් ඉහළ ගියේය. බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා කල් ඉකුත්වන අඩු ද්‍රවශීල වෙළඳාම් අගෝස්තු කොන්ත්‍රාත්තුව ඩොලර් 116.08 කින්, ශත 18 කින් හෝ 0.2% කින් අඩු විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "200",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "රුසියානු",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "හත්දෙනාගේ කණ්ඩායම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bjarne Schieldrop උපුටා දක්වමින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්වීඩන් බැංකුව SEB සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oilprice.com",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "G7",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "G7",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද භාණ්ඩාගාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැනට් යෙලන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපා",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Oilprice.com",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශිල්ඩ්රොප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැරල් මිලියන දෙකක් තරම්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 10.7 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමර්සන්ට්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "800,000 සහ 900,000 අතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔපෙක් +",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.3%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශත 63 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "113.08 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "116.08 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශත 18 යි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.2%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரஷ்ய கச்சா விலை உச்சவரம்பில் எண்ணெய் பீப்பாய் ஒன்றுக்கு 200 அமெரிக்க டாலர்களை தாண்டியுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "குரூப் ஆஃப் செவன் (G7) ரஷ்ய கச்சா எண்ணெயின் விலையைக் கட்டுப்படுத்தினால், எண்ணெய் விலை பீப்பாய்க்கு 200 அமெரிக்க டாலர்களைத் தாண்டி உயரும்.",
        "புதனன்று (ஜூன் 29) ஸ்வீடிஷ் வங்கியான SEB குழுமத்தின் தலைமைப் பொருட்கள் ஆய்வாளரான Bjarne Schieldrop ஐ மேற்கோள் காட்டி, எண்ணெய் சந்தையின் தற்போதைய அழுத்தத்தின் அடிப்படையில், G7 இன் விலைக் கட்டுப்பாடு திட்டம் \"பேரழிவுக்கான செய்முறை\" என்று எரிசக்தி போர்டல் Oilprice.com கூறியது. .",
        "G7 தலைவர்கள் செவ்வாயன்று சர்வதேச அளவில் விற்கப்படும் ரஷ்ய எண்ணெயின் விலையை கட்டுப்படுத்துவதற்கான வழிகளை ஆய்வு செய்ய ஒப்புக்கொண்டனர் மற்றும் \"ஒத்த எண்ணம் கொண்ட\" நாடுகளிடையே ஆதரவை நாடுகின்றனர்.",
        "இந்த வார G7 கூட்டத்தில் விவாதிக்கப்படும் முக்கியமான விஷயங்களில் ஒன்று, குழு தங்களுக்கான ஆற்றல் விலைகளைக் குறைப்பதற்கும், ரஷ்யாவிலிருந்து போதுமான கச்சா சப்ளைகளைப் பராமரிப்பதற்கும் ஆக்கப்பூர்வமான வழிகளைக் கண்டறிய முயல்கிறது - அதே நேரத்தில் ரஷ்யாவைத் தண்டிப்பது சாத்தியமற்றது என்று பலர் கருதுகின்றனர்.",
        "அமெரிக்க கருவூல செயலாளர் ஜேனட் யெல்லன் தொடர்ந்து ஐரோப்பிய நாடுகளுக்கு விலை வரம்பை ஆதரிக்க அழுத்தம் கொடுத்தார்.",
        "Oilprice.com, Schieldrop இன் கூற்றுப்படி, திட்டம் \"காகிதத்தில் நேர்த்தியாகத் தெரிகிறது, ஆனால் அது இப்போது பேரழிவுக்கான செய்முறையாகத் தெரிகிறது\", கச்சா எண்ணெய்க்கான வலுவான தேவை மற்றும் குறைந்த சப்ளைகளின் வலுவான தேவையைக் கருத்தில் கொண்டு, இது இதுவரை ரஷ்யாவிற்கு மேல் கையை அளித்துள்ளது. சந்தை. ரஷியா ஒரு வரம்பு விலையில் எண்ணெய் விற்க வேண்டாம் என்று தேர்வு செய்யலாம் - ரஷ்யாவின் உற்பத்தி ஒரு நாளைக்கு இரண்டு மில்லியன் பீப்பாய்கள் குறைவதற்கு வழிவகுக்கும்.",
        "ரஷ்யாவின் கச்சா மற்றும் மின்தேக்கி உற்பத்தி ஜூன் மாதத்தில் 5% அதிகரித்து 10.7 மில்லியன் bpd ஆக இருந்தது என்று Kommersant ஆதாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன - இது 800,000 மற்றும் 900,000 bpd வரையிலான கண்டன்சேட்டை உள்ளடக்கியது, இது OPEC+ ஒப்பந்தத்தில் சேர்க்கப்படவில்லை.",
        "ஆனால் ரஷ்யாவின் எண்ணெய் ஏற்றுமதி ஜூன் மாதத்தில் உள்நாட்டு சுத்திகரிப்பு தேவை அதிகரிப்புடன் 3.3% சரிந்துள்ளது.",
        "உலகளாவிய விநியோக இறுக்கம் பற்றிய கவலைகள் அமெரிக்க பெட்ரோல் மற்றும் வடிகட்டுதல் சரக்குகளை விட அதிகமாக இருப்பதால், ஆரம்ப ஆசிய வர்த்தகத்தில் வீழ்ச்சியடைந்த பின்னர் எண்ணெய் விலை வியாழனன்று உயர்ந்ததாக ராய்ட்டர்ஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "செப்டம்பர் மாதத்திற்கான ப்ரெண்ட் கச்சா எதிர்காலம், மிகவும் தீவிரமாக வர்த்தகம் செய்யப்பட்ட ஒப்பந்தம், 63 சென்ட்கள் அல்லது 0.6% உயர்ந்து, ஒரு பீப்பாய்க்கு 113.08 அமெரிக்க டாலர்களாக இருந்தது. வியாழன் அன்று காலாவதியாகும் குறைந்த திரவ வர்த்தகம் ஆகஸ்ட் ஒப்பந்தம் 18 சென்ட்கள் அல்லது 0.2% குறைந்து US$116.08 ஆக இருந்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "200",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bjarne Schieldrop ஐ மேற்கோள் காட்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்வீடிஷ் வங்கி SEB குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oilprice.com",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "G7",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "G7",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜேனட் யெலன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Oilprice.com",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்கீல்ட்ராப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு மில்லியன் பீப்பாய்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.7 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொமர்சன்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "800,000 மற்றும் 900,000 இடையே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "OPEC+",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.3%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "63 சென்ட்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "113.08",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "116.08",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 சென்ட்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.2%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}