{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ජනපති-තනතුරට-තුන්-කොන්-සටනක්--/1-616327",
  "time_ut": 1657685692,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ජනපති තනතුරට තුන් කොන් සටනක් ?",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A three-cornered battle for the position of president?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Parliamentary sources state that three names have been proposed for the presidency.",
        "The names of Prime Minister Ranil Wickramasinghe, Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna Member of Parliament Dallas Alahapperuma and Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa have been proposed.",
        "The secret ballot of the Parliament to elect the new President will be held on July 20.",
        "However, the resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has not been officially announced until now."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament Dallas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපති තනතුරට තුන් කොන් සටනක් ?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති ධුරය සඳහා නම් තුනක් යෝජනා වී ඇතැයි  පාර්ලිමේන්තු ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම සහ විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහත්වරුන්ගේ  නම් මෙලෙස යෝජනා වී ඇත.",
        "නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ රහස් ඡන්දය ජූලි 20 වැනිදා පැවැත්වේ.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම පිළිබඳව මේ මොහොත වන තෙක් නිල වශයෙන් දැනුම් දී නැත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு மும்முனைப் போரா?",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு மூன்று பெயர்கள் முன்மொழியப்பட்டுள்ளதாக நாடாளுமன்ற தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச ஆகியோரின் பெயர்கள் முன்மொழியப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "புதிய குடியரசுத் தலைவரை தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதற்கான நாடாளுமன்ற ரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பு ஜூலை 20ஆம் தேதி நடைபெறவுள்ளது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் பதவி விலகல் குறித்து இதுவரை உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக அறிவிக்கப்படவில்லை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}