{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/අනුරත්-ජනපති-සටනට/11-395473",
  "time_ut": 1657967216,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අනුරත් ජනපති සටනට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Anurath for the presidential battle",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Anura Kumara Dissanayake, the leader of Thajanata Vimukti Peramuna, has also joined as a candidate for the election of a new President in the Parliament.",
        "Representing the National People's Force, he joins the presidential battle. The election of the members of parliament to elect a new president is scheduled to be held on the 20th."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Anura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thajanata Vimukti Peramuna",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the National People's Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 20th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අනුරත් ජනපති සටනට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "නව ජනපතිවරයෙක් තෝරා පත්කර ගැනීම වෙනුවෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ  පැවැත්වෙන ඡන්ද විමසීම සඳහා අපේක්ෂකයෙක් ලෙස තජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක මහතාද එක්ව තිබේ.",
        "ජාතික ජන බලවේගය නියෝජනය කරමින් ඔහු මෙසේ ජනපති සටන වෙනුවෙන් එක්වෙයි. නව ජනපතිවරයෙක් තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම වෙනුවෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ ඡන්ද විමසිම එළැඹෙන 20 දා පැවැත්විමට නියමිතව තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තජනට විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලවේගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி போருக்கு அனுரத்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தஜனதா விமுக்தி பெரமுனவின் தலைவர் திரு அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்கவும் புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான வேட்பாளராக பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இணைந்துள்ளார்.",
        "தேசிய மக்கள் படையை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தி, அவர் ஜனாதிபதி போரில் இணைகிறார். புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் தேர்தல் எதிர்வரும் 20ஆம் திகதி நடைபெறவுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தஜனதா விமுக்தி பெரமுன",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}