{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Australia-extends-25-m-more-as-humanitarian-assistance/56-738869",
  "time_ut": 1660852598,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Australia extends $ 25 m more as humanitarian assistance",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Australia extends $ 25 m more as humanitarian assistance",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Australian Government yesterday said it would provide an additional $ 25 million to help Sri Lanka meet urgent food and healthcare needs as it confronts its worst economic crisis in 70 years.",
        "“During this challenging period, Australia stands with the people of Sri Lanka, especially those experiencing severe hardship,” a statement issued by the Australian High Commission said.",
        "The additional support brings Australia’s Official Development Assistance response to $ 75 million. “Our support will be delivered through UN agencies to provide food, health and nutrition services, access to safe water and essential support for those at risk, including women and children,” the statement said.",
        "“Australia’s continued assistance to Sri Lanka supports our mutual interest in a secure and resilient Indian Ocean and reinforces our 75-year-strong relationship built on cooperation and community connection,” it added.",
        "The extra humanitarian assistance is in addition to the $ 23 million in ongoing development assistance to Sri Lanka in 2022-23 from Australia."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Australia",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "25",
          "label": "MONEY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Australian Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "an additional $ 25 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Australian High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 75 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "UN",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian Ocean",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "75-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$ 23 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022-23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මානුෂීය ආධාර ලෙස ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාව තවත් ඩොලර් මිලියන 25ක් දිගු කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "වසර 70ක දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට මුහුණ දී සිටින ශ්‍රී ලංකාව හදිසි ආහාර සහ සෞඛ්‍ය අවශ්‍යතා සපුරාලීම සඳහා අමතර ඩොලර් මිලියන 25ක් ලබා දෙන බව ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු රජය ඊයේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "\"මෙම අභියෝගාත්මක කාල පරිච්ෙඡ්දය තුළ, ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාව සමඟ, විශේෂයෙන් දැඩි දුෂ්කරතා අත්විඳින ජනතාව සමඟ\" සිටින බව ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය නිකුත් කළ නිවේදනයක දැක්වේ.",
        "අතිරේක සහාය ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවේ නිල සංවර්ධන ආධාර ප්‍රතිචාරය ඩොලර් මිලියන 75 දක්වා ගෙන එයි. \"ආහාර, සෞඛ්‍ය සහ පෝෂණ සේවා සැපයීම, ආරක්ෂිත ජලය සඳහා ප්‍රවේශය සහ කාන්තාවන් සහ ළමුන් ඇතුළු අවදානමට ලක්ව සිටින අයට අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ආධාර සැපයීම සඳහා අපගේ සහයෝගය එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ නියෝජිතායතන හරහා ලබා දෙනු ඇත\" යනුවෙන් එම ප්‍රකාශය පවසයි.",
        "\"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාවේ අඛණ්ඩ සහාය ආරක්‍ෂිත සහ ඔරොත්තු දෙන ඉන්දියන් සාගරයක් සඳහා අපගේ අන්‍යෝන්‍ය අවශ්‍යතාවයට සහාය වන අතර සහයෝගීතාවය සහ ප්‍රජා සම්බන්ධතාවය මත ගොඩනගා ඇති අපගේ 75 වසරක ශක්තිමත් සබඳතාව ශක්තිමත් කරයි\" යනුවෙන් එය වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මෙම අතිරේක මානුෂීය ආධාරය ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවෙන් 2022-23 වසර සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට දැනට පවතින සංවර්ධන ආධාර වශයෙන් ඩොලර් මිලියන 23 ට අමතරව වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "25",
          "label": "MONEY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානු රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අතිරේක ඩොලර් මිලියන 25 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 70 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 75 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "එ.ජා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියන් සාගරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 75ක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 23 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022-23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மனிதாபிமான உதவியாக ஆஸ்திரேலியா இன்னும் 25 மில்லியன் டாலர்களை வழங்குகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "70 வருடங்களில் மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ள இலங்கையின் அவசர உணவு மற்றும் சுகாதார தேவைகளை பூர்த்தி செய்ய 25 மில்லியன் டொலர்களை வழங்குவதாக அவுஸ்திரேலிய அரசாங்கம் நேற்று தெரிவித்தது.",
        "\"இந்த சவாலான காலகட்டத்தில், அவுஸ்திரேலியா இலங்கை மக்களுடன் குறிப்பாக கடுமையான கஷ்டங்களை அனுபவிக்கும் மக்களுடன் நிற்கிறது\" என அவுஸ்திரேலிய உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயம் வெளியிட்டுள்ள அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "கூடுதல் ஆதரவு ஆஸ்திரேலியாவின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ மேம்பாட்டு உதவிக்கான பதிலை 75 மில்லியன் டாலர்களாகக் கொண்டுவருகிறது. \"உணவு, சுகாதாரம் மற்றும் ஊட்டச்சத்து சேவைகள், பாதுகாப்பான நீர் அணுகல் மற்றும் பெண்கள் மற்றும் குழந்தைகள் உட்பட ஆபத்தில் உள்ளவர்களுக்கு அத்தியாவசிய ஆதரவை வழங்குவதற்கு ஐ.நா. ஏஜென்சிகள் மூலம் எங்கள் ஆதரவு வழங்கப்படும்\" என்று அந்த அறிக்கையில் கூறப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான அவுஸ்திரேலியாவின் தொடர்ச்சியான உதவியானது பாதுகாப்பான மற்றும் மீள்தன்மை கொண்ட இந்தியப் பெருங்கடலில் எங்களின் பரஸ்பர நலனை ஆதரிக்கிறது மற்றும் ஒத்துழைப்பு மற்றும் சமூக இணைப்பில் கட்டமைக்கப்பட்ட 75 வருட வலுவான உறவை வலுப்படுத்துகிறது,\" என்று அது மேலும் கூறியது.",
        "அவுஸ்திரேலியாவிடமிருந்து 2022-23 ஆம் ஆண்டில் இலங்கைக்கான தற்போதைய அபிவிருத்தி உதவிக்கான 23 மில்லியன் டொலர்களுக்கு மேலதிக மனிதாபிமான உதவியாகும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "25",
          "label": "MONEY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலிய அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கூடுதல் $25 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலிய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 75 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய பெருங்கடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "75-ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$ 23 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022-23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}