{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Red-alert-issued-in-9-districts-over-150mm-rainfall-expected-Met-Dept/342-244325",
  "time_ut": 1662361151,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Red alert issued in 9 districts; over 150mm rainfall expected: Met Dept",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Red alert issued in 9 districts; over 150mm rainfall expected: Met Dept",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A red alert (Take Action) on heavy deluge has been issued in nine districts, the Department of Meteorology said today.",
        "They said fairly heavy rainfall of more than 150 mm could be expected in some places in Western and Sabaragamuwa provinces and in Kandy, Nuwara-Eliya, Galle and Matara districts.",
        "The heavy rainfall is due to a prevailing low-level atmospheric disturbance located to the south-east of Sri Lanka, they said.",
        "Accordingly, the nine districts, including Gampaha, Kegalle, Kandy, Nuwara-Eliya, Colombo, Kalutara, Ratnapura, Galle and Matara have been alerted over the weather conditions.",
        "Furthermore, the department requested the people living in hilly areas (particularly landslide prone areas) and low-lying areas in river basins are requested to be vigilant.",
        "The drivers and people who use roads in the hilly areas are requested to be vigilant.",
        "Public are also requested to take adequate precautions to minimize damages caused by lightning activity.",
        "Beware of fallen trees and power lines requested to be alert on the advisories issued by the Department. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "9",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "150mm",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "Met Dept",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "more than 150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegalle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalutara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දිස්ත්‍රික්ක 9කට රතු නිවේදනයක්; 150mm ට වැඩි වර්ෂාපතනයක් අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ: කාලගුණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දිස්ත්‍රික්ක 9 කට අධික ගංවතුර තත්ත්වයක් පිළිබඳ රතු නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කර ඇති බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව අද ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "බස්නාහිර සහ සබරගමුව පළාත්වලත් මහනුවර, නුවරඑළිය, ගාල්ල සහ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලිමීටර් 150ට වැඩි තරමක තද වර්ෂාපතනයක් අපේක්ෂා කළ හැකි බව ඔවුන් ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ගිනිකොන දෙසින් පවතින පහළ වායුගෝලීය කැළඹීමක් හේතුවෙන් මෙම අධික වර්ෂාපතනය හටගෙන ඇති බව ඔවුහු පවසති.",
        "ඒ අනුව ගම්පහ, කෑගල්ල, මහනුවර, නුවරඑළිය, කොළඹ, කළුතර, රත්නපුර, ගාල්ල සහ මාතර ඇතුළු දිස්ත්‍රික්ක 9 සඳහා කාලගුණික තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව අවධානය යොමු කර ඇත.",
        "තවද, කඳුකර ප්‍රදේශවල (විශේෂයෙන් නාය යෑමේ අවදානම් සහිත ප්‍රදේශ) සහ ගංගා ද්‍රෝණි ආශ්‍රිත පහත් බිම්වල වෙසෙන ජනතාව අවධානයෙන් පසුවන ලෙස එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව ඉල්ලා සිටියි.",
        "කඳුකර ප්‍රදේශවල මාර්ග භාවිත කරන රියදුරන්ගෙන් සහ ජනතාවගෙන් විමසිලිමත් වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටියි.",
        "අකුණු මඟින් සිදුවන අනතුරු අවම කර ගැනීමට අවශ්‍ය පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස ද මහජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටිනු ලැබේ.",
        "ගස් හා විදුලි රැහැන් කඩා වැටීමෙන් ප්‍රවේශම් වන්නැයි දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් නිකුත් කරන ලද උපදෙස් පිළිබඳව අවධානයෙන් සිටින ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටියි. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "9",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "150 මි.මී",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "මෙට් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "150 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "9 மாவட்டங்களில் ரெட் அலர்ட் விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. 150 மிமீ மழை எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது: வானிலை ஆய்வு மையம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஒன்பது மாவட்டங்களில் கடும் வெள்ளம் காரணமாக சிவப்பு எச்சரிக்கை விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் இன்று தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மேல் மற்றும் சப்ரகமுவ மாகாணங்களிலும் கண்டி, நுவரெலியா, காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறை மாவட்டங்களிலும் சில இடங்களில் 150 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான மழைவீழ்ச்சி எதிர்பார்க்கப்படலாம் என அவர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இலங்கையின் தென்கிழக்கு பகுதியில் நிலவும் தாழ்வான வளிமண்டல குழப்பம் காரணமாக இந்த கடும் மழை பெய்துள்ளதாக அவர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "அதன்படி, கம்பஹா, கேகாலை, கண்டி, நுவரெலியா, கொழும்பு, களுத்துறை, இரத்தினபுரி, காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறை உள்ளிட்ட ஒன்பது மாவட்டங்களுக்கு காலநிலை காரணமாக எச்சரிக்கை விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மேலும், மலைப்பாங்கான பகுதிகளில் வசிக்கும் மக்கள் (குறிப்பாக மண்சரிவு அபாயம் உள்ள பகுதிகள்) மற்றும் ஆற்றுப்படுகைகளில் தாழ்வான பகுதிகளில் வசிக்கும் மக்கள் அவதானமாக இருக்குமாறும் திணைக்களம் கேட்டுக்கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "மலையகப் பகுதிகளில் வீதிகளைப் பயன்படுத்தும் சாரதிகளும் மக்களும் அவதானமாக இருக்குமாறு கேட்டுக் கொள்ளப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "மின்னல் தாக்கங்களினால் ஏற்படக்கூடிய பாதிப்புகளை குறைத்துக்கொள்ள போதிய முன்னெச்சரிக்கை நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுக்குமாறும் பொதுமக்கள் கேட்டுக்கொள்ளப்படுகிறார்கள்.",
        "விழும் மரங்கள் மற்றும் மின்கம்பங்கள் குறித்து அவதானமாக இருக்குமாறு திணைக்களத்தினால் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ள அறிவுறுத்தல்கள் தொடர்பில் அவதானமாக இருக்குமாறு கோரப்பட்டுள்ளது. (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "9",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "150மிமீ",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "சந்தித்தது துறை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "150க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}