{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-makes-payment-for-two-fuel-shipments-97249/",
  "time_ut": 1657542180,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka makes payment for two fuel shipments",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka makes payment for two fuel shipments",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka has paid for two fuel ships which are scheduled to arrive in a few days and part payments have been made for another, Power and Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekera.",
        "A shipment that was scheduled to arrive on July 09th had been delayed due to bad weather conditions and is set to arrive on July 15, the minister said in a Tweet.",
        "“Cargo scheduled to arrive on the 9th was delayed due to weather conditions & could not be loaded on time & the supplier has communicated the departure from India this morning,” Minister said.",
        "“The new Laycan has been given as 12-15th. All Dates are given by the suppliers & weather permitting.”",
        "1) On Friday, full payments were made with the assistance of @CBSL & MOF to IOC for a Diesel Cargo to arrive 15-17 & a Petrol Cargo for 22-24. Advance payments were made last week for a Diesel cargo to arrive 15-17 & Petrol 17-19. Balance payment to be made today for the Diesel.",
        "On Friday, with the assistance of the central bank and the finance ministry, Sri Lanka has made payments in advance to Indian Oil Corporation for a Diesel ship that is scheduled to arrive between July – 15-17 and a Petrol Shipment between July 22-24, the minister said.",
        "While an advance payment had been made last week for a Diesel cargo to arrive on July 15-17 & Petrol 17-19. Balance payment to be made today 11 for the Diesel and the balance payment for the petrol will be paid on July 12, he said.",
        "Three more fuel cargos are also set to arrive in Colombo on payment on the delivery basis- 12-15th Diesel, 14-16th Heavy Fuel Oil and 15-17th Crude Oil. (Colombo/Jul11/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "a few days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 09th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Laycan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "12-15th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "@CBSL & MOF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IOC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15-17 &",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22-24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15-17 & Petrol",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian Oil Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "between July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15-17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Petrol Shipment",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "between July 22-24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 15-17 & Petrol 17-19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12-15th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "14-16th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Heavy Fuel Oil",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "15-17th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Crude Oil",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන නැව්ගත කිරීම් දෙකක් සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ගෙවීම් කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - තව දින කිහිපයකින් පැමිණීමට නියමිත ඉන්ධන නැව් දෙකක් සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ගෙවා ඇති අතර තවත් එකක් සඳහා අර්ධ ගෙවීම් කර ඇත, විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර.",
        "ජුලි 09 වෙනිදා පැමිණීමට නියමිතව තිබූ නැව්ගත කිරීමක් අයහපත් කාලගුණික තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් ප්‍රමාද වී ජුලි 15 වෙනිදා පැමිණීමට නියමිත බව අමාත්‍යවරයා ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "\"9 වනදා පැමිණීමට නියමිතව තිබූ භාණ්ඩ කාලගුණික තත්ත්වයන් හේතුවෙන් ප්‍රමාද වූ අතර නියමිත වේලාවට පැටවීමට නොහැකි වූ අතර සැපයුම්කරු අද උදෑසන ඉන්දියාවෙන් පිටත්ව යන බව දන්වා ඇත,\" අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "“අලුත් ලේකන් එක දීලා තියෙන්නේ 12-15 කියලා. සියලුම දිනයන් සැපයුම්කරුවන් සහ කාලගුණ අවසරය මගින් ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "1) සිකුරාදා, ඩීසල් භාණ්ඩයක් 15-17 ට සහ පෙට්‍රල් භාණ්ඩයක් 22-24 ට පැමිණීමට IOC වෙත @CBSL සහ MOF සහාය ඇතිව සම්පූර්ණ ගෙවීම් සිදු කරන ලදී. ඩීසල් භාණ්ඩයක් 15-17 සහ පෙට්‍රල් 17-19 පැමිණීම සඳහා අත්තිකාරම් ගෙවීම් පසුගිය සතියේ සිදු කරන ලදී. ඩීසල් සඳහා ඉතිරි ගෙවීම අද සිදු කෙරේ.",
        "සිකුරාදා, මහ බැංකුවේ සහ මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයේ සහාය ඇතිව, ජූලි - 15-17 අතර පැමිණීමට නියමිත ඩීසල් නෞකාවක් සහ ජූලි 22-24 අතර පෙට්‍රල් නැව්ගත කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඉන්දියානු තෙල් සංස්ථාවට අත්තිකාරම් ගෙවා ඇත. , අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "ඩීසල් භාණ්ඩයක් ජූලි 15-17 සහ පෙට්‍රල් 17-19 යන දිනවල පැමිණීම සඳහා පසුගිය සතියේ අත්තිකාරම් ගෙවීමක් කර ඇත. ඩීසල් සඳහා ඉතිරිය ගෙවීම අද 11 වන අතර පෙට්‍රල් සඳහා ඉතිරි මුදල ජූලි 12 වනදා ගෙවන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ඩීසල් 12-15, 14-16 බර ඉන්ධන සහ 15-17 බොරතෙල් යන බෙදාහැරීමේ පදනම මත තවත් ඉන්ධන භාණ්ඩ තුනක් කොළඹට පැමිණීමට නියමිතය. (කොළඹ/ජූලි11/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලේකන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "12-15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "@CBSL සහ MOF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයි.ඕ.සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15-17 සහ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22-24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15-17 සහ පෙට්‍රල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු තෙල් සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15-17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙට්‍රල් නැව්ගත කිරීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 22-24 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 15-17 සහ පෙට්‍රල් 17-19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12-15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "14-16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බර ඉන්ධන තෙල්",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "15-17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොර තෙල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இரண்டு எரிபொருள் ஏற்றுமதிக்கு இலங்கை பணம் செலுத்துகிறது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இன்னும் சில நாட்களில் வரவிருக்கும் இரண்டு எரிபொருள் கப்பல்களுக்கு இலங்கை பணம் செலுத்தியுள்ளது மற்றும் மற்றொன்றுக்கு பகுதி பணம் செலுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது, மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர.",
        "ஜூலை 09 ஆம் தேதி வரவிருந்த ஒரு சரக்கு மோசமான வானிலை காரணமாக தாமதமாகி, ஜூலை 15 ஆம் தேதி வரும் என்று அமைச்சர் ஒரு ட்வீட்டில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"9 ஆம் தேதி வரவிருந்த சரக்கு வானிலை காரணமாக தாமதமானது மற்றும் சரியான நேரத்தில் ஏற்ற முடியவில்லை மற்றும் சப்ளையர் இன்று காலை இந்தியாவிலிருந்து புறப்பட்டதைத் தெரிவித்தார்\" என்று அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "“புதிய லேகான் 12-15 ஆக கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. அனைத்து தேதிகளும் சப்ளையர்கள் மற்றும் வானிலை அனுமதியால் வழங்கப்படுகின்றன.",
        "1) வெள்ளியன்று, டீசல் சரக்கு 15-17 மற்றும் ஒரு பெட்ரோல் சரக்கு 22-24 வரை ஐஓசிக்கு @CBSL & MOF உதவியுடன் முழுப் பணம் செலுத்தப்பட்டது. டீசல் சரக்கு 15-17 & பெட்ரோல் 17-19 வருவதற்கு கடந்த வாரம் முன்பணம் செலுத்தப்பட்டது. டீசலுக்கான இருப்புத்தொகையை இன்று செலுத்த வேண்டும்.",
        "வெள்ளியன்று, மத்திய வங்கி மற்றும் நிதியமைச்சகத்தின் உதவியுடன், ஜூலை - 15-17 க்கு இடையில் வரவிருக்கும் டீசல் கப்பலுக்கும், ஜூலை 22-24 க்கு இடையில் ஒரு பெட்ரோல் கப்பலுக்கும் இந்தியன் ஆயில் கார்ப்பரேஷனுக்கு இலங்கை முன்கூட்டியே பணம் செலுத்தியுள்ளது. , அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "ஜூலை 15-17 மற்றும் பெட்ரோல் 17-19 ஆகிய தேதிகளில் டீசல் சரக்கு வருவதற்கு கடந்த வாரம் முன்பணம் செலுத்தப்பட்டது. டீசல் நிலுவைத் தொகை இன்று 11ம் தேதியும், பெட்ரோலுக்கான பாக்கித் தொகை ஜூலை 12ம் தேதியும் வழங்கப்படும் என்றார்.",
        "12-15 டீசல், 14-16 கனரக எரிபொருள் எண்ணெய் மற்றும் 15-17 கச்சா எண்ணெய் ஆகிய மூன்று எரிபொருள் சரக்குகளும் கொழும்பிற்கு விநியோக அடிப்படையில் செலுத்தப்பட உள்ளன. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை11/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு சில நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லேகான்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "12-15 வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "@CBSL & MOF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐஓசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15-17 &",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22-24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15-17 & பெட்ரோல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன் ஆயில் கார்ப்பரேஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை இடையே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15-17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோல் ஏற்றுமதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 22-24 க்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 15-17 & பெட்ரோல் 17-19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12-15 வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "14-16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனரக எரிபொருள் எண்ணெய்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "15-17 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கச்சா எண்ணெய்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}