{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/නනිල්වලා-ගඟේ-දිය-නෑ-හතරක්-ගසාගෙන-යයි/101-618814",
  "time_ut": 1661524103,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "නනිල්වලා ගඟේ දිය නෑ හතරක් ගසාගෙන යයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Four rivers of Nanilwala river are washed away",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Pitabeddara police said that five of the 12 people who were swimming in the water at Nilwala in the Dehigaspa area of ​​Siambalagoda, Pitabeddara were swept away and four of them went missing and one survived.",
        "The police said that search operations for the missing persons were carried out until dark today (26) and till then they could not be found and they will search for them again tomorrow (27).",
        "The police say that the missing persons are from Deiendara, Porathota, Watawala Ahangama and Mulatiyana areas.",
        "It has been revealed that these are people working in a rubber factory in Midigama area and preliminary investigations have revealed that this group came in three-wheelers and the Pitabeddara Police are conducting further investigations regarding the incident."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Four",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Nanilwala",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nilwala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dehigaspa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Deiendara, Porathota",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Watawala Ahangama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mulatiyana",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Midigama area",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Pitabeddara Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නනිල්වලා ගඟේ දිය නෑ හතරක් ගසාගෙන යයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පිටබැද්දර ,සියඹලාගොඩ  දෙහිගස්ප ප්‍රදේශයේ නිල්වලා ගගේ අද(26) පස්වරුවේ  දිය නාමින් සිටි පුද්ගලයන් 12 කු ගෙන් පස් දෙනකු දියේ ගසාගෙන ගොස් ඉන් සිව් දෙනකු  අතුරුදන්ව එක් අයකු දිවි බේරාගෙන ඇතැයි පිටබැද්දර පොලීසිය පවසයි.",
        "අතුරුදන් වූ පුද්ගලයන් අද (26) අඳුරු වැටෙන තෙක්ම සොයා මෙහෙයුම් සිදුකළ අතර ඒ වන තෙක් ඔවුන් සොයා ගැනීමට නොහැකි වී ඇති අතර නැවත හෙට (27) ඔවුන් සොයා මෙහෙයුම් සිදු කරන  බව පොලීසිය කියයි.",
        "මෙසේ අතුරුදන්ව ඇත්තේ දෙයියන්දර, පෝරතොට, වටවල අහංගම, මුලටියන ප්‍රදේශයවල පුද්ගලයන් බව පොලීසිය පවසයි.",
        "මොවුන් මිදිගම ප්‍රදේශයේ  රබර්  කර්මාන්තශාලාවක සේවය කරන පුද්ගලයන් බව අනාවරණය වී ඇති අතර මෙම කණ්ඩායම ත්‍රිරෝද රථවලින් පැමිණ ඇති බව මූලික පරීක්ෂණවලින් හෙළි වී ඇති අතර සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් පිටබැද්දර පොලීසිය වැඩි දුර පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හතර",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "නානිල්වල",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිල්වලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙහිගස්ප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙයියන්දර, පෝරතොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වටවල අහංගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුලටියන",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිදිගම ප්‍රදේශයේ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිටබැද්දර පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நானில்வாலா ஆற்றின் நான்கு ஆறுகள் வெள்ளத்தில் அடித்துச் செல்லப்படுகின்றன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிடபெத்தர, சியம்பலாகொட, தெஹிகஸ்ப பிரதேசத்தில் நில்வல என்ற இடத்தில் நீரில் நீராடச் சென்ற 12 பேரில் ஐவர் அடித்துச் செல்லப்பட்டதாகவும் அவர்களில் நால்வர் காணாமல் போயுள்ளதுடன் ஒருவர் உயிர் பிழைத்துள்ளதாகவும் பிடபெத்தர பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "காணாமல் போனவர்களை தேடும் நடவடிக்கைகள் இன்று (26) இருட்டாகும் வரை மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டதாகவும் அதுவரை அவர்களை கண்டுபிடிக்க முடியவில்லை எனவும் நாளை (27) மீண்டும் தேடவுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "காணாமல் போனவர்கள் டீயெந்தர, பொரதொட்ட, வட்டவல அஹங்கம மற்றும் முலட்டியான பிரதேசங்களைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள் என பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "இவர்கள் மிதிகம பிரதேசத்தில் உள்ள இறப்பர் தொழிற்சாலை ஒன்றில் பணிபுரிபவர்கள் என தெரியவந்துள்ளதுடன், முச்சக்கர வண்டிகளில் இந்த கும்பல் வந்துள்ளதாக ஆரம்பகட்ட விசாரணைகளில் தெரியவந்துள்ளதுடன், சம்பவம் தொடர்பான மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை பிடபெத்தரை பொலிஸார் மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நான்கு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "நானில்வாலா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நில்வாலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெஹிகாஸ்பா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டீயெந்தரா, பொரத்தோட்ட",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட்டவல அஹங்கம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முலதியான",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மிதிகம பிரதேசம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிடபெத்தரா காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}