{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78658",
  "time_ut": 1658257020,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President and United National Party Leader Ranil Wickremesinghe while thanking the majority in Parliament for electing him as the 8th Executive President of the country  invites all political parties in Parliament to join hands for the betterment of the country",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President and United National Party Leader Ranil Wickremesinghe while thanking the majority in Parliament for electing him as the 8th Executive President of the country  invites all political parties in Parliament to join hands for the betterment of the country",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "President and United National Party (UNP) Leader Ranil Wickremesinghe yesterday (20) invited all political parties in Parliament to join hands for the betterment of the country, while thanking the majority in Parliament for electing him as the 8th Executive President of the country.",
        "“I spent 45 years of my life in this Parliament. My life was spent in this Parliament. I thank this Parliament for giving me this honour. In 1993, when former President R. Premadasa was assassinated, we convened to select a new President. That was done so without an election. For the first time, in this second instance, we had an election. On the one hand, we showed that this Parliament can select a new President through a vote. I thank everybody who voted for me, and I also thank everybody who participated in this election,” said Wickremesinghe.",
        "He said that the country is in a deep crisis today, with the economic crisis, and noted that the youth are demanding a system change.",
        "“We need to build a new programme. The people are not asking for old politics, but for the Parliament to get together and work. I invite Alahapperuma to join hands with me. I also invite my friend Dissanayake, as he knows how bad the state of the country is at the moment. I also invite my friend Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) and Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa, the Tamil National Alliance (TNA) led by R. Sampanthan, the Tamil National People’s Front (TNPF) led by Ahila Ilankai Tamil Congress (AITC) MP G.G. Ponnambalam, Tamil Makkal Desiya Kuttani MP C.V. Wigneswaran, SLPP MP and former President Mahinda Rajapaksa, and SLPP ‘independent’ MP, Sri Lanka Freedom Party Chairman, and former President Maithripala Sirisena. We were on separate sides for the last 48 hours, but now I request all of you to join hands and begin discussions from tomorrow itself,” he said.",
        "SLPP MP, Minister, and Leader of the House Dinesh Gunawardena, who proposed Wickremesinghe’s name for the Presidential run on Tuesday (19), despite traditionally hailing from opposing political ideologies, said that he has utmost confidence in Wickremesinghe’s ability to lead Sri Lanka out of the current crisis.",
        "“Wickremesinghe is one of the most senior MPs, a former Premier, and senior Minister. He can fulfil his responsibilities and it was the people’s decision that was stated in Parliament today. As the Government side, we are proud that the governing side as well as the Opposition voted for our candidate. That need not be hidden. I have known you for 70 years, since I was a child. We may have different political ideas, but our humanity is the same, as well as the humanity of our countrymen. Your house got burnt, along with your books, which your father, and Leftist politicians Dr. N.M. Perera, Dr. Colvin R. De Silva, and Philip Gunawardena, took to the Welikada and Bogambara Prisons while being imprisoned during the British colonial times. We believe in impermanence in this country. The world has proven that nothing lasts forever. We must overcome this challenge,” said Gunawardena.",
        "Following a massive islandwide protest on 9 July demanding the resignation of former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, the latter resigned on 15 July. Parliament selected the new President through a vote, according to the Constitution, yesterday."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "United National Party",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "8th",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "45 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "R. Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dissanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Tamil National Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "R. Sampanthan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Tamil National People’s Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNPF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ahila Ilankai Tamil Congress",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.G. Ponnambalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Makkal Desiya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "C.V. Wigneswaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last 48 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "N.M. Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colvin R. De Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Philip Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welikada",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bogambara Prisons",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunawardena",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රටේ 8 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස තමන් තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ බහුතර පිරිසට ස්තූතිය පුද කරන අතරම, රටේ අභිවෘද්ධිය සඳහා අත්වැල් බැඳගන්නා ලෙස පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සියලු දේශපාලන පක්ෂවලට ආරාධනා කරන බව ජනාධිපති සහ එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ නායක රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පවසයි.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "රටේ 8 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස තමන් තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ බහුතර පිරිසට ස්තුතිය පුද කරන අතරම, රටේ අභිවෘද්ධිය සඳහා අත්වැල් බැඳගන්නා ලෙස ජනාධිපති සහ එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ නායක රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඊයේ (20) පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සියලුම දේශපාලන පක්ෂවලට ආරාධනා කළේය.",
        "“මම මගේ ජීවිතයේ අවුරුදු 45ක් ගත කළේ මේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ. මගේ ජීවිතය ගෙවුණේ මේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ. මට මේ ගෞරවය ලබා දීම ගැන මම මේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ස්තුතිවන්ත වෙනවා. 1993 දී හිටපු ජනාධිපති ආර්.ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ඝාතනය වූ අවස්ථාවේදී අපි නව ජනාධිපතිවරයකු තෝරා ගැනීමට රැස්වුණා. එහෙම කළේ මැතිවරණයකින් තොරවයි. පළමු වතාවට, මේ දෙවැනි අවස්ථාවේදී අපි මැතිවරණයක් තිබ්බා. එක පැත්තකින් අපි පෙන්නුවා මේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඡන්දයකින් අලුත් ජනාධිපතිවරයෙක් තෝරාගන්න පුළුවන් කියලා. මට ඡන්දය දුන් සියලු දෙනාටම මම ස්තුතිවන්ත වෙනවා වගේම මේ මැතිවරණයට සහභාගි වූ සියලු දෙනාටම මම ස්තුතිවන්ත වෙනවා,” වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ආර්ථික අර්බුදයත් සමඟ අද රට දැඩි අර්බුදයකට ලක්ව ඇති බවත්, තරුණයන් ක්‍රමවේද වෙනසක් ඉල්ලා සිටින බවත් ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "“අපි අලුත් වැඩපිළිවෙළක් හදන්න ඕන. ජනතාව ඉල්ලන්නේ පරණ දේශපාලනය නෙවෙයි, පාර්ලිමේන්තුව එකතු වෙලා වැඩ කරන්න කියලා. මා සමඟ අත්වැල් බැඳගන්නා ලෙස මම අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාට ආරාධනා කරනවා. මේ මොහොතේ රටේ තත්ත්වය කෙතරම් අයහපත් ද යන්න දන්නා බැවින් මම මගේ මිත්‍ර දිසානායකට ද ආරාධනා කරමි. මම මගේ මිත්‍ර සමගි ජන බලවේගයට (SJB) සහ විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාසට, R. සම්බන්ධන් නායකත්වය දෙන දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානය (TNA), අහිල ඉලංකෙයි දෙමළ කොංග්‍රසයේ (AITC) පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ජී.ජී. පොන්නම්බලම්, තමිල් මක්කල් දේශිය කුට්ටනි මන්ත්‍රී සී.වී. විග්නේෂ්වරන්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සහ හිටපු ජනාධිපති මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ 'ස්වාධීන' මන්ත්‍රී, ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ සභාපති සහ හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන. පහුගිය පැය 48 අපි වෙනම පැත්තක හිටියා, නමුත් දැන් මම ඔබ සියලු දෙනාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින්නේ අත්වැල් බැඳගෙන හෙට සිට සාකච්ඡා ආරම්භ කරන ලෙසයි.",
        "සාම්ප්‍රදායිකව විරුද්ධ දේශපාලන මතිමතාන්තරවලින් පැසසුමට ලක් වුවද අඟහරුවාදා (19) දින ජනාධිපතිවරණ සටනට වික්‍රමසිංහගේ නම යෝජනා කළ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී, අමාත්‍ය, සහ සභානායක දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් ගොඩ ඒමට වික්‍රමසිංහට ඇති හැකියාව පිළිබඳව තමාට උපරිම විශ්වාසයක් ඇති බව පැවසීය. වත්මන් අර්බුදය.",
        "“වික්‍රමසිංහ කියන්නේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨතම මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙක්, හිටපු අගමැතිවරයෙක්, ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ ඇමැතිවරයෙක්. ඔහුට තම වගකීම් ඉටු කළ හැකි බවත් අද පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ජනතා තීන්දුවයි. ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂය වගේම විපක්ෂයත් අපේ අපේක්ෂකයාට ඡන්දය දීම ගැන ආණ්ඩුව පැත්තෙන් අපිට ආඩම්බරයි. එය සැඟවිය යුතු නැත. මම ඔබව කුඩා කල සිටම අවුරුදු 70 ක් තිස්සේ හඳුනමි. අපට විවිධ දේශපාලන අදහස් තිබිය හැකි නමුත් අපගේ මනුෂ්‍යත්වය මෙන්ම අපේ රටවැසියන්ගේ මනුෂ්‍යත්වයද එකය. බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය යටත් විජිත සමයේ සිරගතව සිටියදී ඔබේ පියා සහ වාමාංශික දේශපාලනඥයන් වන ආචාර්ය එන්.එම්. පෙරේරා, ආචාර්ය කොල්වින් ආර්. ද සිල්වා සහ පිලිප් ගුණවර්ධන වැලිකඩ සහ බෝගම්බර බන්ධනාගාරවලට රැගෙන ගිය ඔබේ පොත්පත් සමඟ ඔබේ නිවසත් ගිනිබත් විය. අපි මේ රටේ අනිත්‍ය බව විශ්වාස කරනවා. කිසිවක් සදාකාලික නොවන බව ලෝකය ඔප්පු කර ඇත. අපි මේ අභියෝගය ජයගත යුතුයි.” ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බලකරමින් ජූලි 9 වැනිදා දිවයින පුරා පැවති දැවැන්ත විරෝධතාවයකින් අනතුරුව, ජුලි 15 වැනිදා ඔහු ඉල්ලා අස්විය. ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව ප්‍රකාරව ඡන්ද විමසීමකින් නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඊයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් තෝරාගනු ලැබුවා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "8 වැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 45 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටීඑන්ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර් සම්බන්ධන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ජාතික ජනතා පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNPF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අහිල ඉලංකෙයි දෙමළ කොංග්‍රසය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.ජී. පොන්නම්බලම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ මක්කල් දේශිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CV. විග්නේෂ්වරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය පැය 48",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 70 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්.එම් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොල්වින් ආර් ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිලිප් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෝගම්බර බන්ධනාගාරය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாட்டின் 8வது நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியாக தம்மை தெரிவு செய்தமைக்கு பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பெரும்பான்மையினருக்கு நன்றி தெரிவிக்கும் ஜனாதிபதியும் ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தலைவருமான ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, நாட்டின் முன்னேற்றத்திற்காக கைகோர்க்குமாறு பாராளுமன்றத்தில் உள்ள அனைத்து அரசியல் கட்சிகளுக்கும் அழைப்பு விடுக்கிறார்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டின் 8ஆவது நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரம் கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதியாக தம்மை தெரிவு செய்தமைக்காக பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பெரும்பான்மையினருக்கு நன்றி தெரிவிக்கும் அதேவேளை, நாட்டின் முன்னேற்றத்திற்காக கைகோர்க்குமாறு அனைத்து அரசியல் கட்சிகளுக்கும் ஜனாதிபதியும் ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தலைவருமான ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நேற்று (20) அழைப்பு விடுத்தார்.",
        "“நான் எனது வாழ்நாளில் 45 ஆண்டுகளை இந்த நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் கழித்தேன். எனது வாழ்க்கை இந்த பாராளுமன்றத்தில் கழிந்தது. இந்த பெருமையை எனக்கு வழங்கியதற்காக இந்த பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு நன்றி கூறுகிறேன். 1993ஆம் ஆண்டு முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி ஆர்.பிரேமதாச படுகொலை செய்யப்பட்ட போது புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்காக நாங்கள் கூடியிருந்தோம். அது தேர்தல் இல்லாமல் செய்யப்பட்டது. முதல் முறையாக, இந்த இரண்டாவது சந்தர்ப்பத்தில், நாங்கள் ஒரு தேர்தலை சந்தித்தோம். ஒருபுறம், இந்த பாராளுமன்றம் வாக்கெடுப்பு மூலம் புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தேர்ந்தெடுக்க முடியும் என்பதை நாங்கள் காட்டினோம். எனக்கு வாக்களித்த அனைவருக்கும் நான் நன்றி கூறுவதுடன், இந்த தேர்தலில் பங்குபற்றிய அனைவருக்கும் எனது நன்றியை தெரிவித்துக் கொள்கிறேன்” என்று விக்ரமசிங்க கூறினார்.",
        "பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியுடன் நாடு இன்று ஆழ்ந்த நெருக்கடியில் இருப்பதாகத் தெரிவித்த அவர், இளைஞர்கள் அமைப்பு மாற்றத்தை கோரி வருவதாகக் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "\"நாங்கள் ஒரு புதிய திட்டத்தை உருவாக்க வேண்டும். பழைய அரசியலை மக்கள் கேட்கவில்லை, நாடாளுமன்றம் ஒன்று கூடி செயல்பட வேண்டும். என்னுடன் கைகோர்க்க அழகப்பெருமாவை அழைக்கிறேன். நாட்டின் தற்போதைய நிலை எவ்வளவு மோசமாக உள்ளது என்பதை அறிந்த எனது நண்பர் திஸாநாயக்கவையும் நான் அழைக்கிறேன். எனது நண்பர் சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச, ஆர்.சம்பந்தன் தலைமையிலான தமிழ்த் தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பு (TNA), அகில இலங்கை தமிழ் காங்கிரஸ் (AITC) தலைமையிலான தமிழ் தேசிய மக்கள் முன்னணி (TNPF) பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் G.G. பொன்னம்பலம், தமிழ் மக்கள் தேசிய குட்டானி பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சி.வி. விக்னேஸ்வரன், ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினரும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷவும், ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் தலைவரும், முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேனவும், ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் ‘சுயேட்சை’ எம்.பி. கடந்த 48 மணி நேரமாக நாங்கள் தனித்தனியாக இருந்தோம், ஆனால் இப்போது நீங்கள் அனைவரும் கைகோர்த்து நாளையிலிருந்தே விவாதங்களைத் தொடங்குமாறு கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறேன், ”என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (19) ஜனாதிபதி வேட்பாளராக விக்ரமசிங்கவின் பெயரை முன்மொழிந்த ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர், அமைச்சரும், சபைத் தலைவருமான தினேஷ் குணவர்தன, பாரம்பரியமாக அரசியல் சித்தாந்தங்களை எதிர்த்த போதிலும், இலங்கையை வெளியே வழிநடத்தும் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் திறமையில் தனக்கு மிகுந்த நம்பிக்கை இருப்பதாகத் தெரிவித்தார். தற்போதைய நெருக்கடி.",
        "“விக்கிரமசிங்க மிக மூத்த பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களில் ஒருவர், முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மற்றும் மூத்த அமைச்சர். அவரால் தனது பொறுப்புகளை நிறைவேற்ற முடியும் எனவும் மக்களின் தீர்மானமே இன்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. ஆளும் தரப்பும் எதிர்க்கட்சியும் எங்கள் வேட்பாளருக்கு வாக்களித்ததையிட்டு அரசு தரப்பில் பெருமை கொள்கிறோம். அதை மறைக்க வேண்டியதில்லை. எனக்கு உங்களை 70 வருடங்களாக சின்ன வயசுல இருந்தே தெரியும். எங்களிடம் வெவ்வேறு அரசியல் கருத்துக்கள் இருக்கலாம், ஆனால் நமது மனிதாபிமானம் ஒன்றுதான், அதே போல் நம் நாட்டு மக்களின் மனித நேயமும் ஒன்றுதான். பிரித்தானியக் காலனித்துவக் காலத்தில் சிறையில் இருந்தபோது உங்கள் தந்தையும் இடதுசாரி அரசியல்வாதிகளான டாக்டர். என்.எம். பெரேரா, டொக்டர் கொல்வின் ஆர். டி சில்வா, பிலிப் குணவர்தன ஆகியோர் வெலிக்கடை மற்றும் போகம்பரா சிறைச்சாலைகளுக்குக் கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்ட உங்கள் புத்தகங்களுடன் உங்கள் வீடும் எரிக்கப்பட்டது. இந்த நாட்டில் நிலையற்ற தன்மையை நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம். எதுவும் நிரந்தரமில்லை என்பதை உலகம் நிரூபித்துள்ளது. இந்த சவாலை நாம் வெற்றிகொள்ள வேண்டும்” என குணவர்தன கூறினார்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவை பதவி விலகக் கோரி ஜூலை 9 ஆம் திகதி நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் நடைபெற்ற மாபெரும் ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தைத் தொடர்ந்து, அவர் ஜூலை 15 ஆம் திகதி பதவி விலகினார். அரசியலமைப்புச் சட்டத்தின்படி புதிய அதிபரை நாடாளுமன்றம் நேற்று வாக்கெடுப்பு மூலம் தேர்வு செய்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "8வது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "45 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்.பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் தேசிய கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்.சம்பந்தன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் தேசிய மக்கள் முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNPF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அகில இலங்கை தமிழ் காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.ஜி. பொன்னம்பலம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் மக்கள் தேசிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுயவிவரம். விக்னேஸ்வரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த 48 மணிநேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்கவின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்.எம் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொல்வின் ஆர். டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிலிப் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிக்கடை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "போகம்பரா சிறைச்சாலைகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}