{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/11/party-leaders-meeting-heats-up-pm-tries-to-move-proposal-to-purchase-fuel/",
  "time_ut": 1657537860,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Party Leaders meeting heats up, PM tries to move proposal to purchase fuel",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Party Leaders meeting heats up, PM tries to move proposal to purchase fuel",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lankan Party Leaders have decided to convene parliament on the 15th of July, two days after the President steps down.",
        "The Party Leaders including Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, Dinesh Gunawardena, Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa, Kumar Welgama, Dilan Perera Tiran Alles, Dullas Alahapperuma, Mano Ganesan, Lakshaman Kiriella, Rishad Bathiudeen, Udaya Gammanpila, and several other MPs had attended the crucial meeting on Monday (11) afternoon.",
        "MP Rauff Hakeem speaking to reporters said the nominations for the post of President will be taken up on the 19th of July, and then on the 20th of July, an election will be held.",
        "Sri Lanka Muslim Congress Leader Rauff Hakeem speaking to reporters said Ranil Wickremesinghe made another attempt at the meeting to seek the approval of party leaders to make fuel purchases.",
        "He said the party leaders opposed the decision to move such a proposal, adding that it was a decision to be made by the Cabinet of Ministers and NOT the Party Leaders.",
        "Rauf Hakeem said he will NOT accept Ranil Wickremesinghe as the Prime Minister, adding that Wickremesinghe is attempting to pass the blame on to the Party Leaders by moving a proposal at the meeting to make fuel purchases in the absence of any valid document.",
        "“Words were exchanged at the meeting,” said Rauff Hakeem adding that the objective is to form an all-party government, with a large number of ruling party MPs.",
        "He questioned by the President is not directing his decision to step down in writing to the speaker, rather than making phone calls.",
        "Rauff Hakeem said both the President and the Prime Minister must submit their resignations in writing."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 15th of July, two days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumar Welgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dilan Perera Tiran Alles",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakshaman Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Udaya Gammanpila",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11) afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rauff Hakeem",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 19th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 20th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Muslim",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rauff Hakeem",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Cabinet of Ministers and NOT the Party Leaders",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rauf Hakeem",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rauff Hakeem",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rauff Hakeem",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීම උණුසුම් වෙයි, අගමැති ඉන්ධන මිලදී ගැනීමේ යෝජනාව ගෙන ඒමට උත්සාහ කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්වී දින දෙකකට පසු ජූලි 15 වැනිදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කැඳවීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පක්ෂ නායකයින් තීරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන, විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස, කුමාර් වෙල්ගම, ඩිලාන් පෙරේරා ටිරාන් අලස්, ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම, මනෝ ගනේෂන්, ලක්ෂමන් කිරිඇල්ල, රිෂාඩ් බදියුදීන්, උදය ගම්මන්පිල ඇතුළු පක්ෂ නායකයින් ඇතුළු තවත් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පිරිසක් මෙම තීරණාත්මක රැස්වීමට සහභාගී වී සිටියහ. සඳුදා (11) පස්වරුවේ.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රවුෆ් හකීම් මහතා මාධ්‍ය වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් කියා සිටියේ ජනාධිපති ධූරය සඳහා නාමයෝජනා භාර ගැනීම ජූලි 19 වනදා සිදු කෙරෙන අතර අනතුරුව ජූලි 20 වනදා මැතිවරණයක් පැවැත්වෙන බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුස්ලිම් කොංග්‍රසයේ නායක රවුෆ් හකීම් මාධ්‍යවේදීන් අමතමින් කියා සිටියේ ඉන්ධන මිලදී ගැනීම සඳහා පක්ෂ නායකයින්ගේ අනුමැතිය ලබාගැනීමට රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා රැස්වීමේදී තවත් උත්සාහයක් ගත් බවයි.",
        "එවැනි යෝජනාවක් ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට ගත් තීරණයට පක්ෂ නායකයින් විරුද්ධ බව පැවසූ ඔහු එය ගත යුත්තේ පක්ෂ නායකයන් නොව අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය විසින් බව ද පැවසීය.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධූරයට නොපිළිගන්නා බව පැවසූ රවුෆ් හකීම් මහතා, කිසිදු වලංගු ලියවිල්ලක් නොමැති අවස්ථාවක ඉන්ධන මිලදී ගැනීමේ යෝජනාවක් මෙම රැස්වීමේදී ඉදිරිපත් කරමින් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා එම චෝදනාව පක්ෂ නායකයන් මත පැටවීමට උත්සාහ කරන බවද පැවසීය.",
        "“රැස්වීමේදී වචන හුවමාරු වුණා,” ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් විශාල සංඛ්‍යාවක් සිටින සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම අරමුණ බවද රවුෆ් හකීම් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ඔහු ප්‍රශ්න කළේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට ගත් තීරණය දුරකථන ඇමතුම් ලබා දෙනවාට වඩා ලිඛිතව කථානායකවරයාට යොමු නොකිරීමයි.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලිඛිතව ඉල්ලා අස්වීම් ලබාදිය යුතු බව රවුෆ් හකීම් මහතා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 15, දින දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩිලාන් පෙරේරා ටිරාන් අලස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂමන් කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදය ගම්මන්පිල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රවුෆ් හකීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 19 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුස්ලිම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොංග්රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රවුෆ් හකීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය මිස පක්ෂ නායකයන් නොවේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රවුෆ් හකීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රවුෆ් හකීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රවුෆ් හකීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டம் சூடுபிடித்துள்ளது, எரிபொருள் வாங்கும் திட்டத்தை பிரதமர் மாற்ற முயற்சிக்கிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஜனாதிபதி பதவி விலகி இரண்டு நாட்களுக்குப் பின்னர் எதிர்வரும் ஜூலை மாதம் 15ஆம் திகதி நாடாளுமன்றத்தைக் கூட்டுவதற்கு இலங்கைக் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் தீர்மானித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, தினேஸ் குணவர்தன, எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச, குமார் வெல்கம, டிலான் பெரேரா திரான் அலஸ், டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும, மனோ கணேசன், லக்‌ஷமன் கிரியெல்ல, ரிஷாத் பதியுதீன், உதய கம்மன்பில உள்ளிட்ட கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் மற்றும் பல பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் இந்த கூட்டத்தில் கலந்துகொண்டனர். திங்கட்கிழமை (11) பிற்பகல்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரவூப் ஹக்கீம் செய்தியாளர்களிடம் பேசுகையில், ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான வேட்புமனுக்கள் ஜூலை 19 ஆம் திகதி பரிசீலனைக்கு எடுத்துக் கொள்ளப்படும், பின்னர் ஜூலை 20 ஆம் திகதி தேர்தல் நடத்தப்படும்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா முஸ்லிம் காங்கிரஸின் தலைவர் ரவூப் ஹக்கீம் செய்தியாளர்களிடம் பேசுகையில், எரிபொருள் கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்கு கட்சித் தலைவர்களின் ஒப்புதலைப் பெறுவதற்கு ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றுமொரு முயற்சியை மேற்கொண்டார்.",
        "அத்தகைய பிரேரணையை முன்வைக்கும் முடிவை கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் எதிர்த்ததாகவும், இது அமைச்சரவையால் எடுக்கப்பட வேண்டிய முடிவு என்றும் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் அல்ல என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை பிரதமராக ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப் போவதில்லை எனத் தெரிவித்த ரவூப் ஹக்கீம், உரிய ஆவணம் இல்லாத நிலையில் எரிபொருள் கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்கான யோசனையை இந்தக் கூட்டத்தில் முன்வைத்து கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் மீது பழியைப் போட விக்கிரமசிங்க முயற்சிக்கிறார்.",
        "இந்த சந்திப்பில் வார்த்தைகள் பரிமாறப்பட்டதாக ரவூப் ஹக்கீம் மேலும் தெரிவிக்கையில், அதிக எண்ணிக்கையிலான ஆளும் கட்சி பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களைக் கொண்ட சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பதே நோக்கமாகும்.",
        "தொலைபேசி அழைப்புகளை விடுத்து, சபாநாயகருக்கு எழுத்து மூலம் பதவி விலகுவதற்கான தனது முடிவை ஜனாதிபதி வழங்கவில்லை என அவர் கேள்வி எழுப்பியுள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமர் இருவரும் தமது இராஜினாமாக்களை எழுத்து மூலம் சமர்ப்பிக்க வேண்டும் என ரவூப் ஹக்கீம் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 15, இரண்டு நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பார்ட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார் வெல்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திலான் பெரேரா திரன் அலஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்ஷமன் கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உதய கம்மன்பில",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11) பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரவூப் ஹக்கீம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 19 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை முஸ்லிம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரவூப் ஹக்கீம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரிசபை மற்றும் கட்சி தலைவர்கள் அல்ல",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரவூப் ஹக்கீம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரவூப் ஹக்கீம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரவூப் ஹக்கீம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}