{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/29/prison-inmates-pass-a-l-examination-in-sri-lanka/",
  "time_ut": 1661769840,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Prison inmates pass A/L examination in Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Prison inmates pass A/L examination in Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Several Prison inmates held in Sri Lankan prisons have passed the G. C. E. Advanced Level Examination.",
        "The Department of Prisons said that each year, in collaboration with the Department of Examinations directs eligible inmates for high education.",
        "Accordingly, three prisoners held at the Magazine Prison in Colombo were permitted to set for the  G. C. E. Advanced Level Examination for 2021.",
        "A 38-year-old special grade inmate, a former LTTE cadre, had obtained C passes for Geology, and Hindu Heritage and an S pass for Tamil Language.",
        "A 46-year-old inmate held at the Welikada Prison also passed the had passed the examination with S passes for Political Science, Buddhist Heritage, and Sinhala.",
        "Another prisoner also from the Welikada Prison had passed the examination, said Prisons Commission Chandana Ekanayake.",
        "Weerawansa & Co. to form new ‘Historic Alliance’ on 4th September"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the G. C. E. Advanced Level Examination",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department of Prisons",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "each year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Examinations",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Magazine Prison in Colombo",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "38-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LTTE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu Heritage",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Language",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "46-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Welikada Prison",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Political Science",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhist Heritage",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Welikada Prison",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prisons Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandana Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Weerawansa & Co.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "September",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බන්ධනාගාර රැඳවියෝ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ උසස් පෙළ සමත් වෙති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බන්ධනාගාරවල රඳවා සිටින බන්ධනාගාර රැඳවියන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු G. C. E. උසස් පෙළ විභාගය සමත් වී ඇත.",
        "සෑම වසරකම විභාග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සමඟ එක්ව සුදුසුකම් ලත් රැඳවියන් උසස් අධ්‍යාපනය සඳහා යොමු කරන බව බන්ධනාගාර දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව, කොළඹ මැගසින් බන්ධනාගාරයේ රඳවා සිටින සිරකරුවන් තිදෙනෙකුට 2021 වසර සඳහා  G. C. E. උසස් පෙළ විභාගයට පෙනී සිටීමට අවසර ලැබිණි.",
        "හිටපු එල්ටීටීඊ සාමාජිකයෙකු වන 38 හැවිරිදි විශේෂ ශ්‍රේණියේ සිරකරුවෙකු භූ විද්‍යාව සහ හින්දු උරුමය සඳහා C සාමාර්ථයක් සහ දෙමළ භාෂාව සඳහා S සාමාර්ථයක් ලබාගෙන ඇත.",
        "වැලිකඩ බන්ධනාගාරයේ රඳවා සිටි 46 හැවිරිදි රැඳවියෙක් ද දේශපාලන විද්‍යාව, බෞද්ධ උරුමය සහ සිංහල විෂයයන් සඳහා එස් සාමාර්ථ සහිතව විභාගය සමත්ව ඇත.",
        "වැලිකඩ බන්ධනාගාරයේ සිටි තවත් සිරකරුවෙකු ද විභාගය සමත්ව සිටි බව බන්ධනාගාර කොමිසම චන්දන ඒකනායක මහතා පවසයි.",
        "වීරවංශ සහ සමාගම සැප්තැම්බර් 4 වැනිදා නව ‘ඓතිහාසික සන්ධානයක්’ පිහිටුවීමට"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "G. C. E. උසස් පෙළ විභාගය",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බන්ධනාගාර දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෑම වසරකම",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විභාග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ මැගසින් බන්ධනාගාරය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "38 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්ටීටීඊය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු උරුමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ භාෂාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "46 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩ බන්ධනාගාරය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දේශපාලන විද්යාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ උරුමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩ බන්ධනාගාරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්ධනාගාර කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්දන ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වීරවංශ සහ සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சிறைக் கைதிகள் இலங்கையில் உயர்தரப் பரீட்சையில் சித்தியடைந்துள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கை சிறைகளில் தடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பல சிறைக் கைதிகள் G. C. E. உயர்தரப் பரீட்சையில் சித்தியடைந்துள்ளனர்.",
        "ஒவ்வொரு வருடமும் பரீட்சைகள் திணைக்களத்துடன் இணைந்து உயர்கல்விக்கு தகுதியான கைதிகளை வழிநடத்தி வருவதாக சிறைச்சாலைகள் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி, கொழும்பில் உள்ள மெகசின் சிறைச்சாலையில் தடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த மூன்று கைதிகள்  G. C. E. உயர்தரப் பரீட்சைக்கு 2021 ஆம் ஆண்டிற்கான அனுமதியளிக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "38 வயதுடைய சிறப்புத் தரக் கைதி, முன்னாள் விடுதலைப் புலி உறுப்பினர், புவியியல், இந்து மரபு ஆகியவற்றுக்கான சி சித்திகளையும் தமிழ் மொழிக்கான எஸ் சித்தியையும் பெற்றிருந்தார்.",
        "வெலிக்கடை சிறைச்சாலையில் தடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த 46 வயது கைதியும் பரீட்சையில் சித்தியடைந்து அரசியல் விஞ்ஞானம், பௌத்த பாரம்பரியம் மற்றும் சிங்களம் ஆகிய பாடங்களுக்கு எஸ் சித்தியுடன் சித்தியடைந்துள்ளார்.",
        "வெலிக்கடை சிறைச்சாலையில் உள்ள மற்றுமொரு கைதியும் பரீட்சையில் சித்தியடைந்துள்ளதாக சிறைச்சாலைகள் ஆணைக்குழு சந்தன ஏக்கநாயக்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "வீரவன்ச & கோ. செப்டம்பர் 4 ஆம் தேதி புதிய ‘வரலாற்று கூட்டணியை’ உருவாக்க உள்ளது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "G. C. E. உயர்நிலைத் தேர்வு",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிறைத்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒவ்வொரு வருடமும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பரீட்சைகள் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் உள்ள மெகசின் சிறை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "38 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விடுதலைப் புலிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து பாரம்பரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் மொழி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "46 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிக்கடை சிறைச்சாலை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியல் அறிவியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த பாரம்பரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்களம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெலிக்கடை சிறைச்சாலை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறை ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்தன ஏகநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீரவன்ச & கோ.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}