{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/කෘෂි-නියෝජිතයෝ-යූරියා-මිටියෙන්-ගසා-කති/1-616830",
  "time_ut": 1658413447,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කෘෂි නියෝජිතයෝ යූරියා මිටියෙන් ගසා කති",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Agricultural representatives beat urea with hammer",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Farmers have alleged that some representatives of farmers' organizations are running a racket of collecting money from them as rent of 250, 300, 500, 1000 rupees for each bundle of fertilizer during the supply of urea fertilizer by the government to the farmers in Polonnaruwa.",
        "The farmers point out that they unload the bales of fertilizer themselves, and even though they do so, some representatives of farmers' organizations are doing unfair things by charging them money as rent for unloading the urea fertilizer.",
        "The farmers also mention that the farmers' organizations such as Manampitiya, Dalukana, Alleweva, Sanshiyya, Maguldamana have collected 250 to 1000 rupees as unloading rent.",
        "That power cut was allowed for 2 hours and 30 minutes from 6.00 am to 8.30 am for Colombo cities and AITCC category, and for 3 hours from 5.00 am to 8.00 am for M, N, O, X, Y and Z zones. Chairman of the Public Utilities Commission Mr. Janaka Ratnayake said further."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polonnaruwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Manampitiya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dalukana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alleweva",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanshiyya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maguldamana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2 hours and 30 minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.30 am",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janaka Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කෘෂි නියෝජිතයෝ යූරියා මිටියෙන් ගසා කති",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පොළොන්නරුවේ ගොවීන්ට රජය මගින් යූරියා පොහොර ලබාදීමේදී ඇතැම් ගොවි සංවිධාන නියෝජිතයන් පොහොර මිටියට බෑවුම් කුලී වශයෙන් තමන්ගෙන් රුපියල් 250, 300, 500,1000 බැගින් මුදල් එකතු කිරීමේ ජාවාරමක් ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන බව ගොවීහු චෝදනා කරති.",
        "තමන් විසින්ම එම පොහොර මිටි බා ගන්නා බවත්, එසේ බා ගත්තද සමහර ගොවි සංවිධාන නියෝජිතයන් මෙම යූරියා පොහොර බෑමේ කුලි ලෙස තමන්ගෙන් මුදල් අයකර ගනිමින් අසාධාරණ කම් සිදුකරන බවද ගොවීන් පෙන්වා දෙති.",
        "මේ වනවිට මනම්පිටිය, දළුකාන, ඇල්ලෙවැව, පැළෑටියාව, මගුල්දමන, යන ගොවි සංවිධාන එලෙස බෑමේ කුලි ලෙස රුපියල් 250 සිට 1000 දක්වා එකතු කරගෙන ඇති බවද ගොවීහු සඳහන් කරති.",
        "මෙම චෝදනාව පිළිබඳ පොලොන්නරුව ගොවිජන සංවර්ධන සහකාර කොමසාරිස් අරුණ නිරෝෂන් වීරකෝන් මහතාගෙන් දුරකථනයෙන් කල විමසීමකදී සඳහන් කළේ තමන් එවැනි මුදලක් ගොවි සංවිධානවලට එකතු කිරීමට උපදෙස් ලබාදී නෑ. ගොවියකු පොහොර මිටියක් සඳහා රුපියල් 10,000 ක මුදලක් ගොවිජන සේවා මධ්‍යස්ථානයට ලබාදී තිබෙනවා. එම මුදලට ගොවිජන සේවා මධ්‍යස්ථානයට අදාල පොහොර තොග ප්‍රවාහනය කර දීමෙන් පසු ගොවීන් එය බරගත යුතුයි. වෙනම බෑමේ සහ ප්‍රවාහනය කිරීමේ කුලියක් එකතු කිරීමට තමා උපදෙස් ලබාදී නෑ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොළොන්නරුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මනම්පිටිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දළුකාන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇලවේවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංෂිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මගුල්දමන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පැය 2 යි විනාඩි 30 යි",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.30 ට",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 3",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජානක රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "விவசாய பிரதிநிதிகள் யூரியாவை சுத்தியலால் அடித்தனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொலன்னறுவையில் உள்ள விவசாயிகளுக்கு அரசாங்கம் யூரியா உரம் வழங்கும் போது ஒவ்வொரு உர மூட்டைக்கும் 250, 300, 500, 1000 ரூபா வாடகை என விவசாய அமைப்புகளின் பிரதிநிதிகள் சிலர் பணம் வசூலிக்கும் மோசடியில் ஈடுபட்டு வருவதாக விவசாயிகள் குற்றம் சாட்டியுள்ளனர்.",
        "உர மூட்டைகளை தாங்களே இறக்கி விடுவதாகவும், அவ்வாறு செய்தாலும் விவசாய அமைப்புகளின் பிரதிநிதிகள் சிலர் யூரியா உரத்தை இறக்குவதற்கு வாடகையாக பணம் வசூலித்து அநியாயத்தை செய்து வருவதாக விவசாயிகள் சுட்டிக்காட்டுகின்றனர்.",
        "மனம்பிட்டிய, தலுகான, அல்லேவெவ, சன்ஷியா, மகுல்தமன போன்ற விவசாய அமைப்புக்கள் 250 முதல் 1000 ரூபா வரை இறக்கும் வாடகையாக வசூலித்துள்ளதாகவும் விவசாயிகள் குறிப்பிடுகின்றனர்.",
        "இந்த குற்றச்சாட்டு தொடர்பில் பொலன்னறுவை விவசாய அபிவிருத்தி உதவி ஆணையாளர் திரு. அருண நிரோஷன் வீரகோன் தொலைபேசி மூலம் வினவிய போது, ​​விவசாய அமைப்புகளுக்கு அவ்வாறான பணத்தை அறவிடுமாறு பணிப்புரை வழங்கவில்லை என தெரிவித்தார். ஒரு மூட்டை உரத்துக்காக விவசாயி ஒருவர் 10,000 ரூபாயை விவசாய சேவை நிலையத்திற்கு வழங்கியுள்ளார். அந்த தொகைக்கு உர இருப்புகளை வேளாண் சேவை மையத்திற்கு கொண்டு சென்ற பின் விவசாயிகள் எடை போட வேண்டும். தனியாக இறக்குதல் மற்றும் போக்குவரத்து கட்டணம் வசூலிக்க அவர் அறிவுறுத்தவில்லை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலன்னறுவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மனம்பிட்டிய",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலுகானா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அல்லேவேவா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சன்ஷியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகுல்தமன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2 மணி 30 நிமிடங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 8.30 மணி",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனக ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}