{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83821/president-appoints-committee-to-probe-bribery-allegations-against-nimal-siripala",
  "time_ut": 1658553480,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President appoints committee to probe bribery allegations against Nimal Siripala",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President appoints committee to probe bribery allegations against Nimal Siripala",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe has appointed a three-member committee to conduct an investigation into the bribery allegations levelled by Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa against former Minister Nimal Siripala de Silva.",
        "The committee is chaired by Retired High Court Judge, Kusala Sarojini Weerawardena, PC. Retired Senior Deputy Inspector-General (DIG) of Police S.M. Wickremasinghe and Retired Special Grade Officer of Sri Lanka Administrative Service (SLAS) S.M.G.K. Perera will serve as its members.",
        "President Wickremesinghe appointed this committee taking into account the request made by the former minister seeking an impartial probe into the matter raised by the Opposition Leader at a parliamentary session, based on the news item published in the social, print and electronic media that a cabinet minister had demanded a bribe from Japan’s Taisei Company.",
        "The committee has been instructed to submit its report on the investigation to President Wickremesinghe before July 31."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Nimal Siripala",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kusala Sarojini Weerawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "DIG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Police S.M. Wickremasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Administrative Service",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taisei Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නිමල් සිරිපාලට එරෙහි අල්ලස් චෝදනා සෙවීමට ජනපති කමිටුවක් පත් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු අමාත්‍ය නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා මහතාට එරෙහිව විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා විසින් එල්ල කරන ලද අල්ලස් චෝදනා සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමර්ශනයක් සිදු කිරීම සඳහා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් ත්‍රිපුද්ගල කමිටුවක් පත් කර තිබේ.",
        "විශ්‍රාමලත් මහාධිකරණ විනිසුරු කුසලා සරෝජිනී වීරවර්ධන මහත්මියගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් කමිටුව කටයුතු කරයි. විශ්‍රාමික ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති (ඩීඅයිජී) එස්.එම්. වික්‍රමසිංහ සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පරිපාලන සේවයේ විශ්‍රාමික විශේෂ ශ්‍රේණියේ නිලධාරි (SLAS) S.M.G.K. පෙරේරා එහි සාමාජිකයන් ලෙස කටයුතු කරනු ඇත.",
        "කැබිනට් අමාත්‍යවරයකු බවට සමාජ, මුද්‍රිත සහ විද්‍යුත් මාධ්‍යවල පළ වූ පුවත පදනම් කර ගනිමින් විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසිවාරයේදී මතු කළ කරුණු සම්බන්ධයෙන් අපක්ෂපාතී පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා හිටපු අමාත්‍යවරයා කළ ඉල්ලීම සැලකිල්ලට ගනිමින් ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මෙම කමිටුව පත් කළේය. ජපානයේ Taisei සමාගමෙන් අල්ලසක් ඉල්ලා තිබුණා.",
        "විමර්ශනයට අදාළ වාර්තාව ජූලි මස 31 වැනිදාට පෙර ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වෙත ලබාදෙන ලෙසට එම කමිටුවට උපදෙස් දී තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුසලා සරෝජිනී වීරවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.අයි.ජී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් එස්.එම්. වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පරිපාලන සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taisei Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நிமல் சிறிபாலவுக்கு எதிரான இலஞ்ச ஊழல் குற்றச்சாட்டுகளை விசாரிக்க ஜனாதிபதி குழுவொன்றை நியமித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வாவுக்கு எதிராக எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச முன்வைத்துள்ள இலஞ்ச ஊழல் குற்றச்சாட்டு தொடர்பில் விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொள்வதற்காக ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மூவரடங்கிய குழுவொன்றை நியமித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இந்தக் குழுவின் தலைவராக ஓய்வுபெற்ற உயர்நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதி குசலா சரோஜினி வீரவர்தன, பி.சி. ஓய்வுபெற்ற மூத்த துணை காவல் கண்காணிப்பாளர் (டிஐஜி) எஸ்.எம். விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றும் இலங்கை நிர்வாக சேவையின் (SLAS) ஓய்வுபெற்ற விசேட தர அதிகாரி எஸ்.எம்.ஜி.கே. பெரேரா அதன் உறுப்பினர்களாக பணியாற்றவுள்ளனர்.",
        "சமூக, அச்சு மற்றும் இலத்திரனியல் ஊடகங்களில் வெளியான செய்தியின் அடிப்படையில், நாடாளுமன்ற அமர்வில் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் எழுப்பிய விடயம் தொடர்பில் பக்கச்சார்பற்ற விசாரணை நடத்துமாறு கோரி முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் விடுத்த கோரிக்கையை கருத்திற் கொண்டு ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க இந்தக் குழுவை நியமித்துள்ளார். ஜப்பானின் தைசே நிறுவனத்திடம் லஞ்சம் கேட்டிருந்தார்.",
        "விசாரணைகள் தொடர்பான அறிக்கையை ஜூலை 31ஆம் திகதிக்கு முன்னர் ஜனாதிபதி விக்ரமசிங்கவிடம் சமர்ப்பிக்குமாறு குழுவுக்கு அறிவுறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குசலா சரோஜினி வீரவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.ஐ.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "போலீஸ் எஸ்.எம். விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை நிர்வாக சேவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taisei Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}