{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/23/electric-buses-three-wheelers-soon-to-sl/",
  "time_ut": 1661233560,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Electric Buses & Three-wheelers soon to SL",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Electric Buses & Three-wheelers soon to SL",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka's Ministry of Transport and Highways is exploring the possibility of launching an electric bus service in the country.",
        "A preliminary level discussion took place at the Transport Ministry on Monday (22) with UNDP representatives.",
        "The United Nations Development Program has decided to extend its support towards electric three-wheelers and buses in Sri Lanka to reduce the effect of the fuel crisis and the harmful impact of fossil fuel use on the environment.",
        "Under the E-Mobility program implemented as a pilot project of UNDP, it is expected to convert 300 three-wheelers to run on electric power this year and prepare a system for that. The UNDP has allocated one million US dollars for the project.",
        "The Government Information Department said that the discussion focused on the possibility of converting the three-wheelers in Sri Lanka to run on electricity.",
        "The United Nations Development Program has allocated three million US dollars for the entire project.",
        "SL Navy seizes poaching trawler in Sri Lanka’s waters off Mullaitivu"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Electric Buses & Three-wheelers",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Transport",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Transport Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The United Nations Development Program",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one million US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Government Information Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The United Nations Development Program",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three million US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mullaitivu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විදුලි බස් සහ ත්‍රිරෝද රථ ළඟදීම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රවාහන හා මහාමාර්ග අමාත්‍යාංශය විදුලි බස් සේවාවක් රට තුළ ආරම්භ කිරීමේ හැකියාව සොයා බලමින් සිටී.",
        "UNDP නියෝජිතයන් සමඟ පෙරේදා (22) ප්‍රවාහන අමාත්‍යාංශයේදී මූලික මට්ටමේ සාකච්ඡාවක් පැවැත්විණි.",
        "ඉන්ධන අර්බුදයේ බලපෑම සහ පොසිල ඉන්ධන භාවිතයෙන් පරිසරයට සිදුවන අහිතකර බලපෑම් අවම කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදුලි ත්‍රිරෝද රථ සහ බස් රථ සඳහා සහය ලබාදීමට එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවර්ධන වැඩසටහන තීරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "UNDP හි නියමු ව්‍යාපෘතියක් ලෙස ක්‍රියාත්මක E-Mobility වැඩසටහන යටතේ මේ වසරේ ත්‍රිරෝද රථ 300ක් විදුලි බලයෙන් ධාවනය කිරීමට පරිවර්තනය කර ඒ සඳහා ක්‍රමවේදයක් සකස් කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වේ. මෙම ව්‍යාපෘතිය සඳහා UNDP විසින් ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියනයක් වෙන් කර ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ත්‍රිරෝද රථ විදුලි බලයෙන් ධාවනය කිරීමට ඇති හැකියාව පිළිබඳව මෙම සාකච්ඡාවේදී අවධානය යොමු වූ බව රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවර්ධන වැඩසටහන මගින් සම්පූර්ණ ව්‍යාපෘතිය සඳහා ඩොලර් මිලියන තුනක් වෙන් කර ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් මුලතිව් මුහුදු තීරයේදී දඩයම් කළ ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රාවක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "විදුලි බස් සහ ත්‍රිරෝද රථ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රවාහන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්රවාහන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවර්ධන වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියනයක්",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවර්ධන වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන තුනක්",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුලතිව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மின்சார பேருந்துகள் மற்றும் முச்சக்கர வண்டிகள் விரைவில் இலங்கைக்கு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கையின் போக்குவரத்து மற்றும் நெடுஞ்சாலைகள் அமைச்சு நாட்டில் மின்சார பஸ் சேவையை ஆரம்பிப்பதற்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகளை ஆராய்ந்து வருகிறது.",
        "UNDP பிரதிநிதிகளுடன் திங்கட்கிழமை (22) போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சில் ஆரம்ப நிலை கலந்துரையாடல் இடம்பெற்றது.",
        "இலங்கையில் எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடி மற்றும் புதைபடிவ எரிபொருள் பாவனையால் சுற்றுச்சூழலுக்கு ஏற்படும் தீங்கான தாக்கத்தை குறைப்பதற்காக மின்சார முச்சக்கர வண்டிகள் மற்றும் பேருந்துகளுக்கு தனது ஆதரவை வழங்க ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் அபிவிருத்தி திட்டம் தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "யுஎன்டிபியின் முன்னோடித் திட்டமாக செயல்படுத்தப்படும் இ-மொபிலிட்டி திட்டத்தின் கீழ், இந்த ஆண்டு 300 முச்சக்கர வண்டிகளை மின்சாரத்தில் இயங்கும் வகையில் மாற்றி, அதற்கான அமைப்பைத் தயாரிக்கும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது. UNDP திட்டத்திற்காக ஒரு மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களை ஒதுக்கியுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையில் உள்ள முச்சக்கர வண்டிகளை மின்சாரத்தில் இயங்கும் வகையில் மாற்றுவது தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடப்பட்டதாக அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் அபிவிருத்தித் திட்டம் முழுத் திட்டத்திற்கும் மூன்று மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களை ஒதுக்கியுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் முல்லைத்தீவு கடற்பரப்பில் வேட்டையாடிய இழுவை படகை கைப்பற்றியுள்ளனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மின்சார பேருந்துகள் மற்றும் முச்சக்கர வண்டிகள்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் வளர்ச்சித் திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் வளர்ச்சித் திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முல்லைத்தீவு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}