{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/රන්ජන්ට-කොන්දෙසි--සහිත-සමාවක්/11-396623",
  "time_ut": 1661493561,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රන්ජන්ට කොන්දෙසි  සහිත සමාවක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A conditional pardon for Ranjan",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickramasinghe today (26) signed the document regarding the granting of conditional presidential pardon to former state minister Ranjan Ramanayake, who was convicted and sentenced to prison for contempt of court.",
        "This pardon comes under the condition that he will not make any statement or act that will insult the court henceforth.",
        "Arrangements have also been made to assign the Secretary of the Ministry of Justice to carry out further work regarding the release of Mr. Ranjan Ramanayake.",
        "Mr. Ranjan Ramanayake issued an affidavit and apologized for insulting the court yesterday (25).",
        "It has been stated in the affidavit that the statements made by him are completely wrong and he apologizes for causing disrespect to everyone in the legal field including the Chief Justice."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranjan",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රන්ජන්ට කොන්දෙසි  සහිත සමාවක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් වරදකරුවී සිර දඬුවම් ලබන හිටපු රාජ්‍ය ඇමති රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතාට කොන්දේ්සි සහිිත ජනාධිපති සමාව ලබාදීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් වූ ලේඛනයට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අද (26) අත්සන් තැබීය.",
        "මින් ඉදිරියට අධිකරණයට අපහාස වන කිසිදු ප්‍රකාශයක් හෝ ක්‍රියාවක් සිදු නොකරන ලෙස වන කොන්දේසිය යටතේ මෙම සමාව ලැබෙයි.",
        "රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතාට නිදහස ලබාදීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉදිරි කටයුතු සිදුකිරීමට අධිකරණ අමාත්‍යාංශ ලේකම්වරයාට පැවරීමට ද කටයුතු කර තිබේ.",
        "රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා දිවුරුම් ප්‍රකාශයක් යොමු කරමින් අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සමාව අයදීම ඊයේ (25) සිදු කළේය.",
        "තමන් සිදු කළ ප්‍රකාශ සම්පූර්ණයෙන් වැරදි බවත් එම ප්‍රකාශය නිසා අගවිනිසුරු ඇතුළු නීති ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ සියලුදෙනාට අගෞරවයක් ඇතිවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සමාව ඉල්ලා සිටින බවත් එම දිවුරුම් ප්‍රකාශයේ සඳහන් කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රන්ජන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණ අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரஞ்சனுக்கு நிபந்தனையுடன் கூடிய மன்னிப்பு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதித்த குற்றச்சாட்டில் தண்டனை பெற்று சிறைத்தண்டனை விதிக்கப்பட்ட முன்னாள் இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி நிபந்தனையுடன் கூடிய மன்னிப்பு வழங்குவது தொடர்பான ஆவணத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இன்று (26) கையொப்பமிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இனி நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதிக்கும் வகையில் எந்த ஒரு அறிக்கையையும், செயலையும் அவர் வெளியிட மாட்டார் என்ற நிபந்தனையின் கீழ் இந்த மன்னிப்பு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "திரு.ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவின் விடுதலை தொடர்பான மேலதிக பணிகளை மேற்கொள்வதற்கு நீதி அமைச்சின் செயலாளரை நியமிக்கவும் ஏற்பாடுகள் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதித்ததற்காக திரு.ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க நேற்று (25) சத்தியக் கடதாசி ஒன்றை வெளியிட்டு மன்னிப்புக் கோரினார்.",
        "அவர் கூறிய கருத்துகள் முற்றிலும் தவறானவை என்றும், தலைமை நீதிபதி உட்பட சட்டத்துறையில் உள்ள அனைவருக்கும் அவமரியாதையை ஏற்படுத்தியதற்காக மன்னிப்புக் கோருவதாகவும் அந்த வாக்குமூலத்தில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரஞ்சன்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நீதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}