{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/සිරස-මාධ්‍යවේදීන්-පිරිසකට-ආරක්ෂක-අංශයෙන්-ප්‍රහාරයක්/101-616142",
  "time_ut": 1657380335,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "සිරස මාධ්‍යවේදීන් පිරිසකට ආරක්ෂක අංශයෙන් ප්‍රහාරයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "An attack by security forces on a group of journalists in Sirasa",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Four Sirasa journalists who went to report a protest in front of the Prime Minister's private residence were attacked by the security forces and four including a female journalist were admitted to the Colombo National Hospital for treatment.",
        "Sirasa Madhavedi, who was attacked, said that the attack was carried out by a group of police special forces.",
        "Media Day and others who were attacked are currently receiving treatment at the Colombo National Hospital"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sirasa",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo National Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sirasa Madhavedi",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Colombo National Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සිරස මාධ්‍යවේදීන් පිරිසකට ආරක්ෂක අංශයෙන් ප්‍රහාරයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අගමැති පෞද්ගලික නිවෙසට ඉදිරිපිට පැවැති විරෝධතාවක් වාර්තා කිරිමට ගිය සිරස මාධ්‍යවේදීන් සිවු දෙනකුට ආරක්ෂක අංශ වෙතින් ප්‍රහාරයක් එල්ලවීමෙන් තුවාල ලැබූ මාධ්‍යවේදිනියක ඇතුළු සිවු දෙනකු ප්‍රතිකාර සඳහා කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කර තිබේ.",
        "පොලිස් විශේෂ බළකා සාමාජිකයන් පිරිසක් මෙම ප්‍රහාරය එලල කර ඇතැයි පහරකෑමට ලක් වූ සිරස මාධවේදීහු පවසති.",
        "පහරකෑමට ලක්වූ මාධ්‍යවේදිනය ඇතුළු පිරිස මේ වන විට කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහලේ ප්‍රතිකාර ලබති"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සිරස",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිරස මාධවේදී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சிரசவில் ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் குழு மீது பாதுகாப்பு படையினரின் தாக்குதல்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிரதமரின் தனிப்பட்ட வாசஸ்தலத்திற்கு முன்பாக போராட்டம் ஒன்றைப் பதிவு செய்யச் சென்ற சிரச ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் 4 பேர் பாதுகாப்புப் படையினரால் தாக்கப்பட்டதோடு, பெண் ஊடகவியலாளர் ஒருவர் உட்பட நால்வர் சிகிச்சைக்காக கொழும்பு தேசிய வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப்படையினரால் இந்த தாக்குதலை மேற்கொண்டதாக தாக்குதலுக்கு உள்ளான சிரச மாதவெடி தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "தாக்குதலுக்கு உள்ளான மீடியா டே உள்ளிட்டோர் தற்போது கொழும்பு தேசிய வைத்தியசாலையில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வருகின்றனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சிரச",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு தேசிய வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிரச மாதவேதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு தேசிய வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}