{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Payment-to-be-made-today-to-bring-down-petrol-shipment-between-July-13-and-15-Minister/342-240460",
  "time_ut": 1657088551,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Payment to be made today to bring down petrol shipment between July 13 and 15: Minister",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Payment to be made today to bring down petrol shipment between July 13 and 15: Minister",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "An advanced payment would be made today to bring down a petrol shipment between July 13,14 and 15 , earlier than the scheduled shipment which is expected by July 22, Power and Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekara said today.",
        "He told Parliament that proposals were called from suppliers to bring down a petrol shipment between July 10 and 15 but only one supplier offered bids but it was at higher prices.",
        "\"Malasian Company had said they will supply a petrol shipment between July 10 and 15. But, they could not confirm the date. There is another supplier who has offered to supply a petrol shipment between July 13 and 15. But, we will have to pay higher prices for that. We can bring it down if you all agree for that. Unless we purchase this shipment, we will have to wait till July 22,\" he said.",
        "The Minister said some factions had objected to purchasing this shipment at higher prices misleading the people that it was done to get commissions and added that the decision was taken at a technicle committee with the Cabinet approval. \"The President and the Prime Minister also instrcuted me to purchase this shipment which will be due between July 13 and 15 without waiting till July 22.We will make the advanced payment of USD 26 million for that shipment today. If there is any boubt on the procedure, please, do not disturb now and question the procedure at the COPE or COPA,\" he said.",
        "He said this in response to a question raised by NPP MP Vijitha Herath from the Prime Minister. (Ajith Siriwardana and Yohan Perera)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "between July 13 and 15",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "between July 13,14 and 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "between July 10 and 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Malasian Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "between July 10 and 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "between July 13 and 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "between July 13 and 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 22.We",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD 26 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vijitha Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Siriwardana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yohan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජුලි 13 සහ 15 අතර පෙට්‍රල් නැව්ගත කිරීම අඩු කිරීමට අද ගෙවීමට නියමිතයි: ඇමති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජුලි 22 වනදාට බලාපොරොත්තු වන පෙට්‍රල් තොගයට පෙර ජූලි 13,14 සහ 15 අතර පෙට්‍රල් තොගයක් අඩු කිරීම සඳහා අත්තිකාරම් ගෙවීමක් අද සිදු කරන බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර මහතා අද ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ජූලි 10 සහ 15 අතර පෙට්‍රල් තොගයක් අඩු කිරීමට සැපයුම්කරුවන්ගෙන් යෝජනා කැඳවූ නමුත් එක් සැපයුම්කරුවෙකු පමණක් ලංසු ඉදිරිපත් කළ නමුත් එය වැඩි මිලකට බව ඔහු පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැවසීය.",
        "මැලේසියන් සමාගම ජුලි 10 ත් 15 ත් අතර පෙට්‍රල් තොගයක් සපයන බව පවසා ඇත. නමුත් ඔවුන්ට දිනය තහවුරු කර ගැනීමට නොහැකි විය. ජූලි 13 සහ 15 අතර පෙට්‍රල් තොගයක් සැපයීමට ඉදිරිපත් වූ තවත් සැපයුම්කරුවෙකු සිටී. නමුත් අපට සිදු වනු ඇත. ඒ සඳහා වැඩි මිලක් ගෙවන්න, ඔබ සියලු දෙනාම ඒ සඳහා එකඟ වන්නේ නම් අපට එය ගෙන්වා ගත හැකිය. අපි මෙම නැව්ගත කිරීම මිලදී නොගන්නේ නම්, අපට ජූලි 22 දක්වා රැඳී සිටීමට සිදුවනු ඇත,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "කොමිස් ලබාගැනීමට සිදු කළ ඒවා බවට ජනතාව නොමග යවමින් වැඩි මිලට මෙම තොගය මිලදී ගැනීමට ඇතැම් පාර්ශ්ව විරෝධය පළ කළ බවත්, කැබිනට් අනුමැතිය මත තාක්ෂණික කමිටුවකදී මෙම තීරණය ගත් බවත් අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය. “ජනාධිපතිතුමා සහ අගමැතිතුමාත් මට උපදෙස් දුන්නා ජූලි 13 සහ 15 අතර කාලය තුළදී මිලදී ගැනීමට නියමිත මෙම නැව්ගත කිරීම ජූලි 22 දක්වා නොසිට මිලදී ගන්න. ක්‍රියා පටිපාටිය, කරුණාකර, දැන් බාධා නොකර කෝප් හෝ කෝපා හි ක්‍රියා පටිපාටිය ප්‍රශ්න කරන්න,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ඔහු මේ බව කියා සිටියේ එක්සත් ජනතා නිදහස් සන්ධානයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී විජිත හේරත් මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගෙන් අසන ලද ප්‍රශ්නයකට පිළිතුරු දෙමිනි. (අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන සහ යොහාන් පෙරේරා)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූලි 13 සහ 15 අතර",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13,14 සහ 15 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 10 සහ 15 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැලේසියානු සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 10 සහ 15 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13 සහ 15 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13 සහ 15 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 22. අපි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 26 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එන්පීපී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යොහාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜூலை 13 முதல் 15 வரை பெட்ரோல் ஏற்றுமதியை குறைக்க இன்று பணம் செலுத்தப்படும்: அமைச்சர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜூலை 22 ஆம் திகதி எதிர்பார்க்கப்படும் திட்டமிடப்பட்ட ஏற்றுமதியை விட, ஜூலை 13, 14 மற்றும் 15 ஆம் தேதிகளுக்கு இடையில் பெட்ரோல் ஏற்றுமதியை குறைக்க இன்று முன்கூட்டிய கட்டணம் செலுத்தப்படும் என்று மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர இன்று தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜூலை 10 மற்றும் 15 க்கு இடையில் பெட்ரோல் ஏற்றுமதியை குறைக்க சப்ளையர்களிடம் இருந்து முன்மொழிவுகள் கோரப்பட்டதாகவும் ஆனால் ஒரே ஒரு சப்ளையர் மட்டுமே ஏலம் எடுத்ததாகவும் ஆனால் அது அதிக விலையில் இருந்ததாகவும் அவர் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் கூறினார்.",
        "ஜூலை 10 முதல் 15ம் தேதிக்குள் பெட்ரோல் ஷிப்மென்ட் வழங்குவதாக மலேசியன் நிறுவனம் கூறியிருந்தது. ஆனால், தேதியை உறுதி செய்ய முடியவில்லை. மற்றொரு சப்ளையர் ஜூலை 13 முதல் 15ம் தேதிக்குள் பெட்ரோல் சரக்கு அனுப்ப முன்வந்துள்ளார். அதற்கு அதிக விலை கொடுக்க வேண்டும். நீங்கள் அனைவரும் ஒப்புக்கொண்டால் நாங்கள் அதைக் குறைக்கலாம். நாங்கள் இந்த கப்பலை வாங்காவிட்டால், ஜூலை 22 வரை காத்திருக்க வேண்டும்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "இந்த கப்பலை அதிக விலைக்கு கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்கு சில தரப்பினர் எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவித்துள்ளதாகவும், இது கமிஷன் பெறுவதற்காக மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டதாக மக்களை தவறாக வழிநடத்துவதாகவும், அமைச்சரவையின் ஒப்புதலுடன் தொழில்நுட்ப குழுவில் இந்த முடிவு எடுக்கப்பட்டதாகவும் கூறினார். ஜூலை 22 வரை காத்திருக்காமல் ஜூலை 13 மற்றும் 15 க்கு இடையில் வரவிருக்கும் இந்த கப்பலை வாங்குமாறு ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமர் எனக்கு அறிவுறுத்தினர். செயல்முறை, தயவுசெய்து, இப்போது தொந்தரவு செய்யாதீர்கள் மற்றும் கோப் அல்லது கோபாவில் உள்ள நடைமுறையை கேள்விக்குட்படுத்துங்கள்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "NPP பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் விஜித ஹேரத் பிரதமரிடம் எழுப்பிய கேள்விக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் போதே அவர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார். (அஜித் சிறிவர்தன மற்றும் யோஹான் பெரேரா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை 13 மற்றும் 15 க்கு இடையில்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13,14 மற்றும் 15 க்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 10 முதல் 15 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மலேசிய நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 10 முதல் 15 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13 மற்றும் 15 க்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13 மற்றும் 15 க்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 22.நாம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க டாலர் 26 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜித ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோஹான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}