{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/මරණීය-දණ්ඩනයට-අත්සන්-කරන්නේ-නෑ/11-396785",
  "time_ut": 1661940857,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මරණීය දණ්ඩනයට අත්සන් කරන්නේ නෑ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Do not sign the death sentence",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe has informed the Supreme Court today (31st) through the Attorney General that he will not sign for the execution of the death penalty.",
        "Additional Solicitor General Nerin Pulle, who appeared for the Attorney General, stated this when several fundamental rights petitions filed by former President Maithripala Sirisena to annul the decision taken in 2019 to execute the death penalty of four defendants sentenced to death were called.",
        "Vijith Mallalgoda, L.T.B. The petition was called before a three-member Supreme Court bench consisting of Mr. Dehideniya and Mr. Murdu Fernando.",
        "When the Attorney General inquired about this yesterday (30th), the President said that he would not sign for the execution of the death sentence and that he would inform the court about this when the relevant case is heard in the Supreme Court."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nerin Pulle",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dehideniya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Murdu Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "this yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මරණීය දණ්ඩනයට අත්සන් කරන්නේ නෑ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මරණීය දණ්ඩනය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම සඳහා තමන් අත්සන් නොකරන බවට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා නීතිපතිවරයා මඟින් ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයට අද (31දා)  දැනුම්දී තිබේ.",
        "මරණීය දණ්ඩනය නියම වී සිටින විත්තිකරුවන් හතරදෙනෙකුගේ මරණීය දණ්ඩනය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රිපාල සිරිසේන මහතා විසින් 2019 වසරේ ගනු ලැබු තීරණයක් බලරහිත කරන්නැයි ඉල්ලා ගොනුකර ඇති මුලික අයිතිවාසිකම් පෙත්සම්  කිහිපයක්  කැඳවූ අවස්ථාවේදී නීතිපතිවරයා වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි අතිරේක සොලිසිටර් ජෙනරාල් නෙරින් පුල්ලේ මහතා මේ බව සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "විජිත් මළල්ගොඩ, එල්.ටී.බී. දෙහිදෙනිය සහ මුර්දු ප්‍රනාන්දු යන මහත්ම මහත්මීන්ගෙන් සමන්විත ත්‍රිපුද්ගල ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ විනිසුරු මඩුල්ලක් හමුවේ මෙම පෙත්සම කැඳවනු ලැබිණි.",
        "නීතිපතිවරයා මේ පිළිබඳ ඊයේ (30දා) කරුණු විමසූ අවස්ථාවේදී, මරණ දණ්ඩනය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරිම සඳහා තමන්  අත්සන් නොකරන බවද අදාළ නඩුව ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයේදී  විභාගයට ගන්නා අවස්ථාවේ මේ පිළිබඳ අධිකරණයට දන්වා සිටින ලෙසද ජනාධිපතිවරයා පවසා තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නෙරින් පුල්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙහිදෙණිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුර්දු ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மரண தண்டனையில் கையெழுத்திட வேண்டாம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மரண தண்டனையை நிறைவேற்றுவதற்கு தான் கையொப்பமிடப் போவதில்லை என ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இன்று (31) சட்டமா அதிபர் ஊடாக உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்திற்கு அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "2019ஆம் ஆண்டு மரண தண்டனை விதிக்கப்பட்ட நான்கு பிரதிவாதிகளின் மரண தண்டனையை நிறைவேற்றுவதற்கு எடுக்கப்பட்ட தீர்மானத்தை ரத்து செய்யுமாறு முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேனவினால் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட பல அடிப்படை உரிமை மனுக்கள் விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக் கொள்ளப்பட்ட போதே சட்டமா அதிபர் சார்பில் ஆஜரான மேலதிக சொலிசிட்டர் ஜெனரல் நெரின் புள்ளே மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "விஜித் மல்லல்கொட, எல்.டி.பி. தெஹிதெனிய மற்றும் முர்து பெர்னாண்டோ ஆகிய மூவரடங்கிய உச்ச நீதிமன்ற அமர்வு முன்னிலையில் இந்த மனு விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக்கொள்ளப்பட்டது.",
        "இது தொடர்பில் நேற்று (30ம் திகதி) சட்டமா அதிபர் வினவிய போது, ​​மரண தண்டனையை நிறைவேற்றுவதற்கு தான் கையொப்பமிடப் போவதில்லை எனவும், இது தொடர்பான வழக்கு உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தில் விசாரணைக்கு வரும்போது நீதிமன்றத்திற்கு அறிவிப்பதாகவும் ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேரின் புள்ளே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெஹிதெனிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முர்து பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இது நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}