{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/14/350-leprosy-patients-reported-in-2022/",
  "time_ut": 1660453200,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "350+ leprosy patients reported in 2022",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "350+ leprosy patients reported in 2022",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 387 leprosy patients have been reported so far in 2022, said the Anti-Leprosy Campaign.",
        "Its Director, Dr. Prasad Ranaweera stated that about 2,000 patients are being reported each year.",
        "Ranaweera stated that it usually takes about 3 to 5 years for symptoms to appear after coming into contact with the bacteria that causes leprosy.",
        "He said that Leprosy causes severe, disfiguring skin sores and nerve damage in the arms, legs, and skin areas around your body.",
        "Dr. Ranaweera said that about 10% of all patients reported are children under the age of 14.",
        "The World Health Organisation set a 2001 target to eliminate leprosy as a public health problem.",
        "However Sri Lanka eliminated this target five years early, reducing the number of cases by less than one person in every 10,000 of its population in 1995.",
        "Having reached its target the country adopted a lax approach by integrating the disease under the general health services providing treatments through dermatology clinics with the prevention aspect dealt by district control team.",
        "Leprosy is caused by a slow-growing type of bacteria called Mycobacterium leprae (M. leprae). Leprosy is also known as Hansen's disease, after the scientist who discovered M. leprae in 1873.",
        "Will support from Opposition until Tamil people are satisfied: C.V. Wigneswaran"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "350",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "387",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Anti-Leprosy Campaign",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prasad Ranaweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 2,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "each year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranaweera",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 3 to 5 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Leprosy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranaweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 10%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "under the age of 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The World Health Organisation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2001",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this target",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five years early",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "less than one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1995",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mycobacterium",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "M. leprae",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hansen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1873",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "C.V. Wigneswaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "2022 දී ලාදුරු රෝගීන් 350+ වාර්තා වී ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 2022 වසරේ මේ දක්වා ලාදුරු රෝගීන් 387ක් වාර්තා වී ඇති බව ලාදුරු මර්දන ව්‍යාපාරය පවසයි.",
        "එහි අධ්‍යක්ෂ වෛද්‍ය ප්‍රසාද් රණවීර සඳහන් කළේ වසරකට රෝගීන් 2000ක් පමණ වාර්තා වන බවයි.",
        "රණවීර ප්‍රකාශ කළේ සාමාන්‍යයෙන් ලාදුරු රෝගය ඇති කරන බැක්ටීරියාව සමඟ සම්බන්ධ වීමෙන් පසු රෝග ලක්ෂණ මතුවීමට වසර 3ත් 5ත් අතර කාලයක් ගත වන බවයි.",
        "ලාදුරු රෝගය නිසා ඔබේ සිරුර වටා ඇති අත්, පාද සහ සම ප්‍රදේශයන්හි දරුණු, විකෘති සමේ තුවාල සහ ස්නායු ආබාධ ඇති කරන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "වාර්තා වන සියලුම රෝගීන්ගෙන් 10% ක් පමණ වයස අවුරුදු 14 ට අඩු ළමුන් බව වෛද්‍ය රණවීර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානය මහජන සෞඛ්‍ය ගැටලුවක් ලෙස ලාදුරු රෝගය තුරන් කිරීම සඳහා 2001 ඉලක්කයක් තැබීය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මෙම ඉලක්කය වසර පහකට පෙර ඉවත් කළ අතර, 1995 දී එහි ජනගහනයෙන් සෑම 10,000 කටම එක් පුද්ගලයෙකුට වඩා අඩු රෝගීන් සංඛ්‍යාවක් අඩු කළේය.",
        "සිය ඉලක්කය කරා ළඟා වූ පසු, දිස්ත්‍රික් පාලන කණ්ඩායම විසින් ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන ලද වැළැක්වීමේ අංශය සමඟ චර්ම රෝග සායන හරහා ප්‍රතිකාර සපයන සාමාන්‍ය සෞඛ්‍ය සේවා යටතේ රෝගය ඒකාබද්ධ කරමින් රට ලිහිල් ප්‍රවේශයක් අනුගමනය කළේය.",
        "ලාදුරු රෝගය ඇති වන්නේ Mycobacterium leprae (M. leprae) නම් සෙමින් වර්ධනය වන බැක්ටීරියා වර්ගයක් මගිනි. 1873 දී M. leprae සොයා ගත් විද්‍යාඥයාගෙන් පසු ලාදුරු හැන්සන්ගේ රෝගය ලෙසද හැඳින්වේ.",
        "දෙමළ ජනතාව තෘප්තිමත් වන තුරු විපක්ෂයේ සහය දෙනවා: සී.වී. විග්නේෂ්වරන්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "350",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "387",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලාදුරු මර්දන ව්‍යාපාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසාද් රණවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,000 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෑම වසරකම",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රණවීර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 3 සිට 5 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලාදුරු රෝගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රණවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10% පමණ",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 14 ට අඩු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2001",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම ඉලක්කය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු පහකට කලින්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එකකට වඩා අඩුය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1995",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මයිකොබැක්ටීරියම්",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්. ලෙප්රේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හැන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1873",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CV. විග්නේෂ්වරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "2022 இல் 350+ தொழுநோயாளிகள் பதிவாகியுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டில் இதுவரை 387 தொழுநோயாளிகள் பதிவாகியுள்ளதாக தொழுநோய் எதிர்ப்பு பிரச்சாரம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஒவ்வொரு வருடமும் சுமார் 2000 நோயாளர்கள் பதிவாகி வருவதாக அதன் பணிப்பாளர் டாக்டர் பிரசாத் ரணவீர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "தொழுநோயை ஏற்படுத்தும் பாக்டீரியாவுடன் தொடர்பு கொண்ட பிறகு அறிகுறிகள் தோன்றுவதற்கு பொதுவாக 3 முதல் 5 ஆண்டுகள் வரை ஆகும் என்று ரணவீர கூறினார்.",
        "தொழுநோய் உங்கள் உடலைச் சுற்றியுள்ள கைகள், கால்கள் மற்றும் தோல் பகுதிகளில் கடுமையான, சிதைக்கும் தோல் புண்கள் மற்றும் நரம்பு சேதத்தை ஏற்படுத்துகிறது என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "பதிவாகியுள்ள மொத்த நோயாளிகளில் சுமார் 10% பேர் 14 வயதுக்குட்பட்ட குழந்தைகள் என்று டாக்டர் ரணவீர கூறினார்.",
        "உலக சுகாதார நிறுவனம் தொழுநோயை ஒரு பொது சுகாதார பிரச்சனையாக அகற்ற 2001 இலக்கை நிர்ணயித்தது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், இலங்கை இந்த இலக்கை ஐந்து ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பே நீக்கியது, 1995 இல் அதன் மக்கள் தொகையில் ஒவ்வொரு 10,000 பேரில் ஒருவருக்கும் குறைவான நோயாளிகளின் எண்ணிக்கையைக் குறைத்தது.",
        "அதன் இலக்கை எட்டிய பின்னர், மாவட்டக் கட்டுப்பாட்டுக் குழுவால் கையாளப்பட்ட தடுப்பு அம்சத்துடன் தோல் மருத்துவ மையங்கள் மூலம் சிகிச்சைகள் வழங்கும் பொது சுகாதார சேவைகளின் கீழ் நோயை ஒருங்கிணைத்து நாடு ஒரு தளர்வான அணுகுமுறையைக் கடைப்பிடித்தது.",
        "தொழுநோய் மைக்கோபாக்டீரியம் லெப்ரே (எம். லெப்ரே) எனப்படும் மெதுவாக வளரும் பாக்டீரியாவால் ஏற்படுகிறது. 1873 இல் எம். லெப்ரேவைக் கண்டுபிடித்த விஞ்ஞானியின் நினைவாக, தொழுநோய் ஹான்சன் நோய் என்றும் அழைக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "தமிழ் மக்கள் திருப்தி அடையும் வரை எதிர்க்கட்சிகளின் ஆதரவு: சி.வி. விக்னேஸ்வரன்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "350",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "387",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொழுநோய் எதிர்ப்பு பிரச்சாரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரசாத் ரணவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 2,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒவ்வொரு வருடமும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணவீர",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 3 முதல் 5 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தொழுநோய்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 10%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 வயதுக்கு கீழ்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உலக சுகாதார நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2001",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த இலக்கு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்றுக்கும் குறைவானது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1995",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மைக்கோபாக்டீரியம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம். தொழுநோய்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹேன்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1873",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுயவிவரம். விக்னேஸ்வரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}