{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/மலையகம்/இ-தொ-கா-உறுப்பினர்-அட்டகாசம்-சிலிண்டர்களை-பந்தாடினார்/76-300466",
  "time_ut": 1657868914,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இ.தொ.கா உறுப்பினர் அட்டகாசம்: சிலிண்டர்களை பந்தாடினார்:",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "EC Member Atakasam: Hitting the cylinders:",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Susai Alexander, a member of the Sri Lanka Workers' Congress (SLC) of the Norwood Regional Council, kicked and punched the cylinders placed in the fuel queue and warned a bystander. He also took out the bottle hidden in his waist and tried to stab him and lashed out with blasphemous words.",
        "In this case, the general secretary of ECJ Jeevan Thondaman has said that an investigation will be conducted against him and till then, he will be suspended from the party.",
        "\"The High Level Disciplinary Committee of the Sri Lankan Labor Congress will conduct appropriate investigations on the 21st (Thursday) regarding the controversies and accusations against Norwood Regional Council member Soosai Alexander.",
        "Jeevan Thondaman has said that the EC will never allow such activities and all party membership rights of the said Pradeshiya Sabha member have been temporarily suspended with effect."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "EC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Atakasam",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Susai Alexander",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Workers'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Norwood Regional Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ECJ Jeevan Thondaman",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The High Level Disciplinary Committee of the Sri Lankan Labor Congress",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 21st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Norwood Regional Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Soosai Alexander",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jeevan Thondaman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pradeshiya Sabha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "EC සාමාජික අටකාසම්: සිලින්ඩරවලට පහර දීම:",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "නෝර්වුඩ් ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා කම්කරු කොංග්‍රසයේ (SLC) මන්ත්‍රී සුසෙයි ඇලෙක්සැන්ඩර් ඉන්ධන පෝලිමේ තබා තිබූ සිලින්ඩරවලට පයින් ගසා පහර දී අසල සිටි අයෙකුට අවවාද කළේය. ඉනෙහි සඟවාගෙන සිටි බෝතලයද එළියට ගෙන ඔහුට පිහියෙන් ඇනීමට තැත් කළ ඔහු අපහාසාත්මක වචනවලින් පහර දුන්නේය.",
        "මෙම නඩුවේදී ඔහුට එරෙහිව පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන බවත් එතෙක් ඔහුගේ පක්ෂ සාමාජිකත්වය අත්හිටුවන බවත් ECJ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් ජීවන් තොණ්ඩමන් ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත.",
        "“නොර්වුඩ් ප්‍රාදේශීය සභා මන්ත්‍රී සූසෙයි ඇලෙක්සැන්ඩර්ට එරෙහි මතභේද සහ චෝදනා සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා කම්කරු කොංග්‍රසයේ ඉහළ පෙළේ විනය කමිටුව 21 වැනිදා (බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා) සුදුසු පරීක්‍ෂණ පවත්වනු ඇත.",
        "එවැනි කටයුතුවලට මැතිවරණ කොමිසම කිසිවිටකත් ඉඩ නොතබන බවත්, එම ප්‍රාදේශීය සභා මන්ත්‍රීවරයාගේ සියලු පක්ෂ සාමාජිකත්වය තාවකාලිකව අත්හිටුවා ඇති බවත් ජීවන් තොණ්ඩමන් මහතා පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "EC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අටකාසම්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සුසෙයි ඇලෙක්සැන්ඩර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා කම්කරුවන්'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොංග්රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෝර්වුඩ් ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ECJ ජීවන් තොණ්ඩමන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා කම්කරු කොංග්‍රසයේ ඉහළ පෙළේ විනය කමිටුව",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෝර්වුඩ් ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුසෙයි ඇලෙක්සැන්ඩර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජීවන් තොණ්ඩමන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இ.தொ.கா உறுப்பினர் அட்டகாசம்: சிலிண்டர்களை பந்தாடினார்:",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "நோர்வூட் பிரதேச சபையின் இலங்கை தொழிலாளர் காங்கிரஸ் (இ.தொ.கா) உறுப்பினர் சூசை அலக்ஸாண்டர் எரிபொருள் வரிசையில் வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த சிலிண்டர்களை எட்டி உதைத்து பந்தாடிவிட்டு, காத்திருந்த நபர் ஒருவரையும் எச்சரித்துள்ளார். அத்துடன் தனது இடுப்பில் மறைத்து வைத்தியிருந்த போத்தலை எடுத்து குத்துவதற்கு முயற்சித்ததுடன் தூசன வார்த்தைகளால் வசைபாடினார்.",
        "இந்நிலையில், அவர் மீது விசாரணை நடைப்பெறும் எனவும், அதுவரையிலும் அவரை, கட்சியில் இருந்து இடைநிறுத்துவதாகவும் இ.தொ.காவின் பொதுசெயலாளர் ஜீவன் தொண்டமான் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "“நோர்வூட் பிரதேச சபையின் உறுப்பினர் சூசை அலக்ஸாண்டர் மீது எழுந்துள்ள சர்ச்சைகள் மற்றும் குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் தொடர்பில்,இலங்கை தொழிலாளர் காங்கிரஸின் உயர்மட்ட ஒழுக்காற்று குழு, எதிர்வரும் 21ஆம் திகதி (வியாழக்கிழமை) உரிய விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொள்ளவுள்ளது.",
        "இதுபோன்ற செயல்களுக்கு இ.தொ.கா ஒருபொழுதும் அனுமதியளிக்காது என்பதோடு குறித்த பிரதேச சபை உறுப்பினரின் சகல கட்சி உறுப்புரிமைகளும் உடன் அமுலுக்கு வரும் வகையில் தற்காலிகமாக இடைநிறுத்தி வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதை தெரிவித்துக்கொள்கிறேன் என ஜீவன் தொண்டமான் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "EC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "அட்டகாசம்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சூசை அலெக்சாண்டர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தொழிலாளர்கள்'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நோர்வூட் பிராந்திய சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ECJ ஜீவன் தொண்டமான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தொழிலாளர் காங்கிரஸின் உயர் மட்ட ஒழுக்காற்றுக் குழு",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நோர்வூட் பிராந்திய சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சூசை அலெக்சாண்டர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜீவன் தொண்டமான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரதேச சபை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}