{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/lessons-from-libya/",
  "time_ut": 1656866940,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Lessons from Libya",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Lessons from Libya",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "Angry protesters have set the Libyan Parliament building on fire. They have been calling for elections. Continuing power cuts, soaring prices, months of political deadlock, etc., have driven the Libyans to extreme action although their demands have been endorsed by the interim Prime Minister, Abdul Hamid Dbeibah, who has also agreed in principle to the need to overhaul all state institutions. Libya is in chaos today with rival parties vying for power and killing one another because of the western-backed regime change in 2011.",
        "Muammar Gaddafi was an eccentric dictator, who had to be made to uphold democracy, but the West had other plans and destabilised Libya by supporting the anti-Gaddafi forces that included Jihadist fighters. Until the ouster of the Gaddafi regime in 2011, Libya had boasted not only political stability but also excellent living standards, which were the highest in Africa and easily compared with those in the developed countries; it had one of the best social welfare schemes in the world. The Arab Spring has turned out to be a winter of despair for Libyans.",
        "Prevailing economic, social and political conditions in Sri Lanka are similar to those in Libya at present in some respects, and have the potential to plunge the country into lawlessness just like the north African nation in depths of anarchy. This is something both the government and the Opposition should take cognisance of.",
        "The government is groping in the dark. The Opposition parties are pulling in different directions, demanding that they be allowed to govern the country. They have said they will join forces to hold a continuous protest in Colombo, seeking the ouster of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa. The removal of the President may be the most effective way of extricating the country from the tentacles of the Rajapaksa family, which is aggravating the crisis by leveraging Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe’s dependence on Basil Rajapaksa’s SLPP. Now, some Basil loyalists such as SLPP General Secretary Sagara Kariyawasam, are crawling out of the woodwork. But the ground reality is that President Rajapaksa cannot be ousted so easily. Unless he resigns, he has to be impeached. The process of impeaching the President is a tedious one, and the Opposition is without sufficient numbers in Parliament for that purpose. A sustained protest campaign backed by a general strike may be considered an option, but such a course of action will be tantamount to collective suicide in that political upheavals will destroy the economy and deprive the country of the much-needed foreign assistance. The way out, in our book, is to crank up pressure on President Rajapaksa to appoint a truly national government so that all political parties will have to stop protesting and make a contribution towards crisis management.",
        "Sri Lankans are a credulous lot. They swallowed Dhammika  peniya (syrup), which was touted as a cure for Covid-19. Gotabaya offered a political peniya, (read the Vistas of Prosperity) claiming that it was the cure for all ills of Sri Lanka, and the people fell hook, line, and sinker for it only to be disappointed. Now, they are being offered the Sajith  peniya and the Anura Kumara peniya. The SJB consists of a bunch of politicians who were in the yahapalana government, which failed. The country is paying the price for having elected, as its President, a person without any experience in statecraft. The JVP, which could not run even a local government institution properly, is now demanding the reins of government. Its ideology is an anachronism in the modern world, and its utopian dream may be marketable but is not attainable.",
        "The Opposition parties must be prevented from using the present crisis to hoodwink the public, capture power, and thereafter go on asking for time to find a solution while blaming their predecessors. No single party is equal to the task of helping straighten up the economy under its own steam, and there will have to be a concerted effort. That is why all political parties must be made to form a unity government and carry out their promises collectively pending a general election. They have to make necessary laws and policies to enable the technocrats of the Finance Ministry, the Central Bank, etc., to resuscitate the economy. Nobody will be safe if the country slides into anarchy with the irate public marching on Parliament.",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Libya",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Libyan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Libyans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abdul Hamid Dbeibah",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Libya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2011",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Muammar Gaddafi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "West",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Libya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gaddafi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jihadist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gaddafi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2011",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Libya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Africa",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Arab Spring",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Libyans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Libya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "African",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sagara Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Vistas of Prosperity",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yahapalana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Finance Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලිබියාවෙන් පාඩම්",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "කෝපයට පත් විරෝධතාකරුවන් ලිබියානු පාර්ලිමේන්තු ගොඩනැගිල්ලට ගිනි තබා තිබේ. ඒ අය මැතිවරණ ඉල්ලනවා. අඛණ්ඩ විදුලි කප්පාදුව, ඉහළ යන මිල ගණන්, මාස කිහිපයක දේශපාලන අර්බුදය යනාදිය, ලිබියානුවන් අන්ත ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයකට තල්ලු කර ඇතත්, ඔවුන්ගේ ඉල්ලීම් අන්තර්වාර අගමැති අබ්දුල් හමීඩ් ඩ්බෙයිබා විසින් අනුමත කර ඇතත්, සියල්ල ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණය කිරීමේ අවශ්‍යතාවයට ප්‍රතිපත්තිමය වශයෙන් එකඟ වී ඇත. රාජ්ය ආයතන. 2011 බටහිර පිටුබලය ලබන පාලන තන්ත්‍ර වෙනස නිසා බලය සඳහා තරඟ කරන ප්‍රතිවාදී පක්ෂ සමඟ ලිබියාව අද අවුල් ජාලයක පවතී.",
        "මුවම්මර් ගඩාෆි යනු විකේන්ද්රික ආඥාදායකයෙකු වූ අතර, ඔහු ප්රජාතන්ත්රවාදය ආරක්ෂා කිරීම සඳහා කළ යුතු විය, නමුත් බටහිරට වෙනත් සැලසුම් තිබූ අතර ජිහාඩ් සටන්කාමීන් ඇතුළත් ගඩාෆි විරෝධී බලවේගවලට සහය දක්වමින් ලිබියාව අස්ථාවර කළේය. 2011 ගඩාෆි තන්ත‍්‍රය නෙරපා හරින තෙක්, ලිබියාව දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වය පමණක් නොව, අප්‍රිකාවේ ඉහළම සහ සංවර්ධිත රටවලට වඩා පහසුවෙන් සංසන්දනය කළ හැකි විශිෂ්ඨ ජීවන තත්වයන් ගැනද පුරසාරම් දොඩමින් සිටියේය. එය ලෝකයේ හොඳම සමාජ සුබසාධන යෝජනා ක්‍රමවලින් එකක් විය. අරාබි වසන්තය ලිබියානුවන්ට බලාපොරොත්තු සුන්වීමේ ශීත ඍතුවක් බවට පත්ව ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පවතින ආර්ථික, සමාජීය සහ දේශපාලන තත්ත්වයන් යම් යම් අංශවලින් දැනට ලිබියාවේ තත්ත්වයට සමාන වන අතර උතුරු අප්‍රිකානු ජාතිය මෙන් රටත් අරාජිකත්වයේ ගැඹුරට ඇද දැමීමේ හැකියාව ඇත. මෙය ආණ්ඩුව මෙන්ම විපක්ෂය ද අවධානය යොමු කළ යුතු කරුණකි.",
        "ආණ්ඩුව අඳුරේ අතපත ගාමින් සිටී. තමන්ට රට පාලනය කිරීමට ඉඩ දෙන ලෙස ඉල්ලමින් විරුද්ධ පක්ෂ විවිධ පැතිවලට අදිනවා. ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා බලයෙන් පහ කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා කොළඹදී අඛණ්ඩ විරෝධතාවක් පැවැත්වීමට තමන් එක්වන බව ඔවුන් පවසා තිබේ. අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂගේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ මත යැපීම මගින් අර්බුදය උග්‍ර කරන රාජපක්ෂ පවුලේ කූඩාරම්වලින් රට මුදා ගැනීමේ වඩාත් ඵලදායී ක්‍රමය ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉවත් කිරීම විය හැකිය. දැන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් සාගර කාරියවසම් වැනි බැසිල් හිතවාදීන් කිහිප දෙනෙක් ලී වැඩවලින් බඩගාමින් සිටිති. එහෙත් බිම් යථාර්ථය නම් රාජපක්ෂ ජනාධිපතිවරයා එතරම් ලෙහෙසියෙන් නෙරපා හැරිය නොහැකි බවයි. ඉල්ලා අස් නොවුණොත් ඔහුට දෝෂාභියෝගයක් එල්ල කරන්න වෙනවා. ජනාධිපතිවරයාට දෝෂාභියෝගයක් ගෙන ඒමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය වෙහෙසකර ක්‍රියාවලියක් වන අතර ඒ සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රමාණවත් සංඛ්‍යාවක් විපක්ෂයට නොමැත. මහා වැඩවර්ජනයක පිටුබලය සහිත තිරසාර විරෝධතා ව්‍යාපාරයක් විකල්පයක් ලෙස සැලකිය හැකි නමුත්, එවැනි ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයක් සාමූහික සියදිවි නසා ගැනීමකට සමාන වනු ඇත, දේශපාලන නැගිටීම් ආර්ථිකය විනාශ කරන අතර රටට අවශ්‍ය විදේශ ආධාර අහිමි කරයි. අපගේ පොතේ ඇති මාර්ගය නම්, සැබෑ ජාතික ආණ්ඩුවක් පත් කරන ලෙස ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂට පීඩනය යෙදීමයි, එවිට සියලු දේශපාලන පක්ෂවලට විරෝධතා නතර කර අර්බුද කළමනාකරණයට දායක වීමට සිදුවනු ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයෝ විශ්වාසවන්ත පිරිසක්. ඔවුන් කොවිඩ් -19 සඳහා ප්‍රතිකාරයක් ලෙස ප්‍රකාශ කරන ලද ධම්මික පෙනිය (සිරප්) ගිල දැමූහ. ගෝඨාභය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සියලු රෝග සඳහා බෙහෙත යැයි කියමින් දේශපාලන පෙනියක් (විස්ටාස් ඔෆ් සෞභාග්‍යය කියවන්න) පිරිනැමූ අතර ජනතාව එයට කොක්ක, ඉරක් සහ ගිල්වා වැටුණේ බලාපොරොත්තු සුන්වීමට පමණි. දැන් ඒ අයට සජිත් පෑණියයි අනුර කුමාර පෑනියයි පූජා කරනවා. SJB සමන්විත වන්නේ යහපාලන ආණ්ඩුවේ සිටි, අසාර්ථක වූ දේශපාලකයින් රොත්තකිනි. රාජ්‍ය ශිල්පය පිළිබඳ කිසිදු අත්දැකීමක් නොමැති පුද්ගලයෙකු තම ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස තේරී පත්වීමේ වන්දිය රට ගෙවමින් තිබේ. පළාත් පාලන ආයතනයක්වත් හරියට කරගෙන යන්න බැරිවුණ ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ දැන් ආණ්ඩු බලය ඉල්ලනවා. එහි දෘෂ්ටිවාදය නූතන ලෝකයේ අනාත්මවාදයක් වන අතර, එහි මනෝරාජික සිහිනය අලෙවි කළ හැකි නමුත් සාක්ෂාත් කරගත නොහැකි ය.",
        "වත්මන් අර්බුදය මහජනතාව රැවටීමටත්, බලය අල්ලා ගැනීමටත්, ඉන් පසු තම පූර්වගාමීන්ට දොස් පවරමින් විසඳුමක් සෙවීමට කල් ඉල්ලා සිටීමත් විරුද්ධ පක්ෂ විසින් වැළැක්විය යුතුය. කිසිදු තනි පක්ෂයක් තමන්ගේම වාෂ්ප යටතේ ආර්ථිකය සෘජු කිරීමට උදව් කිරීමේ කාර්යයට සමාන නොවන අතර, සාමූහික උත්සාහයක් තිබිය යුතුය. මහ මැතිවරණයක් එනතුරු සියලු දේශපාලන පක්‍ෂ සමගි ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවා තම පොරොන්දු සාමූහිකව ඉටු කිරීමට සැලැස්විය යුත්තේ එබැවිනි. මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයේ, මහ බැංකුවේ යනාදී තාක්‍ෂණවේදීන්ට ආර්ථිකය නගා සිටුවීමට අවශ්‍ය නීති සහ ප්‍රතිපත්ති සම්පාදනය කිරීමට ඔවුන්ට සිදුවේ. කුපිත වූ මහජනයා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පාගමනින් රට අරාජික වුවහොත් කිසිවකුට ආරක්ෂාවක් නැත.",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලිබියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිබියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිබියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබ්දුල් හමීඩ් ඩ්බෙයිබා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිබියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2011",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුවම්මර් ගඩාෆි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිබියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගඩාෆි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිහාඩ්වාදී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගඩාෆි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2011",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිබියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රිකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරාබි වසන්තය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිබියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිබියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞභාග්‍යයේ දැක්ම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yahapalana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "லிபியாவில் இருந்து பாடங்கள்",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஆத்திரமடைந்த போராட்டக்காரர்கள் லிபிய பாராளுமன்ற கட்டிடத்திற்கு தீ வைத்துள்ளனர். தேர்தலுக்கு அழைப்பு விடுத்து வருகின்றனர். தொடர்ச்சியான மின்வெட்டு, உயர்ந்து வரும் விலைவாசிகள், மாதக்கணக்கான அரசியல் முட்டுக்கட்டை போன்றவை லிபியர்களை தீவிர நடவடிக்கைக்கு தள்ளியுள்ளன, இருப்பினும் அவர்களின் கோரிக்கைகளை இடைக்கால பிரதமர் அப்துல் ஹமீட் டிபீபா ஏற்றுக்கொண்டார். அரசு நிறுவனங்கள். 2011 இல் மேற்கத்திய ஆதரவுடன் ஆட்சி மாற்றத்தின் காரணமாக போட்டிக் கட்சிகள் அதிகாரத்திற்காக போட்டியிட்டு ஒருவரையொருவர் கொன்று கொண்டு லிபியா இன்று குழப்பத்தில் உள்ளது.",
        "முயம்மர் கடாபி ஒரு விசித்திரமான சர்வாதிகாரி, அவர் ஜனநாயகத்தை நிலைநிறுத்த வேண்டும், ஆனால் மேற்கு நாடுகள் வேறு திட்டங்களைக் கொண்டிருந்தன மற்றும் ஜிஹாதி போராளிகளை உள்ளடக்கிய கடாபி எதிர்ப்பு சக்திகளை ஆதரிப்பதன் மூலம் லிபியாவை சீர்குலைத்தன. 2011 இல் கடாபி ஆட்சி அகற்றப்படும் வரை, லிபியா அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மையை மட்டுமல்ல, சிறந்த வாழ்க்கைத் தரத்தையும் பெருமையாகக் கொண்டிருந்தது, இது ஆப்பிரிக்காவில் மிக உயர்ந்தது மற்றும் வளர்ந்த நாடுகளுடன் எளிதாக ஒப்பிடப்பட்டது; இது உலகின் சிறந்த சமூக நலத் திட்டங்களில் ஒன்றாகும். அரபு வசந்தம் லிபியர்களுக்கு விரக்தியின் குளிர்காலமாக மாறிவிட்டது.",
        "இலங்கையில் நிலவும் பொருளாதார, சமூக மற்றும் அரசியல் நிலைமைகள் சில விஷயங்களில் தற்போது லிபியாவில் உள்ளதைப் போன்றே உள்ளன, மேலும் வட ஆபிரிக்க நாட்டைப் போலவே நாட்டையும் அராஜகத்தின் ஆழத்தில் ஆழ்த்தும் சாத்தியக்கூறுகள் உள்ளன. இதை அரசும் எதிர்க்கட்சியும் கவனத்தில் கொள்ள வேண்டும்.",
        "அரசாங்கம் இருளில் தத்தளிக்கிறது. நாட்டை ஆள அனுமதிக்க வேண்டும் என்று எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் பல்வேறு திசைகளில் இழுத்து வருகின்றன. ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை பதவி நீக்கம் செய்யக் கோரி கொழும்பில் தொடர்ச்சியான போராட்டத்தை நடத்துவதற்கு ஒன்றிணைந்து செயற்படவுள்ளதாக அவர்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர். பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பசில் ராஜபக்சவின் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவில் தங்கியிருப்பதன் மூலம் நெருக்கடியை மோசமாக்கும் ராஜபக்ச குடும்பத்தின் கூடாரங்களில் இருந்து நாட்டை மீட்டெடுப்பதற்கான மிகச் சிறந்த வழி ஜனாதிபதியை நீக்குவது. இப்போது, ​​SLPP பொதுச் செயலாளர் சாகர காரியவசம் போன்ற சில பசில் விசுவாசிகள் மரவேலையிலிருந்து வலம் வருகின்றனர். ஆனால் ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷவை அவ்வளவு இலகுவாக பதவியில் இருந்து அகற்ற முடியாது என்பதே அடிப்படை யதார்த்தம். அவர் ராஜினாமா செய்யாவிட்டால், அவர் பதவி நீக்கம் செய்யப்பட வேண்டும். ஜனாதிபதியை பதவி நீக்கம் செய்யும் செயல்முறை ஒரு கடினமான ஒன்றாகும், மேலும் அந்த நோக்கத்திற்காக பாராளுமன்றத்தில் எதிர்க்கட்சிக்கு போதுமான எண்ணிக்கை இல்லை. ஒரு பொது வேலைநிறுத்தத்தின் ஆதரவுடன் ஒரு தொடர்ச்சியான எதிர்ப்பு பிரச்சாரம் ஒரு விருப்பமாக கருதப்படலாம், ஆனால் அத்தகைய நடவடிக்கை கூட்டு தற்கொலைக்கு சமமாக இருக்கும், அதில் அரசியல் எழுச்சிகள் பொருளாதாரத்தை அழித்து நாட்டிற்கு மிகவும் தேவையான வெளிநாட்டு உதவியை இழக்கும். எங்கள் புத்தகத்தில், உண்மையான தேசிய அரசாங்கத்தை நியமிக்க ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷவின் மீது அழுத்தம் கொடுப்பது, அனைத்து அரசியல் கட்சிகளும் எதிர்ப்பை நிறுத்தி நெருக்கடி மேலாண்மைக்கு பங்களிக்க வேண்டும்.",
        "இலங்கையர்கள் நம்பிக்கை மிக்கவர்கள். கோவிட்-19க்கு மருந்தாகக் கூறப்பட்ட தம்மிகா பேனியாவை (சிரப்) அவர்கள் விழுங்கினார்கள். கோட்டாபய இலங்கையின் அனைத்து நோய்களுக்கும் நிவாரணம் என்று கூறி அரசியல் பேணியை (விஸ்டாஸ் ஆஃப் செழுமையைப் படியுங்கள்) வழங்கினார், மேலும் மக்கள் ஏமாற்றமடைந்தனர். தற்போது அவர்களுக்கு சஜித் பேணியும், அனுரகுமார பேணியும் வழங்கப்படுகின்றன. SJB யஹபாலன அரசாங்கத்தில் இருந்த ஒரு சில அரசியல்வாதிகளைக் கொண்டுள்ளது, அது தோல்வியடைந்தது. அரசுத்துறையில் எந்த அனுபவமும் இல்லாத ஒருவரை அதிபராகத் தேர்ந்தெடுத்ததன் விலையை நாடு செலுத்துகிறது. உள்ளூராட்சி நிறுவனத்தைக் கூட சரியாக நடத்த முடியாத ஜே.வி.பி., தற்போது ஆட்சிக் கடிவாளத்தைக் கோருகின்றது. அதன் சித்தாந்தம் நவீன உலகில் ஒரு அனாக்ரோனிசம் ஆகும், மேலும் அதன் கற்பனாவாத கனவு சந்தைப்படுத்தக்கூடியதாக இருக்கலாம் ஆனால் அடைய முடியாது.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் தற்போதைய நெருக்கடியைப் பயன்படுத்தி பொதுமக்களை ஏமாற்றி, அதிகாரத்தைக் கைப்பற்றுவதைத் தடுக்க வேண்டும், அதன் பிறகு தங்கள் முன்னோடிகளைக் குற்றம் சாட்டி தீர்வு காண கால அவகாசம் கேட்பதைத் தடுக்க வேண்டும். எந்த ஒரு கட்சியும் அதன் சொந்த நீராவியின் கீழ் பொருளாதாரத்தை நேராக்க உதவும் பணிக்கு சமமாக இல்லை, மேலும் ஒரு ஒருங்கிணைந்த முயற்சி இருக்க வேண்டும். அதனால்தான் அனைத்து அரசியல் கட்சிகளும் ஒரு ஐக்கிய அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க வேண்டும் மற்றும் பொதுத் தேர்தல் நிலுவையில் உள்ள வாக்குறுதிகளை கூட்டாக நிறைவேற்ற வேண்டும். நிதியமைச்சகம், மத்திய வங்கி போன்றவற்றின் தொழில்நுட்ப வல்லுனர்கள் பொருளாதாரத்தை புத்துயிர் பெறுவதற்கு தேவையான சட்டங்களையும் கொள்கைகளையும் அவர்கள் உருவாக்க வேண்டும். ஆத்திரமடைந்த பொதுமக்கள் நாடாளுமன்றத்தை நோக்கி ஊர்வலம் செல்வதால், நாடு அராஜக நிலைக்கு தள்ளப்பட்டால் யாரும் பாதுகாப்பாக இருக்க மாட்டார்கள்.",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "லிபியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "லிபியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிபியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அப்துல் ஹமீத் திபீபா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2011",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முயம்மர் கடாபி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடாபி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜிஹாதிஸ்ட்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடாபி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2011",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரபு வசந்தம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிபியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்பிரிக்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்சவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "துளசி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகர காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "செழிப்பின் காட்சிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yahapalana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}