{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ජනපති-ඉල්ලා-අස්වීම-කතානායකට/101-616423",
  "time_ut": 1657807569,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ජනපති ඉල්ලා අස්වීම කතානායකට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The President's resignation to the speaker",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa has sent the letter of resignation from the post of President to Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena tonight (14).",
        "Mr. Gotabaya Rajapakse, who left the Colombo Fort Presidential Palace and stayed at a security post on the island due to the disturbing situation in the country, left for the Maldives on the 12th with his wife and two security guards in a special plane of the Air Force. He left the Maldives and arrived in Singapore this afternoon.",
        "Parliamentary sources say that the President's resignation letter is being investigated by the Speaker and legal departments.",
        "A special meeting of the Committee on Parliamentary Affairs is scheduled to be held tomorrow morning at the Parliament Complex under the chairmanship of the Speaker and the necessary decisions regarding the appointment of a new President will be taken there, said the sources.",
        "The resignation letter sent by President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa to the speaker reads as follows."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "tonight",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapakse",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Fort Presidential Palace",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 12th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Committee on Parliamentary Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපති ඉල්ලා අස්වීම කතානායකට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ජනාධිපති තනතුරින් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය කතානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතාට අද (14) රාත්‍රීයේ එවා ඇත.",
        "රටේ ඇතිවූ කලබලකාරි තත්වය හේතුවෙන් කොළඹ කොටුව ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයෙන් ඉවත් වී දිවයිනේ ආරක්ෂක ස්ථානයක රැඳී සිටි ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සිය බිරිඳ ද ආරක්ෂකයන් දෙදෙනකු ද සමග ගුවන් හමුදාවේ විශේෂ යානයකින් පසුගිය 12 වෙනිදා මාලදිවයිනට පිටව ගිය අතර මාලදිවයිනෙන් පිටවී සිංගප්පූරුවට පැමිණියේ අද පස්වරුවේය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය කතානායකවරයාගේ සහ නීති අංශවල විමර්ශනයට ලක් වෙමින් පවතින බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු ආරංචි මාර්ගවලින් පැවසේ.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාවේ විශේෂ රැස්වීමක් කතානායකවරයාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණයේදී හෙට පෙරවරුවේ පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත අතර අභිනව ජනාධිපතිවරයකු පත් කර ගැනීමට අදාල පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු සම්බන්ධයෙන් එහිදී අවශ්‍ය තීරණ ගැනෙනු ඇතැයිද එම ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා කතානායකවරයාට එවා ඇති එම ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපියේ මෙසේ සඳහන් වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට උදේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சபாநாயகரிடம் ஜனாதிபதி ராஜினாமா",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ தனது பதவி விலகல் கடிதத்தை சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தனவுக்கு இன்று (14) இரவு அனுப்பி வைத்துள்ளார்.",
        "நாட்டில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள பதற்றமான சூழ்நிலை காரணமாக கொழும்பு கோட்டை ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் இருந்து வெளியேறி தீவிலுள்ள பாதுகாப்பு நிலையத்தில் தங்கியிருந்த திரு.கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ, தனது மனைவி மற்றும் இரண்டு பாதுகாவலர்களுடன் கடந்த 12ஆம் திகதி மாலைதீவுக்கு சென்றுள்ளார். விமானப்படை.மாலத்தீவில் இருந்து புறப்பட்டு இன்று மதியம் சிங்கப்பூர் வந்தடைந்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் இராஜினாமா கடிதம் தொடர்பில் சபாநாயகர் மற்றும் சட்ட திணைக்களங்கள் ஆராய்ந்து வருவதாக நாடாளுமன்ற வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற அலுவல்கள் தொடர்பான குழுவின் விசேட கூட்டம் சபாநாயகர் தலைமையில் நாளை காலை பாராளுமன்ற கட்டிடத் தொகுதியில் நடைபெறவுள்ளதாகவும், புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை நியமிப்பது தொடர்பில் தேவையான தீர்மானங்கள் அங்கு மேற்கொள்ளப்படும் எனவும் தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ சபாநாயகருக்கு அனுப்பி வைத்துள்ள இராஜினாமா கடிதம் பின்வருமாறு."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்றிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற விவகாரங்களுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}