{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Possible-devastating-situation-averted-due-to-COVID-vaccination-rollout-President/108-231932",
  "time_ut": 1645864822,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Possible devastating situation averted due to COVID vaccination rollout- President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Possible devastating situation averted due to COVID vaccination rollout- President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A possible catastrophic situation that could be emerged in the country has been brought under control by implementing COVID-19 vaccination programme, President Gotabaya Rajapaksa said.",
        "The President made these remarks addressing the High-Level Thematic Debate on 'Galvanising Momentum for Universal Vaccination' held at the General Assembly Hall, United Nations Headquarters, yesterday (25), via video link.",
        "“The emergence of new variants of concern remains a dangerous possibility while availability of vaccines remains uneven globally. As I stated in my address to the General Assembly last year, ensuring everyone, everywhere, is vaccinated is the best way out of the pandemic,” the President said.",
        "President of the UN General Assembly Mr. Abdulla Shahid and the Secretary-General of the United Nations António Guterres expressing their views at the beginning of the debate pointed out the importance of vaccination and how different states have acted on it."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "'Galvanising Momentum for",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Universal Vaccination'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the General Assembly Hall",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "United Nations Headquarters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the General Assembly",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the UN General Assembly",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abdulla Shahid",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "António Guterres",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කොවිඩ් එන්නත් ව්‍යාප්තිය නිසා ඇති විය හැකි විනාශකාරී තත්ත්වයක් වැළකුණා - ජනපති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COVID-19 එන්නත් වැඩසටහන ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම තුළින් රට තුළ මතුවිය හැකි ව්‍යසනකාරී තත්ත්වයක් පාලනය කර ඇති බව ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා මේ බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ඊයේ (25) එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මූලස්ථානයේ මහා සභා ශාලාවේ පැවති ‘විශ්ව එන්නත් සඳහා ගැල්වනයිසින් ගම්‍යතාව’ පිළිබඳ ඉහළ පෙළේ තේමා විවාදය වීඩියෝ සබැඳිය ඔස්සේ අමතමිනි.",
        "“එන්නත් ලබා ගැනීමේ හැකියාව ගෝලීය වශයෙන් අසමානව පවතින අතරම, සැලකිලිමත් වීමේ නව ප්‍රභේද මතුවීම භයානක අවස්ථාවක් ලෙස පවතී. පසුගිය වසරේ මහා සභා රැස්වීමේදී මා ප්‍රකාශ කළ පරිදි, සෑම තැනකම, සෑම කෙනෙකුටම එන්නත් ලබා දෙන බවට සහතික වීම වසංගතයෙන් මිදීමට ඇති හොඳම මාර්ගයයි, ”ජනාධිපතිවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මහා මණ්ඩලයේ සභාපති අබ්දුල්ලා ෂාහිඩ් මහතා සහ එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මහලේකම් ඇන්ටෝනියෝ ගුටරෙස් මහතා විවාදය ආරම්භයේදී අදහස් දක්වමින් එන්නත් කිරීමේ වැදගත්කම සහ විවිධ රාජ්‍යයන් ඒ සඳහා ක්‍රියා කර ඇති ආකාරය පෙන්වා දෙන ලදී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "'Galvanising Momentum සඳහා",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශ්ව එන්නත'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහා සභා ශාලාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මූලස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහා සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය අවුරුද්දේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මහා මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබ්දුල්ලා ෂාහිඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇන්ටෝනියෝ ගුටරෙස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோவிட் தடுப்பூசி மூலம் சாத்தியமான பேரழிவு நிலைமை தவிர்க்கப்பட்டது - ஜனாதிபதி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொவிட்-19 தடுப்பூசி திட்டத்தை நடைமுறைப்படுத்துவதன் மூலம் நாட்டில் ஏற்படக்கூடிய பேரழிவு நிலைமை கட்டுப்பாட்டுக்குள் கொண்டுவரப்பட்டுள்ளதாக ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "நேற்று (25) ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் தலைமையகத்தில் உள்ள பொதுச் சபை மண்டபத்தில் நடைபெற்ற 'உலகளாவிய தடுப்பூசிக்கான கால்வனிசிங் வேகம்' தொடர்பான உயர் மட்ட கருப்பொருள் விவாதத்தில் காணொலி மூலம் உரையாற்றும் போதே ஜனாதிபதி இதனைத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"தடுப்பூசிகள் கிடைப்பது உலகளவில் சீரற்றதாக இருக்கும்போது கவலையின் புதிய மாறுபாடுகள் தோன்றுவது ஆபத்தான சாத்தியமாகவே உள்ளது. கடந்த ஆண்டு பொதுச் சபையில் நான் ஆற்றிய உரையில் கூறியது போல், எல்லா இடங்களிலும் தடுப்பூசி போடப்படுவதை உறுதி செய்வதே தொற்றுநோயிலிருந்து சிறந்த வழியாகும், ”என்று ஜனாதிபதி கூறினார்.",
        "ஐநா பொதுச் சபையின் தலைவர் திரு. அப்துல்லா ஷாஹித் மற்றும் ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபையின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் அன்டோனியோ குட்டெரெஸ் ஆகியோர் விவாதத்தின் தொடக்கத்தில் தங்கள் கருத்துக்களைத் தெரிவித்து, தடுப்பூசியின் முக்கியத்துவத்தையும் பல்வேறு மாநிலங்கள் அதில் எவ்வாறு செயல்பட்டன என்பதையும் சுட்டிக்காட்டினர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "'கால்வனிசிங் உந்தம்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலகளாவிய தடுப்பூசி'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுச் சபை மண்டபம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் தலைமையகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொதுச் சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐநா பொதுச் சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அப்துல்லா ஷாஹித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அன்டோனியோ குட்டரெஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}