{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Low-lying-area-residents-of-Gin-Ganga-warned-of-possible-floods/108-240235",
  "time_ut": 1656827293,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Low-lying area residents of Gin Ganga warned of possible floods",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Low-lying area residents of Gin Ganga warned of possible floods",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Irrigation Department requested the residents who are living in the low-lying areas of Gin Ganga and the motorists driving through those areas to be extremely vigilant of possible minor floods.",
        "The Department said that significant rainfall in most of the upstream catchment areas of Gin Ganga Basin as of 8.00 am today.",
        "Analyzing the current deluge and rising water levels of the rivers that flowing into Hydro power Stations which are fed by Gin Ganga, there is a possibility of minor floods in the low-lying areas of Gin Ganga valley situated in Welivitiya Divithura, Baddegama, Kotapola, Hikkaduwa, Niyangama, Neluwa, Tawalama, Akmeemana, Nagoda, Alpitiya, Bope Poddala and Galle D/S Divisions within next 24 hours."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gin Ganga",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Irrigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gin Ganga Basin",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hydro power Stations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gin Ganga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gin Ganga",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welivitiya Divithura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Baddegama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kotapola",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hikkaduwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Niyangama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Neluwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tawalama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Akmeemana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nagoda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alpitiya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bope Poddala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next 24 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගංවතුර ඇතිවිය හැකි බවට ගිං ගඟ පහත් බිම් ප්‍රදේශවාසීන් අනතුරු ඇඟවීය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ගිං ගඟ ආශ්‍රිත පහත් බිම්වල පදිංචිව සිටින ජනතාවගෙන් සහ එම ප්‍රදේශ හරහා වාහන ධාවනය කරන රියදුරන්ගෙන් ඇතිවිය හැකි සුළු ගංවතුර තත්ත්වයන් පිළිබඳව දැඩි අවධානයෙන් පසුවන ලෙස වාරිමාර්ග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව ඉල්ලා සිටියි.",
        "ගිං ගඟ ද්‍රෝණියේ ඉහළ ජල පෝෂක ප්‍රදේශ බොහොමයකට අද පෙරවරු 8.00 වන විට සැලකිය යුතු වර්ෂාපතනයක් ලැබෙන බව එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ගිං ගඟෙන් පෝෂණය වන ජල විදුලි බලාගාරවලට ගලා බසින ගංගාවල වත්මන් ගංවතුර සහ ජල මට්ටම ඉහළ යාම විශ්ලේෂණය කිරීමේදී වැලිවිටිය දිවිතුර, බද්දේගම, කොටපොල, ගිං ගඟ නිම්නයේ පහත් බිම්වල සුළු ගංවතුර තත්ත්වයක් ඇතිවීමේ හැකියාවක් පවතී. හික්කඩුව, නියංගම, නෙළුව, තවලම, අක්මීමන, නාගොඩ, ඇල්පිටිය, බෝපේ පෝද්දල සහ ගාල්ල ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කොට්ඨාස ඉදිරි පැය 24 තුළ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගිං ගඟ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වාරිමාර්ග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෙදපාර්තෙම්න්තුෙව්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිං ගංගා ද්‍රෝණිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජල විදුලි බලාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිං ගඟ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිං ගඟ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිවිටිය දිවිතුර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බද්දේගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටපොල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hikkaduwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නියංගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෙළුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තවලම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අක්මීමන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාගොඩ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල්පිටිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෝපේ පෝද්දල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ පැය 24",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜின் கங்கையில் தாழ்வான பகுதிகளில் வசிப்பவர்கள் வெள்ள அபாய எச்சரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜின்கங்கையின் தாழ்வான பகுதிகளில் வசிக்கும் மக்களும், அவ்வழியாகச் செல்லும் வாகன சாரதிகளும் சிறு வெள்ளப்பெருக்கு ஏற்படக்கூடிய அபாயம் ஏற்பட்டால் மிகவும் அவதானமாக இருக்குமாறு நீர்ப்பாசன திணைக்களம் கேட்டுக்கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "இன்று காலை 8.00 மணி நிலவரப்படி ஜின் கங்கைப் படுகையின் பெரும்பாலான மேல் நீரோடை நீர்ப்பிடிப்புப் பகுதிகளில் கணிசமான மழை பெய்யும் என்று திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜின் கங்கை நீர் மின் நிலையங்களுக்கு பாயும் ஆறுகளின் தற்போதைய பிரளயம் மற்றும் நீர் மட்டம் உயர்வதன் மூலம் வெலிவிட்டிய திவிதுர, பத்தேகம, கொட்டபொல ஆகிய இடங்களில் அமைந்துள்ள ஜின் கங்கை பள்ளத்தாக்கின் தாழ்வான பகுதிகளில் சிறு வெள்ளம் ஏற்பட வாய்ப்பு உள்ளது. ஹிக்கடுவ, நியங்கம, நெலுவ, தவலம, அக்மீமன, நாகொட, அல்பிட்டிய, போபே பொத்தல மற்றும் காலி D/S பிரிவுகள் அடுத்த 24 மணி நேரத்திற்குள்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜின் கங்கா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நீர்ப்பாசன திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜின் கங்கா பேசின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நீர் மின் நிலையங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜின் கங்கா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜின் கங்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிவிடிய திவித்துறை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தேகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொட்டபொல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hikkaduwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நியங்கமா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நெலுவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தவலம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அக்மீமன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாகொட",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அல்பிட்டிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "போப் போத்தலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த 24 மணிநேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}