{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/இன்று-கடும்-மழை/175-303297",
  "time_ut": 1661915164,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இன்று கடும் மழை",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Heavy rain today",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Meteorological Department has announced that heavy rainfall of more than 150 mm is expected in many parts of the country today.",
        "There is a possibility of developing a low atmospheric fog in the areas surrounding Sri Lanka.",
        "Occasional rain or thundershowers are likely in most parts of the country.",
        "Heavy rainfall of more than 150 mm is expected at some places in the Upper, Southern, Sabaragamuwa, Central and Uva provinces.",
        "Heavy rainfall of over 100 mm is expected at some places in other parts of the country. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Meteorological Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "more than 150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Upper",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southern, Sabaragamuwa, Central",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අද මහ වැස්ස",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අද දිනයේ දිවයිනේ බොහෝ ප්‍රදේශවලට මිලිමීටර් 150 ඉක්ම වූ තද වර්ෂාපතනයක් අපේක්ෂා කරන බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව නිවේදනය කරයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අවට ප්‍රදේශවල අඩු වායුගෝලීය මීදුම් තත්ත්වයක් වර්ධනය වීමේ හැකියාවක් පවතිනවා.",
        "දිවයිනේ බොහෝ ප්‍රදේශවල විටින් විට වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇති විය හැක.",
        "ඉහළ, දකුණ, සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම සහ ඌව පළාත්වල ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලිමීටර් 150ට වැඩි තද වර්ෂාපතනයක් අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "දිවයිනේ සෙසු ප්‍රදේශවල ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලිමීටර් 100 ඉක්ම වූ තද වර්ෂාපතනයක් අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ. (ඒ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "150 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "150 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉහළ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණ, සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இன்று கடும் மழை",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டின் பல பகுதிகளில் இன்று 150 மில்லி மீற்றருக்கும்  அதிகமான மிகப் பலத்த மழைவீழ்ச்சி எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுவதாக வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையைச் சூழவுள்ள பிரதேசங்களில் ஒரு கீழ் வளிமண்டலத் தளம்பல் நிலை உருவாகக் கூடிய கூடிய சாத்தியம் காணப்படுகின்றது.",
        "நாட்டின் பெரும்பாலான பிரதேசங்களில் அவ்வப்போது மழையோ அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழையோ பெய்யக் கூடிய சாத்தியம் காணப்படுகின்றது.",
        "மேல், தென், சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய மற்றும் ஊவா மாகாணங்களில் சில இடங்களில் 150 மில்லி மீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான மிகப் பலத்த மழைவீழ்ச்சி எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகின்றது.",
        "நாட்டின் ஏனைய பிரதேசங்களில் சில இடங்களில் 100 மில்லி மீற்றருக்கும்  அளவான பலத்த மழைவீழ்ச்சி எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகின்றது. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வானிலை ஆய்வு மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "150க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "150க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு, சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}