{
  "newspaper_id": "b-b-c-com-sinhala",
  "url": "https://www.bbc.com/sinhala/sri-lanka-62100891",
  "time_ut": 1657277090,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අන්තරේට කඳුළු ගෑස් : \"අපි උඹලට බෝධි පුජා තිබ්බ\"",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Tear gas for Antare: \"We had Bodhi Puja for you\"",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The police fired tear gas and water cannons at the protest that came from Kelaniya to Colombo on June 8, demanding that the President and the Prime Minister should step down and the activists in custody should be released.",
        "While protests are scheduled to be held in many areas including Colombo on July 09, the police headquarters (July 08) imposed a police curfew covering all police jurisdictions of 7 police divisions in the Western Province from 9 p.m. until further notice.",
        "A notice issued with the signature of the Inspector General of Police states that police curfew will be in effect in Colombo North, Colombo South, Colombo Central, Galkissa, Nugegoda, Kelaniya and Migomuwa police divisions until further notice.",
        "Many people are paying attention to the implementation of police curfew in a background where protests will be organized in Colombo tomorrow as a national day of protest, forcing President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe to step down."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Antare",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kelaniya to Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 8",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 08",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Inspector General of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo North, Colombo South, Colombo Central",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nugegoda",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelaniya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Migomuwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අන්තරේට කඳුළු ගෑස් : \"අපි උඹලට බෝධි පුජා තිබ්බ\"",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ අගමැතිවරයා ඉවත් විය යුතු බවට සහ අත්අඩංගුවේ සිටින අරගලකරුවන් නිදහස් කළ යුතු බවට බල කරමින් අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බල මණ්ඩලය අද ජුනි 8  කැලණියේ සිට කොළඹ බලා පැමිණි විරෝධතාවයට පොලිසිය විසින් කඳුළු ගෑස් සහ ජල ප්‍රහාර එල්ල කළේය.",
        "ජූලි 09 වැනිදා කොළඹ ඇතුළු ප්‍රදේශ රැසක විරෝධතා පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතව තිබියදී පොලිස් මූලස්ථානය (ජූලි 08) රාත්‍රී 9 සිට නැවත දැනුම් දෙන තුරු බස්නාහිර පළාතේ පොලිස් කොට්ඨාස 7ක සියලුම පොලිස් බල ප්‍රදේශ ආවරණය වන පරිදි පොලිස් ඇඳිරි නීතිය පනවනු ලැබීය.",
        "කොළඹ උතුර, කොළඹ දකුණ, කොළඹ මධ්‍යම, ගල්කිස්ස, නුගේගොඩ, කැලණිය සහ මිගමුව පොලිස් කොට්ඨාසවල  නැවත දැනුම්දෙන තුරු පොලිස් ඇඳිරි නීතිය ක්‍රියාත්මක බව පොලිස්පතිවරයාගේ අත්සනින් යුතුව නිකුත් කළ නිවේදනයක සඳහන් වේ.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂට සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහට ධුරයෙන් ඉවත් වන ලෙස බලකරමින් ජාතික විරෝධතා දිනයක් ලෙස හෙට කොළඹ කේන්ද්‍ර කරගෙන විරෝධතා සංවිධානය කෙරෙන පසුබිමක පොලිස් ඇඳිරි නීතිය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම ගැන බොහෝ දෙනාගේ අවධානය යොමුව තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අන්තරේ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කැලණියේ සිට කොළඹට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 8",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 08",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 ප.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ උතුර, කොළඹ දකුණ, මැද කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුගේගොඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelaniya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Migomuwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அந்தரேவுக்கு கண்ணீர் புகை: \"உனக்காக போதி பூஜை செய்தோம்\"",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதியும் பிரதமரும் பதவி விலக வேண்டும், தடுப்புக் காவலில் உள்ள செயற்பாட்டாளர்களை விடுதலை செய்ய வேண்டும் எனக் கோரி ஜூன் 8ஆம் திகதி களனியில் இருந்து கொழும்புக்கு வந்த ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தின் மீது பொலிஸார் கண்ணீர்ப்புகை மற்றும் நீர்த்தாரை பிரயோகம் செய்தனர்.",
        "ஜூலை 09 ஆம் திகதி கொழும்பு உட்பட பல பிரதேசங்களில் ஆர்ப்பாட்டங்கள் நடத்தப்படவுள்ள நிலையில், பொலிஸ் தலைமையகம் (ஜூலை 08) மேல் மாகாணத்தின் 7 பொலிஸ் பிரிவுகளுக்கு உட்பட்ட அனைத்து பொலிஸ் அதிகார வரம்புகளிலும் இரவு 9 மணி முதல் மறு அறிவித்தல் வரை பொலிஸ் ஊரடங்குச் சட்டத்தை அமுல்படுத்தியது.",
        "கொழும்பு வடக்கு, கொழும்பு தெற்கு, கொழும்பு மத்திய, கல்கிஸ்ஸ, நுகேகொட, களனி மற்றும் மிகொமுவ ஆகிய பொலிஸ் பிரிவுகளில் மறு அறிவித்தல் வரை பொலிஸ் ஊரடங்குச் சட்டம் அமுலில் இருக்கும் என பொலிஸ் மா அதிபரின் கையொப்பத்துடன் வெளியிடப்பட்ட அறிவித்தலில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவை பதவி விலகுமாறு வலியுறுத்தி நாளை தேசிய எதிர்ப்பு தினமாக கொழும்பில் ஆர்ப்பாட்டம் நடத்தப்படவுள்ள பின்னணியில் பொலிஸ் ஊரடங்குச் சட்டம் அமுல்படுத்தப்படுவது தொடர்பில் பலரும் அவதானம் செலுத்தி வருகின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அந்தரே",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "களனியிலிருந்து கொழும்பு வரை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 8",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 08",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு 9 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்ஸ்பெக்டர் ஜெனரல் ஆஃப் போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு வடக்கு, கொழும்பு தெற்கு, கொழும்பு மத்திய",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுகேகொட",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelaniya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Migomuwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}