{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/වේගයෙන්-පැතිරෙන-කොවිඩ්-අනු-ප්‍රභේදයක්-ශ්‍රී-ලංකාවේ/101-617292",
  "time_ut": 1659173444,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "වේගයෙන් පැතිරෙන කොවිඩ් අනු ප්‍රභේදයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A fast spreading covid variant in Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Professor Chandima Jeevanda, Head of the Department of Allergy Immunology and Cell Biology at the University of Sri Jayewardenepura, said that the rapid-spreading sub-variant of Covid called Omicron BA 5 has been found for the first time in Sri Lanka.",
        "He also mentioned that due to this rapidly spreading variety, a dire situation may arise in the country in the future.",
        "Stating that this is the sub-type of Covid that is spreading rapidly in the world today, Mr. Jeevandara also stated that due to this, the number of Covid patients in Sri Lanka is likely to increase rapidly.",
        "He further said that this subspecies was found especially in the areas around Colombo and considering this situation it is very important for the people to follow the health rules and act carefully."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Chandima Jeevanda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Allergy Immunology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cell Biology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the University of Sri Jayewardenepura",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Covid",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Omicron BA 5",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jeevandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වේගයෙන් පැතිරෙන කොවිඩ් අනු ප්‍රභේදයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "සීඝ්‍ර පැතිරීමක් සහිත ඔමික්‍රොන් බී.ඒ 5 යනුවෙන් හැඳින්වෙන කොවිඩ්  අනු ප්‍රභේදය මෙරටින් ප්‍රථම වතාවට හමුවී ඇතැයි ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ ආසාත්මිකතා ප්‍රතිශක්තිවේද සහ සෛල ජෛව විද්‍යා අධ්‍යයන අංශයේ  ප්‍රධානී මහාචාර්ය චන්දිම ජීවන්දර මහතා පැවැසීය.",
        "වේගයෙන් පැතිරෙන මෙම ප්‍රභේදය නිසා රටේ දරුණු තත්වයක් ඉදිරියේදී මතු විය හැකි බවද  ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "අද ලෝකයේ සීඝ්‍රයෙන් පැතිරෙන කොවිඩ්  අනු ප්‍රභේදය මෙය බව සඳහන් කරන ජීවන්දර මහතා  මේ හේතුවෙන් මෙරට කොවිඩ්  රෝගීන් සංඛ්‍යාව වේගයෙන් ඉහළ යෑමට ඉඩ ඇතැයිද  ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "විශේෂයෙන්ම කොළඹ ආශ්‍රිත ප්‍රදේශවලින් මෙම අනු ප්‍රභේදය  සුලබව  හමුවූ බවත්  මෙම  තත්වය සැලකිල්ලට ගෙන ජනතාව සෞඛ්‍ය නීති පිළිපදිමින්  පරිස්සම්කාරී ලෙස කටයුතු කිරීම ඉතා වැදගත් බවත් හෙතෙම වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චන්දිම ජීවන්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අසාත්මිකතා ප්රතිශක්තිකරණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෛල ජීව විද්යාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොවිඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Omicron BA 5",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජීවන්දර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையில் வேகமாக பரவும் கோவிட் மாறுபாடு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் ஒவ்வாமை நோயெதிர்ப்பு மற்றும் உயிரியல் துறையின் தலைவர் பேராசிரியர் சந்திம ஜீவந்தா, இலங்கையில் முதன்முறையாக ஓமிக்ரோன் பிஏ 5 எனப்படும் கோவிட் இன் அதிவேகமாக பரவும் துணை மாறுபாடு கண்டறியப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "வேகமாகப் பரவிவரும் இந்த இரகத்தின் காரணமாக எதிர்காலத்தில் நாட்டில் மோசமான நிலைமை ஏற்படக் கூடும் எனவும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இதுவே இன்று உலகில் வேகமாகப் பரவி வரும் கோவிட் வகையின் உப வகையாகும் எனத் தெரிவித்த திரு ஜீவந்தர, இதன் காரணமாக இலங்கையில் கொவிட் நோயாளர்களின் எண்ணிக்கை வேகமாக அதிகரிக்க வாய்ப்புள்ளதாகவும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "குறிப்பாக கொழும்பை அண்மித்த பகுதிகளில் இந்த உபரி இனம் காணப்படுவதாகவும், இந்நிலையை கருத்தில் கொண்டு மக்கள் சுகாதார விதிகளை பின்பற்றி கவனமாக செயற்படுவது மிகவும் அவசியமானது எனவும் அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சந்திமா ஜீவந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒவ்வாமை நோய்த்தடுப்பு துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உயிரணு உயிரியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவிட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமிக்ரான் பிஏ 5",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜீவந்தரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}