{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-cuts-petrol-by-rs-20-diesel-by-rs20-97504/",
  "time_ut": 1658065320,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka cuts petrol by Rs.20, Diesel by Rs20",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka cuts petrol by Rs.20, Diesel by Rs20",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s state-run Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC) has reduced fuel prices by 10-20 rupees, effective from 10.00pm on 17 July.",
        "Petrol Octane 92 was reduced by 20 rupees to 450 rupees a litre.",
        "Petrol Octane 95 was reduced by 10 rupees to 540 rupees a litre.",
        "Super Diesel was reduced by 10 rupees to 520 rupees per litre, and Auto Diesel was reduced by 20 rupees to 440 rupees.",
        "The reductions come after prices were raised by up to 100 rupees for Petrol Octane 95 on 26 June.",
        "The CPC urged the public not to queue up in front of fuel stations as it had an effective plan for an uninterrupted supply of Lanka White Diesel and Octane 95 from July 21.",
        "Sri Lanka’s forex crisis has left the country unable to open Letters of Credit to import fuel, and consumers find it difficult to bear the rising costs.",
        "The previous fuel revisions had the ripple effect of increased bread, transport and other commodity prices. (Colombo/Jul17/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Diesel",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10-20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "450",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "540",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Super Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "520",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Auto Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "440",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "up to 100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka White Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Letters of Credit",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලංකාව පෙට්‍රල් රුපියල් 20 කින්, ඩීසල් රුපියල් 20 කින් අඩු කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය විසින් පවත්වාගෙන යනු ලබන ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව (CPC) ජූලි 17 වන දින රාත්‍රී 10.00 සිට බලපැවැත්වෙන පරිදි ඉන්ධන මිල රුපියල් 10-20 කින් අඩු කර ඇත.",
        "පෙට්‍රල් ඔක්ටේන් 92 ලීටරයක් ​​රුපියල් 450 දක්වා රුපියල් 20 කින් අඩු කළා.",
        "පෙට්‍රල් ඔක්ටේන් 95 ලීටරයක් ​​රුපියල් 540 දක්වා රුපියල් 10 කින් අඩු කළා.",
        "සුපර් ඩීසල් ලීටරයක් ​​රුපියල් 520 දක්වා රුපියල් 10 කින් අඩු කළ අතර ඔටෝ ඩීසල් රුපියල් 440 ක් දක්වා රුපියල් 20 කින් අඩු විය.",
        "ජුනි 26 වැනිදා පෙට්‍රල් ඔක්ටේන් 95 සඳහා රුපියල් 100 දක්වා මිල ඉහළ දැමීමෙන් පසුව මෙම අඩු කිරීම් සිදු කර ඇත.",
        "ජුලි 21 වැනිදා සිට ලංකා වයිට් ඩීසල් සහ ඔක්ටේන් 95 අඛණ්ඩව සැපයීම සඳහා ඵලදායී සැලැස්මක් ඇති බැවින් ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් ඉදිරිපිට පෝලිම්වල නොසිටින ලෙස ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව මහජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදේශ විනිමය අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් ඉන්ධන ආනයනය කිරීම සඳහා ණයවර ලිපි විවෘත කිරීමට නොහැකි වී ඇති අතර පාරිභෝගිකයින්ට ඉහළ යන පිරිවැය දරා ගැනීමට අපහසු වී ඇත.",
        "පෙර ඉන්ධන සංශෝධන නිසා පාන්, ප්‍රවාහනය සහ අනෙකුත් භාණ්ඩ මිල ඉහළ යාමේ රැල්ලක් ඇති විය. (කොළඹ/ජූලි17/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඩීසල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10-20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "450",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "540",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුපිරි ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "520",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔටෝ ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "440",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100 දක්වා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා වයිට් ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ණයවර ලිපි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையில் பெட்ரோலுக்கு ரூ.20, டீசலுக்கு ரூ.20 குறைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - இலங்கையின் அரச நிறுவனமான சிலோன் பெட்ரோலியம் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் (CPC) எரிபொருள் விலையை 10-20 ரூபாவால் குறைத்துள்ளது, இது ஜூலை 17 அன்று இரவு 10.00 மணி முதல் நடைமுறைக்கு வருகிறது.",
        "பெற்றோல் ஒக்டேன் 92 ஒரு லீற்றர் 20 ரூபாவால் குறைக்கப்பட்டு 450 ரூபாவாகும்.",
        "பெற்றோல் ஒக்டேன் 95 ஒரு லீற்றர் 10 ரூபாவால் குறைக்கப்பட்டு 540 ரூபாவாகும்.",
        "சுப்பர் டீசல் 10 ரூபாவினால் குறைக்கப்பட்டு 520 ரூபாவாகவும், ஆட்டோ டீசல் 20 ரூபாவினால் குறைக்கப்பட்டு 440 ரூபாவாகவும் விற்பனை செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜூன் 26 அன்று பெட்ரோல் ஒக்டேன் 95 இன் விலை 100 ரூபாய் வரை உயர்த்தப்பட்டதை அடுத்து இந்த குறைப்புக்கள் வந்துள்ளன.",
        "ஜூலை 21 முதல் லங்கா ஒயிட் டீசல் மற்றும் ஒக்டேன் 95 ஆகியவற்றை தடையின்றி வழங்குவதற்கான பயனுள்ள திட்டம் இருப்பதால், எரிபொருள் நிலையங்களுக்கு முன்னால் வரிசையில் நிற்க வேண்டாம் என்று CPC பொதுமக்களை வலியுறுத்தியது.",
        "இலங்கையின் அந்நிய செலாவணி நெருக்கடியால் எரிபொருளை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்கான கடன் கடிதங்களை திறக்க முடியாமல் போனது, மேலும் அதிகரித்து வரும் செலவினங்களை தாங்கிக்கொள்ள நுகர்வோர் சிரமப்படுகின்றனர்.",
        "முந்தைய எரிபொருள் திருத்தங்கள் அதிகரித்த ரொட்டி, போக்குவரத்து மற்றும் பிற பொருட்களின் விலைகளின் சிற்றலை விளைவைக் கொண்டிருந்தன. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை17/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "டீசல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10-20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "450",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "540",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சூப்பர் டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "520",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆட்டோ டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "440",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100 வரை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கா ஒயிட் டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடன் கடிதங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}