{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ගෝඨා-ගෝ-ගමට-පහරදීම-ගැන-විවාදයක්-බදාදා/1-616946",
  "time_ut": 1658655544,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ගෝඨා ගෝ ගමට පහරදීම ගැන විවාදයක් බදාදා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A debate about the attack on Gota Go village on Wednesday",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A debate regarding the evacuation of the protesters from the Colombo Golf Course \"Gota Go Village\" protest site is scheduled to be held in Parliament tomorrow (27).",
        "The main organizer of the opposition, MP Lakshman Kiriella, requested the Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena yesterday (23) to convene the Parliament today (25) to discuss the matter.",
        "As it is practically difficult to convene the parliament today and summon the MPs due to the fuel issue, the government intends to debate the same issue when the parliament meets tomorrow, Wednesday, to pass the emergency law gazette notification.",
        "Prior to this, the Committee on Parliamentary Affairs had decided to pass the gazette notification on the emergency law for the next day's meeting of Parliament.",
        "Lakshman Kiriella, the main organizer of the opposition, said that it is very important to have a dialogue about it as it is an illegal and undemocratic act to beat and kick out the activists."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gota Go",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Wednesday",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gota Go Village",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lakshman Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow, Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Committee on Parliamentary Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next day's",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lakshman Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගෝඨා ගෝ ගමට පහරදීම ගැන විවාදයක් බදාදා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අරගලකරුවන් කොළඹ ගෝල්ෆේස්\" ගෝඨා ගෝ ගම\" අරගල භූමියෙන් ඉවත් කිරීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන්වූ විවාදයක් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී අනිද්දා(27) පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතය.",
        "ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් විවාද කිරීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අද(25) දිනයේ රැස්කරන ලෙස විපක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල මහතා අගමැති දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතාගෙන් පෙරේදා(23) ඉල්ලීමක් කළේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අද දිනයේ රැස් කිරීම සහ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් කැඳවීම ඉන්ධන ප්‍රශ්නය හේතුවෙන් ප්‍රායෝගික වශයෙන් දුෂ්කර හෙයින් හදිසි නීති ගැසට් නිවේදනය සම්මත කිරීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අනිද්දා බදාදා රැස්වන අවස්ථාවේදී එම කාරණයද විවාදයට ගැනීමට රජය අදහස් කර ඇත.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අනිද්දා දිනයේ රැස්වීමට පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව මෙයට පෙර තීරණය කළේ හදිසි නීතිය පිළිබඳ ගැසට් නිවේදනය සම්මත කිරීම සඳහා පමණකි.",
        "අරගලකරුවන් පහරදී පන්නා දැමීම නීති විරෝධී සහ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍ර විරෝධී ක්‍රියාවක් හෙයින් ඒ පිළිබඳව සංවාදයක් ඇති කිරීම ඉතා වැදගත් බව විපක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී නීතීඥ නීතිඥ ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල මහතා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝටා යන්න",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "බදාදා",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝටා ගෝ ගම්මානය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට, බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ දවසේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புதன்கிழமை கோத்தா கோ கிராமத்தின் மீதான தாக்குதல் பற்றிய விவாதம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பு கோல்ஃப் மைதானத்தில் இருந்து போராட்டக்காரர்களை வெளியேற்றுவது தொடர்பான விவாதம் நாளை (27) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நடைபெறவுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த விடயம் தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடுவதற்காக இன்று (25) பாராளுமன்றத்தை கூட்டுமாறு எதிர்க்கட்சியின் பிரதான அமைப்பாளரான பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல, பிரதமர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தனவிடம் நேற்று (23) கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "எரிபொருள் பிரச்சினை காரணமாக இன்று பாராளுமன்றத்தை கூட்டுவதும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களை அழைப்பதும் நடைமுறையில் கடினமானது என்பதால், அவசரகால சட்ட வர்த்தமானி அறிவித்தலை நிறைவேற்றுவதற்காக நாளை புதன்கிழமை பாராளுமன்றம் கூடும் போது இதே விடயத்தை விவாதிப்பதற்கு அரசாங்கம் உத்தேசித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதற்கு முன்னதாக அவசர சட்டம் தொடர்பான வர்த்தமானி அறிவிப்பை நாளை மறுதினம் நடைபெறவுள்ள நாடாளுமன்ற கூட்டத்திற்கு நிறைவேற்ற நாடாளுமன்ற விவகாரங்களுக்கான குழு தீர்மானித்திருந்தது.",
        "செயற்பாட்டாளர்களை அடித்து உதைப்பது சட்டவிரோதமானதும் ஜனநாயகமற்றதுமான செயல் என்பதால் அது தொடர்பில் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்துவது மிகவும் அவசியமானது என எதிர்க்கட்சியின் பிரதான அமைப்பாளர் லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோதா கோ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "புதன்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோதா கோ கிராமம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை, புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற விவகாரங்களுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}