{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/LMD-ranks-ComBank-the-Most-Respected-Bank-in-Sri-Lanka-for-18th-year/34-738625",
  "time_ut": 1660329887,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "LMD ranks ComBank the Most Respected Bank in Sri Lanka for 18th year",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "LMD ranks ComBank the Most Respected Bank in Sri Lanka for 18th year",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Commercial Bank of Ceylon has been declared the Most Respected Bank in Sri Lanka for the 18th consecutive year and has retained its ranking as the fourth Most Respected corporate entity in the country overall, in the 2022 ‘Most Respected Entities in Sri Lanka’ rankings published by the LMD magazine.",
        "The bank was also ranked second overall for Financial Performance, Honesty, and Vision which are three of the 12 attributes covered by the survey commissioned by the magazine. Additionally, it was placed among the Top Five corporate entities in Sri Lanka in 2022 in seven of the attributes and was the highest-ranked bank for nine attributes including Financial Performance, Quality Consciousness, Management Profile, Honesty, Corporate Culture, CSR & Sustainability, Vision, HR & People Management, and Crisis Management.",
        "Commenting on this latest accolade, Commercial Bank Managing Director and Chief Executive Officer Sanath Manatunge said: “The respect Commercial Bank enjoys has been earned and enhanced through decades of dedication, demonstrated integrity and best practices, rigorous quality control and commitment to do the right thing. Despite the difficult socioeconomic conditions we currently operate in, the bank was also ranked fourth overall in ‘National Perspective.’ This is a testament to the bank’s commitment to the highest standards including sustainable business practices and a deep understanding of customer needs.”",
        "LMD noted that Commercial Bank of Ceylon demonstrated remarkable operating resilience throughout the pandemic through customer focus, digital engagement, and operational excellence. The bank also takes pride of place of being among the Top Five Most Respected entities in the country in every one of the 18 years since the magazine launched the ranking in 2005.  The methodology, sample composition, questionnaire and method of ranking for 2022 remain the same as the previous year when LMD shifted to a weighted ranking system based on the opinions of surveyed respondents. The ranking system operates by weighting three nominations for each company by assigning a weight of five points for the first mention, a weight of three for the second, and one for the third mention. The final rankings were based on the total sum value of the weighted scores for each company. The 12 Attributes evaluation criteria was set out by NielsenIQ’s annual peer review.",
        "This latest survey commissioned and conceptualised by LMD and conducted by NielsenIQ, covered a sample of 800 respondents who are managers and above in companies listed in the Colombo Stock Exchange (CSE), the LMD 100 (2020/2021) and Brands Annual 2021."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ComBank",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Respected Bank",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "18th year",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Commercial Bank of Ceylon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 18th consecutive year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "fourth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LMD",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Financial Performance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Honesty",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vision",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Financial Performance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Quality Consciousness",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Honesty",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Corporate Culture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSR & Sustainability",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vision",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "HR & People Management",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Crisis Management",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Commercial Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commercial Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "fourth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Commercial Bank of Ceylon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 18 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the previous year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "annual",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Stock Exchange",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020/2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Annual",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "LMD විසින් 18 වන වසර සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වඩාත්ම ගෞරවනීය බැංකුව ලෙස ComBank ශ්‍රේණිගත කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොමර්ෂල් බැංකුව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වඩාත්ම ගෞරවනීය බැංකුව ලෙස අඛණ්ඩව 18 වන වසරටත් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර ඇති අතර, 2022 ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද 'ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වඩාත්ම ගෞරවනීය ආයතන' ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම් අනුව, සමස්තයක් ලෙස දිවයිනේ සිව්වන වඩාත්ම ගෞරවනීය ආයතනික ආයතනය ලෙස ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම රඳවා ගෙන ඇත. LMD සඟරාව විසිනි.",
        "සඟරාව විසින් පත් කරන ලද සමීක්ෂණය මගින් ආවරණය කරන ලද ගුණාංග 12 න් තුනක් වන මූල්‍ය කාර්ය සාධනය, අවංකභාවය සහ දැක්ම සඳහා බැංකුව සමස්තයක් ලෙස දෙවන ස්ථානයට පත් විය. මීට අමතරව, එය ගුණාංග හතකින් 2022 දී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ හොඳම ආයතනික ආයතන පහ අතරට එක් වූ අතර මූල්‍ය කාර්ය සාධනය, තත්ත්ව සවිඥානකත්වය, කළමනාකරණ පැතිකඩ, අවංකභාවය, ආයතනික සංස්කෘතිය, CSR සහ තිරසාරත්වය ඇතුළු ගුණාංග නවයක් සඳහා ඉහළම ශ්‍රේණිගත බැංකුව විය. දැක්ම, මානව සම්පත් සහ පුද්ගල කළමනාකරණය, සහ අර්බුද කළමනාකරණය.",
        "මෙම නවතම ප්‍රශංසාව පිළිබඳව අදහස් දක්වමින් කොමර්ෂල් බැංකුවේ කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ සහ ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී සනත් මනතුංග මහතා මෙසේ පැවසීය: “දශක ගණනාවක කැපවීම, විදහා දක්වන අඛණ්ඩතාව සහ හොඳම භාවිතයන්, දැඩි තත්ත්ව පාලනය සහ නිවැරදි දේ කිරීමට ඇති කැපවීම තුළින් කොමර්ෂල් බැංකුවට ලැබෙන ගෞරවය උපයාගෙන වැඩි දියුණු කර ඇත. . අප දැනට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන දුෂ්කර සමාජ ආර්ථික තත්ත්වයන් මධ්‍යයේ වුවද, බැංකුව ‘ජාතික ඉදිරිදර්ශනය’ තුළ සමස්ත වශයෙන් සිව්වැනි ස්ථානයට පත් විය. මෙය තිරසාර ව්‍යාපාරික භාවිතයන් සහ පාරිභෝගික අවශ්‍යතා පිළිබඳ ගැඹුරු අවබෝධයක් ඇතුළු ඉහළම ප්‍රමිතීන් සඳහා බැංකුවේ කැපවීම පිළිබඳ සාක්ෂියකි.",
        "පාරිභෝගික අවධානය, ඩිජිටල් නියැලීම සහ මෙහෙයුම් විශිෂ්ටත්වය තුළින් කොමර්ෂල් බැංකුව වසංගතය පුරාවටම කැපී පෙනෙන මෙහෙයුම් ඔරොත්තු දීමේ හැකියාවක් පෙන්නුම් කළ බව LMD සඳහන් කළේය. සඟරාව 2005 දී ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම දියත් කළ දා සිට සෑම වසර 18 කින්ම සෑම වසරකම රටේ ඉහළම ගෞරවනීය ආයතන පහ අතරට පැමිණීමට බැංකුව ආඩම්බර වේ.  ක්‍රමවේදය, නියැදි සංයුතිය, ප්‍රශ්නාවලිය සහ 2022 සඳහා ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීමේ ක්‍රමය එලෙසම පවතී. සමීක්ෂණයට ලක් වූ ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වූවන්ගේ අදහස් මත පදනම්ව LMD බරිත ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීමේ ක්‍රමයකට මාරු වූ විට පෙර වසරේ මෙන්ම. ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීමේ ක්‍රමය ක්‍රියාත්මක වන්නේ පළමු සඳහන සඳහා ලකුණු පහක බරක්, දෙවැන්න සඳහා බර තුනක් සහ තුන්වන සඳහන සඳහා එකක් ලබා දීමෙන් සෑම සමාගමකටම නාමයෝජනා තුනක් බර කිරීමෙනි. අවසාන ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම් එක් එක් සමාගම සඳහා බර කළ ලකුණුවල මුළු එකතුව මත පදනම් විය. ගුණාංග 12 ඇගයීමේ නිර්ණායක NielsenIQ හි වාර්ෂික සම වයසේ සමාලෝචනය මගින් සකසා ඇත.",
        "මෙම නවතම සමීක්ෂණය LMD විසින් ආරම්භ කරන ලද සහ සංකල්පනය කරන ලද සහ NielsenIQ විසින් සිදු කරන ලද අතර, කොළඹ කොටස් වෙළඳපොලේ (CSE), LMD 100 (2020/2021) සහ 2021 Brands වාර්ෂිකව ලැයිස්තුගත කර ඇති සමාගම්වල කළමනාකරුවන් සහ ඊට වැඩි ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වූවන් 800 ක නියැදියක් ආවරණය කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ComBank",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ගෞරවනීය බැංකුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "18 වසර",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොමර්ෂල් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඛණ්ඩව 18 වන වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතරවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LMD",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්යමය ක්රියාකාරිත්වය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවංකභාවය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දැක්ම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්යමය ක්රියාකාරිත්වය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුණාත්මක විඥානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවංකභාවය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආයතනික සංස්කෘතිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSR සහ තිරසාරත්වය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දැක්ම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මානව සම්පත් සහ පුද්ගල කළමනාකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අර්බුද කළමනාකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොමර්ෂල් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමර්ෂල් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දශක",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතරවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොමර්ෂල් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙර වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටස් වෙළෙඳපොළ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020/2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "LMD ஆனது 18வது ஆண்டாக இலங்கையில் மிகவும் மதிக்கப்படும் வங்கியாக ComBank ஐ தரவரிசைப்படுத்தியுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொமர்ஷல் பேங்க் ஆஃப் இலங்கை தொடர்ந்து 18வது ஆண்டாக இலங்கையில் மிகவும் மதிக்கப்படும் வங்கியாக அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதுடன், 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு வெளியிடப்பட்ட 'இலங்கையில் மிகவும் மதிக்கப்படும் நிறுவனங்கள்' தரவரிசையில், ஒட்டுமொத்தமாக நாட்டில் நான்காவது மிகவும் மதிக்கப்படும் நிறுவனமாகத் தனது தரவரிசையைத் தக்க வைத்துக் கொண்டுள்ளது. LMD பத்திரிகை மூலம்.",
        "நிதி செயல்திறன், நேர்மை மற்றும் பார்வை ஆகியவற்றிற்காக வங்கி ஒட்டுமொத்தமாக இரண்டாவது இடத்தைப் பிடித்தது, அவை பத்திரிகையால் நியமிக்கப்பட்ட கணக்கெடுப்பின் 12 பண்புகளில் மூன்று. கூடுதலாக, இது 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டில் ஏழு பண்புக்கூறுகளில் இலங்கையின் முதல் ஐந்து கூட்டாண்மை நிறுவனங்களில் இடம் பெற்றது மற்றும் நிதி செயல்திறன், தர உணர்வு, மேலாண்மை விவரம், நேர்மை, கூட்டாண்மை கலாச்சாரம், CSR & நிலைத்தன்மை, உள்ளிட்ட ஒன்பது பண்புக்கூறுகளில் மிக உயர்ந்த தரவரிசை பெற்ற வங்கியாகும். பார்வை, மனிதவள மற்றும் மக்கள் மேலாண்மை மற்றும் நெருக்கடி மேலாண்மை.",
        "இந்த சமீபத்திய பாராட்டு குறித்து கருத்து தெரிவித்த கொமர்ஷல் வங்கியின் முகாமைத்துவப் பணிப்பாளரும் பிரதம நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரியுமான சனத் மனதுங்க, “பல தசாப்தங்களாக அர்ப்பணிப்பு, வெளிப்படுத்தப்பட்ட ஒருமைப்பாடு மற்றும் சிறந்த நடைமுறைகள், கடுமையான தரக் கட்டுப்பாடு மற்றும் சரியானதைச் செய்வதற்கான அர்ப்பணிப்பு ஆகியவற்றின் மூலம் கொமர்ஷல் வங்கி அனுபவிக்கும் மரியாதை பெறப்பட்டு மேம்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது. . நாங்கள் தற்போது செயல்படும் கடினமான சமூகப் பொருளாதார நிலைமைகள் இருந்தபோதிலும், வங்கி ஒட்டுமொத்தமாக ‘தேசியக் கண்ணோட்டத்தில்’ நான்காவது இடத்தைப் பெற்றுள்ளது. இது நிலையான வணிக நடைமுறைகள் மற்றும் வாடிக்கையாளர் தேவைகள் பற்றிய ஆழமான புரிதல் உள்ளிட்ட உயர் தரங்களுக்கு வங்கியின் அர்ப்பணிப்புக்கு ஒரு சான்றாகும்.",
        "வாடிக்கையாளர் கவனம், டிஜிட்டல் ஈடுபாடு மற்றும் செயல்பாட்டுச் சிறப்பு ஆகியவற்றின் மூலம் கொமர்ஷல் பேங்க் ஆஃப் சிலோன், தொற்றுநோய் முழுவதும் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க இயக்க நெகிழ்ச்சியை வெளிப்படுத்தியதாக LMD குறிப்பிட்டது. 2005 இல் பத்திரிகை தரவரிசையை அறிமுகப்படுத்தியதில் இருந்து ஒவ்வொரு 18 ஆண்டுகளில் நாட்டின் முதல் ஐந்து மிகவும் மதிக்கப்படும் நிறுவனங்களில் ஒன்றாக இருப்பதில் வங்கி பெருமை கொள்கிறது.  2022 ஆம் ஆண்டிற்கான முறை, மாதிரி கலவை, கேள்வித்தாள் மற்றும் தரவரிசை முறை ஆகியவை அப்படியே உள்ளன. கணக்கெடுக்கப்பட்ட பதிலளித்தவர்களின் கருத்துகளின் அடிப்படையில் LMD ஒரு எடையுள்ள தரவரிசை முறைக்கு மாறிய முந்தைய ஆண்டைப் போலவே. தரவரிசை முறையானது, ஒவ்வொரு நிறுவனத்திற்கும் மூன்று பரிந்துரைகளை எடைபோட்டு, முதல் குறிப்புக்கு ஐந்து புள்ளிகள், இரண்டாவதாக மூன்று புள்ளிகள் மற்றும் மூன்றாவது குறிப்புக்கு ஒரு எடையை ஒதுக்குவதன் மூலம் செயல்படுகிறது. இறுதி தரவரிசை ஒவ்வொரு நிறுவனத்திற்கும் எடையிடப்பட்ட மதிப்பெண்களின் மொத்த மதிப்பின் அடிப்படையில் அமைந்தது. 12 பண்புக்கூறுகள் மதிப்பீட்டு அளவுகோல் NielsenIQ இன் வருடாந்திர சக மதிப்பாய்வினால் அமைக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இந்த சமீபத்திய கணக்கெடுப்பு LMD ஆல் நியமிக்கப்பட்ட மற்றும் கருத்தாக்கம் செய்யப்பட்டு, NielsenIQ ஆல் நடத்தப்பட்டது, கொழும்பு பங்குச் சந்தை (CSE), LMD 100 (2020/2021) மற்றும் பிராண்ட்கள் ஆண்டு 2021 இல் பட்டியலிடப்பட்ட நிறுவனங்களில் மேலாளர்கள் மற்றும் அதற்கு மேல் உள்ள 800 பதிலளித்தவர்களின் மாதிரியை உள்ளடக்கியது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "காம்பேங்க்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "மதிப்பிற்குரிய வங்கி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "18 ஆம் ஆண்டு",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கொமர்ஷல் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொடர்ந்து 18வது ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்காவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்எம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதிநிலை செயல்பாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேர்மை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பார்வை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதிநிலை செயல்பாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தர உணர்வு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேர்மை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெருநிறுவன கலாச்சாரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSR & நிலைத்தன்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பார்வை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "HR & மக்கள் மேலாண்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நெருக்கடி மேலாண்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வணிக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வணிக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தாண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்காவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொமர்ஷல் பேங்க் ஆஃப் சிலோன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு பங்குச் சந்தை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020/2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}