{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Aragalaya-President-Wickremesinghe-should-have-initiated-dialogue-with-protesters-Mano-Ganesan/108-241616",
  "time_ut": 1658508849,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Aragalaya President Wickremesinghe should have initiated dialogue with protesters - Mano Ganesan",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Aragalaya President Wickremesinghe should have initiated dialogue with protesters - Mano Ganesan",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Wickremesinghe told party leaders, he will provide Vihara Maha Devi Gardens to protesters",
        "After all the Aragalaya people sent former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa home",
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe should have initiated a dialogue with the Aragalaya protesters, Tamil Progressive Alliance (TPA) Leader Mano Ganesan said yesterday.",
        "“President Wickremesinghe told party leaders, he will provide Vihara Maha Devi Gardens to protesters. Now, what prevented him from forwarding his proposal to protesters and initiating a peaceful transfer of location?” he questioned.",
        "“After all the Aragalaya people sent former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa home, hence, Wickremesinghe is President today” he added."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Aragalaya",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vihara Maha Devi Gardens",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Aragalaya",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aragalaya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Progressive Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vihara Maha Devi Gardens",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Aragalaya",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අරගලය ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ විරෝධතාකරුවන් සමඟ සංවාදයක් ආරම්භ කළ යුතුව තිබුණා - මනෝ ගනේෂන්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට විහාර මහා දේවී උද්‍යානය ලබාදෙන බව ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ පක්ෂ නායකයින්ට ප්‍රකාශ කළේය",
        "අරගලය ජනතාව හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ ගෙදර යැව්වා",
        "අරගලය විරෝධතාකරුවන් සමඟ සංවාදයක් ආරම්භ කළ යුතුව තිබුණේ ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා බව දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානයේ නායක මනෝ ගනේෂන් මහතා ඊයේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "“විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට විහාර මහා දේවී උද්‍යාන ලබා දෙන බව ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ පක්ෂ නායකයින්ට පැවසීය. දැන්, ඔහුගේ යෝජනාව විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමෙන් සහ සාමකාමීව ස්ථාන මාරුවක් ආරම්භ කිරීමට ඔහුට බාධා කළේ කුමක්ද? ඔහු ප්‍රශ්න කළේය.",
        "\"අරගලය ජනතාව හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ ගෙදර යැව්වාට පස්සේ අද වික්‍රමසිංහ ජනාධිපති\" ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අරගලය",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විහාර මහා දේවි උද්‍යානය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අරගලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරගලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විහාර මහා දේවි උද්‍යානය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අරගලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரகலய தலைவர் விக்கிரமசிங்க போராட்டக்காரர்களுடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தையை ஆரம்பித்திருக்க வேண்டும் - மனோ கணேசன்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களுக்கு விஹார மகாதேவி தோட்டத்தை வழங்குவதாக கட்சித் தலைவர்களிடம் ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க தெரிவித்தார்",
        "அரகலய மக்கள் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை வீட்டுக்கு அனுப்பி வைத்தனர்",
        "அரகலய எதிர்ப்பாளர்களுடன் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பேச்சுவார்த்தையை ஆரம்பித்திருக்க வேண்டும் என தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணியின் தலைவர் மனோ கணேசன் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "“விஹார மகாதேவி தோட்டத்தை எதிர்ப்பாளர்களுக்கு வழங்குவதாக கட்சித் தலைவர்களிடம் ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க கூறினார். இப்போது, ​​அவரது முன்மொழிவை எதிர்ப்பாளர்களுக்கு அனுப்புவதற்கும் அமைதியான இடமாற்றத்தைத் தொடங்குவதற்கும் அவரைத் தடுத்தது எது? என்று கேள்வி எழுப்பினார்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை அரகலய மக்கள் வீட்டுக்கு அனுப்பியதன் பின்னர், விக்கிரமசிங்க இன்று ஜனாதிபதியாக உள்ளார் என அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அரகலயா",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஹார மகா தேவி தோட்டம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரகலயா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரகலயா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஹார மகா தேவி தோட்டம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரகலயா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}