{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/T-56-firearm-magazines-stolen-from-soldier-by-protesters-during-unrest-near-Parliament/342-241062",
  "time_ut": 1657770497,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "T-56 firearm, magazines stolen from soldier by  protesters during unrest near Parliament",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "T-56 firearm, magazines stolen from soldier by  protesters during unrest near Parliament",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A T-56 firearm and two magazines containing 60 rounds of live ammunition, which were in the possession of a soldier during unrest near Parliament last night, were stolen by the protesters, police said.",
        "A tense flared up last evening at Polduwa Junction near Parliament between protesters and security forces when the protesters tried to advance towards Speaker's house and Parliament.",
        "They said the army soldier attached to a camp in Wellawaya was also injured during the attack by the protestors and he is currently undergoing treatment in the hospital.",
        "A complaint has been lodged to the Borella Police Station about the stolen firearm and ammunition. Welikada and Borella police stations are conducting investigations.",
        "Police said a policeman was also injured while trying to control protesters.",
        "The policeman who was seriously injured in the attack was from the Kalutara Police Training College and is currently receiving treatment in the hospital.",
        "Meanwhile, hospital sources said 42 people were admitted to the National Hospital in Colombo following a clash near Parliament. (Darshana Sanjeewa Balasuriya)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "T-56",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        },
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "A T-56",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polduwa Junction",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wellawaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Welikada",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Borella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Kalutara Police Training College",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "42",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Hospital in Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Darshana Sanjeewa Balasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අසල ඇති වූ නොසන්සුන්තාව අතරතුර විරෝධතාකරුවන් විසින් සොල්දාදුවෙකුගෙන් ටී 56 ගිනි අවියක් සහ මැගසින් සොරකම් කර ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ආසන්නයේ ඇති වූ නොසන්සුන්තාවකදී හමුදා සෙබළෙකු සතුව තිබූ ටී 56 ගිනි අවියක් සහ ජීව උණ්ඩ 60ක් අඩංගු මැගසින් දෙකක් විරෝධතාකරුවන් විසින් සොරකම් කර ඇති බව පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "ඊයේ සවස පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අසල පොල්දූව හන්දියේදී විරෝධතාකරුවන් කථානායක නිවසට සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව දෙසට යාමට උත්සාහ කිරීමේදී විරෝධතාකරුවන් සහ ආරක්ෂක අංශ අතර උණුසුම් තත්ත්වයක් ඇති විය.",
        "විරෝධතාකරුවන්ගේ ප්‍රහාරයෙන් වැල්ලවාය ප්‍රදේශයේ කඳවුරකට අනුයුක්තව සේවය කළ යුද හමුදා සෙබළා ද තුවාල ලබා ඇති අතර ඔහු මේ වනවිට රෝහල්ගතව ප්‍රතිකාර ලබන බව ඔවුන් සඳහන් කළා.",
        "සොරාගත් ගිනි අවිය සහ පතොරම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් බොරැල්ල පොලිස් ස්ථානයට පැමිණිල්ලක් ලැබී තිබෙනවා. වැලිකඩ සහ බොරැල්ල පොලිස් ස්ථාන පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වයි.",
        "පොලීසිය පැවසුවේ, විරෝධතාකරුවන් පාලනය කිරීමට යාමේදී පොලිස් නිලධාරියෙකු ද තුවාල ලබා ඇති බව ය.",
        "ප්‍රහාරයෙන් බරපතල තුවාල ලැබූ පොලිස් නිලධාරියා කළුතර පොලිස් අභ්‍යාස විද්‍යාලයේ අයෙක් වන අතර ඔහු මේ වනවිට රෝහල් ගතව ප්‍රතිකාර ලබනවා.",
        "මේ අතර, පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අසල ඇති වූ ගැටුමකින් පුද්ගලයින් 42 දෙනෙකු කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කර ඇති බව රෝහල් ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කළේය. (දර්ශන සංජීව බාලසූරිය)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ටී-56",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "T-56 එකක්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොල්දූව හන්දිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වැල්ලවාය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරැල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "කළුතර පොලිස් අභ්‍යාස විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "42",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දර්ශන සංජීව බාලසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு அருகில் அமைதியின்மையின் போது போராட்டக்காரர்களால் சிப்பாயிடமிருந்து T-56 துப்பாக்கி, பத்திரிகைகள் திருடப்பட்டுள்ளன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நேற்றிரவு பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு அருகில் அமைதியின்மையின் போது ஒரு சிப்பாய் வசம் இருந்த T-56 துப்பாக்கி மற்றும் 60 தோட்டாக்கள் அடங்கிய இரண்டு மகசீன்கள் போராட்டக்காரர்களால் திருடப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "நேற்று மாலை பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு அருகில் உள்ள பொல்துவ சந்தியில் ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் சபாநாயகர் மாளிகை மற்றும் பாராளுமன்றத்தை நோக்கி செல்ல முற்பட்ட போது போராட்டக்காரர்களுக்கும் பாதுகாப்பு படையினருக்கும் இடையில் பதற்றம் ஏற்பட்டது.",
        "போராட்டக்காரர்களின் தாக்குதலின் போது வெல்லவாய முகாமில் பணியாற்றிய இராணுவ சிப்பாயும் காயமடைந்துள்ளதாகவும், அவர் தற்போது வைத்தியசாலையில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வருவதாகவும் அவர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "திருடப்பட்ட துப்பாக்கி மற்றும் தோட்டாக்கள் தொடர்பில் பொரளை பொலிஸ் நிலையத்தில் முறைப்பாடு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது. வெலிக்கடை மற்றும் பொரளை பொலிஸ் நிலையங்கள் விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றன.",
        "போராட்டக்காரர்களை கட்டுப்படுத்த முயன்றபோது ஒரு போலீஸ்காரரும் காயமடைந்ததாக போலீசார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "தாக்குதலில் படுகாயமடைந்த களுத்துறை பொலிஸ் பயிற்சிக் கல்லூரியைச் சேர்ந்த பொலிஸ் அதிகாரி தற்போது வைத்தியசாலையில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வருகின்றார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு அருகில் ஏற்பட்ட மோதலில் 42 பேர் கொழும்பு தேசிய வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக வைத்தியசாலை வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளன. (தர்ஷன சஞ்சீவ பாலசூரிய)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டி-56",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "டி-56",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொல்துவ சந்தி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெல்லவாய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெலிக்கடை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொரளை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை பொலிஸ் பயிற்சிக் கல்லூரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "42",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் உள்ள தேசிய வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தர்ஷன சஞ்சீவ பாலசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}