{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/03/more-arrests-for-damaging-mps-property/",
  "time_ut": 1662183840,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "More arrests for damaging MPs property",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "More arrests for damaging MPs property",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Police have arrested four suspects for causing damages to the property of MPs Samanpriya Herath and Kokila Harshani Gunawardena, on the 9th of May.",
        "Police say a 42-year-old person was arrested for setting fire to the Party Office of MP Samanpriya Herath located in Kuliyapitiya.",
        "The suspect was arrested in the Mahalanda area in Upper-Elathalawa.",
        "Police have also arrested three suspects for setting fire to the house and office of MP Kokila Harshani Gunawardena located in Lolawagoda.",
        "According to the Police, the three suspects are also accused of causing damages and setting fire to the house and vehicles of the brother of MP Kokila Harshani Gunawardena.",
        "The three suspects aged 19, 22, and 30 are residents of Meerigama and Loluwagoda."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kokila Harshani Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "42-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Party Office of MP Samanpriya Herath",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kuliyapitiya",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahalanda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Upper-Elathalawa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kokila",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunawardena",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lolawagoda",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kokila",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harshani Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19, 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Meerigama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Loluwagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ දේපළවලට හානි කළ තවත් අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන සමන්ප්‍රිය හේරත් සහ කෝකිලා හර්ෂණී ගුණවර්ධන යන මහත්ම මහත්මීන්ගේ දේපළවලට අලාභ හානි සිදුකිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සැකකරුවන් 4 දෙනෙකු පසුගිය 09 වනදා පොලීසිය අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "කුලියාපිටියේ පිහිටි පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සමන්ප්‍රිය හේරත්ගේ පක්ෂ කාර්යාලයට ගිනි තැබූ 42 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව පොලීසිය පවසයි.",
        "සැකකරු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත්තේ ඉහළ එලතලාව - මහලන්ද ප්‍රදේශයේදීයි.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී කෝකිලා හර්ෂණී ගුණවර්ධන මහත්මියගේ ලෝලවාගොඩ පිහිටි නිවසට සහ කාර්යාලයට ගිනි තැබූ සැකකරුවන් තිදෙනෙකු ද පොලිසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී කෝකිලා හර්ෂණී ගුණවර්ධනගේ සොහොයුරාගේ නිවසට සහ වාහනවලට අලාභහානි සිදුකිරීම සහ ගිනි තැබීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ද සැකකරුවන් තිදෙනාට චෝදනා එල්ල වී ඇති බවයි පොලිසිය පවසන්නේ.",
        "සැකකරුවන් තිදෙනා අවුරුදු 19, 22 සහ 30 වයස්වල පසුවන මීරිගම සහ ලෝලුවාගොඩ ප්‍රදේශවල පදිංචිකරුවන්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝකිලා හර්ෂනී ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "42 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සමන්ප්‍රිය හේරත් මහතාගේ පක්ෂ කාර්යාලයයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුලියාපිටිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහලන්ද",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉහළ-එලතලාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝකිලා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝලවාගොඩ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝකිලා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂනී ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19, 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීරිගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝලුවාගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எம்.பி.க்களின் சொத்துகளை சேதப்படுத்தியதற்காக அதிக கைதுகள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான சமன்பிரிய ஹேரத் மற்றும் கோகிலா ஹர்ஷனி குணவர்தன ஆகியோரின் சொத்துக்களுக்கு சேதம் விளைவித்த நான்கு சந்தேக நபர்களை கடந்த மே மாதம் 9 ஆம் திகதி பொலிஸார் கைது செய்துள்ளனர்.",
        "குளியாப்பிட்டியவில் அமைந்துள்ள பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சமன்பிரிய ஹேரத்தின் கட்சி அலுவலகத்திற்கு தீ வைத்த குற்றச்சாட்டில் 42 வயதுடைய நபர் ஒருவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "மேல்-எலத்தலாவ, மஹலந்த பிரதேசத்தில் வைத்து சந்தேகநபர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "லோலவகொடவில் அமைந்துள்ள பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் கோகிலா ஹர்ஷனி குணவர்தனவின் வீடு மற்றும் அலுவலகத்திற்கு தீ வைத்த சந்தேகநபர்கள் மூவரையும் பொலிஸார் கைது செய்துள்ளனர்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் கோகிலா ஹர்ஷனி குணவர்தனவின் சகோதரரின் வீடு மற்றும் வாகனங்களுக்கு சேதம் விளைவித்தமை மற்றும் தீ வைத்தமை தொடர்பில் சந்தேகநபர்கள் மூவர் மீதும் குற்றம் சுமத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "19, 22 மற்றும் 30 வயதுடைய மூன்று சந்தேக நபர்களும் மீரிகம மற்றும் லோலுவாகொட பிரதேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோகிலா ஹர்ஷனி குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "42 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சமன்பிரிய ஹேரத்தின் கட்சி அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குளியாபிட்டிய",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹாலந்தா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல்-எலத்தலாவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோகிலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லோலாவகொட",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோகிலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷனி குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19, 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மீரிகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லொலுவாகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}