{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-rajapaksa-fails-to-resign-despite-repeated-promises-97388/",
  "time_ut": 1657744500,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka Rajapaksa fails to resign despite repeated promises",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka Rajapaksa fails to resign despite repeated promises",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka President Gotabaya Rajapaksa failed to resign on Wednesday as promised three times after fleeing the country in an Air Force flight following thousands of youth-led protesters stormed into his Presidential Palace over the weekend.",
        "When the protesters stormed in on Saturday (09), he had already fled his official residence. He, through Parliament Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena, on the same day announced, will resign on July 13 in a move to deescalate the anger.",
        "On Monday, Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe’s office said Rajapaksa has confirmed the July 13 resignation while on Wednesday (13), the Speaker said the president has once again confirmed to quit as promised.",
        "However, Rajapaksa did not resign on July 13 as promised while he was on the run to a safer area amid Sri Lankan migrants in other countries who had also been backing the protests.",
        "“It is 00:00 which means that Gotabaya Rajapaksa lied. The Speaker of Sri Lankan Parliament lied. Prime Minister… lied that the letter of resignation will be received before the end of 13 July,” opposition legislator Harsha de Silva tweeted.",
        "“Actions of you people will lead to bloodshed and the end of democracy in Sri Lanka.”",
        "The delay in Rajapaksa’s designation has resulted in a slight rise in agitation and some of the protesters have started to behave violently.",
        "Rajapaksa along with his wife Ioma Rajapaksa and two personal security guards left in an Air Force flight to Male from Sri Lanka’s Bandaranaike International Airport.",
        "Government sources have said Rajapaksa had conveyed that the letter of resignation will be given to the Speaker only after he reached a safer place. The sources said he was expected to reach the final destination at 08.00 pm on Wednesday.",
        "However, Rajapaksa had asked the Maldivian authorities for an aircraft instead of going on the scheduled commercial flight. fearing backlashes. The war winning defence secretary is planning to leave for Singapore on Wednesday, sources said.  (Colombo/July 14/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Rajapaksa",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Presidential Palace",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the weekend",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the same day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "00:00",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of 13 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harsha de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ioma Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandaranaike International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "08.00 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldivian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රාජපක්ෂ නැවත නැවතත් පොරොන්දු වුවද ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට අසමත් වේ",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "EconomyNext - ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ, සති අන්තයේ සිය ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට කඩා වැදුණු දහස් ගණන් තරුණයින් ප්‍රමුඛ විරෝධතාකරුවන්ගෙන් පසු ගුවන් හමුදා ගුවන් යානයකින් රටින් පලා යාමෙන් පසු තුන් වතාවක් පොරොන්දු වූ පරිදි බදාදා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට අපොහොසත් විය.",
        "සෙනසුරාදා (09) විරෝධතාකරුවන් කඩා වැදුණු විට ඔහු ඒ වන විටත් සිය නිල නිවසින් පලා ගොස් තිබුණි. ඔහු, පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මාර්ගයෙන් එදිනම නිවේදනය කර, කෝපය සමනය කර ගැනීමේ පියවරක් ලෙස ජූලි 13 වැනිදා ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව දන්වා සිටියේය.",
        "සඳුදා, අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ කාර්යාලය කියා සිටියේ රාජපක්ෂ ජූලි 13 ඉල්ලා අස්වීම තහවුරු කළ බව වන අතර බදාදා (13) කථානායකවරයා පැවසුවේ පොරොන්දු වූ පරිදි ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව ජනාධිපතිවරයා නැවත වරක් තහවුරු කළ බව ය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, විරෝධතාවලට සහාය දැක්වූ වෙනත් රටවල සිටින ශ්‍රී ලාංකික සංක්‍රමණිකයන් මධ්‍යයේ ආරක්ෂිත ප්‍රදේශයකට පලා යමින් සිටියදී රාජපක්ෂ පොරොන්දු වූ පරිදි ජූලි 13 වෙනිදා ඉල්ලා අස් වූයේ නැත.",
        "“දැන් වෙලාව 00.00 යි ඒ කියන්නේ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ බොරු කිව්වා. ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කථානායක බොරු කීවේය. අගමැති... ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය ජූලි 13 අවසන් වීමට පෙර ලැබෙනු ඇතැයි බොරු කීවේය.",
        "\"ඔබගේ ක්‍රියාවන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ලේ වැගිරීම්වලට සහ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදයේ අවසානයට හේතු වනු ඇත.\"",
        "රාජපක්ෂගේ නම් කිරීම ප්‍රමාද වීම හේතුවෙන් උද්ඝෝෂණයේ සුළු වැඩිවීමක් සිදුවී ඇති අතර විරෝධතාකරුවන්ගෙන් සමහරක් ප්‍රචණ්ඩකාරී ලෙස හැසිරීමට පටන් ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ සිය බිරිඳ අයෝමා රාජපක්ෂ සහ පෞද්ගලික ආරක්ෂකයින් දෙදෙනෙකු සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපලේ සිට මාලේ දක්වා ගුවන් හමුදා ගුවන් යානයකින් පිටත් විය.",
        "ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය කථානායකවරයාට ලබා දෙන්නේ ඔහු ආරක්ෂිත ස්ථානයකට පැමිණි පසු පමණක් බව රාජපක්ෂ මහතා දන්වා ඇති බව රජයේ ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි. ඔහු බදාදා රාත්‍රී 08.00 ට අවසන් ගමනාන්තයට ළඟා වනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කරන බව ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, රාජපක්ෂ නියමිත වාණිජ ගුවන් යානයේ යාම වෙනුවට ගුවන් යානයක් මාලදිවයිනේ බලධාරීන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා ඇත. පසුබෑම් වලට බියෙන්. යුද්ධය ජයග්‍රහණය කළ ආරක්ෂක ලේකම්වරයා බදාදා සිංගප්පූරුව බලා පිටත්ව යාමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති බව ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි. (කොළඹ/ජූලි 14/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති අන්තය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එදිනම",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "00:00",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13 අවසානයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයෝමා රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "08.00 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பலமுறை வாக்குறுதி அளித்தும் இலங்கை ராஜபக்சே ராஜினாமா செய்யவில்லை",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ வார இறுதியில் ஆயிரக்கணக்கான இளைஞர்கள் தலைமையிலான எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் அவரது ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்குள் நுழைந்ததைத் தொடர்ந்து விமானப்படை விமானத்தில் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறிய பின்னர் மூன்று முறை வாக்குறுதியளித்தபடி புதன்கிழமை ராஜினாமா செய்யத் தவறிவிட்டார்.",
        "சனிக்கிழமை (09) ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் உள்ளே நுழைந்தபோது, ​​அவர் ஏற்கனவே தனது உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லத்தை விட்டு வெளியேறிவிட்டார். அவர், நாடாளுமன்ற சபாநாயகர் மகிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தனவின் ஊடாக, அன்றே அறிவித்தார், கோபத்தை தணிக்கும் நடவடிக்கையாக ஜூலை 13 அன்று பதவி விலகுவார்.",
        "திங்களன்று, பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கேவின் அலுவலகம், ஜூலை 13 ராஜினாமாவை ராஜபக்ஷ உறுதிப்படுத்தியதாகக் கூறியது, புதன்கிழமை (13) சபாநாயகர், உறுதியளித்தபடி ராஜினாமா செய்வதை ஜனாதிபதி மீண்டும் உறுதிப்படுத்தியதாகக் கூறினார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், மற்ற நாடுகளில் உள்ள இலங்கை புலம்பெயர்ந்தோருக்கு மத்தியில் அவர் பாதுகாப்பான பகுதிக்கு ஓடிக்கொண்டிருந்தபோது, ​​வாக்குறுதியின்படி ஜூலை 13 அன்று ராஜபக்சே ராஜினாமா செய்யவில்லை, அவர்களும் எதிர்ப்புகளை ஆதரித்தனர்.",
        "“மணி 00:00 ஆகிவிட்டது, அதாவது கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ பொய் சொன்னார். இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் சபாநாயகர் பொய் சொன்னார். பிரதமர்... ஜூலை 13 இறுதிக்குள் ராஜினாமா கடிதம் பெறப்படும் என்று பொய் கூறினார்” என்று எதிர்க்கட்சி சட்டமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"உங்கள் செயல்கள் இலங்கையில் இரத்தக்களரி மற்றும் ஜனநாயகத்தின் முடிவுக்கு வழிவகுக்கும்.\"",
        "ராஜபக்சேவின் பதவி தாமதம் சிறிது கிளர்ச்சியை ஏற்படுத்தியது மற்றும் எதிர்ப்பாளர்களில் சிலர் வன்முறையில் நடந்து கொள்ளத் தொடங்கியுள்ளனர்.",
        "இலங்கையின் பண்டாரநாயக்கா சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தில் இருந்து மாலே நோக்கி விமானப்படை விமானத்தில் ராஜபக்சே தனது மனைவி அயோமா ராஜபக்சே மற்றும் இரண்டு தனிப்படை காவலர்களுடன் புறப்பட்டார்.",
        "ராஜினாமா கடிதம் சபாநாயகர் பாதுகாப்பான இடத்திற்கு வந்த பின்னரே அவருக்கு வழங்கப்படும் என ராஜபக்சே தெரிவித்ததாக அரசு வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளன. புதன்கிழமை இரவு 08.00 மணிக்கு அவர் இறுதி இலக்கை அடைவார் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுவதாக அந்த வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன.",
        "இருப்பினும், திட்டமிடப்பட்ட வணிக விமானத்தில் செல்வதற்குப் பதிலாக மாலத்தீவு அதிகாரிகளிடம் ராஜபக்சே விமானம் கேட்டிருந்தார். பின்னடைவுகளுக்கு பயந்து. போரில் வெற்றி பெற்ற பாதுகாப்பு செயலாளர் புதன்கிழமை சிங்கப்பூர் செல்ல திட்டமிட்டுள்ளதாக தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை 14/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வார இறுதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதே நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "00:00",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13 இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அயோமா ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு 08.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}