{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/28/sri-lanka-seeks-fuel-credit-line-from-qatar/",
  "time_ut": 1656423180,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka seeks Fuel Credit Line from Qatar",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka seeks Fuel Credit Line from Qatar",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Minister of Power and Energy Kachana Wijesekera says that he met with the Deputy Director-General of the Qatar Fund for Development and discussed a possible Credit Line facility for Petroleum and Gas supply.",
        "He tweeted that funds have been allocated for medical supplies and the Qatar Fund for Development will consider the request for a credit facility and support the International monetary fund (IMF) program for Sri Lanka"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Qatar",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Qatar Fund for Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Credit Line",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Petroleum and Gas",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Qatar Fund for Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කටාරයෙන් ඉන්ධන ණය මාර්ගයක් අපේක්ෂා කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); සංවර්ධන කටයුතු සඳහා කටාර් අරමුදලේ නියෝජ්‍ය අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල්වරයා හමුවී ඛනිජ තෙල් සහ ගෑස් සැපයීම සඳහා ලබාදිය හැකි ණය පහසුකම් පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කළ බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කචන විජේසේකර මහතා පවසයි.",
        "වෛද්‍ය සැපයුම් සඳහා මුදල් වෙන් කර ඇති බවත්, සංවර්ධනය සඳහා වන කටාර් අරමුදල ණය පහසුකම් සඳහා වන ඉල්ලීම සලකා බලමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා වන ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) වැඩසටහනට සහාය දක්වන බවත් ඔහු ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "කටාර්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සංවර්ධනය සඳහා කටාර් අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ණය රේඛාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඛනිජ තෙල් සහ ගෑස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සංවර්ධනය සඳහා කටාර් අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை கத்தாரிடம் இருந்து எரிபொருள் கடன் வரியை நாடுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); கத்தார் அபிவிருத்திக்கான நிதியத்தின் பிரதிப் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகத்தை சந்தித்து பெற்றோலியம் மற்றும் எரிவாயு விநியோகத்திற்கான சாத்தியமான கடன் இணைப்பு வசதி குறித்து கலந்துரையாடியதாக மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் கச்சன விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மருத்துவப் பொருட்களுக்கு நிதி ஒதுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும், அபிவிருத்திக்கான கத்தார் நிதியம் கடன் வசதிக்கான கோரிக்கையை பரிசீலித்து இலங்கைக்கான சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் (IMF) திட்டத்திற்கு ஆதரவளிக்கும் என்றும் அவர் ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "கத்தார்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வளர்ச்சிக்கான கத்தார் நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடன் வரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோலியம் மற்றும் எரிவாயு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வளர்ச்சிக்கான கத்தார் நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}