{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83434/litro-gas-summoned-before-cope-today",
  "time_ut": 1656988920,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Litro Gas summoned before COPE today",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Litro Gas summoned before COPE today",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A number of Parliamentary committees including the Committee on Public Enterprises (COPE) and the Committee on Public Accounts (COPA) are scheduled to meet this week.",
        "Accordingly, Litro Gas Lanka Limited and Litro Gas Terminal Lanka (Private) Limited have been summoned before the COPE which is scheduled to meet today (05). The COPE shall meet under the chairmanship of Member of Parliament (Prof) Charita Herath.",
        "Also, the Ministry of Transport and Highways has been called to the Committee on Public Accounts (COPA) which will also meet today under the chairmanship of Member of Parliament (Prof) Tissa Vitharana.",
        "The Ministerial Consultative Committee on Urban Development and Housing is scheduled to meet on the 5th under the chairmanship of Minister Prasanna Ranatunga.",
        "In addition to that, the Committee on Public Finance will also meet under the chairmanship of Anura Priyadarshana Yapa, to which the Inland Revenue Department has been summoned.",
        "Furthermore, the Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka has been summoned before the COPE which is scheduled to meet on the 6th."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Litro Gas",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "COPE",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Committee on Public Enterprises",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Committee on Public Accounts",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas Lanka Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas Terminal Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Charita Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Transport and Highways",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Committee on Public Accounts",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ministerial Consultative Committee on Urban Development and Housing",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Committee on Public Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Priyadarshana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Inland Revenue Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් සමාගම අද කෝප් කමිටුව හමුවට කැඳවයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව (COPE) සහ රාජ්‍ය ගිණුම් පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව (COPA) ඇතුළු පාර්ලිමේන්තු කාරක සභා ගණනාවක් මේ සතියේ රැස්වීමට නියමිතය.",
        "ඒ අනුව ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා ලිමිටඩ් සහ ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ටර්මිනල් ලංකා (පෞද්ගලික) සමාගම අද (05) රැස්වීමට නියමිත කෝප් කමිටුව හමුවට කැඳවා තිබේ. පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී (මහාචාර්ය) චරිත හේරත් මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් කෝප් කමිටුව රැස්වේ.",
        "එමෙන්ම, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී (මහාචාර්ය) තිස්ස විතාරණ මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් අද ද රැස්වීමට නියමිත රාජ්‍ය ගිණුම් පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව (COPA) වෙත ප්‍රවාහන හා මහාමාර්ග අමාත්‍යාංශය කැඳවා තිබේ.",
        "නාගරික සංවර්ධන හා නිවාස පිළිබඳ අමාත්‍ය උපදේශක කාරක සභාව ලබන 5 වැනිදා අමාත්‍ය ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් රැස්වීමට නියමිතය.",
        "ඊට අමතරව අනුර ප්‍රියදර්ශන යාපා මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් රාජ්‍ය මුදල් පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාවද රැස්වන අතර, ඊට දේශීය ආදායම් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව කැඳවා තිබේ.",
        "තවද ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව ලබන 6 වැනිදා රැස්වීමට නියමිත කෝප් කමිටුව හමුවට කැඳවා තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලිට්රෝ ගෑස්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "කෝප්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය ගිණුම් පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ ගෑස් පර්යන්තය ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චරිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රවාහන හා මහාමාර්ග අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය ගිණුම් පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාගරික සංවර්ධන හා නිවාස පිළිබඳ අමාත්‍ය උපදේශක කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය මුදල් පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර ප්‍රියදර්ශන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දේශීය ආදායම් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் நிறுவனம் இன்று கோப் முன்னிலையில் அழைக்கப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொது நிறுவனங்களுக்கான குழு (கோப்) மற்றும் பொதுக் கணக்குகளுக்கான குழு (கோபா) உள்ளிட்ட பல நாடாளுமன்றக் குழுக்கள் இந்த வாரம் கூடவுள்ளன.",
        "அதன்படி, லிட்ரோ கேஸ் லங்கா லிமிடெட் மற்றும் லிட்ரோ கேஸ் டெர்மினல் லங்கா (பிரைவேட்) லிமிடெட் ஆகிய நிறுவனங்கள் இன்று (05) கூடவுள்ள கோப் குழுவின் முன்னிலையில் அழைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன. நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் (பேராசிரியர்) சரித ஹேரத் தலைமையில் கோப் குழு கூடும்.",
        "அத்துடன், பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் (பேராசிரியர்) திஸ்ஸ விதாரண தலைமையில் இன்று கூடவுள்ள பொதுக் கணக்குகளுக்கான குழுவுக்கு (கோபா) போக்குவரத்து மற்றும் நெடுஞ்சாலைகள் அமைச்சு அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "நகர அபிவிருத்தி மற்றும் வீடமைப்பு தொடர்பான அமைச்சர்களின் ஆலோசனைக் குழு எதிர்வரும் 5ஆம் திகதி அமைச்சர் பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க தலைமையில் கூடவுள்ளது.",
        "அதற்கு மேலதிகமாக, பொது நிதி தொடர்பான குழுவும் அநுர பிரியதர்சன யாப்பாவின் தலைமையில் கூடவுள்ளதுடன், உள்நாட்டு இறைவரி திணைக்களத்திற்கு அழைப்பு விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மேலும், எதிர்வரும் 6ஆம் திகதி கூடவுள்ள கோப் குழுவின் முன்னிலையில் இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழுவுக்கு அழைப்பு விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "கோப்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொது நிறுவனங்களுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது கணக்குகளுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் லங்கா லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் டெர்மினல் லங்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரிதா ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "போக்குவரத்து மற்றும் நெடுஞ்சாலைகள் அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது கணக்குகளுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நகர்ப்புற மேம்பாடு மற்றும் வீட்டுவசதி தொடர்பான அமைச்சர்களின் ஆலோசனைக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொது நிதிக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர பிரியதர்ஷன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உள்நாட்டு இறைவரி திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}