{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/මම-රාජපක්ෂලාගේ-මිතුරෙක්-නෙමෙයි/11-395600",
  "time_ut": 1658370168,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මම රාජපක්ෂලාගේ මිතුරෙක් නෙමෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "I am not a friend of Rajapaksa",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickramasinghe said that he is not a friend of the Rajapaksas but a friend of the people at Hunupitiya Gangarama Temple.",
        "The President said this in response to a question put to him after joining the religious ceremonies at Hunupitiya Gangarama Temple after being elected as the President.",
        "Question - Mr. President, the people say they want change. You are a friend of the Rajapaksa, aren't you? Then how can there be a change?",
        "Answer- How can Rajapaksa become my old friends? I was always against them. You came today and the Rajapaksa's are my friends.",
        "I will say one thing. When you become a journalist, you need to study deeply. Do not ask such questions."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Rajapaksa",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hunupitiya Gangarama Temple",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hunupitiya Gangarama Temple",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මම රාජපක්ෂලාගේ මිතුරෙක් නෙමෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "තමන් රාජපක්ෂවරුන්ගේ මිතුරෙක් නොවන බවත් තමන් ජනතාවගේ මිතුරෙක් බවත් ජනපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා හුණුපිටිය ගංඟාරාම විහාරස්ථානයේදී පැවැසිය.",
        "ජනපති ලෙස තේරීපත්වීමෙන් අනතුරුව හුණුපිටිය ගංඟාරාම විහාරස්ථානයේ ආගමික වතාවත්වලට එක්වීමෙන් අනතුරුව ඔහුට යොමුකළ ප්‍රශ්නයකට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් ජනපතිවරයා මේ බව පැවැසීය.",
        "ප්‍රශ්නය - ජනපතිතුමනි ජනතාව කියනවා වෙනසක් ඕන කියලා. ඔබ රාජපක්ෂලාගේ මිතුරෙක් නේද?එතකොට කොහොමද වෙනසක් වෙන්නේ?",
        "පිළිතුර- රාජපක්ෂලා කොහොමද මගේ පැරණි මිතුරන් වෙන්නේ. මම හැමදාම හිටියේ ඔවුන්ට විරුද්ධව. ඔයා අද ඇවිල්ලා කියලා රාජපක්ෂලා මගේ මිතුරන් කියලා.",
        "මම එක දෙයක් කියන්නම්. ජනමාධ්‍ය වේදියෙක් වුණාම ඔබ ගැඹුරින් අධ්‍යනය කරන්න ඕන. මේ වගේ ප්‍රශ්න අහන්න එපා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හුණුපිටිය ගංගාරාම විහාරස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හුණුපිටිය ගංගාරාම විහාරස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நான் ராஜபக்சேவின் நண்பன் அல்ல",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தான் ராஜபக்ஷக்களின் நண்பன் அல்ல என்றும் ஹுனுபிட்டிய கங்காராம விகாரையில் உள்ள மக்களின் நண்பன் என்றும் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியாக தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டதன் பின்னர் ஹுனுப்பிட்டிய கங்காராம விகாரையில் இடம்பெற்ற சமய நிகழ்வுகளில் கலந்து கொண்டதன் பின்னர் அவரிடம் எழுப்பப்பட்ட கேள்விக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் போதே ஜனாதிபதி மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கேள்வி - ஜனாதிபதி அவர்களே, மக்கள் மாற்றம் வேண்டும் என்று கூறுகிறார்கள். நீ ராஜபக்சேவின் நண்பன் அல்லவா.. பிறகு எப்படி மாற்றம் வரும்?",
        "பதில்- ராஜபக்ச எப்படி எனது பழைய நண்பர்களாக முடியும்? நான் எப்போதும் அவர்களுக்கு எதிராக இருந்தேன். நீங்கள் இன்று வந்தீர்கள், ராஜபக்சேக்கள் எனது நண்பர்கள்.",
        "ஒன்று சொல்கிறேன். பத்திரிக்கையாளராக மாறும்போது ஆழ்ந்து படிக்க வேண்டும். போன்ற கேள்விகளை கேட்காதீர்கள்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹுனுபிட்டிய கங்காராம ஆலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹுனுபிட்டிய கங்காராம ஆலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}