{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/දිවි-සැරිය-ගැට-ගසන්න-මසකට-12-444-ඇතිලු/1-618283",
  "time_ut": 1660733250,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "දිවි සැරිය ගැට ගසන්න මසකට 12,444 ඇතිලු",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "12,444 per month to tie the knot",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to the latest reports of the Department of Population and Statistics, a minimum amount of 12444 rupees was enough for one person to live for a month in Sri Lanka by meeting basic needs.",
        "According to the report, a minimum amount of 13,421 rupees was required to meet the basic needs of last June in Colombo district and it is the highest amount needed for a month of living in a district of Sri Lanka.",
        "According to the report issued by the Department of Population and Statistics, last June in Monaragala district, an amount of 11899 rupees was required to live for a month by meeting the basic needs and that is the lowest amount required to live for a month by meeting the basic needs of a district in Sri Lanka."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "12,444 per month",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Department of Population and Statistics",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "12444",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "a month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13,421",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "last June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Department of Population and Statistics",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monaragala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11899",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දිවි සැරිය ගැට ගසන්න මසකට 12,444 ඇතිලු",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "එක් පුද්ගලයෙකුට මූලික අවශ්‍යතා සපුරා ගනිමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මාසයක් ජීවත් වීම සඳහා ඉකුත් ජූනි මසදී අවම රුපියල් 12444 ක මුදලක් ප්‍රමාණවත් වූ බව ජන හා සංඛ්‍යා ලේඛන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ නවතම වාර්තා පෙන්වා දෙයි.",
        "දිස්ත්‍රික්ක වශයෙන් ගත් කළ ඉකුත් ජූනි මස මූලික අවශ්‍යතා සපුරා ගනිමින් කොළඹ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ මාසයක් ජීවත් වීම සඳහා අවම රුපියල් 13421 ක මුදලක් අවශ්‍ය වූ බවත් එය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයක මූලික අවශ්‍යතා සපුරා ගනිමින් මාසයක් ජීවත්වීම සඳහා අවශ්‍ය වැඩිම මුදල බවත් එම වාර්තාවේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "ඉකුත් ජූනි මස මොණරාගල දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ මූලික අවශ්‍යතා සපුරා ගනිමින් මාසයක් ජීවත් වීම සඳහා රුපියල් 11899 ක මුදලක් අවශ්‍ය වූ බවත් එය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයක මූලික අවශ්‍යතා සපුරා ගනිමින් මාසයක් ජීවත් වීමට අවශ්‍ය වූ අඩුම මුදල බවත් ජන හා සංඛ්‍යා ලේඛන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව නිකුත් කළ වාර්තාවේ දැක්වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මසකට 12,444",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනගහන හා සංඛ්‍යාලේඛන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "12444",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13,421 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය ජුනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනගහන හා සංඛ්‍යාලේඛන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය ජුනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොනරාගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11899",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தாலி கட்டுவதற்கு மாதம் 12,444 ரூபாய்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சனத்தொகை மற்றும் புள்ளிவிபரத் திணைக்களத்தின் அண்மைய அறிக்கைகளின்படி, இலங்கையில் அடிப்படைத் தேவைகளைப் பூர்த்தி செய்துகொள்வதன் மூலம் ஒருவர் இலங்கையில் ஒரு மாதத்திற்கு வாழ குறைந்தபட்ச தொகையான 12444 ரூபா போதுமானது.",
        "அந்த அறிக்கையின்படி, கடந்த ஆண்டு ஜூன் மாதம் கொழும்பு மாவட்டத்தில் ஒரு மாதத்திற்கு வசிப்பதற்காக குறைந்தபட்சம் 13,421 ரூபா தேவைப்பட்டது, இது இலங்கையில் ஒரு மாவட்டத்தில் வாழ்வதற்கு தேவையான அதிகூடிய தொகையாகும்.",
        "சனத்தொகை புள்ளிவிபர திணைக்களத்தினால் கடந்த ஜூன் மாதம் மொனராகலை மாவட்டத்தில் அடிப்படைத் தேவைகளைப் பூர்த்தி செய்து ஒரு மாதம் வாழ 11899 ரூபா தேவைப்படுவதாகவும், அதுவே ஒரு மாதத்திற்குச் சந்திக்கத் தேவையான மிகக் குறைந்த தொகை எனவும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. இலங்கையில் ஒரு மாவட்டத்தின் அடிப்படைத் தேவைகள்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மாதம் 12,444",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மக்கள்தொகை மற்றும் புள்ளியியல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "12444",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13,421",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மக்கள்தொகை மற்றும் புள்ளியியல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொனராகலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11899",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}