{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ජොනී--නාමල්--මහින්දානන්ද--රෝහිත--පවිත්‍රා-ඇතුළු-පිරිසකට-ඇමතිධුර-දෙන්නැයි-බැසිල්-ජනපතිගෙන්-ඉල්ලයි/11-396289",
  "time_ut": 1660528272,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ජොනී, නාමල්, මහින්දානන්ද, රෝහිත, පවිත්‍රා ඇතුළු පිරිසකට ඇමතිධුර දෙන්නැයි බැසිල් ජනපතිගෙන් ඉල්ලයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Basil requests the President to give ministerial posts to Johnny, Namal, Mahindananda, Rohitha, Pavitra and others.",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A spokesman for the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna told 'Ada' that there is now a belief in the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna that the appointment of the new cabinet will be delayed.",
        "He pointed out that the President's approval of the party's national organizer Mr. Basil Rajapaksa's request to get cabinet ministerships including the district leaders of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna has been temporarily postponed.",
        "Also, the spokesman pointed out that the protest raised by the Samagijana Balawega and the MPs associated with it was the reason for this and said that the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna internally believes that the President will work to find a solution for it.",
        "Mr. Basil Rajapaksa has asked the President to give ministerial posts in the new cabinet to be appointed to a group of Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna members including Johnston Fernando, Namal Rajapaksa, Mahindananda Aluthgamage, Rohitha Abeygunawardena, Pavithradevi Vanniarachchi, and together with the Saagi Jana Balawega A group of MPs protested."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Johnny, Namal, Mahindananda",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        },
        {
          "text": "Rohitha",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ada",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Samagijana Balawega",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Johnston Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Namal Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahindananda Aluthgamage",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rohitha Abeygunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pavithradevi Vanniarachchi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජොනී, නාමල්, මහින්දානන්ද, රෝහිත, පවිත්‍රා ඇතුළු පිරිසකට ඇමතිධුර දෙන්නැයි බැසිල් ජනපතිගෙන් ඉල්ලයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "නව කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය පත්කිරීම තවදුරටත් කල්යනු ඇති බවට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණතුළ මේ වනවිට විශ්වාසයක් හටගෙන ඇතැයි එම පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙකු 'අද' ට පැවසීය.",
        "ඔහු පෙන්වා දුන්නේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණෙහි දිස්ත්‍රික් නායකයන් ඇතුළු පිරිසකට කැබිනට් අමාත්‍ය ධුර ලබාගැනීම සඳහා පක්ෂයේ ජාතික සංවිධායක බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ඉල්ලීමට ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ අනුමැතිය ලබාදීම තාවකාලිකව කල්දමා ඇති බවයි.",
        "එසේම සමගිජන බලවේගය හා ඒ හා සම්බන්ධ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගෙන් මතුව ඇති විරෝධතාව මීට හේතුවී ඇති බව පෙන්වා දුන් එම ප්‍රකාශකයා ඒ සඳහා යම් විසඳුමක් ලබාගැනීමට ජනාධිපතිවරයා කටයුතු කරනු ඇති බවට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණු අභ්‍යන්තරය විශ්වාස කරන බවද පවසා සිටියේය.",
        "ජොන්ස්ටන් ප්‍රනාන්දු, නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ, මහින්දානන්ද අලුත්ගමගේ, රෝහිත අබේගුණවර්ධන, පවිත්‍රාදේවි වන්නිආරච්චි ඇතුළු ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණෙහි පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීන් පිරිසකට, පත් කිරීමට නියමිත නව කැබිනට් මන්ඩලයේ අමාත්‍ය ධුර ලබාදෙන ලෙසට බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතා විසින් ජනාධිපතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා ඇති අතර, ඊට සමගි ජන බලවේගය හා ඒ හා එක්ව කටයුතු කරන මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පිරිසක් විරෝධය පළ කර තිබිණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජොනී, නාමල්, මහින්දානන්ද",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        },
        {
          "text": "රෝහිත",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගිජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොන්ස්ටන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්දානන්ද අලුත්ගමගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෝහිත අබේගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පවිත්‍රාදේවි වන්නිආරච්චි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜொனி, நாமல், மஹிந்தானந்த, ரோஹித, பவித்ரா உள்ளிட்டோருக்கு அமைச்சுப் பதவிகளை வழங்குமாறு பசில் ஜனாதிபதியிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதிய அமைச்சரவை நியமனம் தாமதமாகும் என ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவில் தற்போது நம்பிக்கை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பேச்சாளர் ஒருவர் 'அட'விடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் மாவட்டத் தலைவர்கள் உட்பட அமைச்சரவை அமைச்சுப் பதவிகளைப் பெறுமாறு கட்சியின் தேசிய அமைப்பாளர் பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ விடுத்த கோரிக்கைக்கு ஜனாதிபதியின் அங்கீகாரம் தற்காலிகமாக ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அவர் சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளார்.",
        "மேலும், சமகிஜன பலவேக மற்றும் அதனுடன் தொடர்புடைய பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் எதிர்ப்பே இதற்குக் காரணம் என சுட்டிக்காட்டிய பேச்சாளர், அதற்கான தீர்வொன்றைப் பெற்றுக்கொடுக்க ஜனாதிபதி பாடுபடுவார் என ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன உள்ளக நம்புவதாகவும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜொன்ஸ்டன் பெர்னாண்டோ, நாமல் ராஜபக்ஷ, மஹிந்தானந்த அளுத்கமகே, ரோஹித அபேகுணவர்தன, பவித்ராதேவி வன்னியாராச்சி உள்ளிட்ட ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன உறுப்பினர்களை கொண்ட குழுவிற்கு புதிய அமைச்சரவையில் அமைச்சுப் பதவிகளை வழங்குமாறு பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ ஜனாதிபதியிடம் கோரியுள்ளார். பலவேக எம்.பி.க்கள் குழு எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவித்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜொனி, நாமல், மஹிந்தானந்த",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரோஹிதா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகிஜன பலவேக",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜோன்ஸ்டன் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாமல் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்தானந்த அளுத்கமகே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோஹித அபேகுணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பவித்ராதேவி வன்னியாராச்சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}