{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Blood-donation-camp/342-244148",
  "time_ut": 1662037466,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Blood donation camp...",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Blood donation camp...",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "On the occasion of the 120th anniversary of the Kotuguda Sri Rahula National School in Gampaha, a blood donation campaign has been organised today at the school under the initiative of the school Principal Thilakman Pathmasiri Fernando and the teaching staff and with the participation of area residents. Pix by Pradeep Pathirana"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "120th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "National School",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Principal Thilakman Pathmasiri Fernando",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pathirana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලේ දන්දීමේ කඳවුර...",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ගම්පහ කොටුගුඩ ශ්‍රී රාහුල ජාතික පාසලට වසර 120ක් පිරීම නිමිත්තෙන් එම විද්‍යාලයේ විදුහල්පති තිලක්මන් පත්මසිරි ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් එම විද්‍යාලයේ ආචාර්ය මණ්ඩලය සහ ප්‍රදේශවාසීන්ගේ සහභාගිත්වයෙන් ලේ දන්දීමේ වැඩසටහනක් සංවිධානය කර ඇත. පික්ස් - ප්‍රදීප් පතිරණ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "120 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික පාසල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදුහල්පති තිලක්මන් පත්මසිරි ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පතිරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இரத்த தான முகாம்...",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கம்பஹா கொடுகுடா ஸ்ரீ ராகுல தேசிய பாடசாலையின் 120வது ஆண்டு நிறைவை முன்னிட்டு பாடசாலை அதிபர் திலக்மன் பத்மசிறி பெர்னாண்டோ மற்றும் ஆசிரிய ஊழியர்களின் ஏற்பாட்டில் பிரதேசவாசிகளின் பங்களிப்புடன் இரத்ததானம் வழங்கும் நிகழ்வு இன்று பாடசாலையில் ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது. படங்கள் பிரதீப் பத்திரன"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "120வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பள்ளி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதிபர் திலக்மன் பத்மசிறி பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்திரனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}