{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/CMG-future-focused-to-get-leadership-closer-to-the-ground/34-737012",
  "time_ut": 1656880128,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "CMG future-focused to get leadership closer to the ground",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CMG future-focused to get leadership closer to the ground",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "From left: CMG Chairman and Managing Director Sashi Rajamahendran, Group Director/COO Nedra Weerasinghe, Group Director/CEO Sunil Kanojia and Group Director/COO S.C. Weerasekera",
        "A year after Sashi Rajamahendran took over the reins of the Capital Maharaja Group (CMG), the conglomerate is going through some sweeping changes.",
        "The Group is broad basing its decision-making processes to give more opportunity for career growth at all levels of its management structure. In line with that, two new positions have been layered in, with Group Directors Nedra Weerasinghe and S.C. Weerasekera, both appointed as Group Director/Chief Operating Officer (COO) to helm the Group’s Industrial and Retail/Strategic Business hubs respectively.",
        "CMG Chairman Sashi Rajamahendran says apart from laying a strong emphasis on recognising the sustained achievement of its people from time to time, the Group believes in blending its expertise across  the Group’s multiple businesses.",
        "“This allows for maximum synergistic benefits to them as well as the Group. Nedra and Shan are two Group Directors on the main Board, involved in handling operations. They have served the Group with panache and have handled two of the most important business hubs over the  past several years. We believe the specific portfolios assigned to them under the new positions will give them the impetus to further grow the business.”",
        "Effective 23 June 2022, Weerasekera will be Group Director/COO of CMG’s Industrial Hub, continuing to give leadership and grow business for S-Lon, PE+, Kevilton, Kansai Lanka and Herrero. Weerasinghe will be the Group Director/COO heading the Group’s retail hub and strategic business initiatives. While the retail segments of the Group are relatively new, it is a key area of focus for the future expansion and development of the Group. CMG Group Director/CEO Sunil Kanojia will continue to lead all CMG operations and he will guide both Shan and Nedra in their new roles.",
        "The media company which has organically grown in the last 30 years is also being restructured to ensure better clarity and focus in the news and entertainment business. Chevaan Daniel, who is currently the Group Director in charge of News First, will also now provide leadership to MTV Channel Ltd.  “The current situation in the country requires all of us to be agile and receptive to change. We as a Group, throughout our 90 years of existence have faced many adversities and overcome them with fortitude and  innovative thinking. In facing today’s crisis which is not only local but spreading across the globe, we need  our leaders to be closer to the ground, and respond intelligently and appropriately to the changes that can  come very fast and even be devastating at times.",
        "“This is not a time to be relying only on our standard  operating procedures but to be creative in our approach. I am confident the management restructuring will  get CMG ready for the next level of growth and wealth creation,” says Chairman Rajamahendran.",
        "The Group with its ‘Employees First’ ethos is moving boldly to its next phase in the ever-changing business  environment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sashi Rajamahendran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunil Kanojia",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerasekera",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "A year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sashi Rajamahendran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Capital Maharaja Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group Directors Nedra Weerasinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "S.C. Weerasekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CMG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sashi Rajamahendran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "23 June 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerasekera",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMG’s Industrial Hub",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "S-Lon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kevilton",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kansai Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Herrero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMG Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunil Kanojia",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the last 30 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chevaan Daniel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "News First",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MTV Channel Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "90 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajamahendran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "First",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "CMG අනාගතය-කේන්ද්‍ර වී ඇත්තේ නායකත්වය බිමට සමීප කර ගැනීම සඳහා ය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "වමේ සිට: CMG සභාපති සහ කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ ශෂී රාජමහේන්ද්‍රන්, සමූහ අධ්‍යක්ෂ/COO නේද්‍රා වීරසිංහ, සමූහ අධ්‍යක්ෂ/ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී සුනිල් කනොජියා සහ සමූහ අධ්‍යක්ෂ/COO S.C වීරසේකර",
        "ශෂී රාජමහේන්ද්‍රන් කැපිටල් මහරාජා සමූහ ව්‍යාපාරයේ (CMG) පාලනය භාරගෙන වසරකට පසුව, සමූහ ව්‍යාපාරය විශාල වෙනස්කම් කිහිපයක් සිදු කරයි.",
        "සමූහය සිය කළමනාකරණ ව්‍යුහයේ සෑම තරාතිරමකම වෘත්තීය වර්ධනය සඳහා වැඩි අවස්ථාවක් ලබා දීම සඳහා එහි තීරණ ගැනීමේ ක්‍රියාවලීන් පුළුල් ලෙස පදනම් කරයි. ඊට සමගාමීව, සමූහ අධ්‍යක්ෂවරුන් වන නේද්‍රා වීරසිංහ සහ එස්.සී. වීරසේකර යන දෙදෙනාම සමූහ අධ්‍යක්ෂ/ප්‍රධාන මෙහෙයුම් නිලධාරී (COO) ලෙස සමූහ ව්‍යාපාරයේ කාර්මික සහ සිල්ලර/උපායමාර්ගික ව්‍යාපාර කේන්ද්‍රස්ථාන මෙහෙයවීම සඳහා පත් කර ඇති අතර, නව තනතුරු දෙකක් ඇතුළත් කර ඇත.",
        "CMG සභාපති ශෂී රාජමහේන්ද්‍රන් පවසන්නේ තම ජනතාවගේ තිරසාර ජයග්‍රහණ කලින් කලට හඳුනා ගැනීම කෙරෙහි දැඩි අවධානයක් යොමු කිරීමට අමතරව සමූහයේ බහුවිධ ව්‍යාපාර හරහා තම විශේෂඥතාව මුසු කිරීමට සමූහය විශ්වාස කරන බවයි.",
        "“මෙය ඔවුන්ට මෙන්ම සමූහයට උපරිම සහයෝගීතා ප්‍රතිලාභ ලබා දීමට ඉඩ සලසයි. නේද්‍රා සහ ෂාන් ප්‍රධාන මණ්ඩලයේ සමූහ අධ්‍යක්ෂවරුන් දෙදෙනෙකි, මෙහෙයුම් හැසිරවීමට සම්බන්ධ වෙති. ඔවුන් සමූහ ව්‍යාපාරයට සේවය කර ඇති අතර පසුගිය වසර කිහිපය තුළ වඩාත් වැදගත් ව්‍යාපාරික මධ්‍යස්ථාන දෙකක් හසුරුවා ඇත. නව තනතුරු යටතේ ඔවුන් වෙත පවරා ඇති විශේෂිත අමාත්‍යාංශ ව්‍යාපාරය තවදුරටත් වර්ධනය කර ගැනීමට ඔවුන්ට ශක්තියක් වනු ඇතැයි අපි විශ්වාස කරමු.",
        "2022 ජූනි 23 සිට බලපැවැත්වෙන පරිදි, වීරසේකර CMG හි කාර්මික මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ සමූහ අධ්‍යක්ෂ/COO වනු ඇත, S-Lon, PE+, Kevilton, Kansai Lanka සහ Herrero සඳහා අඛණ්ඩව නායකත්වය ලබා දෙමින් ව්‍යාපාර වර්ධනය කරයි. වීරසිංහ සමූහයේ සිල්ලර මධ්‍යස්ථානය සහ උපාය මාර්ගික ව්‍යාපාර මුලපිරීම් වල ප්‍රධානියා වන සමූහ අධ්‍යක්ෂ/COO වේ. සමූහයේ සිල්ලර කොටස් සාපේක්ෂ වශයෙන් අලුත් වන අතර, එය සමූහයේ අනාගත ව්‍යාප්තිය සහ සංවර්ධනය සඳහා අවධානය යොමු කළ යුතු ප්‍රධාන අංශයකි. CMG සමූහ අධ්‍යක්ෂ/ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී සුනිල් කනොජියා සියලු CMG මෙහෙයුම් දිගටම මෙහෙයවනු ඇති අතර ඔහු ෂාන් සහ නේද්‍රා යන දෙදෙනාටම ඔවුන්ගේ නව භූමිකාවන් සඳහා මඟ පෙන්වනු ඇත.",
        "පසුගිය වසර 30 තුළ ඓන්ද්‍රීයව වර්ධනය වූ මාධ්‍ය සමාගම ප්‍රවෘත්ති සහ විනෝදාස්වාද ව්‍යාපාරයේ වඩා හොඳ පැහැදිලි බවක් සහ අවධානයක් සහතික කිරීම සඳහා ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කෙරේ. දැනට නිවුස් ෆස්ට් භාර සමූහ අධ්‍යක්ෂවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කරන චෙවාන් ඩැනියෙල්, දැන් සීමාසහිත එම්ටීවී චැනල් ලිමිටඩ් වෙත නායකත්වය ද ලබා දෙනු ඇත.  “රටේ වත්මන් තත්ත්වය අනුව අප සියලු දෙනාම වෙනස් වීමට කඩිසරව සහ ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වීමට අවශ්‍ය වේ. අපි කණ්ඩායමක් වශයෙන්, අපගේ වසර 90 ක පැවැත්ම පුරාවට බොහෝ විපත්තිවලට මුහුණ දී ඇති අතර ඒවා ධෛර්ය සම්පන්නව සහ නව්‍ය චින්තනයෙන් ජය ගත්තෙමු. දේශීය පමණක් නොව ලොව පුරා ව්‍යාප්ත වී ඇති වර්තමාන අර්බුදයට මුහුණ දීමේදී, අපට අවශ්‍ය වන්නේ  අපගේ නායකයින් බිමට සමීපව සිටීමත්, ඉතා වේගයෙන් පැමිණිය හැකි සහ විටෙක විනාශකාරී විය හැකි වෙනස්කම්වලට බුද්ධිමත්ව සහ සුදුසු ලෙස ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වීමත්ය.",
        "“මෙය අපගේ සම්මත මෙහෙයුම් ක්‍රියා පටිපාටි මත පමණක් විශ්වාසය තැබීමට නොව අපගේ ප්‍රවේශය තුළ නිර්මාණශීලී වීමට කාලයකි. කළමනාකරණ ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම මීළඟ මට්ටමේ වර්ධනයට සහ ධනය උත්පාදනය සඳහා CMG සූදානම් කරනු ඇතැයි මට විශ්වාසයි,” සභාපති රාජමහේන්ද්‍රන් පවසයි.",
        "සමූහය එහි 'සේවකයින් ප්‍රථමයෙන්' ආචාර ධර්ම සමඟින් නිරන්තරයෙන් වෙනස් වන ව්‍යාපාරික පරිසරය තුළ සිය මීළඟ අදියර වෙත නිර්භීතව ගමන් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශෂී රාජමහේන්ද්‍රන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුනිල් කනොජියා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරසේකර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුද්දක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශෂී රාජමහේන්ද්‍රන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැපිටල් මහරාජා සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමූහ අධ්‍යක්ෂවරුන් වන නේද්‍රා වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.සී වීරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රධාන මෙහෙයුම් නිලධාරී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CMG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශෂී රාජමහේන්ද්‍රන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූනි 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරසේකර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMG හි කාර්මික මධ්යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "S-Lon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙවිල්ටන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kansai Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙරේරෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMG සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුනිල් කනොජියා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසර 30 තුළ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චෙවාන් ඩැනියෙල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "News First",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත MTV චැනල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 90 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජමහේන්ද්‍රන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "CMG எதிர்காலத்தை மையமாக கொண்டு தலைமைத்துவத்தை மைதானத்திற்கு நெருக்கமாக்குகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இடமிருந்து: CMG தலைவர் மற்றும் முகாமைத்துவ பணிப்பாளர் சஷி ராஜமகேந்திரன், குழும பணிப்பாளர்/சிஓஓ நேத்ரா வீரசிங்க, குழும பணிப்பாளர்/தலைமை நிர்வாக அதிகாரி சுனில் கனோஜியா மற்றும் குழும பணிப்பாளர்/சிஓஓ எஸ்.சி.வீரசேகர",
        "சஷி ராஜமகேந்திரன் கேப்பிட்டல் மஹாராஜா குழுமத்தின் (CMG) ஆட்சியைப் பொறுப்பேற்ற ஒரு வருடத்திற்குப் பிறகு, குழுமம் சில பெரிய மாற்றங்களைச் சந்தித்து வருகிறது.",
        "குழுவானது அதன் நிர்வாகக் கட்டமைப்பின் அனைத்து மட்டங்களிலும் தொழில் வளர்ச்சிக்கு அதிக வாய்ப்பை வழங்க அதன் முடிவெடுக்கும் செயல்முறைகளை பரந்த அடிப்படையாக கொண்டுள்ளது. அதற்கு இணங்க, குழுவின் பணிப்பாளர்களான நேத்ரா வீரசிங்க மற்றும் எஸ்.சி. வீரசேகர ஆகியோர் குழுமத்தின் தொழில்துறை மற்றும் சில்லறை/மூலோபாய வணிக மையங்களுக்கு தலைமை தாங்குவதற்காக குழுவின் பணிப்பாளர்/தலைமைச் செயற்பாட்டு அதிகாரியாக (COO) நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள நிலையில், இரண்டு புதிய பதவிகள் அடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "CMG தலைவர் சஷி ராஜமகேந்திரன் கூறுகையில், குழுமத்தின் பல வணிகங்களில் அதன் நிபுணத்துவத்தை ஒருங்கிணைக்க குழு நம்புகிறது.",
        "\"இது அவர்களுக்கும் குழுவிற்கும் அதிகபட்ச ஒருங்கிணைந்த நன்மைகளை அனுமதிக்கிறது. நேத்ரா மற்றும் ஷான் ஆகியோர் முக்கிய குழுவில் இரண்டு குழு இயக்குநர்கள், கையாளுதல் செயல்பாடுகளில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர். அவர்கள் குழுவிற்கு பனாச்சே மூலம் சேவை செய்திருக்கிறார்கள் மற்றும் கடந்த பல ஆண்டுகளாக  இரண்டு மிக முக்கியமான வணிக மையங்களைக் கையாண்டுள்ளனர். புதிய பதவிகளின் கீழ் அவர்களுக்கு ஒதுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள குறிப்பிட்ட போர்ட்ஃபோலியோக்கள் வணிகத்தை மேலும் வளர்ப்பதற்கான உத்வேகத்தை அளிக்கும் என்று நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம்.",
        "23 ஜூன் 2022 முதல், வீரசேகர CMG இன் இன்டஸ்ட்ரியல் ஹப்பின் குழு இயக்குனராக/சிஓஓவாக இருப்பார், S-Lon, PE+, Kevilton, Kansai Lanka மற்றும் Herrero ஆகியவற்றிற்குத் தொடர்ந்து தலைமைத்துவத்தையும் வணிகத்தையும் மேம்படுத்துவார். குழுமத்தின் சில்லறை வர்த்தக மையம் மற்றும் மூலோபாய வணிக முயற்சிகளுக்கு தலைமை தாங்கும் குழுவின் பணிப்பாளர்/சிஓஓவாக வீரசிங்க இருப்பார். குழுமத்தின் சில்லறை விற்பனைப் பிரிவுகள் ஒப்பீட்டளவில் புதியவை என்றாலும், குழுவின் எதிர்கால விரிவாக்கம் மற்றும் மேம்பாட்டிற்கான முக்கியப் பகுதி இதுவாகும். CMG குழுமத்தின் இயக்குனர்/தலைமை நிர்வாக அதிகாரி சுனில் கனோஜியா அனைத்து CMG செயல்பாடுகளையும் தொடர்ந்து வழிநடத்துவார், மேலும் அவர் ஷான் மற்றும் நேத்ரா இருவரையும் அவர்களின் புதிய பாத்திரங்களில் வழிநடத்துவார்.",
        "கடந்த 30 ஆண்டுகளில் இயற்கையாகவே வளர்ந்த மீடியா நிறுவனம், செய்தி மற்றும் பொழுதுபோக்கு வணிகத்தில் சிறந்த தெளிவு மற்றும் கவனத்தை உறுதிப்படுத்தும் வகையில் மறுசீரமைக்கப்படுகிறது. தற்போது நியூஸ் ஃபர்ஸ்ட் குழும இயக்குனராக இருக்கும் செவான் டேனியல், இப்போது எம்டிவி சேனல் லிமிடெட் நிறுவனத்திற்கு தலைமைப் பொறுப்பை வழங்குவார்.  “நாட்டின் தற்போதைய சூழ்நிலையில் நாம் அனைவரும் சுறுசுறுப்பாகவும் மாற்றங்களை ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளவும் வேண்டும். ஒரு குழுவாக, எங்களின் 90 ஆண்டுகால வாழ்க்கை முழுவதும், பல இன்னல்களை எதிர்கொண்டோம், மேலும் துணிச்சலுடனும், புதுமையான சிந்தனையுடனும் அவற்றைக் கடந்து வந்துள்ளோம். உள்ளூர் மட்டுமன்றி உலகம் முழுவதும் பரவி வரும் இன்றைய நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொள்ளும் போது, ​​நமது தலைவர்கள் பூமிக்கு நெருக்கமாக இருக்க வேண்டும், மேலும் மிக வேகமாக வரக்கூடிய மற்றும் சில சமயங்களில் பேரழிவை ஏற்படுத்தக்கூடிய மாற்றங்களுக்கு புத்திசாலித்தனமாகவும் சரியானதாகவும் பதிலளிக்க வேண்டும்.",
        "“இது எங்களின் நிலையான  இயக்க நடைமுறைகளை மட்டும் நம்பியிருக்க வேண்டிய நேரம் அல்ல, ஆனால் எங்கள் அணுகுமுறையில் ஆக்கப்பூர்வமாக இருக்க வேண்டும். நிர்வாக மறுசீரமைப்பு  CMG ஐ அடுத்த கட்ட வளர்ச்சிக்கும் செல்வத்தை உருவாக்குவதற்கும் தயாராகும் என்று நான் நம்புகிறேன்,” என்கிறார் தலைவர் ராஜமகேந்திரன்.",
        "எப்போதும் மாறிவரும் வணிகச் சூழலில், ‘பணியாளர்களுக்கு முதலில்’ என்ற நெறிமுறைகளைக் கொண்ட குழு, அதன் அடுத்த கட்டத்திற்குத் தைரியமாக நகர்கிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சசி ராஜமகேந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுனில் கனோஜியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரசேகர",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சசி ராஜமகேந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைநகர் மகாராஜா குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழுவின் பணிப்பாளர்கள் நேத்ரா வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.சி.வீரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஓஓ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CMG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சசி ராஜமகேந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "23 ஜூன் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரசேகர",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMG இன் தொழில்துறை மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்-லோன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெவில்டன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kansai Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹெர்ரெரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMG குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுனில் கனோஜியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த 30 ஆண்டுகளாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவான் டேனியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நியூஸ் ஃபர்ஸ்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்டிவி சேனல் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "90 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜமகேந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}