{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/රන්ජන්-තනතුර-බාර-ගනී/101-618825",
  "time_ut": 1661563010,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රන්ජන් තනතුර බාර ගනී",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ranjan takes over the position",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Ranjan Ramanayake assumed the position of ambassador for the welfare and promotion of expatriate workers.",
        "After receiving the presidential amnesty, the Minister of Labor and Foreign Employment Mr. Manusha Nanayakkara announced that Mr. Ranjan Ramanayake will be offered this position.",
        "Mr. Ranjan Ramanayake went to Madivela councilor's house where he used to reside the previous night with Mr. Manusha Nanayakkara and his supporters, where Mr. Manusha Nanayakkara officially offered the relevant position.",
        "Member of Parliament Mr. Wimalaweera Dissanayake also came to that event and said that he was happy that his neighbor was freed."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranjan",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Manusha Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Madivela",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the previous night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manusha Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manusha Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wimalaweera Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රන්ජන් තනතුර බාර ගනී",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "විදේශගත ශ්‍රමිකයන්ගේ සුබ සාධනය සහ ප්‍රවර්ධනය සඳහා වන තානාපති තනතුර රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා විසින් භාර ගනු ලැබීය.",
        "ජනාධිපති පොදු සමාව ලැබීමෙන් පසු කම්කරු හා විදේශ රැකියා අමාත්‍ය මනූෂ නානායක්කාර මහතා රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතාට මෙම තනතුර පිරිනමන බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා ඔහු කලින් පදිංචිව සිටි මාදිවෙල මන්ත්‍රී නිවාසයට පෙර දින රාත්‍රියේ මනුෂ නානායක්කාර මහතා සහ ආධාරකරුවන් සමග ගිය අතර එහිදී මනුෂ නානායක්කාර මහතා අදාළ තනතුර නිල වශයෙන් පිරිනැමීය.",
        "එම අවස්ථාවට පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී විමලවීර දිසානායක මහතා ද පැමිණි අතර තම අසල්වැසියා නිදහස් වීම ගැන සතුට පළ කරන බව විමලවිර දිසානායක මහතා එහිදී පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රන්ජන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මනූෂ නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාඩිවෙල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙර රාත්‍රියේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනූෂ නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනූෂ නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමලවීර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரஞ்சன் பதவியேற்றார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "புலம்பெயர்ந்த தொழிலாளர்களின் நலன் மற்றும் ஊக்குவிப்புக்கான தூதுவராக திரு.ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க பதவியேற்றார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் பொதுமன்னிப்பு கிடைத்ததன் பின்னர், திரு ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவிற்கு இந்தப் பதவி வழங்கப்படவுள்ளதாக தொழிலாளர் மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்பு அமைச்சர் திரு மனுஷ நாணயக்கார அறிவித்தார்.",
        "திரு.ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க, திரு.மனுஷ நாணயக்கார மற்றும் அவரது ஆதரவாளர்களுடன் நேற்று இரவு அவர் வசித்த மடிவெல சபை உறுப்பினரின் வீட்டிற்குச் சென்றிருந்தார், அங்கு திரு.மனுஷ நாணயக்கார உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக உரிய பதவியை வழங்கினார்.",
        "அந்த நிகழ்விற்கு பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் திரு.விமலவீர திஸாநாயக்கவும் வருகை தந்து தனது அயலவர் விடுதலை செய்யப்பட்டதில் மகிழ்ச்சியடைவதாக தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரஞ்சன்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மனுஷ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதிவேலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனுஷ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனுஷ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமலவீர திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}