{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/01/jacqueline-fernandez-knew-of-conman-s-cases-enjoyed-gifts-probe-agency/",
  "time_ut": 1662005580,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Jacqueline Fernandez Knew Of Conman’s Cases, Enjoyed Gifts: Probe Agency",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Jacqueline Fernandez Knew Of Conman’s Cases, Enjoyed Gifts: Probe Agency",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "New Delhi: Bollywood actress Jacqueline Fernandez was aware of conman Sukesh Chandrashekhar's criminal history and \"cooked up a false story\" to wriggle out of investigations in a multi-crore money laundering case, the Enforcement Directorate has said in its chargesheet.",
        "Jacqueline Fernandez's claim that she never knew of Sukesh Chandrashekhar's cases is false, the Enforcement Directorate says in the chargesheet that has been accessed by NDTV.",
        "\"Jacqueline Fernandez was well aware about the criminal antecedents of Sukesh Chandrashekhar and also the fact that Leena Maria Paul is his wife in February 2021,\" the chargesheet says.",
        "\"She consciously chose to overlook his criminal past and continued to indulge in financial transactions with him,\" it says.",
        "It was her hair stylist Shaan who informed her about the identity and criminal history of Sukesh Chandrashekhar in February 2021.",
        "\"Despite this, Jacqueline Fernandez ignored this fact and continued the relationship with Sukesh and also received, used and enjoyed the financial benefits from Sukesh, which are nothing but proceeds of crime,\" the agency says.",
        "The Enforcement Directorate, which is investigating the money trail in a ₹ 200 crore extortion case against the conman, named Jacqueline Fernandez as an accused earlier this month.",
        "Jacqueline Fernandez admitted to receiving five watches, 20 pieces of jewellery, 65 pairs of shoes, 47 dresses, 32 bags, 4 Hermes bags, nine paintings and one Versace crockery set as gifts from the conman, according to the chargesheet.",
        "The agency says Sukesh Chandrashekhar gifted two cars to the parents of Jacqueline Fernandez in April 2021, which she did not disclose during her questioning. Only after being confronted with evidence did she admit that Sukesh had bought her a property at Welgana in Sri Lanka.",
        "\"Despite being fully aware of his criminal history and that he is lodged in Tihar Jail, Jacqueline Fernendez was knowingly a party or actually involved in the process (money laundering) by using or enjoying the proceeds of crime by the way of valuable gifts,\" the agency says. She allegedly also requested her staff to delete data on their phone related to the conman.",
        "The Enforcement Directorate alleges that Jacqueline Fernandez tried to cover up by constantly stating that she had in fact been a victim of Sukesh. \"However, during investigation she has failed to provide any substantial material to establish the victimisation by Sukesh,\" the chargesheet says.",
        "She wiped her phone clean, deleting crucial evidence and this counted as tampering with evidence, says the agency.",
        "The chargesheet says Chandrashekhar gave ₹ 7.12 crore to the actor – ₹ 1.26 crore to her sister in the US, ₹ 15 lakh to her brother in Australia and gifts worth ₹ 5.71 crore.",
        "\"The lure of money ensured that the criminal history of the person Jacqueline Fernandez was engaging with did not matter,\" the Enforcement Directorate says in its chargesheet.",
        "When Jacqueline Fernandez was questioned along with the conman, she had admitted to receiving from him four bags from Gucci, Chanel, Yves Saint Laurent, Dior, three shoes from Louis Vuitton and Louboutin, two outfits from Gucci, perfumes, four cats, a Mini Cooper, two diamond earrings and a multi colored diamond bracelet.",
        "Known for films like \"Kick\", \"Bhoot Police'' and \"Vikrant Rona\", the actor is the only accused named in a supplementary chargesheet. She has said she is a victim of a larger criminal conspiracy and that she was cheated.",
        "Sukesh Chandrashekhar was arrested by the Delhi Police for allegedly extorting around ₹ 215 crore from Aditi Singh and Shivender Singh, former promoters of pharmaceutical giant Ranbaxy.",
        "Jeyaraj Murder Case: Former SP & Ex-LTTE cadre acquitted and released",
        "Jacqueline Fernandez Knew Of Conman’s Cases, Enjoyed Gifts: Probe Agency"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez Knew Of Conman’s Cases",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sukesh Chandrashekhar's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Enforcement Directorate",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sukesh Chandrashekhar's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Enforcement Directorate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDTV",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Leena Maria Paul",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "February 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shaan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sukesh Chandrashekhar",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "February 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sukesh",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Enforcement Directorate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "earlier this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "65",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "32",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Versace",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sukesh Chandrashekhar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "April 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welgana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernendez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Enforcement Directorate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "7.12",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.71",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Enforcement Directorate",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gucci",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chanel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yves Saint Laurent",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dior",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Louis Vuitton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Louboutin",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gucci",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mini Cooper",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bhoot Police''",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vikrant Rona",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "around ₹ 215",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aditi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shivender Singh",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jeyaraj Murder Case",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SP & Ex-LTTE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez Knew Of Conman’s Cases",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් කොන්මන්ගේ නඩු ගැන දැන සිටියා, තෑගි භුක්ති වින්දා: පරීක්ෂණ ඒජන්සිය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "නවදිල්ලිය: බොලිවුඩ් නිළි ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් කොම්මන් සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රශේඛර්ගේ අපරාධ ඉතිහාසය ගැන දැන සිටි අතර කෝටි ගණනක මුදල් විශුද්ධිකරණයේ නඩුවක විමර්ශනවලින් මිදීමට “බොරු කතාවක් පිසූ” බව බලාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය සිය චෝදනා පත්‍රයේ සඳහන් කර ඇත.",
        "සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රශේඛර්ගේ නඩු ගැන තමන් කිසිදාක දැන නොසිටි බවට ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් කළ ප්‍රකාශය අසත්‍ය බව, NDTV වෙත ප්‍රවේශ වී ඇති චෝදනා පත්‍රයේ බලාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය පවසයි.",
        "\"Jacqueline Fernandez සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රශේඛර්ගේ අපරාධ පූර්වාදර්ශ සහ Leena Maria Paul 2021 පෙබරවාරි මාසයේදී ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ බව හොඳින් දැන සිටියා\" යැයි චෝදනා පත්‍රයේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "\"ඇය දැනුවත්ව ඔහුගේ සාපරාධී අතීතය නොසලකා හැරීමට තෝරා ගත් අතර ඔහු සමඟ මූල්‍ය ගනුදෙනුවල නිරත වූවාය\" යනුවෙන් එහි සඳහන් වේ.",
        "2021 පෙබරවාරි මාසයේදී සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රශේඛර්ගේ අනන්‍යතාවය සහ අපරාධ ඉතිහාසය පිළිබඳව ඇයට දැනුම් දුන්නේ ඇගේ කොණ්ඩා මෝස්තර ශිල්පී ෂාන් ය.",
        "\"මෙසේ තිබියදීත්, ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් මෙම කරුණ නොසලකා හැර සුකේෂ් සමඟ සබඳතාව දිගටම කරගෙන ගිය අතර සුකේෂ්ගෙන් මූල්‍ය ප්‍රතිලාභ ලබාගෙන, භාවිතා කර සහ භුක්ති වින්දා, ඒවා අපරාධවලින් ලැබෙන ආදායම මිස අන් කිසිවක් නොවේ,\" ඒජන්සිය පවසයි.",
        "වංචාකරුට එරෙහිව රුපියල් කෝටි 200 ක කප්පම් නඩුවක මුදල් සම්බන්ධව විමර්ශනය කරන බලාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය, මේ මස මුලදී ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් විත්තිකාරියක් ලෙස නම් කරන ලදී.",
        "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් විසින් අත් ඔරලෝසු පහක්, ස්වර්ණාභරණ කැබලි 20 ක්, සපත්තු ජෝඩු 65 ක්, ඇඳුම් පැළඳුම් 47 ක්, බෑග් 32 ක්, හර්මීස් බෑග් 4 ක්, සිතුවම් 9 ක් සහ වර්සෙස් පිඟන් කෝප්පයක් ත්‍යාග වශයෙන් ලබා ගත් බවට චෝදනා පත්‍රයේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "ඒජන්සිය පවසන්නේ සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රශේකර් 2021 අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්ගේ දෙමාපියන්ට මෝටර් රථ දෙකක් තෑගි කළ බවත්, ඇය ප්‍රශ්න කිරීමේදී එය හෙළි නොකළ බවත්ය. සුකේෂ් ඇයට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වෙල්ගාන ප්‍රදේශයෙන් දේපළක් මිල දී ගෙන ඇති බව ඇය පිළිගත්තේ සාක්‍ෂිවලට මුහුණ දීමෙන් පසුවය.",
        "\"ඔහුගේ අපරාධ ඉතිහාසය සහ ඔහු තිහාර් බන්ධනාගාරයේ රඳවා සිටින බව හොඳින් දැන සිටියද, ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් දැනුවත්ව පාර්ශවකරුවෙකු හෝ සැබවින්ම අපරාධයේ ආදායම වටිනා තෑගි මාර්ගයෙන් භාවිතා කිරීමෙන් හෝ භුක්ති විඳීමෙන් (මුදල් විශුද්ධිකරණය) ක්‍රියාවලියට සම්බන්ධ වී ඇත.\" ආයතනය පවසයි. වංචාකරුට අදාළ ඔවුන්ගේ දුරකථනයේ දත්ත මකා දමන ලෙස ඇය තම කාර්ය මණ්ඩලයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියාය.",
        "තමා සැබවින්ම සුකේෂ්ගේ ගොදුරක් වූ බව නිරන්තරයෙන් ප්‍රකාශ කරමින් ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් වසන් කිරීමට උත්සාහ කළ බවට බලාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය චෝදනා කරයි. \"කෙසේ වෙතත්, විමර්ශනයේදී ඇය සුකේෂ් විසින් වින්දිතයා බවට පත් කිරීම සඳහා සැලකිය යුතු කරුණු කිසිවක් ලබා දීමට අපොහොසත් වී ඇත,\" චෝදනා පත්‍රයේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "ඇය සිය දුරකථනය පිරිසිදු කර, තීරණාත්මක සාක්ෂි මකා දැමූ අතර මෙය සාක්ෂි විකෘති කිරීමක් ලෙස ගණන් ගත් බව ඒජන්සිය පවසයි.",
        "චෝදනා පත්‍රයේ සඳහන් වන්නේ චන්ද්‍රශේඛර් නළුවාට රුපියල් කෝටි 7.12ක් – ඩොලර් කෝටි 1.26ක් එක්සත් ජනපදයේ සිටින ඇගේ සොහොයුරියට, ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාවේ සිටින ඇගේ සොහොයුරාට රුපියල් ලක්ෂ 15ක් සහ රුපියල් කෝටි 5.71ක් වටිනා තෑගි ලබා දුන් බවයි.",
        "“ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් සමඟ සම්බන්ධ වූ පුද්ගලයාගේ අපරාධ ඉතිහාසය වැදගත් නොවන බව මුදල් ආකර්ශනය සහතික කළේය,” බලාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය සිය චෝදනා පත්‍රයේ පවසයි.",
        "Jacqueline Fernandez ගෙන් ප්‍රශ්න කිරීමේදී ඔහුගෙන් Gucci, Chanel, Yves Saint Laurent, Dior යන අයගෙන් බෑග් හතරක්, Louis Vuitton සහ Louboutin ගෙන් සපත්තු තුනක්, Gucci වලින් ඇඳුම් දෙකක්, සුවඳ විලවුන් වර්ග, බළලුන් හතරක්, Mini එකක් ලැබුණු බව ඇය පිළිගෙන ඇත. කූපර්, දියමන්ති කරාබු දෙකක් සහ බහු වර්ණ දියමන්ති බ්රේස්ලට් එකක්.",
        "\"කික්\", \"භූත පොලිස්\" සහ \"වික්‍රාන්ත් රෝනා\" වැනි චිත්‍රපට සඳහා ප්‍රසිද්ධියක් උසුලන මෙම නළුවා පරිපූරක චෝදනා පත්‍රයක නම් කර ඇති එකම චූදිතයා වන අතර තමා විශාල අපරාධ කුමන්ත්‍රණයක ගොදුරක් බවත් තමා වංචා කළ බවත් ඇය පවසා ඇත.",
        "සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රශේඛර් දිල්ලි පොලිසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගනු ලැබුවේ ඖෂධ නිෂ්පාදන දැවැන්තයෙකු වන Ranbaxy හි හිටපු ප්‍රවර්ධකයින් වන Aditi Singh සහ Shivender Singh ගෙන් රුපියල් කෝටි 215 ක පමණ මුදලක් ලබා ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ය.",
        "ජෙයරාජ් ඝාතන නඩුව: හිටපු එස්පී සහ හිටපු එල්ටීටීඊ සාමාජිකයා නිදොස් කොට නිදහස් කෙරේ",
        "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් කොන්මන්ගේ නඩු ගැන දැන සිටියා, තෑගි භුක්ති වින්දා: පරීක්ෂණ ඒජන්සිය"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් කොන්මන්ගේ නඩු ගැන දැන සිටියාය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර්ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්රියාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර්ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්රියාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDTV",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලීනා මරියා පෝල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 පෙබරවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෂාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර්",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 පෙබරවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුකේෂ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බලාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ මස මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "65",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "32",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වර්සෙස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙල්ගන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බලාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "7.12",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.71",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්රියාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gucci",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චැනල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yves Saint Laurent",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩයර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලුවී වුටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලූබුටින්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gucci",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිනි කූපර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බූත් පොලිසිය''",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රාන්ත් රෝනා",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුපියල් 215 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "අදිති",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශිවෙන්දර් සිං",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජෙයරාජ් ඝාතන නඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්පී සහ හිටපු එල්.ටී.ටී.ඊ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් කොන්මන්ගේ නඩු ගැන දැන සිටියාය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ் கான்மேனின் வழக்குகள் பற்றி அறிந்தவர், பரிசுகளை அனுபவித்தார்: விசாரணை நிறுவனம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதுடெல்லி: பாலிவுட் நடிகை ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ், குற்றவாளி சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகரின் குற்ற வரலாற்றை அறிந்திருந்தார் என்றும், பல கோடி ரூபாய் பணமோசடி வழக்கில் விசாரணையில் இருந்து தப்பிக்க பொய் கதையை சமைத்துள்ளார் என்றும் அமலாக்க இயக்குனரகம் தனது குற்றப்பத்திரிகையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகரின் வழக்குகள் பற்றி தனக்கு ஒருபோதும் தெரியாது என்று ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ் கூறியது தவறானது என்று என்டிடிவி அணுகிய குற்றப்பத்திரிகையில் அமலாக்க இயக்குனரகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "\"ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ், சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகரின் கிரிமினல் முன்னோடிகளைப் பற்றியும், பிப்ரவரி 2021 இல் லீனா மரியா பால் அவரது மனைவி என்பதையும் நன்கு அறிந்திருந்தார்\" என்று குற்றப்பத்திரிகை கூறுகிறது.",
        "\"அவள் உணர்வுபூர்வமாக அவனது குற்றவியல் கடந்த காலத்தை கவனிக்கத் தேர்ந்தெடுத்தாள், அவனுடன் தொடர்ந்து நிதி பரிவர்த்தனைகளில் ஈடுபட்டாள்,\" என்று அது கூறுகிறது.",
        "பிப்ரவரி 2021 இல் சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகரின் அடையாளம் மற்றும் குற்றவியல் வரலாற்றைப் பற்றி அவருக்குத் தெரிவித்தது அவரது ஹேர் ஸ்டைலிஸ்ட் ஷான் தான்.",
        "\"இருப்பினும், ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ் இந்த உண்மையைப் புறக்கணித்து, சுகேஷுடனான உறவைத் தொடர்ந்தார், மேலும் சுகேஷிடமிருந்து நிதிப் பலன்களைப் பெற்றார், பயன்படுத்தினார் மற்றும் அனுபவித்தார், அவை குற்றத்தின் வருமானத்தைத் தவிர வேறில்லை\" என்று நிறுவனம் கூறுகிறது.",
        "200 கோடி ரூபாய் மிரட்டி பணம் பறித்த வழக்கில் ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ் குற்றவாளியாக இந்த மாத தொடக்கத்தில் அமலாக்க இயக்குனரகம் விசாரணை நடத்தியது.",
        "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ் 5 கைக்கடிகாரங்கள், 20 நகைகள், 65 ஜோடி காலணிகள், 47 ஆடைகள், 32 பைகள், 4 ஹெர்ம்ஸ் பைகள், ஒன்பது ஓவியங்கள் மற்றும் ஒரு வெர்சேஸ் கிராக்கரி செட் ஆகியவற்றை கடத்தல்காரனிடமிருந்து பரிசாகப் பெற்றதாக குற்றப்பத்திரிகையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஏப்ரல் 2021 இல் ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸின் பெற்றோருக்கு சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகர் இரண்டு கார்களை பரிசளித்தார், அதை அவர் தனது விசாரணையின் போது வெளியிடவில்லை என்று நிறுவனம் கூறுகிறது. ஆதாரங்களுடன் எதிர்கொண்ட பின்னரே, சுகேஷ் இலங்கையில் உள்ள வெல்கனாவில் தனக்கு ஒரு சொத்து வாங்கியதை ஒப்புக்கொண்டார்.",
        "\"தனது குற்றவியல் வரலாறு மற்றும் அவர் திகார் சிறையில் அடைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார் என்பதை முழுமையாக அறிந்திருந்தும், ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ் தெரிந்தே ஒரு கட்சியாக இருந்துள்ளார் அல்லது மதிப்புமிக்க பரிசுகள் மூலம் குற்றத்தின் வருமானத்தைப் பயன்படுத்தி அல்லது அனுபவிப்பதன் மூலம் செயல்பாட்டில் (பணமோசடி) ஈடுபட்டுள்ளார்.\" நிறுவனம் கூறுகிறது. கான்மேன் தொடர்பான தங்கள் தொலைபேசியில் உள்ள தரவை நீக்குமாறு அவர் தனது ஊழியர்களிடம் கோரினார்.",
        "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ், தான் சுகேஷால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டதாக தொடர்ந்து கூறி மூடி மறைக்க முயன்றதாக அமலாக்க இயக்குனரகம் குற்றம் சாட்டியுள்ளது. \"இருப்பினும், விசாரணையின் போது, ​​சுகேஷால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டதை நிறுவுவதற்கு கணிசமான எந்த ஆதாரத்தையும் அவர் வழங்கத் தவறிவிட்டார்\" என்று குற்றப்பத்திரிகை கூறுகிறது.",
        "அவர் தனது தொலைபேசியை சுத்தமாக துடைத்து, முக்கிய ஆதாரங்களை நீக்கினார், மேலும் இது ஆதாரங்களை சேதப்படுத்தியதாகக் கருதப்பட்டது என்று நிறுவனம் கூறுகிறது.",
        "சந்திரசேகர் நடிகருக்கு ₹ 7.12 கோடி - அமெரிக்காவில் உள்ள அவரது சகோதரிக்கு ₹ 1.26 கோடி, ஆஸ்திரேலியாவில் உள்ள அவரது சகோதரருக்கு ₹ 15 லட்சம் மற்றும் ₹ 5.71 கோடி மதிப்புள்ள பரிசுகள் கொடுத்ததாக குற்றப்பத்திரிகை கூறுகிறது.",
        "பண மோகம், ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸுடன் தொடர்பு கொண்ட நபரின் குற்றவியல் வரலாறு ஒரு பொருட்டல்ல என்பதை உறுதிப்படுத்தியது என்று அமலாக்க இயக்குனரகம் தனது குற்றப்பத்திரிகையில் கூறுகிறது.",
        "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸிடம் விசாரணை நடத்தியபோது, ​​அவரிடம் இருந்து குஸ்ஸி, சேனல், யவ்ஸ் செயிண்ட் லாரன்ட், டியோர் ஆகிய நான்கு பைகள், லூயிஸ் உய்ட்டன் மற்றும் லூபௌடின் ஆகியோரிடமிருந்து 3 ஷூக்கள், குஸ்ஸியின் இரண்டு ஆடைகள், வாசனை திரவியங்கள், நான்கு பூனைகள், ஒரு மினி ஆகியவற்றைப் பெற்றதாக ஒப்புக்கொண்டார். கூப்பர், இரண்டு வைர காதணிகள் மற்றும் பல வண்ண வைர காப்பு.",
        "\"கிக்\", \"பூட் போலீஸ்\" மற்றும் \"விக்ராந்த் ரோனா\" போன்ற படங்களுக்கு பெயர் பெற்ற நடிகர், துணை குற்றப்பத்திரிகையில் மட்டுமே குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்டவர். தான் ஒரு பெரிய குற்றச் சதியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டதாகவும், தான் ஏமாற்றப்பட்டதாகவும் கூறியுள்ளார்.",
        "மருந்து தயாரிப்பு நிறுவனமான ரான்பாக்ஸியின் முன்னாள் விளம்பரதாரர்களான அதிதி சிங் மற்றும் ஷிவேந்தர் சிங் ஆகியோரிடம் இருந்து சுமார் ₹ 215 கோடியை மிரட்டியதாக சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகர் டெல்லி போலீசாரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டார்.",
        "ஜெயராஜ் கொலை வழக்கு: முன்னாள் எஸ்பி மற்றும் முன்னாள் விடுதலைப் புலி உறுப்பினர் விடுதலை",
        "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ் கான்மேனின் வழக்குகள் பற்றி அறிந்தவர், பரிசுகளை அனுபவித்தார்: விசாரணை நிறுவனம்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸுக்கு கான்மேன் வழக்குகள் தெரியும்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகரின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமலாக்க இயக்குநரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ் தான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகரின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமலாக்க இயக்குநரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்டிடிவி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லீனா மரியா பால்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிப்ரவரி 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஷான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகர்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிப்ரவரி 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகேஷ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமலாக்க இயக்குநரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாத தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "65",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "32",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெர்சேஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெல்கனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமலாக்க இயக்குநரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "7.12",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.71",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமலாக்க இயக்குநரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குஸ்ஸி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சேனல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yves Saint Laurent",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டியோர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லூயிஸ் உய்ட்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Louboutin",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குஸ்ஸி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மினி கூப்பர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பூட் போலீஸ்''",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்ராந்த் ரோனா",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் ₹ 215",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதிதி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷிவேந்தர் சிங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெயராஜ் கொலை வழக்கு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்பி & முன்னாள் எல்டிடிஇ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸுக்கு கான்மேன் வழக்குகள் தெரியும்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}