{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132577",
  "time_ut": 1659174872,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ரஞ்சனுக்கு வெகுவிரைவில் விடுதலை கிடைக்கும் என நம்புகின்றேன் - சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "I hope Ranjan will be released soon - Sajith Premadasa",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "Leader of the Opposition Sajith Premadasa said that he hopes that humanitarian politician Ranjan Ramanayake will get full release soon.",
        "The Leader of the Opposition said this while speaking to the media after visiting former Member of Parliament Ranjan Ramanayake in Welikada prison on Saturday.",
        "Ranjan Ramanayake is waiting with positive expectation that he will get full release soon. It is my hope and that of the entire Sri Lankan people that he should be fully released. We pray for this. As per our prayers, we hope that he will get full release soon, not long days.",
        "We are waiting for Ranjan Ramanayake, who is everyone's expectation before long days, to get complete release and we are waiting for that day to come. He is a true philanthropist and a people's artist and has accomplished great works.",
        "Ranjan Ramanayake, a humanitarian politician and popular artist who continues to influence the people, said that our only aim is to see him return to the society as a free citizen and strive for social justice with determination."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranjan",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Opposition Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welikada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "that day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රන්ජන් ළඟදීම නිදහස් වෙයි කියලා හිතනවා - සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "මානුෂීය දේශපාලඥ රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා කඩිනමින් සම්පූර්ණයෙන් නිදහස් කරනු ඇතැයි තමන් බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා මේ බව පැවසුවේ සෙනසුරාදා වැලිකඩ බන්ධනාගාරයට ගොස් සිටින හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායකගේ සුවදුක් විමසීමෙන් අනතුරුව මාධ්‍ය වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින්.",
        "රන්ජන් රාමනායක තමාට ඉක්මනින්ම සම්පූර්ණ නිදහස ලැබෙනු ඇතැයි ධනාත්මක අපේක්ෂාවෙන් බලා සිටී. ඔහු සම්පූර්ණයෙන් නිදහස් කිරීම මගේත් සමස්ත ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනතාවගේත් බලාපොරොත්තුවයි. අපි මේ සඳහා යාච්ඤා කරමු. අපගේ ප්‍රාර්ථනාව අනුව ඔහුට වැඩි දිනක් නොව ඉක්මනින්ම සම්පූර්ණ නිදහස ලැබේවායි ප්‍රාර්ථනා කරමු.",
        "වැඩි දවසක් යන්න කලින් කාගෙත් බලාපොරොත්තුව වන රන්ජන් රාමනායක සම්පූර්ණයෙන් නිදහස් වෙනකම් අපි බලාගෙන ඉන්නවා ඒ දවස එනකම් අපි බලාගෙන ඉන්නවා. ඔහු සැබෑ දානපතියෙක් සහ ජනතා කලාකරුවෙක් වන අතර විශිෂ්ට කෘති ඉටු කර ඇත.",
        "ඔහු නිදහස් පුරවැසියෙකු ලෙස නැවත සමාජයට පැමිණ අධිෂ්ඨානශීලීව සමාජ සාධාරණත්වය වෙනුවෙන් වෙහෙසෙනු දැකීම අපගේ එකම අරමුණ බව තවදුරටත් ජනතාවට බලපෑම් කරන මානව හිතවාදී දේශපාලනඥයකු මෙන්ම ජනප්‍රිය කලාකරුවෙකු වන රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රන්ජන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂය සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரஞ்சனுக்கு வெகுவிரைவில் விடுதலை கிடைக்கும் என நம்புகின்றேன் - சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "மனிதாபிமானம் மிக்க அரசியல்வாதியான ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க வெகுவிரைவில் முழுமையான விடுதலை பெறுவார் என்று தான் நம்புவதாக எதிர்க்கட்சி தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "வெலிக்கடை சிறைச்சாலையில் முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவை நேற்று சனிக்கிழமை நேரில் சென்று பார்வையிட்டதன் பின்னர் ஊடகங்களுக்கு கருத்து வெளியிடும் போது இதனைத் தெரிவித்த எதிர்க்கட்சி தலைவர் மேலும் குறிப்பிடுகையில்,",
        "வெகுவிரைவில் தனக்கு முழுமையான விடுதலை கிடைக்கும் என்ற சாதகமான எதிர்பார்ப்புடன் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க காத்திருக்கின்றார். அவருக்கு முழுமையான விடுதலை கிடைக்க வேண்டும் என்பதே, என்னுடையதும் முழு இலங்கை மக்களதும் எதிர்பார்ப்பாகும். இதற்காக நாம் பிரார்த்திற்கின்றோம். எமது பிரார்த்தைக்கு ஏற்ப நீண்ட நாட்கள் அன்றி , மிக விரைவில் அவருக்கு முழுமையான விடுதலை கிடைக்கும் என்றும் நம்புகின்றோம்.",
        "நீண்ட நாட்கள் செல்வதற்கு முன் அனைவரின் எதிர்பார்ப்பாக இருக்கும் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க முழுமையான விடுதலை கிடைக்கும் எதிர்பார்பார்ப்பதோடு, அந்நாள் வரும் வரை காத்திருக்கின்றோம். அவர் ஓர் உண்மையான மனிதாபிமானி என்பதோடு ஒரு மக்கள் சார் கலைஞராகவும்  மகத்தான பணிகளை நிறைவேற்றியுள்ளார்.",
        "மனிதாபிமான மிக்க அரசியல்வாதிவாதியும், மக்கள் சார் கலைஞராகவும் தொடர்ந்து மக்கள் செல்வாக்குள்ள பிரபலம் மிக்க ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க, சுதந்திரமான பிரஜையாக சமூகத்திற்குத் திரும்பி, உறுதியுடன் சமூக நீதிக்காக பாடுபடுவதை பார்க்க வேண்டும் என்பதே எமது ஒரேயொரு நோக்கமாகும் என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரஞ்சன்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்க்கட்சியான சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிக்கடை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}