{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83452/uk-pm-boris-johnson-in-crisis-as-top-ministers-quit",
  "time_ut": 1657045200,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "UK PM Boris Johnson in crisis as top ministers quit",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "UK PM Boris Johnson in crisis as top ministers quit",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "LONDON, July 5 (Reuters) - Britain’s finance and health ministers resigned on Tuesday in what could spell the end for Prime Minister Boris Johnson’s premiership after he had tried to apologise for the latest scandal to blight his administration.",
        "Both finance minister Rishi Sunak and health minister Sajid Javid sent resignation letters within minutes of each other to the prime minister, in which both took aim at his ability to run an administration that adhered to standards.",
        "The resignations came as Johnson was apologising for what he said was a mistake for not realising that a former minister in charge of pastoral care was unsuitable for a job in government after complaints of sexual misconduct were made against him, in the latest embarrassment to have engulfed his government.",
        "Both Sunak and Javid had formerly publicly supported Johnson during months of scandal over his administration’s conduct and a damning report into parties at his Downing Street office and residence that broke strict COVID-19 lockdown rules.",
        "Sunak, who had reportedly clashed with the prime minister in private about spending, said: “For me to step down as Chancellor while the world is suffering the economic consequences of the pandemic, the war in Ukraine and other serious challenges is a decision that I have not taken lightly.”",
        "“However, the public rightly expect government to be conducted properly, competently and seriously. I recognise this may be my last ministerial job, but I believe these standards are worth fighting for and that is why I am resigning.”",
        "Javid said many lawmakers and the public had lost confidence in Johnson’s ability to govern in the national interest.",
        "“I regret to say, however, that it is clear to me that this situation will not change under your leadership - and you have therefore lost my confidence too,” Javid said in a letter to Johnson.",
        "Their resignations came just minutes after Johnson went on television to apologise for appointing lawmaker Christopher Pincher to a role involved in offering pastoral care in the Conservative Party.",
        "Pincher’s resignation last Thursday triggered days of a changing narrative from Downing Street over what the prime minister knew of the deputy chief whip’s behaviour and when he knew it.",
        "Earlier on Tuesday after a former top official accused Johnson’s office of lying, the prime minister’s spokesman was forced into a quick about-turn to say the British leader had been briefed in “some form” about the case but had forgotten about that last week.",
        "For many in the governing party, another allegation of lying and the explanation of a loss of memory only heightened their frustration with the Johnson administration, which some lawmakers say is paralysed by having to deal with scandals.",
        "Some Conservative lawmakers are trying to renew attempts to unseat him, just a month after the prime minister survived a confidence vote, while others earlier appealed to his top team of cabinet ministers to move against Johnson.",
        "“He’s finished,” said one previously loyal Conservative lawmaker on condition of anonymity. “He shouldn’t prolong the agony. It’s disrespectful to his colleagues, his party and his country.”",
        "Another previously loyal lawmaker agreed: “It is all over. I would be amazed if he lasts until the summer now.”",
        "Local media reported that Johnson did still command the support of a number of senior ministers including Foreign Secretary Liz Truss and Defence Secretary Ben Wallace.",
        "But among lawmakers, there was speculation that other junior ministers could also quit.",
        "Opposition Labour leader Keir Starmer said those who had backed Johnson were complicit in how he had performed his job.",
        "“After all the sleaze, the scandals and the failure, it’s clear that this government is now collapsing,” he said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "UK",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Boris Johnson",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "LONDON",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 5",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Britain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boris Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rishi Sunak",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajid Javid",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sunak",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Javid",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Downing Street",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sunak",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Javid",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Javid",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "just minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Christopher Pincher",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Conservative Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Downing Street",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Johnson’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Conservative",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "just a month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Conservative",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the summer",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liz Truss",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ben Wallace",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Keir Starmer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "එක්සත් රාජධානියේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය බොරිස් ජොන්සන් ප්‍රධාන අමාත්‍යවරුන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමත් සමඟ අර්බුදයක",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලන්ඩන්, ජූලි 5 (රොයිටර්) - බ්‍රිතාන්‍යයේ මුදල් සහ සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරු අඟහරුවාදා ඉල්ලා අස්වූයේ අගමැති බොරිස් ජොන්සන්ගේ පරිපාලනය අවුල් කිරීමේ නවතම සෝලිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් සමාව අයැදීමට උත්සාහ කිරීමෙන් පසුව ඔහුගේ අගමැති ධුරයේ අවසානය විය හැකි දෙයකි.",
        "මුදල් අමාත්‍ය රිෂි සුනක් සහ සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය සජිඩ් ජාවිඩ් යන දෙදෙනාම මිනිත්තු කිහිපයක් ඇතුළත ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපි අගමැතිවරයා වෙත යවා ඇති අතර, එහිදී දෙදෙනාම ප්‍රමිතීන්ට අනුකූල වන පරිපාලනයක් පවත්වාගෙන යාමේ ඔහුගේ හැකියාව ඉලක්ක කර ගත්හ.",
        "එඬේර රැකවරණය භාර හිටපු අමාත්‍යවරයෙකුට එරෙහිව ලිංගික අපචාර චෝදනා එල්ල වීමත් සමඟ ඔහු රජයේ රැකියාවකට නුසුදුසු බව තේරුම් නොගැනීම නිසා සිදුවූ වරදක් බව ජොන්සන් සමාව අයැදීමත් සමඟ මෙම ඉල්ලා අස්වීම් සිදුවී ඇති අතර, එය නවතම ලැජ්ජාවට පත් විය. ඔහුගේ රජය.",
        "සුනක් සහ ජාවිඩ් යන දෙදෙනාම ජොන්සන්ගේ පරිපාලනයේ හැසිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් මාස ගණනාවක් තිස්සේ අපකීර්තියට පත් වූ අතර ඔහුගේ ඩව්නිං වීදියේ කාර්යාලයේ සහ නිවසේ දැඩි COVID-19 අගුලු දැමීමේ නීති කඩ කළ සාදවලට සම්බන්ධ වාර්තාවක් ප්‍රසිද්ධියේ ප්‍රසිද්ධියේ සහාය දක්වා ඇත.",
        "වියදම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් අගමැතිවරයා සමඟ පුද්ගලිකව ගැටුණු බව වාර්තා වූ සුනක් මෙසේ පැවසීය: “ලෝකය වසංගතයේ ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිවිපාක, යුක්‍රේනයේ යුද්ධය සහ අනෙකුත් බරපතල අභියෝගවලට මුහුණ දෙන අතරතුර මට චාන්සලර් ධුරයෙන් ඉවත් වීම මම ගත් තීරණයකි. සැහැල්ලුවට ගත්තේ නැහැ.”",
        "“කෙසේ වෙතත්, මහජනතාව නිවැරැදිව අපේක්ෂා කරන්නේ රජය නිසි ලෙස, නිපුණව සහ බැරෑරුම් ලෙස පවත්වාගෙන යාමයි. මෙය මගේ අවසාන අමාත්‍ය ධූරය විය හැකි බව මම දනිමි, නමුත් මෙම ප්‍රමිතීන් වෙනුවෙන් සටන් කිරීම වටී යැයි මම විශ්වාස කරමි, ඒ නිසා මම ඉල්ලා අස්වෙනවා.",
        "ජාවිඩ් පැවසුවේ බොහෝ නීති සම්පාදකයින්ට සහ මහජනතාවට ජාතික අවශ්‍යතා අනුව පාලනය කිරීමට ජොන්සන්ට ඇති හැකියාව පිළිබඳ විශ්වාසය නැති වී ඇති බවයි.",
        "“කෙසේ වෙතත්, ඔබගේ නායකත්වය යටතේ මෙම තත්ත්වය වෙනස් නොවන බව මට පැහැදිලි බව පැවසීමට මම කනගාටු වෙමි - එබැවින් ඔබට මගේ විශ්වාසය ද නැති වී ඇත,” ජාවිඩ් ජොන්සන් වෙත ලිපියක් යවමින් පැවසීය.",
        "කොන්සර්වේටිව් පක්ෂයේ එඬේර රැකවරණය පිරිනැමීමේ භූමිකාවකට නීති සම්පාදක ක්‍රිස්ටෝපර් පින්චර් පත් කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සමාව අයැදීමට ජොන්සන් රූපවාහිනියට ගොස් මිනිත්තු කිහිපයකට පසුව ඔවුන්ගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම් සිදුවිය.",
        "පසුගිය බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා පින්චර්ගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම, නියෝජ්‍ය ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායකවරයාගේ හැසිරීම ගැන අගමැති දැන සිටි දේ සහ ඔහු එය දැනගත් විට ඩව්නිං වීදියේ සිට වෙනස්වන ආඛ්‍යානයකට දින කිහිපයකට මුල පිරුවේය.",
        "මීට පෙර අඟහරුවාදා හිටපු ඉහළ නිලධාරියෙකු ජොන්සන්ගේ කාර්යාලයට බොරු කී බවට චෝදනා කිරීමෙන් පසුව, අගමැතිගේ ප්‍රකාශකයාට ඉක්මන් හැරීමට බල කෙරුනේ බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය නායකයාට මෙම නඩුව පිළිබඳව “යම් ආකාරයකින්” දැනුවත් කර ඇති නමුත් පසුගිය සතියේ එය අමතක වූ බව පැවසීමටය.",
        "ආණ්ඩු පක්‍ෂයේ බොහෝ දෙනෙකුට, බොරු කීම පිළිබඳ තවත් චෝදනාවක් සහ මතකය නැතිවීම පිළිබඳ පැහැදිලි කිරීම ජොන්සන් පරිපාලනය පිළිබඳ ඔවුන්ගේ කලකිරීම වැඩි කිරීමට හේතු වූ අතර, සමහර නීති සම්පාදකයින් පවසන්නේ අපකීර්තියට මුහුණ දීමට සිදුවීමෙන් එය අඩපණ වී ඇති බවයි.",
        "සමහර කොන්සර්වේටිව් නීති සම්පාදකයින් ඔහුව ඉවත් කිරීමේ උත්සාහයන් අලුත් කිරීමට උත්සාහ කරයි, අගමැතිවරයා විශ්වාසභංගයෙන් බේරී මාසයකට පසුව, තවත් සමහරු ජොන්සන්ට එරෙහිව ගමන් කරන ලෙස ඔහුගේ ඉහළම කැබිනට් අමාත්‍ය කණ්ඩායමට මීට පෙර ආයාචනා කළහ.",
        "නිර්නාමිකභාවයේ කොන්දේසිය මත කලින් විශ්වාසවන්ත කොන්සර්වේටිව් නීති සම්පාදකයෙකු පැවසුවේ “ඔහු ඉවරයි. “ඔහු වේදනාව දිගු නොකළ යුතුය. එය ඔහුගේ සගයන්ට, ඔහුගේ පක්ෂයට සහ ඔහුගේ රටට කරන අගෞරවයක්.",
        "මීට පෙර විශ්වාසවන්ත තවත් නීති සම්පාදකයෙක් එකඟ විය: “සියල්ල අවසන්. ඔහු දැන් ගිම්හානය දක්වා පැවතුනහොත් මම පුදුම වෙමි.",
        "ප්‍රාදේශීය මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කළේ ජොන්සන් තවමත් විදේශ ලේකම් ලිස් ට්‍රස් සහ ආරක්ෂක ලේකම් බෙන් වොලස් ඇතුළු ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ අමාත්‍යවරුන් ගනනාවකගේ සහාය ලබාගෙන ඇති බවයි.",
        "එහෙත් අනෙකුත් කනිෂ්ඨ අමාත්‍යවරුන් ද ඉල්ලා අස්විය හැකි බවට නීති සම්පාදකයින් අතර මතයක් පැවතිණි.",
        "විපක්ෂ කම්කරු නායක Keir Starmer පැවසුවේ ජොන්සන්ට සහාය දුන් අය ඔහු තම කාර්යය ඉටු කළ ආකාරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් හවුල් වූ බවයි.",
        "\"සියලු මඩ ගැසීම්, අපවාදයන් සහ අසාර්ථකත්වයට පසුව, මේ රජය දැන් බිඳ වැටෙමින් පවතින බව පැහැදිලිය,\" ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "බොරිස් ජොන්සන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලන්ඩන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 5",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරිස් ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රිෂි සුනක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිඩ් ජාවිඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිනිත්තු",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුනක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාවිඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩව්නිං වීදිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුනක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාවිඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාවිඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිනිත්තු කිහිපයක් පමණි",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්රිස්ටෝපර් පින්චර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොන්සර්වේටිව් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගිය බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩව්නිං වීදිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොන්සන්ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොන්සර්වේටිව්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසයක් පමණි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොන්සර්වේටිව්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගිම්හානය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිස් ට්‍රස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෙන් වොලස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "කීර් ස්ටාමර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "உயர்மட்ட அமைச்சர்கள் ராஜினாமா செய்ததால் இங்கிலாந்து பிரதமர் போரிஸ் ஜான்சன் நெருக்கடியில் சிக்கியுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "லண்டன், ஜூலை 5 (ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்) - பிரதம மந்திரி போரிஸ் ஜான்சன் தனது நிர்வாகத்தை சீர்குலைக்கும் சமீபத்திய ஊழலுக்கு மன்னிப்பு கேட்க முயற்சித்ததை அடுத்து, அவரது பிரதமர் பதவிக்கு முற்றுப்புள்ளி வைக்கும் வகையில், பிரிட்டனின் நிதி மற்றும் சுகாதார அமைச்சர்கள் செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை ராஜினாமா செய்தனர்.",
        "நிதியமைச்சர் ரிஷி சுனக் மற்றும் சுகாதார அமைச்சர் சஜித் ஜாவித் இருவரும் பிரதமருக்கு சில நிமிடங்களில் ராஜினாமா கடிதங்களை அனுப்பினர், அதில் இருவரும் தரநிலைகளுக்கு இணங்கக்கூடிய நிர்வாகத்தை நடத்துவதற்கான அவரது திறனை இலக்காகக் கொண்டனர்.",
        "ஆயர் பராமரிப்புப் பொறுப்பில் உள்ள முன்னாள் அமைச்சர், தனக்கு எதிராக பாலியல் துஷ்பிரயோகம் செய்ததாக புகார் எழுந்ததையடுத்து, அவர் அரசாங்கப் பணிக்கு தகுதியற்றவர் என்பதை உணராததற்காக ஜான்சன் செய்த தவறுக்கு மன்னிப்பு கேட்டதால், ராஜினாமாக்கள் நடந்துள்ளன. அவரது அரசாங்கம்.",
        "சுனக் மற்றும் ஜாவித் இருவரும் ஜான்சனின் நிர்வாகத்தின் நடத்தை மற்றும் அவரது டவுனிங் ஸ்ட்ரீட் அலுவலகம் மற்றும் குடியிருப்பில் கடுமையான COVID-19 லாக்டவுன் விதிகளை மீறிய கட்சிகளில் ஒரு மோசமான அறிக்கையின் ஊழல்களின் போது பல மாதங்களாக அவருக்கு பகிரங்கமாக ஆதரவளித்தனர்.",
        "செலவினம் தொடர்பாக பிரதமருடன் தனிப்பட்ட முறையில் மோதியதாகக் கூறப்படும் சுனக் கூறினார்: “தொற்றுநோய், உக்ரைனில் நடந்த போர் மற்றும் பிற கடுமையான சவால்களின் பொருளாதார விளைவுகளை உலகம் அனுபவிக்கும் போது நான் அதிபர் பதவியில் இருந்து விலகுவது நான் எடுத்த முடிவு. இலகுவாக எடுத்துக் கொள்ளவில்லை.\"",
        "“இருப்பினும், அரசாங்கம் முறையாகவும், திறமையாகவும், தீவிரமாகவும் நடத்தப்பட வேண்டும் என்று பொதுமக்கள் எதிர்பார்க்கிறார்கள். இது எனது கடைசி மந்திரி வேலையாக இருக்கலாம் என்பதை நான் அங்கீகரிக்கிறேன், ஆனால் இந்த தரநிலைகள் போராடுவதற்கு தகுதியானவை என்று நான் நம்புகிறேன், அதனால்தான் நான் ராஜினாமா செய்கிறேன்.",
        "பல சட்டமியற்றுபவர்களும் பொதுமக்களும் ஜான்சனின் தேசிய நலனுக்காக ஆட்சி செய்யும் திறனில் நம்பிக்கை இழந்து விட்டதாக ஜாவித் கூறினார்.",
        "\"எவ்வாறாயினும், உங்கள் தலைமையின் கீழ் இந்த நிலைமை மாறாது என்பது எனக்கு தெளிவாக உள்ளது என்பதை நான் வருந்துகிறேன் - எனவே நீங்கள் என் நம்பிக்கையையும் இழந்துவிட்டீர்கள்\" என்று ஜாவித் ஜான்சனுக்கு எழுதிய கடிதத்தில் கூறினார்.",
        "கன்சர்வேடிவ் கட்சியில் ஆயர் பராமரிப்பை வழங்குவதில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள சட்டமியற்றுபவர் கிறிஸ்டோபர் பின்சரை நியமித்ததற்காக மன்னிப்பு கேட்க ஜான்சன் தொலைக்காட்சியில் சென்ற சில நிமிடங்களில் அவர்களின் ராஜினாமாக்கள் வந்தன.",
        "கடந்த வியாழன் அன்று பிஞ்சரின் ராஜினாமா, துணைத் தலைமைக் கொறடாவின் நடத்தையைப் பற்றி பிரதம மந்திரிக்கு என்ன தெரியும், அது எப்போது தெரியும் என்பது குறித்து டவுனிங் ஸ்ட்ரீட்டில் இருந்து மாறிவரும் கதையின் நாட்களைத் தூண்டியது.",
        "செவ்வாயன்று, முன்னாள் உயர் அதிகாரி ஜான்சனின் அலுவலகம் பொய் சொன்னதாக குற்றம் சாட்டியதை அடுத்து, பிரதம மந்திரியின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர், பிரிட்டிஷ் தலைவருக்கு இந்த வழக்கு பற்றி \"சில வடிவத்தில்\" விளக்கப்பட்டதாகவும், ஆனால் கடந்த வாரம் அதை மறந்துவிட்டதாகவும் கூறுவதற்கு விரைவாக திரும்ப வேண்டிய கட்டாயம் ஏற்பட்டது.",
        "ஆளும் கட்சியில் உள்ள பலருக்கு, பொய் என்ற மற்றொரு குற்றச்சாட்டு மற்றும் நினைவாற்றல் இழப்பு பற்றிய விளக்கம் ஜான்சன் நிர்வாகத்தின் மீதான அவர்களின் விரக்தியை அதிகப்படுத்தியது, சில சட்டமியற்றுபவர்கள் ஊழல்களைச் சமாளிக்க வேண்டியதன் மூலம் முடங்கிவிட்டதாக கூறுகிறார்கள்.",
        "சில கன்சர்வேடிவ் சட்டமியற்றுபவர்கள் நம்பிக்கை வாக்கெடுப்பில் இருந்து தப்பிய ஒரு மாதத்திற்குப் பிறகு, அவரை பதவி நீக்கம் செய்வதற்கான முயற்சிகளை புதுப்பிக்க முயற்சிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "\"அவர் முடித்துவிட்டார்\" என்று முன்னர் விசுவாசமான கன்சர்வேடிவ் சட்டமியற்றுபவர் ஒருவர் பெயர் தெரியாத நிலையில் கூறினார். “அவன் வேதனையை நீடிக்கக் கூடாது. இது அவரது சகாக்களுக்கும், கட்சிக்கும், நாட்டுக்கும் அவமரியாதையாகும்.",
        "மற்றொரு விசுவாசமான சட்டமியற்றுபவர் ஒப்புக்கொண்டார்: “எல்லாம் முடிந்துவிட்டது. அவர் இப்போது கோடை காலம் வரை நீடித்தால் நான் ஆச்சரியப்படுவேன்.",
        "வெளியுறவுச் செயலர் லிஸ் ட்ரஸ் மற்றும் பாதுகாப்புச் செயலர் பென் வாலஸ் உட்பட பல மூத்த அமைச்சர்களின் ஆதரவை ஜான்சன் இன்னமும் பெற்றிருப்பதாக உள்ளூர் ஊடகங்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளன.",
        "ஆனால், மற்ற ஜூனியர் அமைச்சர்களும் ராஜினாமா செய்யலாம் என்ற ஊகங்கள் சட்டமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் மத்தியில் நிலவியது.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் கெய்ர் ஸ்டார்மர், ஜான்சனை ஆதரித்தவர்கள் அவர் தனது வேலையை எப்படிச் செய்தார் என்பதற்கு உடந்தையாக இருந்தனர் என்றார்.",
        "\"அனைத்து ஊழல்கள், ஊழல்கள் மற்றும் தோல்விகளுக்குப் பிறகு, இந்த அரசாங்கம் இப்போது வீழ்ச்சியடைகிறது என்பது தெளிவாகிறது,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "யுகே",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "போரிஸ் ஜான்சன்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "லண்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 5",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "போரிஸ் ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரிஷி சுனக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் ஜாவித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிமிடங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுனக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாவித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டவுனிங் தெரு",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுனக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜாவித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜாவித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெறும் நிமிடங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிறிஸ்டோபர் பின்சர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கன்சர்வேடிவ் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டவுனிங் தெரு",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான்சனின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பழமைவாதி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பழமைவாதி",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோடை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிஸ் டிரஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பென் வாலஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கெய்ர் ஸ்டார்மர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}