{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/31/chinese-ship-set-to-dock-in-sri-lanka/",
  "time_ut": 1659242820,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Chinese ship set to dock in Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Chinese ship set to dock in Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "(The Hindu); Days after denying reports of the scheduled arrival of a Chinese research vessel, and following India’s “clear message” about “carefully monitoring” the development, Sri Lanka’s Ministry of Defence on Saturday confirmed that the vessel had sought clearance to call at the southern Hambantota Port in August.",
        "“The vessel will be in Hambantota from August 11 to 17, mainly for replenishment, including fuel,” Sri Lanka’s Defence Ministry media spokesman Col. Nalin Herath said.",
        "Reports of the vessel — Yuan Wang 5 — involved in space and satellite tracking, came to New Delhi’s notice earlier this week, when External Affairs Ministry spokesman Arindam Bagchi told the weekly media briefing that India “carefully monitors any development having a bearing on its security and economic interests”.",
        "Soon after, China said it hopes that “relevant parties” would refrain from interfering with its “legitimate maritime activities”, news agency Reuters reported. The remark indicated that the Chinese vessel’s arrival could potentially leave Colombo caught between New Delhi and Beijing’s interests once again.",
        "While the Ministry of Defence in Colombo did not explain why it had earlier denied the vessel’s arrival, Col. Herath said: “Such vessels periodically come from various countries such as India, China, Japan, Australia. It is nothing unusual.”",
        "However, geostrategic analysts are closely watching the development, given past tensions between Colombo and New Delhi, especially after Colombo allowed a Chinese nuclear-powered submarine Changzheng 2 to dock at its port in 2014.",
        "QR system in effect from 1st August : 12 important points to know before heading to pump fuel"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 11 to 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defence Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalin Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "earlier this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "External Affairs Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arindam Bagchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Defence in Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Changzheng 2",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීන නෞකාවක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "(ද හින්දු); චීන පර්යේෂණ යාත්‍රාවක් පැමිණීමට නියමිතව ඇති බවට පළ වූ වාර්තා ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කිරීමෙන් දින කිහිපයකට පසු, සංවර්ධනය “පරෙස්සමින් අධීක්ෂණය කිරීම” පිළිබඳ ඉන්දියාවේ “පැහැදිලි පණිවිඩය” අනුගමනය කරමින්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය සෙනසුරාදා තහවුරු කළේ යාත්‍රාව දකුණු හම්බන්තොට වරායට පැමිණීමට අවසර ඉල්ලා ඇති බවයි. අගෝස්තුවේදී.",
        "\"ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් ඉන්ධන ඇතුළු නැවත පිරවීම සඳහා යාත්‍රාව අගෝස්තු 11 සිට 17 දක්වා හම්බන්තොට පවතිනු ඇත\" යනුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයේ මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක කර්නල් නලින් හේරත් පැවසීය.",
        "අභ්‍යවකාශ හා චන්ද්‍රිකා ලුහුබැඳීමේ යෙදී සිටින යුආන් වැන්ග් 5 නෞකාවේ වාර්තා මේ සතිය මුලදී නවදිල්ලියේ අවධානයට ලක්විය, විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශක අරින්දම් බග්චි සතිපතා මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී පැවසුවේ ඉන්දියාව “එහි ආරක්ෂාවට බලපාන ඕනෑම වර්ධනයක් ප්‍රවේශමෙන් නිරීක්ෂණය කරන බවයි. සහ ආර්ථික අවශ්යතා\".",
        "වැඩි කල් යන්නට මත්තෙන්, “අදාළ පාර්ශ්වයන්” තම “නීත්‍යානුකූල සමුද්‍රීය ක්‍රියාකාරකම්” වලට මැදිහත් වීමෙන් වැළකී සිටිනු ඇතැයි බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව චීනය ප්‍රකාශ කළ බව රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවය වාර්තා කළේය. චීන යාත්‍රාවේ පැමිණීම නවදිල්ලිය සහ බීජිං හි අවශ්‍යතා අතර නැවත වරක් කොළඹින් පිටවිය හැකි බව එම ප්‍රකාශයෙන් ඇඟවීය.",
        "කොළඹ ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය මීට පෙර යාත්‍රාව පැමිණීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේ මන්දැයි පැහැදිලි කර නොමැති අතර කර්නල් හේරත් පැවසුවේ “එවැනි යාත්‍රා වරින් වර ඉන්දියාව, චීනය, ජපානය, ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව වැනි විවිධ රටවලින් පැමිණේ. එය අසාමාන්ය දෙයක් නොවේ. ”",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, භූ මූලෝපායික විශ්ලේෂකයින්, කොළඹ සහ නව දිල්ලිය අතර අතීත ආතතීන් සැලකිල්ලට ගෙන, විශේෂයෙන්ම 2014 දී චීනයේ න්‍යෂ්ටික බලයෙන් ක්‍රියාත්මක වන Changzheng 2 සබ්මැරීනයක් එහි වරායට නැව්ගත කිරීමට අවසර දීමෙන් පසුව, සංවර්ධනය සමීපව නිරීක්ෂණය කරති.",
        "QR පද්ධතිය අගෝස්තු 1 සිට ක්රියාත්මක වේ : ඉන්ධන පොම්ප කිරීමට පෙර දැනගත යුතු වැදගත් කරුණු 12 ක්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 11 සිට 17 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නලින් හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවදිල්ලියේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ සතියේ මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arindam Bagchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Changzheng 2",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சீனக் கப்பல் இலங்கையில் நிறுத்தப்பட உள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "(தி இந்து); ஒரு சீன ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பல் வரவுள்ளதாகத் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்ட செய்திகளை மறுத்த சில நாட்களுக்குப் பிறகு, இந்தியாவின் \"தெளிவான செய்தியை\" தொடர்ந்து வளர்ச்சியை \"கவனமாக கண்காணித்தல்\", இலங்கையின் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம் சனிக்கிழமையன்று கப்பல் தெற்கு அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்திற்கு வர அனுமதி கோரியுள்ளது. ஆகஸ்ட் மாதத்தில்.",
        "\"கப்பல் ஆகஸ்ட் 11 முதல் 17 வரை ஹம்பாந்தோட்டையில் இருக்கும், முக்கியமாக எரிபொருள் உள்ளிட்ட நிரப்புதலுக்காக,\" என்று இலங்கையின் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சின் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர் கேணல் நலின் ஹேரத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "விண்வெளி மற்றும் செயற்கைக்கோள் கண்காணிப்பில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள யுவான் வாங் 5 என்ற கப்பலின் அறிக்கைகள், இந்த வார தொடக்கத்தில் புது தில்லியின் கவனத்திற்கு வந்தன, வெளியுறவு அமைச்சக செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் அரிந்தம் பாக்சி வாராந்திர செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பில், “இந்தியா அதன் பாதுகாப்பில் தாக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்தும் எந்தவொரு வளர்ச்சியையும் கவனமாக கண்காணிக்கிறது. மற்றும் பொருளாதார நலன்கள்.\"",
        "விரைவில், \"சம்பந்தப்பட்ட கட்சிகள்\" அதன் \"சட்டபூர்வமான கடல்சார் நடவடிக்கைகளில்\" தலையிடுவதைத் தவிர்க்கும் என்று நம்புவதாக சீனா கூறியதாக ராய்ட்டர்ஸ் செய்தி நிறுவனம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. சீனக் கப்பலின் வருகை மீண்டும் புது டெல்லி மற்றும் பெய்ஜிங்கின் நலன்களுக்கு இடையில் கொழும்பை விட்டுச் செல்லக்கூடும் என்று குறிப்பு சுட்டிக்காட்டுகிறது.",
        "கொழும்பில் உள்ள பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சு ஏன் கப்பலின் வருகையை முன்னதாக மறுத்தது என்பதை விளக்கவில்லை என்றாலும், கேணல் ஹேரத் கூறினார்: “இந்தியா, சீனா, ஜப்பான், ஆஸ்திரேலியா போன்ற பல்வேறு நாடுகளில் இருந்து அவ்வப்போது இத்தகைய கப்பல்கள் வருகின்றன. இது ஒன்றும் அசாதாரணமானது அல்ல.”",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், புவிசார் மூலோபாய ஆய்வாளர்கள், கொழும்பிற்கும் புது டெல்லிக்கும் இடையே கடந்தகால பதட்டங்களைக் கருத்தில் கொண்டு, குறிப்பாக 2014 இல் சீன அணுசக்தியால் இயங்கும் நீர்மூழ்கிக் கப்பலான Changzheng 2 ஐ அதன் துறைமுகத்தில் நிறுத்த அனுமதித்த பின்னர், வளர்ச்சியை உன்னிப்பாகக் கவனித்து வருகின்றனர்.",
        "QR அமைப்பு ஆகஸ்ட் 1 முதல் அமலுக்கு வருகிறது : எரிபொருளை பம்ப் செய்வதற்கு முன் தெரிந்து கொள்ள வேண்டிய 12 முக்கிய புள்ளிகள்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாட்களில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 11 முதல் 17 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நளின் ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது டெல்லியின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வார தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரிந்தம் பாக்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாங்செங் 2",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}