{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130296",
  "time_ut": 1656344466,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "படகு மூலம் தனுஷ்கோடி சென்ற  மன்னாரைச் சேர்ந்த வயோதிப தம்பதிகளின்  நிலை கவலைக்கிடம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The condition of an elderly couple from Mannar who went to Dhanushkodi by boat is worrying",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "The elderly couple who went to Dhanushkodi by boat from Sri Lanka in the early hours of Monday (27) were rescued from the beach and admitted to the Ramanathapuram District Government Medical College Hospital and are undergoing intensive treatment.",
        "Parameswari and Sivan, an elderly couple from Murunganpitiya, Mannar, traveled to Dhanushkodi by boat from Sri Lanka.",
        "The two were admitted to the Ramanathapuram District Government Medical College Hospital and are receiving intensive care.",
        "District Attorney John Tom Varghese visited the two men in medical treatment and instructed them to carry out the necessary medical treatment.",
        "He was referred to Madurai Government Rajaji Hospital as his health was critical.",
        "More than 85 people have so far fled to Tamil Nadu as refugees due to the severe economic crisis in Sri Lanka.",
        "Parameswari and Sivan, an elderly couple from Murunganpitiya, Mannar, landed at Dhanushkodi beach near Rameshwaram this morning (27).",
        "It is noteworthy that the two have been found lying unconscious on the beach."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Mannar",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the early hours of Monday",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ramanathapuram District Government Medical College Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parameswari",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sivan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Murunganpitiya, Mannar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhanushkodi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ramanathapuram District Government Medical College Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "John Tom Varghese",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Madurai Government Rajaji Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "More than 85",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parameswari",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sivan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Murunganpitiya, Mannar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhanushkodi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rameshwaram",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බෝට්ටුවෙන් ධනුෂ්කොඩි ගිය මන්නාරමේ වයෝවෘද්ධ අඹුසැමි යුවළකගේ තත්ත්වය කණගාටුදායකයි",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "සඳුදා (27) අලුයම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිට බෝට්ටුවකින් ධනුෂ්කොඩි වෙත ගිය වයෝවෘද්ධ අඹුසැමි යුවළ මුහුදු වෙරළෙන් මුදාගෙන රාමනාතපුරම් දිස්ත්‍රික් රජයේ වෛද්‍ය විද්‍යාල රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කර දැඩි ප්‍රතිකාර ලබමින් සිටිති.",
        "මන්නාරම මුරුංගන්පිටියේ පරමේශ්වරී සහ ශිවන් නමැති වයෝවෘද්ධ අඹුසැමි යුවළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිට බෝට්ටුවකින් ධනුෂ්කොඩි වෙත ගියහ.",
        "ඔවුන් දෙදෙනා රාමනාතපුරම් දිස්ත්‍රික් රජයේ වෛද්‍ය විද්‍යාල රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කර දැඩි සත්කාර ලබමින් සිටිති.",
        "දිස්ත්‍රික් නීතීඥ ජෝන් ටොම් වර්ගීස් මහතා වෛද්‍ය ප්‍රතිකාර ලබන පුද්ගලයන් දෙදෙනා බැලීමට ගොස් අවශ්‍ය වෛද්‍ය ප්‍රතිකාර සිදු කරන ලෙස උපදෙස් දුන්නේය.",
        "ඔහුගේ තත්ත්වය බරපතල බැවින් ඔහු මදුරෙයි රජයේ රාජාජි රෝහල වෙත යොමු කර ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පවතින දැඩි ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් මේ වන විට පුද්ගලයින් 85කට අධික පිරිසක් සරණාගතයින් ලෙස තමිල්නාඩුවට පළා ගොස් තිබෙනවා.",
        "මන්නාරම මුරුංගන්පිටිය ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිව සිටි පරමේශ්වරී සහ සිවන් නමැති වයෝවෘද්ධ යුවළ අද (27) උදෑසන රාමේෂ්වරම් අසල ධනුෂ්කොඩි වෙරළට ගොඩ බැස්සේය.",
        "ඔවුන් දෙදෙනා සිහිසුන්ව මුහුදු වෙරළේ වැටී සිටියදී හමුවී තිබීම විශේෂත්වයකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මන්නාරම",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා හිමිදිරියේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනාතපුරම් දිස්ත්‍රික් රජයේ වෛද්‍ය විද්‍යාල රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පරමේශ්වරී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිවන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුරුංගන්පිටිය, මන්නාරම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධනුෂ්කොඩි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනාතපුරම් දිස්ත්‍රික් රජයේ වෛද්‍ය විද්‍යාල රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජෝන් ටොම් වර්ගීස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මදුරෙයි රජයේ රාජාජි රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "85 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පරමේශ්වරී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිවන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුරුංගන්පිටිය, මන්නාරම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධනුෂ්කොඩි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමේෂ්වරම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "படகு மூலம் தனுஷ்கோடி சென்ற  மன்னாரைச் சேர்ந்த வயோதிப தம்பதிகளின்  நிலை கவலைக்கிடம்",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையில் இருந்து படகு மூலம் இன்று திங்கட்கிழமை (27) அதிகாலை தனுஷ்கோடி சென்ற வயதான தம்பதியர் கடற்கரையில் மயங்கிக் கிடந்த நிலையில் மீட்கப்பட்டு இராமநாதபுரம் மாவட்ட அரசு மருத்துவக்கல்லூரி மருத்துவமனையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டு தீவிர சிகிச்சை அளிக்கப்பட்டு வருகிறது.",
        "மன்னார் முருங்கன் பிட்டி பகுதியை சேர்ந்த பரமேஸ்வரி மற்றும் சிவன், ஆகிய வயோதிப தம்பதிகளான இருவருமே இலங்கையிலிருந்து படகு மூலம் தனுஷ்கோடிக்கு சென்றனர்.",
        "இந்த நிலையில் குறித்த இருவரும் மயக்க நிலையில்  கடற்கரையில் மீட்கப்பட்ட நிலையில்  இராமநாதபுரம் மாவட்ட அரசு மருத்துவக்கல்லூரி மருத்துவமனையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டு தீவிர சிகிச்சை அளிக்கப்பட்டு வருகிறது.",
        "மருத்துவ சிகிச்சையில் உள்ள இருவரையும் மாவட்ட ஆட்சித் தலைவர் ஜான் டாம் வர்கீஸ் நேரில் சென்று பார்வையிட்டதோடு : அவர்களுக்கு தேவையான மருத்துவ சிகிச்சையை மேற்கொள்ளுமாறு அறிவுறுத்தினார்.",
        "மேலும் இருவரின் உடல்நிலை மிக மோசமாக இருப்பதால் மதுரை அரசு ராஜாஜி மருத்துவமனைக்கு பரிந்துரை செய்து அனுப்பி வைத்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் ஏற்பட்ட கடும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி காரணமாக இதுவரையில் 85-க்கும் மேற்பட்டவர்கள் அகதிகளாக தமிழகம் சென்றுள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்த நிலையில் மன்னார் முருங்கன் பிட்டி பகுதியை சேர்ந்த பரமேஸ்வரி மற்றும் சிவன்,ஆகிய வயோதிப தம்பதிகளான இருவரும் படகு மூலம்  இன்று (27) அதிகாலை இராமேஸ்வரம் அருகே உள்ள தனுஷ்கோடி கடற்கரையில் இறங்கினர்.",
        "இதையடுத்து குறித்த இருவரும் மயக்க நிலையில் கடற்கரையில்  விழுந்து கிடந்த நிலையில் மீட்கப்பட்டுள்ளமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மன்னார்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாதபுரம் மாவட்ட அரசு மருத்துவக் கல்லூரி மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பரமேஸ்வரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிவன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முருங்கன்பிட்டிய, மன்னார்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனுஷ்கோடி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாதபுரம் மாவட்ட அரசு மருத்துவக் கல்லூரி மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜான் டாம் வர்கீஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மதுரை அரசு ராஜாஜி மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "85க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பரமேஸ்வரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிவன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முருங்கன்பிட்டிய, மன்னார்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனுஷ்கோடி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமேஸ்வரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}