{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/79295",
  "time_ut": 1661888460,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka  has reached only a  preliminary agreement with the International Monetary Fund (IMF) prior to  a staff-level agreement for an Extended Fund Facility (EFF) and Rapid Financing Instrument (RFI)  states former Central Bank of Sri Lanka (CBSL) Deputy Governor Dr. W.A. Wijewardena",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka  has reached only a  preliminary agreement with the International Monetary Fund (IMF) prior to  a staff-level agreement for an Extended Fund Facility (EFF) and Rapid Financing Instrument (RFI)  states former Central Bank of Sri Lanka (CBSL) Deputy Governor Dr. W.A. Wijewardena",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka has only reached a preliminary agreement with the International Monetary Fund (IMF) prior to a staff-level agreement for an Extended Fund Facility (EFF) and Rapid Financing Instrument (RFI), stated former Central Bank of Sri Lanka (CBSL) Deputy Governor Dr. W.A. Wijewardena, clarifying a report by Reuters published yesterday (31 August).",
        "“The IMF has neither confirmed nor denied the Reuters report. We don’t know whether it’s true or not. But preliminary means we need to have further consultations. This is not the final agreement,” he stated.",
        "Reuters reported yesterday, quoting four sources, that Sri Lanka and the IMF have reached a preliminary agreement on an emergency loan, while a formal announcement in this regard will be made today (1).",
        "Following the report, IMF Senior Mission Chief for Sri Lanka Peter Breuer and IMF Mission Chief for Sri Lanka Masahiro Nozaki said in a statement that the IMF Mission in Colombo has extended its stay by one day, as discussions are still underway with the authorities. They had stated that they planned to conclude the mission and issue a press release today.",
        "Speaking to The Morning Business, Dr Wijewardena said that a preliminary agreement means Sri Lanka needs to have further consultations with the IMF to reach a staff-level agreement.",
        "He said that the IMF team in Sri Lanka extended its stay by another day as the two parties had been unable to arrive at a final decision.",
        "Further, he said that discussions with the IMF are towards the obtaining of an EFF as well as an RFI, which Sri Lanka did not opt for in 2020 when RFIs were handed to countries to address the economic impacts of the Covid-19 pandemic.",
        "“The preliminary agreement is surely for two fund arrangements. The discussions are going on for both an EFF and RFI. The main reason an RFI is not available to Sri Lanka is because it is not a low-income country, but on this occasion, the RFI is being extended to Sri Lanka as a special case, considering the extraordinary situation we are facing,” he added.",
        "In 2020, out of the countries in the South Asian region, Bangladesh and Pakistan received $ 488 million and $ 1.3 billion, respectively, under the RFI facility.",
        "The former central banker said that Sri Lanka is set to receive a 100% quota of about $ 800 million under an RFI as an immediate payment and $ 3.2 billion under an EFF over a period of three years based on IMF Board approval.",
        "Meanwhile, University of Colombo Lecturer Umesh Moramudali told The Morning Business that given the fact that the US is a big member of the IMF, implementing the policies suggested by the US, such as those related to ensuring the independence of the CBSL, will be required for IMF Executive Board approval.",
        "“Sri Lanka would have to properly implement the reforms this time. We cannot get away by providing a statement on the Central Bank’s independence. The new Central Bank Act has to be implemented.”",
        "Both Wijewardena and Moramudali stated that Sri Lanka’s human rights issues would not impact the staff-level agreement, but would play a role in obtaining approval for fund disbursement from the IMF Executive Board."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "an Extended Fund Facility",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "EFF",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Rapid Financing Instrument",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "RFI",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "W.A. Wijewardena",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "an Extended Fund Facility",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rapid Financing Instrument",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RFI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "W.A. Wijewardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "31 August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peter Breuer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the IMF Mission in Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Morning Business",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dr Wijewardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "another day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RFI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RFI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RFI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "RFI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 488 million and $ 1.3 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "RFI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "about $ 800 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "RFI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 3.2 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "University of Colombo Lecturer Umesh Moramudali",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Morning Business",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF Executive Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank Act",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijewardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moramudali",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the IMF Executive Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව විස්තීරණ අරමුදල් පහසුකම (EFF) සහ වේගවත් මූල්‍යකරණ උපකරණ (RFI) සඳහා කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමකට පෙර ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ මූලික එකඟතාවකට පැමිණ ඇති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවේ (CBSL) හිටපු නියෝජ්‍ය අධිපති පවසයි. විජේවර්ධන ආචාර්ය ඩබ්ලිව්.ඒ",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ මූලික එකඟතාවකට පැමිණ ඇත්තේ විස්තීරණ අරමුදල් පහසුකම (EFF) සහ වේගවත් මූල්‍ය උපකරණ (RFI) සඳහා කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමකට පෙර පමණක් බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවේ (CBSL) හිටපු නියෝජ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. ඊයේ (අගෝස්තු 31) ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කළ රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවයේ වාර්තාවක් පැහැදිලි කරමින් ආණ්ඩුකාර ආචාර්ය ඩබ්ලිව්.ඒ.",
        "“ජාමූඅ රොයිටර් වාර්තාව තහවුරු කර හෝ ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කර නැත. එය ඇත්තද නැත්තද යන්න අපි නොදනිමු. නමුත් මූලික අදහස් වන්නේ අපට තවදුරටත් උපදේශන පැවැත්විය යුතු බවයි. මෙය අවසන් ගිවිසුම නොවේ,” ඔහු ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල හදිසි ණයක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් මූලික එකඟතාවකට පැමිණ ඇති අතර, ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් විධිමත් නිවේදනයක් අද (1) නිකුත් කිරීමට නියමිත බව මූලාශ්‍ර හතරක් උපුටා දක්වමින් රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවය ඊයේ වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "වාර්තාවෙන් පසුව, IMF ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ දූත මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානී Peter Breuer සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා IMF දූත මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානී Masahiro Nozaki නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ බලධාරීන් සමඟ තවමත් සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වෙන බැවින් IMF කොළඹ දූත මණ්ඩලය එහි රැඳී සිටීම එක් දිනකින් දීර්ඝ කර ඇති බවයි. එම මෙහෙයුම අවසන් කර අද දින මාධ්‍ය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කිරීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති බවයි ඔවුන් ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබුණේ.",
        "The Morning Business වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් ආචාර්ය විජේවර්ධන කියා සිටියේ මූලික ගිවිසුමක් යනු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමකට එළඹීම සඳහා IMF සමඟ තවදුරටත් උපදේශන පැවැත්විය යුතු බවයි.",
        "දෙපාර්ශවයට අවසන් තීරණයකට එළැඹීමට නොහැකි වීම හේතුවෙන් ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ කණ්ඩායම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රැඳී සිටීම තවත් දිනකින් දීර්ඝ කළ බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "තවද, කොවිඩ්-19 වසංගතයේ ආර්ථික බලපෑම් ආමන්ත්‍රණය කිරීම සඳහා 2020 දී RFIs රටවල් වෙත භාර දුන් විට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තෝරා නොගත් EFF මෙන්ම RFI ද ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා IMF සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කරන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "“මූලික ගිවිසුම නිසැකවම අරමුදල් විධිවිධාන දෙකක් සඳහා වේ. EFF සහ RFI යන දෙකම සඳහා සාකච්ඡා සිදුවෙමින් පවතී. RFI එකක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට නොලැබීමට ප්‍රධාන හේතුව එය අඩු ආදායම්ලාභී රටක් නොවන නිසා නමුත් මෙම අවස්ථාවේදී අප මුහුණ දී සිටින අසාමාන්‍ය තත්ත්වය සලකා බලා විශේෂ අවස්ථාවක් ලෙස RFI ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දක්වා ව්‍යාප්ත කරන බව ඔහු පැවසීය. එකතු කළා.",
        "2020 දී RFI පහසුකම යටතේ දකුණු ආසියානු කලාපයේ රටවල් අතරින් බංග්ලාදේශය සහ පාකිස්තානය පිළිවෙලින් ඩොලර් මිලියන 488ක් සහ ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.3ක් ලබා ගත්හ.",
        "හිටපු මහ බැංකුකරු පැවසුවේ, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට RFI යටතේ ඩොලර් මිලියන 800 ක 100% කෝටාවක් ක්ෂණික ගෙවීමක් ලෙස සහ IMF මණ්ඩල අනුමැතිය මත පදනම්ව වසර තුනක කාලයක් තුළ EFF යටතේ ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.2 ක් ලැබීමට නියමිත බවයි.",
        "මේ අතර, කොළඹ විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ කථිකාචාර්ය උමේෂ් මොරමුදලි The Morning Business වෙත පැවසුවේ, එක්සත් ජනපදය ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ විශාල සාමාජිකයෙකු වන බැවින්, මහ බැංකුවේ ස්වාධීනත්වය සහතික කිරීම වැනි එක්සත් ජනපදය යෝජනා කරන ප්‍රතිපත්ති ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම අවශ්‍ය වනු ඇති බවයි. IMF විධායක මණ්ඩල අනුමැතිය සඳහා.",
        "“මෙවර ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ නිසි ලෙස ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සිදුවනු ඇත. මහ බැංකුවේ ස්වාධීනත්වය ගැන ප්‍රකාශයක් දීලා අපිට ගැලවෙන්න බැහැ. නව මහ බැංකු පනත ක්‍රියාත්මක කළ යුතුයි.”",
        "විජේවර්ධන සහ මොරමුදලි යන දෙදෙනාම කියා සිටියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මානව හිමිකම් ගැටළු කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමට බලපාන්නේ නැති නමුත් IMF විධායක මණ්ඩලයෙන් අරමුදල් බෙදා හැරීම සඳහා අනුමැතිය ලබා ගැනීමේ කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කරන බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "විස්තීරණ අරමුදල් පහසුකමකි",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "EFF",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "වේගවත් මූල්‍ය උපකරණ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "RFI",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඩබ්ලිව්.ඒ විජේවර්ධන",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විස්තීරණ අරමුදල් පහසුකමකි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වේගවත් මූල්‍ය උපකරණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RFI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩබ්ලිව්.ඒ විජේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peter Breuer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ IMF මෙහෙයුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන ව්යාපාරය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආචාර්ය විජේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තවත් දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RFI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RFI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RFI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "RFI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 488 ක් සහ ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.3 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "RFI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 800 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "RFI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.2 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ කථිකාචාර්ය උමේෂ් මොරමුදලි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන ව්යාපාරය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF විධායක මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුවේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකු පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොරමුදලි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF විධායක මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட நிதி வசதி (EFF) மற்றும் விரைவான நிதியளிப்பு கருவி (RFI) ஆகியவற்றுக்கான பணியாளர் அளவிலான உடன்படிக்கைக்கு முன்னதாக சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் (IMF) இலங்கை பூர்வாங்க உடன்படிக்கையை எட்டியுள்ளது என இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கியின் (CBSL) முன்னாள் பிரதி ஆளுநர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். கலாநிதி டபிள்யூ.ஏ.விஜேவர்தன",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட நிதி வசதி (EFF) மற்றும் விரைவான நிதியளிப்பு கருவி (RFI) ஆகியவற்றுக்கான பணியாளர் அளவிலான ஒப்பந்தத்திற்கு முன்னதாகவே சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் (IMF) இலங்கை பூர்வாங்க உடன்படிக்கையை எட்டியுள்ளது என்று இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கியின் (CBSL) முன்னாள் பிரதித் தெரிவித்தார். நேற்று (ஆகஸ்ட் 31) வெளியிடப்பட்ட ராய்ட்டர்ஸ் செய்தித் தொடர்பிற்கு ஆளுநர் கலாநிதி டபிள்யூ.ஏ.விஜேவர்தன தெளிவுபடுத்தினார்.",
        "\"ராய்ட்டர்ஸ் அறிக்கையை சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் உறுதிப்படுத்தவில்லை அல்லது மறுக்கவில்லை. அது உண்மையா பொய்யா என்பது எங்களுக்குத் தெரியாது. ஆனால் பூர்வாங்கம் என்றால் நாம் மேலும் ஆலோசனைகள் வேண்டும். இது இறுதி ஒப்பந்தம் அல்ல,'' என்றார்.",
        "இலங்கையும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியமும் அவசரக் கடன் தொடர்பான ஆரம்ப உடன்படிக்கைக்கு வந்துள்ளதாகவும், இது தொடர்பான உத்தியோகபூர்வ அறிவிப்பு இன்று (1) வெளியிடப்படும் என்றும் நான்கு ஆதாரங்களை மேற்கோள் காட்டி ராய்ட்டர்ஸ் நேற்று செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த அறிக்கையைத் தொடர்ந்து, சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் இலங்கைக்கான மூத்த தூதரகத் தலைவர் பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர் மற்றும் இலங்கைக்கான சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத் தலைவர் மசாஹிரோ நோசாகி ஆகியோர், கொழும்பில் உள்ள சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் அதிகாரிகளுடன் இன்னும் கலந்துரையாடல்களை மேற்கொண்டு வருவதால், அதன் தங்குமிடத்தை ஒரு நாள் நீட்டித்துள்ளதாக ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர். பணியை முடித்து இன்று செய்திக்குறிப்பு வெளியிட திட்டமிட்டுள்ளதாக அவர்கள் கூறியிருந்தனர்.",
        "தி மார்னிங் பிசினஸிடம் பேசிய டாக்டர் விஜேவர்தன, பூர்வாங்க ஒப்பந்தம் என்றால், பணியாளர் அளவிலான ஒப்பந்தத்தை எட்டுவதற்கு இலங்கை சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் மேலும் ஆலோசனைகளை நடத்த வேண்டும் என்று கூறினார்.",
        "இரு தரப்பினரும் இறுதித் தீர்மானத்திற்கு வராத காரணத்தினால் இலங்கையில் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் குழு தங்கியிருப்பதை மேலும் ஒரு நாள் நீட்டித்துள்ளதாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "மேலும், IMF உடனான கலந்துரையாடல்கள் EFF மற்றும் RFI ஐப் பெறுவதை நோக்கியதாக அவர் கூறினார், 2020 இல் கோவிட்-19 தொற்றுநோயின் பொருளாதார தாக்கங்களை நிவர்த்தி செய்வதற்காக RFIக்கள் நாடுகளிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டபோது இலங்கை அதைத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கவில்லை.",
        "“பூர்வாங்க ஒப்பந்தம் நிச்சயமாக இரண்டு நிதி ஏற்பாடுகளுக்கானது. EFF மற்றும் RFI இரண்டிற்கும் விவாதங்கள் நடந்து வருகின்றன. இலங்கைக்கு RFI கிடைக்காததற்கு முக்கிய காரணம் அது குறைந்த வருமானம் கொண்ட நாடாக இல்லாததால் தான், ஆனால் இந்த சந்தர்ப்பத்தில், நாம் எதிர்நோக்கும் அசாதாரண சூழ்நிலையை கருத்தில் கொண்டு RFI சிறப்பு வழக்காக இலங்கைக்கு நீட்டிக்கப்படுகிறது,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார். சேர்க்கப்பட்டது.",
        "2020 ஆம் ஆண்டில், தெற்காசிய பிராந்தியத்தில் உள்ள நாடுகளில், வங்காளதேசம் மற்றும் பாகிஸ்தான் ஆகியவை RFI வசதியின் கீழ் முறையே $488 மில்லியன் மற்றும் $1.3 பில்லியன் பெற்றன.",
        "IMF வாரியத்தின் ஒப்புதலின் அடிப்படையில் மூன்று வருட காலத்திற்குள் இலங்கை RFI இன் கீழ் 100% ஒதுக்கீட்டை 800 மில்லியன் டாலர்களையும் EFF இன் கீழ் $3.2 பில்லியன்களையும் பெற உள்ளது என்று முன்னாள் மத்திய வங்கியாளர் கூறினார்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், கொழும்பு பல்கலைக்கழக விரிவுரையாளர் உமேஷ் மொரமுதலி தி மோர்னிங் பிசினஸிடம் கூறுகையில், அமெரிக்கா சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தில் பெரிய அங்கத்துவம் பெற்றுள்ள நிலையில், இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கியின் சுதந்திரத்தை உறுதிப்படுத்துவது போன்ற அமெரிக்காவால் பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்ட கொள்கைகளை நடைமுறைப்படுத்துவது அவசியமாகும். IMF நிர்வாகக் குழுவின் ஒப்புதலுக்கு.",
        "“இம்முறை சீர்திருத்தங்களை இலங்கை சரியாக நடைமுறைப்படுத்த வேண்டும். மத்திய வங்கியின் சுதந்திரம் பற்றிய அறிக்கையை வழங்குவதன் மூலம் நாம் தப்பிக்க முடியாது. புதிய மத்திய வங்கிச் சட்டம் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட வேண்டும்” என்றார்.",
        "விஜேவர்தன மற்றும் மொரமுதலி இருவரும், இலங்கையின் மனித உரிமைகள் பிரச்சினைகள் பணியாளர் மட்ட உடன்படிக்கையை பாதிக்காது, ஆனால் IMF நிர்வாக சபையிடமிருந்து நிதி வழங்கலுக்கான ஒப்புதலைப் பெறுவதில் பங்கு வகிக்கும் என்று கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஒரு விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட நிதி வசதி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "EFF",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "விரைவான நிதியளிப்பு கருவி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "RFI",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "டபிள்யூ.ஏ.விஜேவர்தன",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட நிதி வசதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விரைவான நிதியளிப்பு கருவி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RFI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டபிள்யூ.ஏ.விஜேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "31 ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் உள்ள IMF மிஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலை வணிகம்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "டாக்டர் விஜேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மற்றொரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RFI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RFI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RFI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "RFI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 488 மில்லியன் மற்றும் $ 1.3 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "RFI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் $ 800 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "RFI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 3.2 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று வருடங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு பல்கலைக்கழக விரிவுரையாளர் உமேஷ் மொரமுதலி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை வணிகம்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிபிஎஸ்எல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF நிர்வாக வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கியின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி சட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொரமுதலி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF நிர்வாக வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}