{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/உலக-செய்திகள்/மதுபோதையில்-ஆட்டம்-போட்ட-பிரதமர்/50-302610",
  "time_ut": 1660885205,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "மதுபோதையில் ஆட்டம் போட்ட பிரதமர்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The prime minister played under the influence of alcohol",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Finland's female Prime Minister Sanna Marin has come under heavy criticism after a video of her drunken friends doing punches was released.",
        "Sanna Marin is the Prime Minister of Finland's ruling Social Democratic Party. In this case, a video of Channa Marin playing a game after drinking alcohol with her friends in an apartment is going viral on social media.",
        "There has been a strong protest among the people of the country as they have acted in a way that disrespects and tarnishes the post of Prime Minister. The media is also criticizing."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Finland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanna Marin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sanna Marin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Social Democratic Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අගමැතිතුමා බීමතින් සෙල්ලම් කළා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ෆින්ලන්ත අගමැතිනි සන්නා මැරින් බීමත්ව සිටි මිතුරන් විසින් පහර දෙන වීඩියෝවක් නිකුත් වීමත් සමඟ දැඩි විවේචනයට ලක්ව තිබේ.",
        "Sanna Marin ෆින්ලන්තයේ පාලක සමාජ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී පක්ෂයේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරියයි. මේ අවස්ථාවේ චන්න මැරින් සිය මිතුරන් සමඟ මහල් නිවාසයක මත්පැන් පානය කර ගේමක් ගසන වීඩියෝවක් සමාජ මාධ්‍ය තුළ වයිරල් වෙමින් පවතී.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධූරයට අගෞරවයක් සහ කැළලක් වන අයුරින් කටයුතු කිරීම හේතුවෙන් රටේ ජනතාව අතර දැඩි විරෝධයක් මතුව තිබෙනවා. මාධ්‍යවලත් විවේචන එල්ල වෙනවා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆින්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සනා මැරින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සනා මැරින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆින්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාජ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැරින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மதுபோதையில் ஆட்டம் போட்ட பிரதமர்",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "மதுபோதையில் தனது நண்பர்களுடன் பின்லாந்தின் பெண் பிரதமர் சன்னா மரீன் குத்தாட்டம் போடும் வீடியோ வெளியானதால், அவர் மீது கடும் விமர்சனம் எழுந்துள்ளது.",
        "பின்லாந்தின் ஆளும் சோசியல் டெமாக்ரடிக் கட்சியின் பிரதமராக, சன்னா மரீன் பதவி வகித்து வருகிறார்.  இந்நிலையில், அடுக்குமாடி குடியிருப்பில் தனது நண்பர்களுடன் மது அருந்திவிட்டு சன்னா மரீன் ஆட்டம் போடும் வீடியோ சமூக வலைதளங்களில் பரவி வருகிறது.",
        "பிரதமர் பதவிக்கு அவமரியாதையும், களங்கத்தையும் ஏற்படுத்தும் விதமாக செயல்பட்டதால், அந்நாட்டு மக்களிடையே கடும் எதிர்ப்பு கிளம்பியுள்ளது. ஊடகங்களும் விமர்சனம் செய்து வருகின்றன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பின்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சன்னா மரின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சன்னா மரின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பின்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமூக ஜனநாயகக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மரின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}