{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83676/sajith-premadasa-says-he-will-vie-for-presidency",
  "time_ut": 1657912620,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sajith Premadasa says he will vie for presidency",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sajith Premadasa says he will vie for presidency",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa says he will contest in the parliament to elect the next President of Sri Lanka.",
        "In a tweet, the leader of Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) said: “I am contesting to be the President. Electorate is confined to 225 MPs with the GR coalition dominating the numbers. Even though it is an uphill struggle I am convinced that truth will prevail.”",
        "The post of the Head of State was left vacant after former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa stepped down, bowing to months-long public protests demanding his resignation.",
        "The other two frontrunners in the race to become the next President of the country are Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe and former Mass Media Minister Dullas Alahapperuma.",
        "On Friday, Alahapperuma, who represents the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) in the parliament, announced his intention to vie for the post. However, the party later pledged support for the Acting President.",
        "The parliament will elect a new President on July 20 and nominations will be called next Tuesday (July 19). Following the voting in the House, a Member of Parliament will be appointed for the presidency on July 20."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "months-long",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "(July 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තමන් ජනාධිපතිවරණයට තරග කරන බව සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පවසයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මීළඟ ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනීම සඳහා තමන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් වන බව විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පවසයි.",
        "සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ (SJB) නායකයා ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ, “මම ජනාධිපති වීමට තරඟ කරනවා. ඡන්ද කොට්ඨාසය මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 225 කට සීමා වී ඇති අතර සංඛ්‍යාවේ ආධිපත්‍යය දරන ජීආර් සභාගයයි. එය කඳු නැගීමේ අරගලයක් වුවද සත්‍යය ජය ගන්නා බව මට ඒත්තු ගොස් ඇත.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බලකරමින් මාස ගණනාවක් පුරා පැවති මහජන විරෝධතාවලට හිස නමමින් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු රාජ්‍ය නායකයා පුරප්පාඩු විය.",
        "රටේ මීළඟ ජනාධිපතිවරයා වීමේ තරගයේ සිටින අනෙක් ඉදිරියෙන්ම සිටින දෙදෙනා වන්නේ වැඩ බලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ සහ හිටපු ජනමාධ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම ය.",
        "සිකුරාදා, පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ (SLPP) නියෝජනය කරන අලහප්පෙරුම, එම තනතුර සඳහා තරඟ කිරීමට තම අභිප්‍රාය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. කෙසේ වෙතත් පසුව වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සහය පළ කිරීමට පක්ෂය ප්‍රතිඥා දුන්නේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ජූලි 20 වැනිදා නව ජනාධිපතිවරයකු තෝරා පත් කර ගන්නා අතර නාමයෝජනා කැඳවීම ලබන අඟහරුවාදා (ජූලි 19) සිදු කෙරේ. සභාවේ ඡන්ද විමසීමෙන් අනතුරුව ජුලි 20 වැනිදා ජනාධිපති ධුරය සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු පත් කිරීමට නියමිතයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස-දිග",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "(ජූලි 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் போட்டியிடப் போவதாக சஜித் பிரேமதாச தெரிவித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் அடுத்த ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்காக நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் போட்டியிடவுள்ளதாக எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா (SJB) தலைவர் ஒரு ட்வீட்டில், “நான் ஜனாதிபதியாக போட்டியிடுகிறேன். வாக்காளர்கள் எண்ணிக்கையில் ஆதிக்கம் செலுத்தும் ஜிஆர் கூட்டணியுடன் 225 எம்.பி.க்களுக்கு மட்டுப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது. இது ஒரு மலையகப் போராட்டமாக இருந்தாலும், உண்மை வெல்லும் என்பதில் நான் உறுதியாக இருக்கிறேன்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச பதவி விலகக் கோரி பல மாதங்களாக மக்கள் நடத்திய போராட்டங்களுக்கு அடிபணிந்து பதவி விலகியதை அடுத்து அரச தலைவர் பதவி வெற்றிடமாக இருந்தது.",
        "நாட்டின் அடுத்த ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியேற்கும் போட்டியில் முன்னிலையில் உள்ள மற்றைய இருவர் பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றும் முன்னாள் வெகுஜன ஊடக அமைச்சர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும.",
        "வெள்ளிக்கிழமை, நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவை (SLPP) பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் அழகப்பெரும, அந்தப் பதவிக்கு போட்டியிட விருப்பம் தெரிவித்தார். இருப்பினும், கட்சி பின்னர் செயல் தலைவருக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதாக உறுதியளித்தது.",
        "பாராளுமன்றம் ஜூலை 20 ஆம் தேதி புதிய ஜனாதிபதியைத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கும் மற்றும் வேட்புமனுக்கள் அடுத்த செவ்வாய் (ஜூலை 19) அழைக்கப்படும். சபையில் வாக்கெடுப்பு நடத்தப்பட்டதைத் தொடர்ந்து ஜூலை 20ஆம் தேதி ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஒருவர் நியமிக்கப்படுவார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள் நீடித்தது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "(ஜூலை 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}