{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/නිවසේ-ගින්නෙන්-පියා-මරුට/101-615396",
  "time_ut": 1656216367,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "නිවසේ ගින්නෙන් පියා මරුට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Father killed in house fire",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Kahathuduwa Police say that a father was killed and three others including a six year old daughter were seriously injured in a fire that broke out in a basement of a two storey house in the Magammana area in Homagama.",
        "The deceased has been identified as SA Lasantha Buddhika Ranasinghe (47), a resident of Magammana, Homagama and a father of two.",
        "The victim was in a basement room with his wife (38), eldest daughter (19) and six-year-old daughter when a fire broke out at around 8 last night (26).",
        "The couple and their eldest daughter sustained serious burn injuries and the six-year-old daughter sustained minor injuries in the fire.",
        "The mother and relatives of the deceased were in the adjoining part of the house at the time of the fire and the eldest daughter who was with them had come to the room to comb her hair.",
        "The fire was put out by the residents of the area and the injured were admitted to the Homagama Base Hospital for treatment, police said.",
        "The six injured were rushed to the Borella Children's Hospital and the other three were admitted to the Colombo National Hospital. The 47 - year - old died on the spot, police said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kahathuduwa Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "six year old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magammana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magammana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "six-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "six-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Homagama Base Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Borella Children's Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo National Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "47 - year - old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නිවසේ ගින්නෙන් පියා මරුට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "හෝමාගම මාගම්මන ප්‍රදේශයේ  දෙමහල් නිවසක පහල මාලයේ කාමරයක් තුළ  ඇති වූ ගින්නකින් පියා මියගොස් සය හැවිරිදි දියණියක ඇතුළු තිදෙනෙකු බරපතළ තුවාල ලබා  රෝහල් ගතකර ඇතැයි කහතුඩුව පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "මෙසේ මිය ගොස් ඇත්තේ හෝමාගම මාගම්මන පදිංචි එස්.ඒ.ලසන්ත බුද්ධික  රණසිංහ නමැති (47) හැවිරිදි දෙදරු පියකු බව පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "මියගිය පුද්ගලයා තම බිරිඳ (38)  වැඩිමහල් දියණිය (19) හා සය හැවිරිදි දියණිය සමග දෙමහල් නිවසේ පහළ මාලයේ කාමරයක් තුළ සිටියදී   ඊයේ (26) රාත්‍රී  8 පමණ එක්වරම මෙසේ ගින්නක් හටගෙන තිබුණි .",
        "ගින්නෙන් අඹුසැමි යුවළ හා වැඩිමහල්  දියණිය බරපතළ පිළිස්සුම් තුවාල ලබා තිබූ අතර සය හැවිරිදි දියණිය සුළු තුවාල ලබා තිබුණි .",
        "ගින්න  වන අවස්ථාවේදී නිවසේ යාබද කොටසේ මියගිය පුද්ගලයාගේ මව සහ ඥාතීන් සිට ඇති අතර ඔවුන් සමග සිටි වැඩිමහල් දියණිය කොන්ඩය පීරා ගැනීම සඳහා කාමරයට පැමිණ තිබේ.",
        "පසුව ප්‍රදේශවාසීන් එක්ව ගින්න නිවා දමා තුවාලකරුවන් ප්‍රතිකාර සඳහා හෝමාගම මූලික රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කිරීමට පියවර ගෙන  තිබූ බව පොලිසිය කියයි .",
        "පසුව එහිදී තුවාලකරුවන් සිව්දෙනාට  මුළික ප්‍රතිකාර ලබාදී වැඩිදුර ප්‍රතිකාර සඳහා සය හැවිරිදි දියණිය බොරැල්ල ළමා රෝහලටත් සෙසු තිදෙනා කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහලටත් ඇතුළත් කිරීමට පියවර ගෙන තිබූ අතර ඒ යන අතරතුරදී 47 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයා මෙසේ මියගොස් ඇති බව මූලික විමර්ශනවලදී අනාවරණය වී ඇතැයි පොලීසිය පවසයි ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කහතුඩුව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය හැවිරිදි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාගම්මන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාගම්මන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය හැවිරිදි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හය හැවිරිදි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෝමාගම මූලික රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරැල්ල ළමා රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "47 - වයස අවුරුදු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வீட்டில் தீயில் சிக்கி தந்தை பலி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஹோமாகம, மாகம்மன பிரதேசத்தில் இரண்டு மாடி வீடொன்றின் அடித்தளத்தில் ஏற்பட்ட தீ விபத்தில் தந்தை ஒருவர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளதுடன், ஆறு வயதுடைய மகள் உட்பட மூவர் படுகாயமடைந்துள்ளதாக கஹதுடுவ பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "உயிரிழந்தவர் ஹோமாகம, மாகம்மன பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த இரண்டு பிள்ளைகளின் தந்தையான எஸ்.ஏ.லசந்த புத்திக ரணசிங்க (வயது 47) என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "நேற்றிரவு (26) இரவு 8 மணியளவில் தீ விபத்து ஏற்பட்ட போது உயிரிழந்தவர் தனது மனைவி (38), மூத்த மகள் (19) மற்றும் ஆறு வயது மகளுடன் அடித்தள அறையில் இருந்துள்ளார்.",
        "இந்த தீ விபத்தில் தம்பதியருக்கும் அவர்களது மூத்த மகளுக்கும் பலத்த தீக்காயங்களும், ஆறு வயது மகள் லேசான காயமும் அடைந்தனர்.",
        "தீ விபத்து ஏற்பட்ட போது இறந்தவரின் தாய் மற்றும் உறவினர்கள் வீட்டின் பக்கத்து பகுதியில் இருந்ததாகவும் அவர்களுடன் இருந்த மூத்த மகள் தலைமுடியை சீவுவதற்காக அறைக்கு வந்துள்ளார்.",
        "பிரதேசவாசிகளால் தீ அணைக்கப்பட்டதுடன், காயமடைந்தவர்கள் ஹோமாகம ஆதார வைத்தியசாலையில் சிகிச்சைக்காக அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "படுகாயமடைந்த 6 பேர் பொரளை சிறுவர் வைத்தியசாலையிலும், ஏனைய மூவரும் கொழும்பு தேசிய வைத்தியசாலையிலும் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.47 வயதுடையவர் சம்பவ இடத்திலேயே உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கஹதுடுவ பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகம்மன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகம்மன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹோமாகம ஆதார வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொரளை சிறுவர் வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு தேசிய வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "47 - வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}