{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Heavy-rains-four-sluice-gates-of-Deduru-Oya-opened-Irrigation-Dept/342-244101",
  "time_ut": 1662001626,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Heavy rains; four sluice gates of Deduru Oya opened: Irrigation Dept.",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Heavy rains; four sluice gates of Deduru Oya opened: Irrigation Dept.",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Irrigation (Hydrology) Director S.P.C. Sugeeshwara said due to worsening weather conditions, four spill gates of the Deduru Oya were opened last night to release 8,400 cubic metres per second.",
        "He said the water levels at the gauge stations at Panadugama of the Nilwala river, Baddegama of the Gin river, and Kalawellawa (Millakanda) of the Kuda Ganga were reported to have risen to record levels with the present inclement weather.",
        "There is a possibility of flash floods along the low-lying areas of Kalu Ganga if the heavy rains in the catchment areas would continue.",
        "He mentioned that several tributaries have come to the level of minor floods. As a result, residents living adjacent to major (Kelani and Gin rivers) and tributary rivers should exercise extreme caution in the event of floods.",
        "Due to possible flooding in the said areas, motorists have been advised to use alternative routes.",
        "Meanwhile, the Metrology Department said owing to low-level atmospheric disturbances, which still persist in the vicinity of the island, showers would continue in the Western, Sabaragamuwa, Central, North-western, and Northern provinces and in Anuradhapura, Galle, and Matara districts.",
        "Heavy showers exceeding 75 mm could be expected in some places in the Western, Sabaragamuwa, Central, North-western and Northern provinces.",
        "Thunderstorms will strike several locations in Uva and the Eastern provinces during the evening or night.",
        "Therefore, the general public are cautioned to take adequate precautionary measures to safeguard themselves against damage caused by squall and lightning during thundershowers. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "four",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Deduru Oya",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "S.P.C. Sugeeshwara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,400 cubic metres",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Panadugama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nilwala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Baddegama of the Gin river",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalawellawa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kalu Ganga",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kelani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Metrology Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Northern",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Northern",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eastern",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අධික වැසි; දැදුරු ඔයේ වාන් දොරටු හතරක් විවෘත කෙරේ: වාරිමාර්ග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව.",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "වාරිමාර්ග (ජල විද්‍යා) අධ්‍යක්ෂ එස්.පී.සී. අයහපත් කාලගුණික තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ දැදුරු ඔයේ වාන් දොරටු හතරක් විවෘත කර තත්පරයට ඝන මීටර් 8,400ක් මුදා හැරීමට කටයුතු කළ බව සුගීෂ්වර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "පවතින අයහපත් කාලගුණයත් සමඟ නිල්වලා ගඟේ පානදුගම, ගිං ගඟේ බද්දේගම සහ කුඩා ගඟේ කලවැල්ලාව (මිල්ලකන්ද) යන මාපක ස්ථානවල ජල මට්ටම වාර්තාගත මට්ටමට ඉහළ ගොස් ඇති බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ජල පෝෂක ප්‍රදේශවලට ඇදහැලෙන ධාරානිපාත වර්ෂාව තවදුරටත් පැවතුනහොත් කළුගඟේ පහත් බිම් ආශ්‍රිතව හදිසි ගංවතුර තත්ත්වයක් ඇතිවීමේ හැකියාවක් පවතී.",
        "අතු ගංගා කිහිපයක් සුළු ගංවතුර මට්ටමට පැමිණ ඇති බව ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය. මේ හේතුවෙන් ප්‍රධාන (කැලණි සහ ගිං ගංඟා) සහ අතු ගංගා ආශ්‍රිතව වෙසෙන වැසියන් ගංවතුර තත්ත්වයකදී දැඩි අවධානයෙන් සිටිය යුතුය.",
        "එම ප්‍රදේශවල ගංවතුර තත්ත්වයක් ඇති විය හැකි බැවින් විකල්ප මාර්ග භාවිත කරන ලෙස රියදුරන්ට දැනුම් දී තිබේ.",
        "මේ අතර, කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පැවසුවේ, දිවයින ආසන්නයේ තවමත් පවතින පහළ මට්ටමේ වායුගෝලීය කැළඹීම් හේතුවෙන් බස්නාහිර, සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම, වයඹ සහ උතුරු පළාත්වල සහ අනුරාධපුර, ගාල්ල සහ මාතර යන ප්‍රදේශවලට වැසි තවදුරටත් පවතිනු ඇති බවයි. දිස්ත්රික්ක.",
        "බස්නාහිර, සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම, වයඹ සහ උතුරු පළාත්වල ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලිමීටර් 75 ඉක්ම වූ තද වැසි අපේක්ෂා කළ හැක.",
        "සවස් කාලයේ හෝ රාත්‍රී කාලයේදී ඌව සහ නැගෙනහිර පළාත්වල ස්ථාන කිහිපයකට ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇති වේ.",
        "එබැවින් ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇති වන විට ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇති වන විට අකුණු මඟින් සිදුවන අනතුරුවලින් ආරක්ෂා වීමට ප්‍රමාණවත් පූර්වාරක්‍ෂක පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස මහජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හතර",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "දැදුරු ඔය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.පී.සී. සුගීෂ්වර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඝන මීටර් 8,400 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පානදුගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිල්වලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිං ගඟේ බද්දේගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කලවැල්ලාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කළු ගඟ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kelani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිනුම් විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උතුරු",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பலத்த மழை; தெதுரு ஓயாவின் நான்கு வான் கதவுகள் திறக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன: நீர்ப்பாசன திணைக்களம்.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நீர்ப்பாசனம் (நீரியல்) இயக்குநர் எஸ்.பி.சி. சீரற்ற காலநிலை காரணமாக தெதுரு ஓயாவின் நான்கு வான் கதவுகள் நேற்று இரவு திறந்து வினாடிக்கு 8,400 கனமீற்றர் வீதம் விடுவிக்கப்பட்டதாக சுகீஸ்வர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நில்வலா ஆற்றின் பாணடுகம, ஜின் ஆற்றின் பத்தேகம மற்றும் குடா கங்கையின் கலவெல்லவ (மில்லகந்த) ஆகிய இடங்களில் உள்ள மானி நிலையங்களின் நீர் மட்டம் தற்போதைய சீரற்ற காலநிலையுடன் சாதனை மட்டத்திற்கு உயர்ந்துள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "நீர்பிடிப்பு பகுதிகளில் தொடர்ந்து கனமழை பெய்தால் களுகங்கையின் தாழ்வான பகுதிகளில் வெள்ளப்பெருக்கு ஏற்பட வாய்ப்புள்ளது.",
        "பல துணை ஆறுகள் சிறு வெள்ளப்பெருக்கு நிலைக்கு வந்துள்ளதாக அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். இதன் விளைவாக, பிரதான (களனி மற்றும் ஜின் ஆறுகள்) மற்றும் கிளை நதிகளை அண்டியுள்ள குடியிருப்பாளர்கள் வெள்ளம் ஏற்பட்டால் மிகுந்த அவதானத்துடன் இருக்க வேண்டும்.",
        "குறித்த பிரதேசங்களில் வெள்ளப்பெருக்கு ஏற்படக் கூடிய சாத்தியம் காணப்படுவதால், வாகன சாரதிகள் மாற்று வீதிகளைப் பயன்படுத்துமாறு அறிவுறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இதேவேளை, தீவை அண்மித்த பகுதிகளில் தொடர்ந்தும் நிலவும் குறைந்த மட்ட வளிமண்டல குழப்பங்கள் காரணமாக மேல், சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய, வடமேல் மற்றும் வடமாகாணங்களிலும் அனுராதபுரம், காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறையிலும் மழை தொடரும் என திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. மாவட்டங்கள்.",
        "மேல், சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய, வடமேல் மற்றும் வடக்கு மாகாணங்களில் சில இடங்களில் 75 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான பலத்த மழை பெய்யக்கூடும்.",
        "ஊவா மற்றும் கிழக்கு மாகாணங்களில் பல இடங்களில் மாலை அல்லது இரவு நேரங்களில் இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை பெய்யும்.",
        "எனவே, இடியுடன் கூடிய மழையின் போது மழை மற்றும் மின்னலினால் ஏற்படும் பாதிப்புகளில் இருந்து தங்களை பாதுகாத்துக்கொள்ள போதுமான முன்னெச்சரிக்கை நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுக்குமாறு பொதுமக்கள் அறிவுறுத்தப்படுகிறார்கள். (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நான்கு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "தெதுரு ஓயா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.பி.சி. சுகீஷ்வரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,400 கன மீட்டர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பனடுகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நில்வாலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜின் ஆற்றின் பத்தேகம",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கலவெல்லவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "களு கங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kelani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "அளவியல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாயங்காலம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}