{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/26/conditional-presidential-pardon-for-ranjan-ramanayake-says-pmd/",
  "time_ut": 1661495760,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Conditional Presidential Pardon for Ranjan Ramanayake, says PMD",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Conditional Presidential Pardon for Ranjan Ramanayake, says PMD",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): A statement from the President's Media Division on Friday (26) noted that Former MP Ranjan Ramanayake will be granted conditional Presidential Pardon.",
        "The statement noted that President Ranil Wickremesinghe had signed the Presidential Pardon document on Friday (26).",
        "It also noted that the Pardon will be subject to the conditions that Ranjan Ramanayake no long make any statement that is in contempt of court, and does not act in such a manner.",
        "The President's Media Division said that the Justice Secretary was vested with the task of proceeding with the necessary action required for Ranjan Ramanayake's release.",
        "Secretary to the President Saman Ekanayake on Friday (26) confirmed that he signed the documents for the release of imprisoned MP Ranjan Ramanayake, with permission from President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "On Thursday (25) Sri Lankan Minister Harin Fernando tweeted that imprisoned Former MP Ranjan Ramanayake would most likely be released from jail on Friday (26) or on Monday (29).",
        "Ranjan Ramanayake who is serving time for contempt of court apologized to the court via an affidavit on Thursday (25).",
        "The affidavit produced to the court on Thursday (25) notes that Ranjan Ramanayake apologizes to the court with regard to both contempt of court cases filed against him.",
        "On the 12th of January 2021, Ranjan Ramanayake was sentenced to jail for contempt of court.",
        "Ramanayake was sentenced to four years Rigorous Imprisonment by the Supreme Court of Sri Lanka.",
        "Ranjan Ramanayake was accused of Contempt of Court for making a statement on Judges and Lawyers at a media briefing close to Temple Trees on the 21st of August 2017. Following a trial the Supreme Court of Sri Lanka sentenced him to 04 years of rigorous imprisonment.",
        "In January 2020, Ramanayake was arrested for committing a crime in terms of Article 111C (2) of the Constitution by interfering with the functions of judges. He was later granted bail, following the conclusion of the trial, he was sentenced.",
        "On the 7th of April 2021, Sri Lankan Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardene informed Parliament that the Parliamentary seat of Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) MP Ranjan Ramanayake has been declared vacant.",
        "He said the Parliament Secretary General has informed the Elections Commission that MP Ranjan Ramanayake ceases to be an MP as per Parliamentary Act."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Conditional Presidential Pardon for Ranjan Ramanayake",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "PMD",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pardon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saman Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25) Sri Lankan",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 12th of January 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Contempt of Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Judges and Lawyers",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 21st of August 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "04 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "January 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 111C (2",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 7th of April 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Elections Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "per Parliamentary Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රන්ජන් රාමනායකට ජනාධිපති සමාව කොන්දේසි සහිත බව අගමැති කියයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතාට කොන්දේසි සහිත ජනාධිපති සමාව හිමිවන බව ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය සිකුරාදා (26) නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "සිකුරාදා (26) ජනාධිපති සමාව ලබා දීමේ ලේඛනයට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අත්සන් තබා ඇති බව එම නිවේදනයේ දැක්වේ.",
        "අධිකරණයට අපහාස වන ආකාරයේ කිසිදු ප්‍රකාශයක් රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා විසින් දීර්ඝ කාලයක් සිදු නොකිරීමට සහ එලෙස ක්‍රියා නොකිරීමේ කොන්දේසිවලට යටත්ව මෙම සමාව හිමිවන බවද එහි සඳහන් කර ඇත.",
        "ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය පැවසුවේ, රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා නිදහස් කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාමේ වගකීම අධිකරණ ලේකම්වරයාට පැවරී ඇති බවයි.",
        "සිරගත කර සිටින පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක නිදහස් කර ගැනීමේ ලිපි ලේඛනවලට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ අවසරය මත තමා අත්සන් කළ බව ජනාධිපති ලේකම් සමන් ඒකනායක සිකුරාදා (26) තහවුරු කළේය.",
        "සිරගතව සිටින හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක බොහෝ විට සිකුරාදා (26) හෝ සඳුදා (29) බන්ධනාගාරයෙන් නිදහස් වනු ඇතැයි ශ්‍රී ලංකා අමාත්‍ය හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (25) ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කළේය.",
        "අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමේ චෝදනාව මත බන්ධනාගාර ගතව සිටින රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා දිවුරුම් ප්‍රකාශයක් මගින් බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (25) අධිකරණයෙන් සමාව අයැද සිටියේය.",
        "තමාට එරෙහිව පවරා ඇති අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමේ නඩු දෙකම සම්බන්ධයෙන් රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා අධිකරණයෙන් සමාව ඉල්ලා සිටින බව බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (25) අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කළ දිවුරුම් ප්‍රකාශයේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "2021 ජනවාරි 12 වැනිදා රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමේ චෝදනාවට සිර දඬුවම් නියම විය.",
        "රාමනායක මහතාට ශ්‍රී ලංකා ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය විසින් වසර හතරක බරපතළ සිර දඬුවමක් නියම කළේය.",
        "2017 අගෝස්තු 21 වැනිදා අරලියගහ මන්දිරයට ආසන්නයේ පැවැති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී විනිසුරුවරුන් සහ නීතිඥවරුන් සම්බන්ධයෙන් කළ ප්‍රකාශයක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් අධිකරණයට අපහාස කළ බවට රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතාට චෝදනා එල්ල විය. නඩු විභාගයකින් අනතුරුව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය ඔහුට වසර 04ක බරපතළ වැඩ සහිත සිර දඬුවමක් නියම කළේය.",
        "2020 ජනවාරි මාසයේදී රාමනායක මහතා ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 111 සී (2) වගන්තිය ප්‍රකාරව විනිසුරුවරුන්ගේ කාර්යයන්ට බාධා කරමින් අපරාධයක් සිදු කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා ලදී. පසුව ඔහුට ඇප නියම වූ අතර, නඩු විභාගය අවසන් වීමෙන් පසු ඔහුට දඬුවම් නියම විය.",
        "සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ (SJB) පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතාගේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධුරය පුරප්පාඩු වී ඇති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා 2021 අප්‍රේල් 7 වන දින පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට දැනුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු පනතට අනුව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක මන්ත්‍රී ධූරයෙන් ඉවත් වන බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම්වරයා මැතිවරණ කොමිසමට දැනුම් දී ඇති බව ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායකට කොන්දේසි සහිත ජනාධිපති සමාව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "පීඑම්ඩී",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමාවෙන්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායකගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමන් ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25) ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021 ජනවාරි 12 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණයට අපහාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විනිසුරුවන් සහ නීතිඥයින්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017 අගෝස්තු 21 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 04 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020 ජනවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වගන්තිය 111C (2",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021 අප්‍රේල් 7 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැතිවරණ කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු පනත අනුව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி நிபந்தனையுடன் மன்னிப்பு வழங்க வேண்டும் என பிரதமர் மோடி தெரிவித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு நிபந்தனையுடன் கூடிய ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு வழங்கப்படவுள்ளதாக ஜனாதிபதி ஊடகப் பிரிவு வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (26) விடுத்துள்ள அறிக்கையில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் மன்னிப்பு ஆவணத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (26) கையொப்பமிட்டதாக அந்த அறிக்கையில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதிக்கும் வகையிலான எந்தவொரு அறிக்கையையும் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க நீண்ட காலமாக வெளியிடக்கூடாது என்ற நிபந்தனைகளுக்கு உட்பட்டு இந்த மன்னிப்பு வழங்கப்படும் என்றும் அதில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவின் விடுதலைக்கு தேவையான நடவடிக்கைகளை முன்னெடுக்கும் பொறுப்பு நீதித்துறை செயலாளரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக ஜனாதிபதி ஊடகப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் அனுமதியுடன், சிறையில் உள்ள பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவின் விடுதலைக்கான ஆவணங்களில் தாம் கையொப்பமிட்டதாக ஜனாதிபதியின் செயலாளர் சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (26) உறுதிப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "சிறையில் இருக்கும் முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (26) அல்லது திங்கட்கிழமை (29) சிறையில் இருந்து விடுவிக்கப்படுவார் என்று வியாழன் (25) இலங்கை அமைச்சர் ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ ட்வீட் செய்திருந்தார்.",
        "நீதிமன்ற அவமதிப்பு வழக்கில் தண்டனை அனுபவித்து வரும் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க, வியாழன் (25) வாக்குமூலம் மூலம் நீதிமன்றத்தில் மன்னிப்புக் கோரினார்.",
        "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க தமக்கு எதிராக தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட இரண்டு நீதிமன்ற அவமதிப்பு வழக்குகள் தொடர்பாக நீதிமன்றில் மன்னிப்பு கோருவதாக வியாழக்கிழமை (25) நீதிமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்ட வாக்குமூலத்தில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "2021 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜனவரி மாதம் 12 ஆம் திகதி, நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதித்த குற்றத்திற்காக ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு சிறைத்தண்டனை விதிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு இலங்கை உச்ச நீதிமன்றம் நான்கு ஆண்டுகள் கடுங்காவல் தண்டனை விதித்தது.",
        "2017ஆம் ஆண்டு ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் 21ஆம் திகதி அலரிமாளிகைக்கு அண்மையில் நடைபெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் நீதிபதிகள் மற்றும் சட்டத்தரணிகள் தொடர்பில் கருத்து வெளியிட்டதற்காக நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதித்ததாக ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க மீது குற்றம் சுமத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "ஜனவரி 2020 இல், நீதிபதிகளின் செயல்பாடுகளில் தலையிடுவதன் மூலம் அரசியலமைப்பின் 111 சி (2) பிரிவுகளின்படி குற்றம் செய்ததற்காக ராமநாயக்க கைது செய்யப்பட்டார். பின்னர் அவருக்கு ஜாமீன் வழங்கப்பட்ட நிலையில், வழக்கு விசாரணை முடிவடைந்ததை தொடர்ந்து அவருக்கு தண்டனை விதிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "2021 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஏப்ரல் மாதம் 7 ஆம் திகதி, இலங்கை சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன, சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவின் பாராளுமன்ற ஆசனம் வெற்றிடமாக இருப்பதாக அறிவிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற சட்டத்தின் பிரகாரம் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க எம்பி பதவியில் இருந்து விலகுவதாக பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் தேர்தல்கள் ஆணைக்குழுவிற்கு அறிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி நிபந்தனையுடன் மன்னிப்பு",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "பிஎம்டி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மன்னிக்கவும்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25) இலங்கை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 12, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு வருடங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதிமன்ற அவமதிப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதிபதிகள் மற்றும் வழக்கறிஞர்கள்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 21, 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "04 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிவு 111C (2",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 7, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேர்தல் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற சட்டத்தின்படி",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}