{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/සබරගමුව-සහ-මධ්‍යම-පළාත්වලට-මහ-වැසි/101-616843",
  "time_ut": 1658460467,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "සබරගමුව සහ මධ්‍යම පළාත්වලට මහ වැසි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Heavy rains in Sabaragamuwa and Central Provinces",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Department of Meteorology says that there will be occasional rain or thundershowers in Sabaragamuwa and Central Provinces today (22).",
        "A spokesman of the department said that there will be several periods of rain in the Western and North-Western provinces.",
        "The spokesman said that scattered rain or thundershowers will occur in other areas in the evening or during the night.",
        "The spokesperson said that in some places in Sabaragamuwa, Central, Eastern, North Central and Uva provinces, more than 75 mm of heavy rain will occur.",
        "The department also states that thunderstorms may be accompanied by lightning and temporary gusty winds."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sabaragamuwa and Central Provinces",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "North-Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa, Central",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eastern",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "North Central",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සබරගමුව සහ මධ්‍යම පළාත්වලට මහ වැසි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "සබරගමුව සහ මධ්‍යම පළාත්වල අද (22) විටින් විට වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇතිවන බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "බස්නාහිර සහ වයඹ පළාත්වල ද වැසි වාර කිහිපයක් ඇතිවන බව එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "සෙසු ප්‍රදේශවල සවස් කාලයේ දී හෝ රාත්‍රී කාලයේදී තැනින් තැන වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇතිවන බව එම ප්‍රකාශකයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම, නැගෙනහිර, උතුරුමැද සහ ඌව පළාත්වල ඇතැම් ස්ථානයන්හි මිලිමීටර 75 ට වැඩි තරමක තද වැසි ඇතිවන බව එම ප්‍රකාශකයා පැවසීය.",
        "ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි සමඟ අකුණු අනතුරු සහ තාවකාලික තද සුළං ඇතිවිය හැකි බව ද එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සඳහන් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සබරගමුව සහ මධ්‍යම පළාත්වල",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු මැද",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சப்ரகமுவ மற்றும் மத்திய மாகாணங்களில் பலத்த மழை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சப்ரகமுவ மற்றும் மத்திய மாகாணங்களில் இன்று (22) அவ்வப்போது மழை அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை பெய்யும் என வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மேல் மற்றும் வடமேல் மாகாணங்களில் பல தடவைகள் மழை பெய்யும் என திணைக்களத்தின் பேச்சாளர் ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஏனைய பிரதேசங்களில் மாலை அல்லது இரவு வேளைகளில் மழையோ அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழையோ பெய்யும் என பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய, கிழக்கு, வடமத்திய மற்றும் ஊவா மாகாணங்களில் சில இடங்களில் 75 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான பலத்த மழை பெய்யக்கூடும் என பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இடியுடன் கூடிய மழையுடன் மின்னலுடன் தற்காலிகமாக பலத்த காற்றும் வீசக்கூடும் எனவும் திணைக்களம் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சப்ரகமுவ மற்றும் மத்திய மாகாணங்கள்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடமேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட மத்திய",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}