{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132191",
  "time_ut": 1658723047,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "கறுப்பு ஜூலை நினைவுநாள் காலிமுகத்திடலில் அனுஷ்டிப்பு ! தமிழ் மக்களின் படுகொலையை ஆற்றுகை மூலம் வெளிப்படுத்திய கலைஞர் !",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Celebrating Black July Memorial Day in Khalimagut! The artist who revealed the massacre of Tamil people through the music!",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "The 39th anniversary of the Black July riots against the Tamil people was observed.",
        "On July 23, 1983, ethnic riots against the Tamil people were unleashed in Sri Lanka.",
        "During this, thousands of Tamil people from Colombo and other areas were looted, destroyed and driven northwards as refugees.",
        "In July 1983, JR. An event to remember the Tamil people who were massacred by thugs with the support of the Jayawardene government was held in Kalimugathidal area yesterday.",
        "Thus commemoration events were conducted in various places on the occasion of the 39th anniversary of Black July when the genocide against Tamils ​​was unleashed.",
        "In this case, artist Prabhutha Dhanushka had staged a river in Kalimugathidal to symbolize the brutal massacre of Tamil people in July 1983.",
        "It was staged in a heart-melting manner as a painful work of art by artist Prabhutha Dhanushka in memory of the massacred Tamil people.",
        "Meanwhile, a commemoration of the Tamil people who were massacred by government-backed Quails in July 1983 was held yesterday at the Boralai Cemetery in Colombo. It is noteworthy that the event was organized by the North-East-South-Malayalam-Diaspora Brotherhood."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Black July Memorial Day",
          "label": "EVENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "Khalimagut",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tamil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "39th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Black July",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 23, 1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "JR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayawardene",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalimugathidal",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "39th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Black July",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prabhutha Dhanushka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalimugathidal",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prabhutha Dhanushka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Boralai Cemetery in Colombo",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "North-East-South-Malayalam-Diaspora Brotherhood",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කලිමගුට් හි කළු ජූලි අනුස්මරණ දිනය සමරමින්! දෙමළ ජන සංහාරය සංගීතයෙන් හෙළිකළ කලාකරුවා!",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "දෙමළ ජනතාවට එරෙහි කළු ජූලි කෝලාහලයේ 39 වැනි සංවත්සරය පැවැත්විණි.",
        "1983 ජුලි 23 වැනිදා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ දෙමළ ජනතාවට එරෙහිව වාර්ගික කෝලාහල දියත් විය.",
        "මේ කාලය තුළ කොළඹ සහ අනෙකුත් ප්‍රදේශවල දෙමළ ජනතාව දහස් ගණනක් කොල්ලකෑම්, විනාශ කර සරණාගතයන් ලෙස උතුරු දෙසට පලවා හරින ලදී.",
        "1983 ජූලි මාසයේදී ජේ.ආර්. ජයවර්ධන රජයේ අනුග්‍රහය ඇතිව මැරයන් විසින් සමූල ඝාතනය කළ දෙමළ ජනතාව සිහිපත් කිරීමේ උත්සවයක් ඊයේ කලිමුගතිඩාල් ප්‍රදේශයේදී පැවැත්වුණා.",
        "දෙමළ ජනතාවට එරෙහි ජන සංහාරය මුදාහරින ලද කළු ජූලියේ 39 වැනි සංවත්සරය නිමිත්තෙන් විවිධ ස්ථානවල සමරු උත්සව පැවැත්විණි.",
        "මෙම නඩුවේදී ප්‍රභූත ධනුෂ්ක කලාකරුවා 1983 ජුලි මස සිදුවූ දෙමළ ජනයාගේ ම්ලේච්ඡ සංහාරය සංකේතවත් කිරීම සඳහා කලිමුගතිඩාල් ප්‍රදේශයේ ගංගාවක් වේදිකාගත කර තිබුණි.",
        "සමූල ඝාතනයට ලක්වූ දෙමළ ජනතාව සිහිකරමින් ප්‍රභූත ධනුෂ්ක කලාකරුවාගේ වේදනාත්මක කලා කෘතියක් ලෙස එය හදවත උණුවන අයුරින් වේදිකාගත විය.",
        "මේ අතර, 1983 ජුලි මස රජයේ ආධාර ලබන වටුවන් විසින් සමූල ඝාතනය කරන ලද දෙමළ ජනතාව සැමරීමේ උත්සවයක් ඊයේ කොළඹ බොරලෙයි කනත්තේදී පැවැත්විණි. උතුරු - නැගෙනහිර - දකුණු - මලයාලම් - ඩයස්පෝරා සහෝදරත්වය විසින් මෙම උත්සවය සංවිධානය කර තිබීම විශේෂත්වයකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කළු ජූලිය අනුස්මරණ දිනය",
          "label": "EVENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "කලිමගුට්",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "දෙමළ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "39 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළු ජූලිය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 23, 1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1983 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජේ.ආර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කලිමුගතිඩාල්",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "39 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළු ජූලිය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රභූත ධනුෂ්ක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කලිමුගතිඩාල්",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1983 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රභූත ධනුෂ්ක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1983 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ බොරලෙයි කනත්ත",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු-නැගෙනහිර-දකුණු-මලයාලම්-ඩයස්පෝරා සහෝදරත්වය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கறுப்பு ஜூலை நினைவுநாள் காலிமுகத்திடலில் அனுஷ்டிப்பு ! தமிழ் மக்களின் படுகொலையை ஆற்றுகை மூலம் வெளிப்படுத்திய கலைஞர் !",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "தமிழ் மக்களுக்கு எதிராக நிகழ்த்தப்பட்ட கறுப்பு ஜூலை இனக்கலவரங்களின் 39 ஆவது நினைவு நாள் அனுஷ்டிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "1983 ஆம் ஆண்டு , ஜூலை 23 ஆம் திகதி நாடு முழுவதும் தமிழ் மக்களுக்கு எதிரான இனக்கலவரம் இலங்கையில் கட்டவிழ்த்து விடப்பட்டது.",
        "இதன்போது கொழும்பிலும், ஏனைய பகுதிகளிலும் இருந்து ஆயிரக்கணக்கான தமிழ் மக்களின் சொத்துக்கள் சூறையாடப்பட்டும், அழிக்கப்பட்டும், வடக்கு நோக்கி அகதிகளாகவும் விரட்டியடிக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "1983ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜூலை மாதம் ஜே.ஆர். ஜெயவர்தன அரசாங்கத்தின் ஆதரவுடன்  குண்டர்களால் படுகொலை செய்யப்பட்ட தமிழ் மக்களை நினைவுகூரும் நிகழ்வு நேற்றையதினம் காலிமுகத்திடல் பகுதியில் இடம்பெற்றது.",
        "இவ்வாறு, தமிழருக்கு எதிரான இனஅழிப்பு கட்டவிழ்த்து விடப்பட்ட கறுப்பு ஜூலையின் 39 ஆவது நினைவு தினத்தினை முன்னிட்டு பல்வேறு, இடங்களிலும் நினைவேந்தல் நிகழ்வுகள் முன்னெடுக்கப்பட்டன.",
        "இந்நிலையில், 1983 ஜூலையில் கொடூரமாக தமிழ் மக்கள் படுகொலை செய்யப்பட்டமையை அடையாளப்படுத்தும் வகையில் கலைஞர் பிரபுத்த தனுஷ்க காலிமுகத்திடலில் ஆற்றுகையொன்றை அரங்கேற்றியிருந்தார்.",
        "படுகொலை செய்யப்பட்ட தமிழ் மக்களை நினைவுகூர்ந்து கலைஞர் பிரபுத்த தனுஷ்க என்பவரால் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட வலிமிகுந்த கலைப்படைப்பாக மனதை உருக்கும் விதத்தில் அரங்கேற்றியிருந்தார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, 1983 ஜூலை மாதம் அரசாங்கத்தின் ஆதரவுடன் காடையர்களால் படுகொலை செய்யப்பட்ட தமிழ் மக்களை நினைவுகூரும் நிகழ்வு நேற்றையதினம் கொழும்பு பொரளை மயானமருகில் இடம்பெற்றது. வடக்கு-கிழக்கு-தெற்கு-மலையகம்-புலம்பெயர் சகோதரத்துவம் இந்த நிகழ்வை ஏற்பாடு செய்திருந்தமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கருப்பு ஜூலை நினைவு தினம்",
          "label": "EVENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "காலிமகட்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "தமிழ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "39வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருப்பு ஜூலை",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 23, 1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.ஆர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயவர்த்தனே",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கலிமுகத்திடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "39வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருப்பு ஜூலை",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரபுதா தனுஷ்கா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கலிமுகத்திடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரபுதா தனுஷ்கா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு பொரளை மயானம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு - கிழக்கு - தெற்கு - மலையாளம் - புலம்பெயர் சகோதரத்துவம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}