{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/பதவி-விலக-நான்-தயார்-ரணில்/175-300066",
  "time_ut": 1657370385,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "பதவி விலக நான் தயார்: ரணில்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "I am ready to resign: Ranil",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe has announced that he is ready to resign after securing a majority in Parliament and forming an all-party government.",
        "The Prime Minister's Media Unit informed that the matter was announced in the conference of party leaders held under the chairmanship of the Speaker.",
        "Prime Minister Ranil has said that this decision has been taken because of the resumption of fuel supply nationwide this week, the World Food Program Director visiting the country this week, and the debt sustainability report for the International Monetary Fund."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Media Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Food Program",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මම ඉල්ලා අස්වෙන්න සූදානම් :රනිල්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ බහුතර බලය තහවුරු කරගෙන සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමෙන් පසු තමන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට සූදානම් බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "කථානායකවරයාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් පැවති පක්ෂ නායක සමුළුවේදී මේ බව ප්‍රකාශ කළ බවයි අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මාධ්‍ය අංශය දැනුම් දුන්නේ.",
        "මේ සතියේ රට පුරා ඉන්ධන සැපයීම නැවත ආරම්භ කිරීමත්, ලෝක ආහාර වැඩසටහන් අධ්‍යක්ෂවරයා මේ සතියේ දිවයිනට පැමිණීමත්, ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ණය තිරසාර වාර්තාවත් නිසා මෙම තීරණය ගත් බව අගමැති රනිල් පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාධ්‍ය ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක ආහාර වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பதவி விலக நான் தயார்: ரணில்",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பெரும்பான்மையை நிரூபித்து சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைத்த பின்னர், தனது பதவியை இராஜினாமா செய்யத் தயார் என்று பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "சபாநாயகர் தலைமையில் நடைபெற்ற கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் மாநாட்டில் இவ்விடயம் அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பிரதமர் ஊடகப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் எரிபொருள் விநியோகம் இந்த வாரம் மீள ஆரம்பிக்கப்படவுள்ளதாலும், உலக உணவுத் திட்டப் பணிப்பாளர் இந்த வாரம் நாட்டுக்கு வருகை தரவுள்ளதாலும், சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துக்கான கடன் நிலைத்தன்மை அறிக்கை காரணமாகவும் இந்த முடிவை எடுத்துள்ளதாக பிரதமர் ரணில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக உணவு திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}