{
  "newspaper_id": "b-b-c-com-sinhala",
  "url": "https://www.bbc.com/sinhala/sri-lanka-62062640",
  "time_ut": 1657079641,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "\"යුද්ධේ කරපු මහලොකු විරුවට එන්න කියපන් එළියට!\" - හිරුණිකා ගෝටාභයට අභියෝග කරයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "\"Tell the great hero of the war to come out!\" - Hirunika challenges Gotabha",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Police arrested nine people, including Hirunika Premachandra, a former member of Parliament of Samagi Jana Balavega, who held a protest in front of the President's official residence in Fort Colombo today (July 6).",
        "These people who were arrested by the Fort Police have now been taken to the Harbor Police. Among the arrested people are Rehan Jayawickrama, the vice president of the youth organization of the Samagi Jana Balavegaye, the secretary and the vice president of the Samagi Jana Balavegaya. The majority of those arrested are women.",
        "The group had gathered in front of the President's Palace to protest against the hardships the people have had to suffer due to the ongoing economic crisis.",
        "Former MP Premachandra challenged the President to come out of the mansion and meet her.",
        "\"Tell the country that ate the country, the country that deprived the children of food and drink, the people of the country who go to the parliament and laugh loudly even when they are dying in the highway queues!\" She said this in front of the officials at the President's House.",
        "\"Tell the great hero of the war to come out!\" In the videos, Hirunika Premachandra is seen voicing.",
        "\"Now tell Gotabhaya Rajapaksa to come. Hirunika has come with three or four women... I could not find even one of you until I came here, great intelligence,\" Premachandra shouted in front of the President's House.",
        "Former councilor Premachandra took the lead in protesting in front of President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa's Mirihana residence.",
        "When she went to Fort area recently, social activists alleged that the police put up roadblocks and blocked the public road.",
        "At that time, the former councilor said that she did not come to see the President but to go to a bank, and also stated that the President is afraid of some women.",
        "The group including Hirunika Premachandra had previously protested at President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa's Mirihana residence as well as near the house of the woman known as 'Gnana Akka' who runs a temple in Anuradhapura.",
        "There, the security forces including the police prevented the protesters from entering the house. In the video released by Rehan Jayawickrama on social media, it was seen that the police officers took possession of Premachandra's phone despite the protest of the people when the protesters were arrested in front of the Presidential Palace.",
        "\"Gentlemen, think about whether there is anything to eat or drink at home, we are being picked up by stray dogs.\" Someone who was among the arrested said.",
        "When the bus left near the President's official residence, the crowd shouted at the police.",
        "Meanwhile, another protest organized by a group of MPs of Samagi Janabalawega had come from Aluthkade to Chatham Street and when the police tried to move forward by breaking the roadblocks, the police fired tear gas and water cannons to disperse the protest.",
        "In a video released by Rehan Jayawickrama to social media from the police station, Sajith Premadasa, the leader of the Samagi Jana Balavega, was seen at the police station, but the video has now been removed."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hirunika Premachandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balavega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fort Colombo",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 6",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Fort Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Harbor Police",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rehan Jayawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Samagi Jana Balavegaye",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Samagi Jana Balavegaya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the President's Palace",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premachandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hirunika Premachandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three or four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premachandra",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mirihana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fort",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hirunika Premachandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mirihana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rehan Jayawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premachandra",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Palace",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi Janabalawega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aluthkade",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chatham Street",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rehan Jayawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Samagi Jana Balavega",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "\"යුද්ධේ කරපු මහලොකු විරුවට එන්න කියපන් එළියට!\" - හිරුණිකා ගෝටාභයට අභියෝග කරයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොළඹ , කොටුව ජනපති නිල නිවෙස ඉදිරිපිට අද (ජූලි 6) විරෝධතාවක් පැවැත්වූ සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රිනී හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර ඇතුලු නව දෙනෙකු පොලීසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගනු ලැබීය.",
        "කොටුව පොලීසිය අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් මෙම පිරිස මේ වන විට වරාය පොලීසියට ගෙනගොස් ඇත.අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් පිරිස අතර සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ තරුණ සංවිධානයේ උප සභාපති රෙහාන් ජයවික්‍රම, සමගි කාන්තා බලවේගයේ ලේකම්වරිය, උපසභාපතිනිය ද සිටිති. අත්අඩංගුවට පත්වූ බහුතරය කාන්තාවන්ය.",
        "පිරිස ජනාධිපති මන්ධිරය ඉදිරියට රැස්ව තිබුණේ පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හමුවේ ජනතාවට විඳවීමට සිදුව ඇති දුෂ්කරතාවන්ට එරෙහි විරෝධය පෑමට ය.",
        "මන්දිරයෙන් පිටතට පැමිණ තමා හමුවට එන්නැයි හිටපු මන්ත්‍රිනී ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර ජනපතිට අභියෝග කළාය.",
        "\"රට කාපු පරයට, ළමයින්ට කන්න බොන්න නැතිකරපු පරයට, රටේ මිනිස්සුන්ට මහපාරේ පෝලිම්වල මැරිලා ඇදවැටෙනකොටත් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ගිහින් බක බක ගගා හිනාවෙලා ඉන්න පරයට එන්න කියපන්!\" ඇය ජනපති මන්දිර භූමියේ සිටි නිලධාරීන් හමුවේ පවසා සිටියා ය.",
        "\"යුද්දේ කරපු මහලොකු විරුවට එන්න කියපන් එළියට!\" හිරුණීකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර හඬ නඟන අයුරු වීඩියෝවල දක්නට ලැබේ.",
        "\"දැන් කියපන් ගෝටාභය රාජපක්ෂට එන්න කියලා. හිරුණිකා ඇවිල්ලා ඉන්නවා ගෑණු තුන් හතරදෙනෙක් එක්ක... උඹලා එකෙක්ටවත් හොයාගන්න බැරිවුණා මං මෙතෙන්ට එනකල්, මහලොකු බුද්ධි අංශ,\" ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර ජනපති මන්දිරය ඉදිරියේ දී කෑගසා පැවසූවා ය.",
        "ජනපති ගෝටාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ මිරිහාන නිවාස ඉදිරියේ ද උද්ඝෝෂණ කිරීමට පෙරමුණ ගත්තේ හිටපු මන්ත්‍රිනී ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර ය.",
        "ඇය පසුගිය දා කොටුව ප්‍රදේශයට ගිය අවස්ථාවක ද පොලීසිය මාර්ග බාධක දමා පොදු මාර්ගය අවහිර කරනු ලැබූ බවට සමාජ ක්‍රියාකාරීන් චෝදනා නැගීය.",
        "ඒ අවස්ථාවේ දී තමා පැමිණියේ ජනපති හමුවට නොව බැංකුවක් වෙත යෑමට බව පැවසූ හිටපු මන්ත්‍රිනිය, ජනපති කාන්තාවන් කීපදෙනෙකුට බියව සිටින්නේ යැයි එහිදී ද ප්‍රකාශ කළා ය.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ මිරිහාන නිවසට මෙන්ම, අනුරාධපුරයේ දේවාලයක් පවත්වාගෙන යන 'ඤාණා අක්කා \"නමින් ප්‍රසිද්ධි කාන්තාවගේ නිවස අසලද හිරුණීකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර ඇතුලු පිරිස මීට පෙර විරෝධතා පැවත්වූහ.",
        "එහිදී ද පොලීසිය ඇතුලු ආරක්ෂක අංශ විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට නිවස දෙසට ඇතුලුවීම අවහර කළහ.අද දහවල් ජනාධීපති මන්ධිරය ඉදිරිපිට විරෝධතාකරුවන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් අවස්ථාවේ දී පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් විසින්, පිරිසගේ විරෝධය නොතකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍රගේ දුරකථනය තම සන්තකයට ගැනීමට කටයුතු කළ අයුරු රෙහාන් ජයවික්‍රම සමාජ මාධ්‍ය වෙත නිකුත්කළ වීඩියෝවල දක්නට තිබේ.",
        "\"මහත්තයෝ කල්පනා කරලා බලන්න ගෙදර කන්න බොන්න තියෙනවා ද කියලා, අපිව උස්සන් එන්නේ පර බල්ලොයි කියලා.\" අත්අඩංගුවට පත් පිරිස අතර සිටි අයෙකු ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ය.",
        "බස් රථය ජනපති නිල නිවෙස අසලින් පිටත්වන අවස්ථාවේ දී පිරිස පොලීසිය දෙසට හූ තැබීය.",
        "මේ අතර සමගි ජනබලවේගයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පිරිසක් විසින් සංවිධානය කරනු ලැබූ තවත් විරෝධතාවයක් අලුත්කඩේ සිට චැතම් වීදිය දක්වා පැමිණ තිබූ අතර පොලිස් මාර්ග බාධක බිඳ දමමින් ඉදිරියට ගමන් කිරීමට උත්සාහ කිරීමත් සමග එම විරෝධතාවය විසුරුවා හැරීම සඳහා පොලීසිය කදුළු ගෑස් සහ ජල ප්‍රහාර එල්ල කර තිබේ.",
        "පොලිස් ස්ථානයේ සිට රෙහාන් ජයවික්‍රම සමාජ මාධ්‍ය වෙත නිකුත්කළ වීඩියෝවක සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස පොලිස් ස්ථානයට පැමිණ සිටින අයුරු දැක්වුණ ද, මේ වන විට එම වීඩියෝව ඉවත්කොට තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 6",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොටුව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වරාය පොලිසිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෙහාන් ජයවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුනක් හෝ හතරක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිරිහාන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බලකොටුව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිරිහාන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රෙහාන් ජයවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජනබලවේග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලුත්කඩේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චැතම් වීදිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රෙහාන් ජයවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"போர் வீரனை வெளியே வரச் சொல்!\" - கோத்தபாவுக்கு ஹிருணிகா சவால்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இன்று (ஜூலை 6) கொழும்பு கோட்டையில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதியின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லத்திற்கு முன்பாக ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்ட சமகி ஜன பலவேகவின் முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர உட்பட 9 பேரை பொலிஸார் கைது செய்துள்ளனர்.",
        "கோட்டை பொலிஸாரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட இவர்கள் தற்போது துறைமுக பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர்களில் சமகி ஜன பலவேகயேயின் இளைஞர் அமைப்பின் உபதலைவர் ரெஹான் ஜெயவிக்ரம, செயலாளரும், சமகி ஜன பலவேகயேயின் உபதலைவருமான ரெஹான் ஜயவிக்ரம ஆகியோர் அடங்குவர். . கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர்களில் பெரும்பாலானோர் பெண்கள்.",
        "தற்போது நிலவும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி காரணமாக மக்கள் படும் இன்னல்களுக்கு எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவிக்கும் வகையில் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்கு முன்பாக குழு ஒன்று கூடியிருந்தது.",
        "முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பிரேமச்சந்திர, ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் இருந்து வெளியே வந்து தன்னை சந்திக்குமாறு சவால் விடுத்தார்.",
        "\"நாட்டைத் தின்ன தேசம், பிள்ளைகளுக்கு உணவும், பானமும் கிடைக்காமல் தவித்த நாடு, நெடுஞ்சாலையில் கியூவில் செத்து மடியும் போதும் நாடாளுமன்றம் சென்று சத்தமாகச் சிரிக்கும் நாட்டு மக்களைச் சொல்லுங்கள்!\" ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் அதிகாரிகள் முன்னிலையில் அவர் இதனைத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"போர் வீரனை வெளியே வரச் சொல்!\" வீடியோக்களில், ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர குரல் கொடுப்பதைக் காணலாம்.",
        "\"இப்போது கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்சவை வரச் சொல்லுங்கள். ஹிருணிகா மூன்று நான்கு பெண்களுடன் வந்திருக்கிறார்... நான் இங்கு வரும் வரை உங்களுள் ஒருவரைக் கூட கண்டுபிடிக்க முடியவில்லை, பெரிய புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினர்\" என்று பிரேமச்சந்திர ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்கு முன்பாக கத்தினார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் மிரிஹான இல்லத்திற்கு முன்னால் முன்னாள் சபை உறுப்பினர் பிரேமச்சந்திர தலைமையில் ஆர்ப்பாட்டம் முன்னெடுக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "சமீபத்தில் அவர் கோட்டை பகுதிக்கு சென்றபோது, ​​போலீசார் சாலை மறியல் செய்து பொதுமக்கள் சாலையை மறித்ததாக சமூக ஆர்வலர்கள் குற்றம் சாட்டினர்.",
        "அப்போது முன்னாள் கவுன்சிலர், தான் ஜனாதிபதியை பார்க்க வரவில்லை, வங்கிக்கு செல்ல வந்ததாக கூறியதுடன், சில பெண்களுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி பயப்படுவதாகவும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர உள்ளிட்ட குழுவினர் இதற்கு முன்னர் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் மிரிஹான இல்லத்திலும் அநுராதபுரத்தில் விகாரை நடத்தும் 'ஞான அக்கா' என்ற பெண்ணின் வீட்டிற்கு அருகிலும் ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டனர்.",
        "அங்கு போராட்டக்காரர்களை வீட்டுக்குள் நுழையவிடாமல் பொலிசார் உள்ளிட்ட பாதுகாப்புப் படையினர் தடுத்துள்ளனர்.போராட்டக்காரர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட போது மக்களின் எதிர்ப்பையும் மீறி பிரேமச்சந்திரவின் தொலைபேசியை பொலிஸ் உத்தியோகத்தர்கள் கைப்பற்றியமை சமூக வலைத்தளங்களில் ரெஹான் ஜெயவிக்ரம வெளியிட்ட காணொளியில் காணப்படுகின்றது. ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்கு முன்னால்.",
        "\"தந்தையர்களே, வீட்டில் சாப்பிட அல்லது குடிக்க ஏதாவது இருக்கிறதா என்று சிந்தியுங்கள், நாங்கள் தெருநாய்களால் தூக்கிச் செல்லப்படுகிறோம்.\" கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர்களில் ஒருவர் கூறினார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லத்திற்கு அருகில் பஸ் புறப்பட்டபோது, ​​மக்கள் பொலிஸாரை நோக்கி கூச்சலிட்டனர்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், சமகி ஜனபலவேக உறுப்பினர்கள் குழுவினால் ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்ட மற்றொரு போராட்டம் அளுத்கடையில் இருந்து சத்தம் தெருவுக்கு வந்துள்ளது, மேலும் போலீசார் சாலைத் தடைகளை உடைத்து முன்னேற முயன்றபோது, ​​​​போலீசார் போராட்டத்தை கலைக்க கண்ணீர் புகை மற்றும் தண்ணீர் பீரங்கிகளை வீசினர்.",
        "ரெஹான் ஜெயவிக்ரம பொலிஸ் நிலையத்தில் இருந்து சமூக ஊடகங்களுக்கு வெளியிட்ட காணொளியில், சமகி ஜன பலவேகவின் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச பொலிஸ் நிலையத்தில் காணப்பட்டதாகவும், ஆனால் அந்த காணொளி தற்போது நீக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 6",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறைமுக போலீஸ்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரெஹான் ஜெயவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமச்சந்திர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று அல்லது நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமச்சந்திர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிரிஹானா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிரிஹானா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரெஹான் ஜெயவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமச்சந்திர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜனபாலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அழுத்கடே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாத்தம் தெரு",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரெஹான் ஜெயவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}