{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132532",
  "time_ut": 1659194251,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "1983 ஜூலை இன வன்முறையில் மலையக மக்கள் முகம்கொடுத்த இன்னல்கள்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "1983 July communal violence and the hardships faced by the hill people",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "Left-wing activist Joe from the highlands at an event held in Kota Ko village to commemorate Black July in 1983. Jagan's speech on behalf of the mass organization for social justice and the ethnic violence faced by the highlanders after the independence of Sri Lanka, including Black July, is recorded here.",
        "It can be said that the Black July of 1983 is an indelible scar in the minds of the Tamil people living in Sri Lanka. However, till date not much attention has been paid to how the people of the hills were affected in this tragic incident. The July 1983 communal violence in the uplands must be seen in the context of the long history of the unique tragedies of the upland people.",
        "The people of the highlands have a history of coming from the southern districts of Tamil Nadu, India to Thalaimannar via Dhanushkodiut and alighting on foot from Mannar to Kandy Matala. Our mountain people are the people who have a history of coming on foot after clearing the forest path that they walked for hundreds of kilometers and risking their lives. It can be said that the hill people have been subjected to economic, exploitation and racial oppression since the British period till today.",
        "After the independence of Sri Lanka, the separate Sinhalese Act, the famine during Srimao Bandaranaike's era, the Srima-Sastri Agreement, the half of the highlanders who lived here went to India and the rest went to Sri Lanka, and the incidents of separating the lives of those living people like dividing the property were subjected to ethnic oppression by the Sri Lankan government.",
        "There are many heart-warming incidents recorded during the Srima-Sastri pact where the wife was separated and sent to India and the husband to Sri Lanka after a few days of marriage. Not only that, even during the famine of 1972, even though the livelihood of the people living in other areas of Sri Lanka was seen as their own land, the landless people of the highlands, who had no livelihood for themselves, lived in a very miserable life during this famine. When talking about the year 1972 in the highlands, people would say that during the famine, we ate maravalli kilang, and ten people shared two loaves of bread.",
        "After that in 1977 after JR Jayawardena assumed office, some Tamil villages in Ratnapura Kekalai were burnt by Sinhalese goons in the name of racism. During the tenure of JR Jayawardena, one of the most significant incidents of violence against the hill people was the burning of the delta plantation in Pussalla.",
        "Similarly, JR Jayawardena, who met the affected people in a lake garden in Ratnapura district, told JR Jayawardena that when the people were crying that their relatives were killed and their property was destroyed, the then President JR Jayawardena accused racism, \"We will give you a queen, we will give you rice, we will give you chicken, we will give you a cow, but only a separate country. It is said that he gave a sarcastic reply, \"We will not\".",
        "One of the prominent writers currently living in India records some true incidents in his life during the riots of 1977 as follows \"The riots started in Kandy at 7 pm in 1977. Knowing that communal riots had started in other parts of the country, the Sinhalese and Tamil activists living in Kandy filed a complaint at the Kandy Police Station. The police officer in charge at that time was a Tamil.",
        "However, he said that he could not do anything about it but would inform the higher up. However, no security was provided by the police. The communal riots started around 7 pm. At that time, the role of some Sinhalese comrades in the forefront in providing protection to the Tamil people living in Kandy was insignificant, especially many left-wing Sinhalese comrades like Jayaratna Mallikagoda were important\".",
        "During the time of JR Jayawardena, a practice of portraying the Malays as 'Indian expansionists' was developed to create a violent ideology against the Tamils ​​of the hills. A centralism was propagated that the hilly people were more in population and would pose a threat to Sri Lanka.",
        "As the riots of 1983 affected the Tamil people living in Colombo, the hilly Tamil people living among the Sinhalese like Ratnapuri Kekalai Padulai Matalai Nuwarelia also faced untold damage and loss of life and property. And the town of Nuwara Eliya was burnt down in a public riot.",
        "The main reason for this was the Minister of that day, Kamini Dissanayake, who said that 'Nuwaraeliya city was built by the British, and as some ancient things were found in it, we destroyed them and burnt them to build a new city'. The July 1983 violence in which two schools were burnt down in the public Badula Lunugalai area is also noteworthy.",
        "Thus, in the ethnic riots unleashed by the Sinhalese Buddhist government to destroy the existence and education of the mountain people in the mountainous areas after independence, the 1983 ethnic riots have been an indelibly dark incident in history."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "1983 July",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Joe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kota Ko",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Black July",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jagan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Black July",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Black July of 1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thalaimannar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy Matala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "hundreds of kilometers",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhalese Act",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Srimao Bandaranaike's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Srima-Sastri Agreement",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "half",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a few days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1972",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year 1972",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "maravalli kilang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ten",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "JR Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura Kekalai",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhalese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "JR Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pussalla",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "JR Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "JR Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "JR Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "7 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhalese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kandy Police Station",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "around 7 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhalese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayaratna Mallikagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "JR Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malays",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhalese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapuri Kekalai Padulai",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matalai Nuwarelia",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwara Eliya",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "that day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kamini Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Badula Lunugalai",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sinhalese Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "1983 ජූලි වාර්ගික ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය සහ කඳුකර ජනතාව මුහුණ දුන් දුෂ්කරතා",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "1983 කළු ජූලිය සැමරීම සඳහා කොට කෝ ගම්මානයේ පැවති උත්සවයකදී කඳුකරයේ වාම ක්‍රියාකාරිකයෙකු වූ ජෝ. කළු ජූලිය ඇතුළු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව නිදහස ලැබීමෙන් පසු උඩරට ජනතාව මුහුණ දුන් ජනවාර්ගික ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය සහ සමාජ සාධාරණත්වය සඳහා වූ බහුජන සංවිධානය වෙනුවෙන් ජගන් කළ කතාව මෙහි සටහන් වේ.",
        "1983 කළු ජූලිය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වෙසෙන දෙමළ ජනතාවගේ සිත්වල මැකිය නොහැකි කැළලක් බව කිව හැකිය. කෙසේ වෙතත් මෙම ඛේදනීය සිදුවීමෙන් කඳුකරයේ ජනතාව පීඩාවට පත් වූ ආකාරය පිළිබඳව අද වනතුරුත් වැඩි අවධානයක් යොමු වී නැහැ. 1983 ජූලි මස උඩරට ඇති වූ වාර්ගික ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය දැකිය යුත්තේ උඩරට ජනතාවගේ අනන්‍ය ඛේදවාචකයන්ගේ දීර්ඝ ඉතිහාසය තුළය.",
        "ඉන්දියාවේ තමිල්නාඩුවේ දකුණු දිස්ත්‍රික්කවල සිට ධනුෂ්කොඩියුට් හරහා තලෙයිමන්නාරමට පැමිණ මන්නාරමේ සිට මහනුවර මාතලට පා ගමනින් බැස ගිය ඉතිහාසයක් කඳුකරයේ ජනතාවට ඇත. ජීවිත පරදුවට තබා කිලෝමීටර් සිය ගණනක් පයින් ගමන් කළ කැලෑ මාවත එළිපෙහෙළි කර පා ගමනින් පැමිණි ඉතිහාසයක් ඇති ජනතාව අපේ කඳුකර ජනතාවයි. ඉංග්‍රීසි යුගයේ සිට අද දක්වාම කඳුකර ජනතාව ආර්ථික, සූරාකෑම, වාර්ගික පීඩනයට ලක් වූ බව කිව හැකිය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව නිදහස ලැබීමෙන් පසු වෙනම සිංහල පනත, ශ්‍රීමාඕ බණ්ඩාරනායක යුගයේ සාගතය, ශ්‍රීමා-ශාස්ත්‍රී ගිවිසුම, මෙහි ජීවත් වූ උස්බිම් වැසියන්ගෙන් අඩක් ඉන්දියාවට ගොස් ඉතිරි පිරිස ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ගොස් වෙන්වීමේ සිද්ධීන් දේපල බෙදීම වැනි ජීවමාන මිනිසුන්ගේ ජීවිත ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය විසින් වාර්ගික පීඩනයට ලක් කරන ලදී.",
        "විවාහ වී දින කිහිපයකින් බිරිඳ වෙන් කර ඉන්දියාවටත් සැමියා ලංකාවටත් යවන ලද ශ්‍රීමා ශාස්‌ත්‍රී ගිවිසුම තුළ හද කම්පා කරවන සිදුවීම් රැසක්‌ සටහන්ව ඇත. ඒ විතරක් නෙවෙයි 1972 සාගත කාලෙත් ලංකාවේ අනිත් ප්‍රදේශවල ජීවත්වෙන මිනිස්සුන්ගේ ජීවනෝපාය තමන්ගේ ඉඩමක් විදිහට දැක්කත්, තමන්ටම කියා ජීවනෝපායක් නැති කඳුකරයේ ඉඩම් නැති මිනිස්සු ජීවත් වුණේ බොහොම මේ සාගත කාලය තුළ දුක්ඛිත ජීවිතය. 1972 වසර ගැන උස්බිම්වල කතා කරන විට, සාගතයේ දී අපි මාරවල්ලි කිලං කෑවා, දස දෙනෙක් පාන් ගෙඩි දෙකක් බෙදා ගත් බව මිනිසුන් කියනු ඇත.",
        "ඉන් පසු 1977 දී ජේ.ආර්.ජයවර්ධන මහතා බලයට පත්වීමෙන් පසු රත්නපුර කැකාලෙයි ප්‍රදේශයේ දෙමළ ගම් කිහිපයක් ජාතිවාදයේ නාමයෙන් සිංහල මැරයන් විසින් ගිනිබත් කරන ලදී. ජේ.ආර්.ජයවර්ධන මහතාගේ පාලන සමයේදී කඳුකර ජනතාවට එරෙහිව සිදුවූ ප්‍රචණ්ඩ ක්‍රියාවලින් කැපී පෙනෙන සිදුවීමක් වූයේ පුස්සල්ලේ ඩෙල්ටා වතුයාය ගිනි තැබීමයි.",
        "එලෙසම රත්නපුර දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ වැව් වත්තකදී විපතට පත් ජනතාව හමුවූ ජේ.ආර්.ජයවර්ධන මහතා ජේ.ආර්.ජයවර්ධන මහතාට කියා සිටියේ ජනතාව තම ඥාතීන් මරා දේපළ විනාශ කළ බවට හඬා වැටෙන විට එවකට ජනාධිපති ජේ.ආර්.ජයවර්ධන ජාතිවාදයට චෝදනා කළේ “අපි දෙන්නම්. ඔබට රැජිනක්, අපි ඔබට බත් දෙන්නෙමු, අපි ඔබට කුකුල් මස් දෙන්නෙමු, අපි ඔබට හරක් දෙන්නෙමු, නමුත් වෙනම රටක් පමණක්, \"අපි එපා\" යනුවෙන් උපහාසාත්මක පිළිතුරක් දුන් බව පැවසේ.",
        "දැනට ඉන්දියාවේ වෙසෙන ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ ලේඛකයෙක් 1977 කැරැල්ලේදී තම ජීවිතයේ සත්‍ය සිදුවීම් කිහිපයක් සටහන් කරන්නේ මෙසේය \"1977 රාත්‍රී 7 ට මහනුවර කෝලාහල ආරම්භ විය. රටේ අනෙකුත් ප්‍රදේශවල ජාතිවාදී කෝලාහල ආරම්භ වී ඇති බව දැනගත් සිංහල සහ මහනුවර ප්‍රදේශයේ වෙසෙන ද්‍රවිඩ ක්‍රියාකාරීන් විසින් මහනුවර පොලිස් ස්ථානයට පැමිණිල්ලක් ගොනු කරන ලදී.එවකට භාරව සිටි පොලිස් නිලධාරියා දෙමළ ජාතිකයෙකි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් තමන්ට කිසිවක් කළ නොහැකි නමුත් ඉහළ නිලධාරීන්ට දැනුම් දෙන බවද ඔහු කියා සිටියා. එහෙත් පොලිසියෙන් කිසිදු ආරක්‍ෂාවක්‌ සපයා නැත. ජාතිවාදී කෝලාහල ආරම්භ වූයේ සවස 7 ට පමණය. එකල මහනුවර ජීවත්වන දෙමළ ජනතාවට ආරක්‍ෂාව සැලසීමට පෙරටුගාමීව සිටි ඇතැම් සිංහල සහෝදරවරුන්ගේ කාර්යභාරය සුළුපටු නැත, විශේෂයෙන්ම ජයරත්න මල්ලිකාගොඩ වැනි බොහෝ වාමාංශික සිංහල සහෝදරවරු වැදගත් වූහ.",
        "ජේ.ආර්.ජයවර්ධන මහතාගේ කාලයේ දී කඳුකරයේ දෙමළ ජනයාට එරෙහිව ප්‍රචණ්ඩ මතවාදයක් නිර්මාණය කිරීම සඳහා මැලේවරුන් ‘ඉන්දියානු ව්‍යාප්තවාදීන්’ ලෙස හුවා දැක්වීමේ පුරුද්දක් වර්ධනය විය. කඳුකර ජනතාව ජනගහණයෙන් වැඩි බවත් එය ලංකාවට තර්ජනයක් වනු ඇති බවත් මධ්‍යගතවාදයක් ප්‍රචාරය විය.",
        "1983 කෝලාහල කොළඹ ජීවත් වූ දෙමළ ජනතාවට බලපෑවා සේම රත්නපුරි කැකාලයි පදුලයි මාතලෙයි නුවරලියා වැනි සිංහල ජනතාව අතර ජීවත් වූ කඳුකර දෙමළ ජනතාවද අප්‍රමාණ හානිවලට හා ජීවිත හා දේපළ හානිවලට මුහුණ දුන්හ. එමෙන්ම නුවරඑළිය නගරය මහජන කෝලාහලයකින් ගිනිබත් විය.",
        "එයට ප්‍රධාන හේතුව වූයේ ‘නුවරඑළිය නගරය ඉංගිරිසින් විසින් ගොඩනඟන ලද්දක් බවත්, එහි ඇතැම් පෞරාණික දේ හමු වූ නිසා අපි ඒවා විනාශ කර නව නගරයක් හදන්නට ගිනි තබා විනාශ කළ බවත්’ කීවේ එදා කාමිණී දිසානායක ඇමැතිවරයාය. 1983 ජුලි මාසයේ බදුල ලුණුගලෙයි ප්‍රදේශයේ පාසල් දෙකක් ගිනිබත් කළ ප්‍රචණ්ඩ ක්‍රියා ද විශේෂත්වයකි.",
        "මේ අනුව නිදහසින් පසු කඳුකර ප්‍රදේශවල කඳුකර ජනතාවගේ පැවැත්ම හා අධ්‍යාපනය විනාශ කිරීමට සිංහල බෞද්ධ රජය විසින් මුදා හරින ලද වාර්ගික කෝලාහල තුළ 1983 වාර්ගික කෝලාහලය ඉතිහාසයේ නොමැකෙන අඳුරු සිදුවීමකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "1983 ජූලි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොට කෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළු ජූලිය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජගන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළු ජූලිය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1983 කළු ජූලිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1983 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලෙයිමන්නාරම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර මාතල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝමීටර් සිය ගණනක්",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල පනත",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීමාඕ බණ්ඩාරනායකගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීමා-ශාස්ත්‍රී ගිවිසුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඩක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1972",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1972 වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාරවල්ලි කිලං",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජේ ආර් ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුර කැකාලයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජේ ආර් ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුස්සල්ලා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජේ ආර් ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජේ ආර් ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජේ ආර් ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස 7",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර පොලිස් ස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සවස 7ට පමණ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයරත්න මල්ලිකාගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජේ ආර් ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැලේ ජාතිකයන්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරි කැකාලයි පදුලයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතලයි නුවරලියා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුවරඑළිය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාමිණී දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "1983 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදුල ලුණුගලයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංහල බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "1983 ஜூலை இன வன்முறையில் மலையக மக்கள் முகம்கொடுத்த இன்னல்கள்",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "“1983 ஆம் ஆம் ஆண்டு இடம்பெற்ற  கருப்பு ஜூலையை நினைவுக் கூறும் முகமாக காலி முகத்திடல் கோட்டா கோ கிராமத்தில் நடைபெற்ற நிகழ்வில்  மலையகத்தை சேர்ந்த  இடது சாரி செயற்பாட்டாளர் ஜோ. ஜெகன்  அவர்கள் சமூக நீதிக்கான வெகுஜன அமைப்பை பிரதிநிதித்துவப் படுத்தி மலையக மக்கள் இலங்கை சுதந்திரம் அடைந்த பின்பு கருப்பு ஜூலை உட்பட முகம் கொடுத்த இன வன்முறைகளை பற்றி ஆற்றிய பேச்சு இங்கு பதியப்பட்டுள்ளது”",
        "1983 ஆம் ஆம் ஆண்டு இடம்பெற்ற  கருப்பு ஜூலை இலங்கை பூராக வாழ்ந்த தமிழ் மக்களின் மனதில் நீங்காது இடம் பிடித்த வடு என்றே கூறலாம். எனினும்  இந்த கோர சம்பவத்தில் மலையாக மக்கள் எவ்வாறு பாதிக்கப்பட்டனர் என்பதில் இன்றுவரை அதிக படியான கவனம் செலுத்தப்படவில்லை. 1983 ஜூலை மாதம் மலையக பிரதேசங்களில் நடந்த இன வன்முறைகளை மலையக மக்களின் தனித்துவமான துயரம் சார்ந்த நீண்ட வரலாற்றின் பின்னணியில் பார்க்க வேண்டும்.",
        "இந்தியாவின் தமிழ் நாட்டின் தென்மாவட்டங்களில் இருந்து தனுஷ்கோடியூடாக ஊடாக படகுகள் மூலம் தலைமன்னாருக்கு வந்து இறங்கி மன்னாரில் இருந்து கண்டி மாத்தளை வரைக்கும் நடந்தே வந்த வரலாற்றை கொண்டவர்கள் மலையக மக்கள். பல நூறு கிலோமீட்டருக்கு அப்பால் தாம் நடந்து சென்ற காட்டுப் பாதையை தாமே துப்பரவு செய்து, உயிர்களை காவு கொடுத்து கால்நடையாகவே வந்த வரலாற்றை கொண்டவர்கள் தான் எமது மலையக மக்கள். மலையக மக்கள் பிருத்தானிய காலப்பகுதியில் இருந்து இன்று வரை பொருளாதாரம், சுரண்டல் மற்றும் இனரீதியான அடக்குமுறைக்கு உட்படுத்தப்பட்டு வருகின்றார்கள் என்றே கூறலாம்.",
        "இலங்கை சுதந்திரம் அடைந்த பின்னர் தனி சிங்கள சட்டம்,  ஸ்ரீமாவோ பண்டாரநாயக காலத்தில் ஏற்பட்ட பஞ்சம், ஸ்ரீமா – சாஸ்த்ரி ஒப்பந்தத்தின்இங்கு வாழ்ந்த மலையக மக்களில் பாத்தியாளவானோர் இந்தியாவுக்கும் மீதமானவர்கள்  இலங்கைக்குமென, சொத்தை பிரிப்பதை போல் உயிருள்ள அந்த மக்களின் வாழ்வியலை பிரிதெடுத்த சம்பவங்கள் போன்ற இன ஒடுக்குமுறைக்கும் இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தினால் உட்படுத்தப்பட்டனர்.",
        "ஸ்ரீமா-சாஸ்த்ரி ஒப்பந்தத்தின் போது பதியப்பட்ட சம்பவங்களில் திருமணம் முடித்து சில நாட்களின் பின்னர் மனைவி இந்தியாவுக்கும் கணவர் இலங்கையில் என்று பிரித்து  அனுப்பப்பட்ட  மனதை நெகிழ்த்தும் பல சம்பவங்களும் உள்ளன. அது மட்டுமல்லாது 1972 ஆம் ஆண்டு பஞ்சம் ஏற்பட்ட காலப்பகுதில் கூட இலங்கையில் ஏனைய பிரதேசங்களில் வாழ்ந்த மக்களுக்கு வாழ்வாதாரம் சொந்த நிலம் என்று காணப்பட்ட போதும்  நிலமற்ற தமக்கென்று வாழ்வாதாரமற்ற மலையக மக்கள் இந்த பஞ்ச காலத்தில் மிகவும் ஒரு துன்பகரமான வாழ்கையில் தான் வாழ்ந்திருக்கின்றனர். 1972 ஆம் ஆண்டு காலத்தை பற்றி மலையக பிரதேசத்தில் பேசும் போது பஞ்ச காலத்தில் மரவள்ளி கிழங்கை அவித்து உண்டோம், இரண்டு ரொட்டியை பத்து பேர் பிரித்து சாப்பிட்டோம் என்றெல்லாம் கூறுவார்கள்.",
        "அதன் பின்னர் 1977 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜெ.ஆர் ஜெயவர்த்தன பதவி ஏற்ற பின்பு இரத்தினபுரி கேகாலையில் சில தமிழ் கிராமங்கள் இனவாதத்தின் பெயரால் சிங்கள காடையர்களால் எரிக்கப்பட்டன. ஜெ ஆர் ஜெயவர்த்தனவின் காலப்பகுதியில் மலையக மக்களிற்கெதிராக பதியப்பட்ட வன்முறை சம்பவங்களில்ஒன்று புஸ்ஸல்லாவையில் எரிக்கப்பட்ட டெல்டா தோட்ட சம்பவம் மூக்கியமானததொன்று.",
        "இதே போல் ரத்தினபுரி மாவட்டத்தில் ஏரிக்கப்பட்ட தோட்டம் ஒன்றின்றில் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட மக்களை சந்தித்த  ஜெ.ஆர் ஜெயவர்த்தனவிடம் மக்கள் தமது சொந்தங்கள் கொல்லப்பட்டதையும், தமது உடைமைகள் அழிக்கப்பட்டதையும் சொல்லி அழும் போது அன்றைய ஜனாதிபதியாக இருந்த ஜெ.ஆர் ஜெயவர்த்தன இனவாதத்தை கக்கி \"நாம் உங்களுக்கு அரசி தருவோம் சோறு தருவோம் கோழி தருவோம் மாடு தருவோம் ஆனால் தனி நாடு மட்டும் தர மாட்டோம்” என்ற ஒரு ஏளனமான பதிலை கூறினார் என்று கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "1977 ஆம் ஆண்டு கலவரத்தின் போது தனது வாழ்கையில் நடந்த சில உண்மை சம்பவங்களை தற்போது இந்தியாவில் வசிக்கும் முக்கிய எழுத்தளர்களில்  ஒருவர்  பின்வருமாறு பதிவு செய்கிறார் \"1977 ஆம் ஆண்டு இரவு 7 மணியளவில் கண்டியில் கலவரம் ஆரம்பமாகியது. நாட்டின் ஏனைய பகுதிகளில் இனக்கலவரம் ஆரம்பித்துவிட்டது என்று அறிந்த கண்டியில் வசித்த சிங்களம் மற்றும் தமிழ் செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் கண்டி போலிஸ் நிலையத்திற்கு முறைப்பாடொன்றை பதியசென்றனர். அந்த காலத்தில் பொறுப்பாக இருந்த போலிஸ் அதிகாரி தமிழர் ஒருவர்.",
        "இருந்த போதிலும் தனக்கு அது தொடர்பாக ஒன்றும் செய்ய முடியாது என்றும் எனினும் மேல் இடத்திற்கு அறிவிப்பதாகவும் கூறினார். எனினும் போலிஸ் தரப்பில் இருந்து எந்தவிதமான பாதுகாப்பும் கொடுக்கப்படவில்லை.  இரவு 7 மணியளவில் இனக்கலவரம் ஆரம்பித்தது. அவ்வேளைகளில் கண்டியில் வாழ்ந்த தமிழ் மக்களுக்கு பாதுகாப்பு கொடுத்ததில் முன்னணியில் சில சிங்கள  தோழர்களின் பங்கு அளப்பறியது குறிப்பாக ஜெயரட்ன மல்லிககொட போன்ற பல இடது சாரி சிங்கள தோழர்கள் முக்கியமானவர்கள்\".",
        "ஜே ஆர் ஜெயவர்த்தனவின் காலத்தில் மலையக தமிழ் மக்களிற்கெதிரான வன்முறை கருத்தியலை உருவாக்குவதற்காக ‘இந்திய விஸ்தரிப்பு வாதிகள்’ என்று மலையாக மக்களை சித்தரிக்கும் ஒரு வழக்கம் உருவாக்கப்பட்டது. மலையக மக்கள் சனத்தொகையில் அதிகமாக இருப்பதாகவும் அவர்கள் இலங்கை நாட்டிற்கு அச்சுறுத்தலாக வந்துவிடுவார்கள் என்ற ஒரு கருத்து மையவாதமும் பரப்பப்பட்டது.",
        "1983 ஆம் ஆண்டு கலவரம் கொழும்பில் வாழும் தமிழ் மக்களை எவ்வாறு பாதித்ததோ அதே போன்று இரத்தினபுரி கேகாலை பதுளை மாத்தளை நுவரெலியா  போன்று சிங்கள மக்களின் மத்தியில் வாழ்ந்த மலையக தமிழ் மக்களும் சொல்லில் அடங்காத பாதிப்பிற்கும் உயிர் சொத்து சேதத்திற்கும் முகம் கொடுத்தனர். மேலும் கலவரத்தின் பொது  நுவரெலிய நகரம் எரிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இதற்கு பிரதான காரணமாக இருந்த அன்றைய அமைச்சர் காமினி திசாநாயக ‘நுவரெலிய நகரம் பிருதானியர்களினால் கட்டமைக்கப்பட்டது, இதில் சில பழமையான விடயங்கள் காணப்பட்டதால் அவற்றை அழித்து புதிதாக நகரை உருவாக்குவதற்கே எரித்தோம்’ என்று கூறினார். 1983 ஜூலை வன்முறையின் பொது பதுளை லுணுகலை பகுதியில் இரண்டு பாடசாலைகள் எரிக்கப்பட்டதும் குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது.",
        "இவ்வாறு சுதந்திரத்தின் பின் மலையக பகுதிகளில் மலையாக மக்களின் இருப்பையும் கல்வியையும் அழிக்க சிங்கள பௌத்த அரசினால் கட்டவிழ்த்து விடப்பட்ட இனக்கலவரங்களில் 1983 ஆம் ஆண்டு இனக்கலவரம் வரலாற்றில் அழிக்கமுடியாத இருண்ட சம்பவமாக இருந்து வருகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "1983 ஜூலை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டா கோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருப்பு ஜூலை",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெகன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருப்பு ஜூலை",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1983 கறுப்பு ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமன்னார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி மாத்தளை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நூற்றுக்கணக்கான கிலோமீட்டர்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கள சட்டம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீமாவோ பண்டாரநாயக்கவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீமா-சாஸ்திரி ஒப்பந்தம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதி",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு சில நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1972",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1972 ஆம் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மரவல்லி கிழங்கு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.ஆர்.ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி கேகலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்களவர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.ஆர்.ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "புஸ்ஸல்லா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜே.ஆர்.ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.ஆர்.ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.ஆர்.ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை 7 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்களவர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி பொலிஸ் நிலையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 7 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்களவர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜயரத்ன மல்லிகாகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜே.ஆர்.ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலாய்க்காரர்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்களவர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரத்னபுரி கேக்கலை பதுளை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தளை நுவரெலியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுவரெலியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அந்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமினி திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதுல லுணுகலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்கள பௌத்தர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}