{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83699/sri-lanka-concludes-bilateral-consultations-with-japan",
  "time_ut": 1658044020,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka concludes bilateral consultations with Japan",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka concludes bilateral consultations with Japan",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Secretary of Foreign Affairs Aruni Wijewardane led bilateral consultations with a senior delegation from the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Japan led by the Assistant Minister of the Southwest and Southeast Asia Affairs Division of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Japan, Kano Takehiro.",
        "The Sri Lanka delegation included the Governor of the Central Bank Dr. P. Nandalal Weerasinghe, Secretary to the Treasury Mahinda Siriwardana and senior officials of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Defence and Sri Lanka Navy.",
        "The discussions focused on enhancing bilateral political, economic and defence cooperation as well as strengthening people to people ties, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Aruni Wijewardane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Japan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southwest",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southeast Asia Affairs Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kano Takehiro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "P. Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Siriwardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජපානය සමඟ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික උපදේශන අවසන් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජපාන විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ නිරිතදිග සහ අග්නිදිග ආසියානු කටයුතු අංශයේ සහකාර අමාත්‍ය Kano Takehiro ප්‍රමුඛ ජපාන විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නියෝජිත පිරිසක් සමඟ විදේශ කටයුතු ලේකම් අරුණි විජේවර්ධන මහත්මිය ද්විපාර්ශ්වික උපදේශන පැවැත්වීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දූත පිරිසට මහ බැංකු අධිපති ආචාර්ය පී. නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ, භාණ්ඩාගාර ලේකම් මහින්ද සිරිවර්ධන සහ විදේශ කටයුතු, ආරක්ෂක සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාවේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරීන් ඇතුළත් විය.",
        "ද්විපාර්ශ්වික දේශපාලන, ආර්ථික සහ ආරක්ෂක සහයෝගීතාව වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම මෙන්ම ජනතාව සමඟ ජනතාව අතර සබඳතා ශක්තිමත් කිරීම පිළිබඳව මෙම සාකච්ඡාවලදී අවධානය යොමු වූ බව විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අරුණි විජේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානයේ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිරිතදිග",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අග්නිදිග ආසියානු කටයුතු අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kano Takehiro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පී.නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜப்பானுடனான இருதரப்பு ஆலோசனைகளை இலங்கை நிறைவு செய்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜப்பான் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் தென்மேற்கு மற்றும் தென்கிழக்கு ஆசிய விவகாரப் பிரிவின் உதவி அமைச்சர் கானோ டேகிரோ தலைமையில் ஜப்பான் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் சிரேஷ்ட பிரதிநிதிகளுடன் வெளிவிவகார செயலாளர் அருணி விஜேவர்தன இருதரப்பு ஆலோசனைகளை நடத்தினார்.",
        "இலங்கை தூதுக்குழுவில் மத்திய வங்கியின் ஆளுநர் கலாநிதி பி.நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க, திறைசேரியின் செயலாளர் மஹிந்த சிறிவர்தன மற்றும் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் சிரேஷ்ட அதிகாரிகள், பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் ஆகியோர் அடங்கியிருந்தனர்.",
        "இருதரப்பு அரசியல், பொருளாதாரம் மற்றும் பாதுகாப்பு ஒத்துழைப்பை மேம்படுத்துவது மற்றும் மக்களுடன் மக்களுடனான உறவுகளை வலுப்படுத்துவது குறித்து இந்த விவாதங்கள் கவனம் செலுத்தியதாக வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அருணி விஜேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானின் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்மேற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்கிழக்கு ஆசிய விவகாரங்கள் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kano Takehiro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பி.நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}