{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/international/පූටින්-G20-සමුළුවට-සහභාගී-වන-බව-කියයි/3-394907",
  "time_ut": 1656392718,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පූටින් G20 සමුළුවට සහභාගී වන බව කියයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Putin says he will attend the G20 summit",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Indonesia is chairing the G20 this year, and the United States has been pressured by major Western nations to exclude Russia from the meeting.",
        "The Kremlin says it has accepted an invitation from Russian President Vladimir Putin to attend the G20 summit in Indonesia from November 15 to 16.",
        "Kremlin aide Yuri Ushakov told the media on Monday that the pattern of Putin's participation was not yet clear.",
        "\"Currently, they have been invited to attend in person, but there is a lot of time for that. I hope the epidemic will allow this important forum to be held face to face, I would like to avoid speculation,\" he said.",
        "Indonesia is chairing the G20 this year, and the United States has been pressured by major Western nations to exclude Russia from the meeting.",
        "However, Indonesian President and G20 President Joko Widodo did not cancel the invitation to Russia. In early April, he announced that he would address Ukrainian President Volodymyr Selensky as a guest at the G20 summit and join world leaders.",
        "Widodo is reportedly planning to travel to Russia and Ukraine to meet with the leaders of those countries and call for peace talks this week."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Putin",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Indonesia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kremlin",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indonesia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "November 15 to 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kremlin",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuri Ushakov",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indonesia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indonesian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "G20",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joko Widodo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "early April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukrainian",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Volodymyr Selensky",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පූටින් G20 සමුළුවට සහභාගී වන බව කියයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මෙම වසරේ G20 හි සභාපතිත්වය ඉන්දුනීසියාව විසින් දරන අතර, රුසියාව රැස්වීමෙන් බැහැර කරන ලෙස එක්සත් ජනපදය ප්‍රමුඛ බටහිර රටවල් විසින් බලපෑම් කර තිබේ.",
        "නොවැම්බර් 15 සිට 16 දක්වා ඉන්දුනීසියාවේ පැවැත්වෙන 20 කණ්ඩායමේ (G20) සමුළුවට සහභාගි වන ලෙස රුසියානු ජනාධිපති ව්ලැදිමීර් පූටින් වෙත කළ ආරාධනය පිළිගෙන ඇති බව ක්‍රෙම්ලිනය පවසයි.",
        "ක්‍රෙම්ලිනයේ සහායක යූරි උෂකොව් සඳුදා මාධ්‍ය වෙත පැවසුවේ පූටින්ගේ සහභාගීත්වයේ ආකෘතිය තවමත් නිශ්චිතව ප්‍රකාශ කළ නොහැකි බවයි.",
        "\" දැනට, ඔවුන් පෞද්ගලිකව සහභාගී වීමට ආරාධනා කර තිබෙනවා. නමුත් බොහෝ කාලයක් ඒ සඳහා පවතිනවා. මෙම වැදගත් සංසදය මුහුණට මුහුණ පැවැත්වීමට වසංගත තත්ත්වය ඉඩ දෙනු ඇතැයි මා බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා මම අනුමාන කිරීමෙන් වැළකී සිටීමට කැමතියි\" ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මෙම වසරේ G20 හි සභාපතිත්වය ඉන්දුනීසියාව විසින් දරන අතර, රුසියාව රැස්වීමෙන් බැහැර කරන ලෙස එක්සත් ජනපදය ප්‍රමුඛ බටහිර රටවල් විසින් බලපෑම් කර තිබේ.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ඉන්දුනීසියානු ජනාධිපති සහ G20 සභාපති ජෝකෝ විඩෝඩෝ රුසියාවට කළ ආරාධනය අවලංගු කළේ නැත. අප්‍රේල් මස මුලදී, ඔහු යුක්රේන ජනාධිපති වොලොදොමීර් සෙලෙන්ස්කි අමතා G20 සමුළුවට ආගන්තුකයෙකු ලෙස ලෝක නායකයින් අතරට එක්වන ලෙස ආරාධනා කළ බව නිවේදනය කළේය.",
        "එමෙන්ම, විඩෝඩෝ රුසියාවට සහ යුක්රේනයට ගොස් එම රටවල නායකයන් හමුවී, මේ සතියේ සාම සාකච්ඡා ඉල්ලා සිටීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති බවද වාර්තා වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පුටින්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දුනීසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ක්රෙම්ලිනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දුනීසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොවැම්බර් 15 සිට 16 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ක්රෙම්ලිනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යූරි උෂාකොව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දුනීසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දුනීසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "G20",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝකෝ විඩෝඩෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනියානු",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Volodymyr Selensky",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜி20 மாநாட்டில் கலந்து கொள்வதாக புடின் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்தோனேசியா இந்த ஆண்டு G20 க்கு தலைமை தாங்குகிறது, மேலும் ரஷ்யாவை கூட்டத்தில் இருந்து விலக்குமாறு அமெரிக்காவிற்கு முக்கிய மேற்கத்திய நாடுகள் அழுத்தம் கொடுத்துள்ளன.",
        "நவம்பர் 15 முதல் 16 வரை இந்தோனேசியாவில் நடைபெறும் G20 உச்சி மாநாட்டில் கலந்து கொள்ள ரஷ்ய அதிபர் விளாடிமிர் புடினின் அழைப்பை ஏற்றுக்கொண்டதாக கிரெம்ளின் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "கிரெம்ளின் உதவியாளர் யூரி உஷாகோவ் திங்களன்று செய்தி ஊடகத்திடம், புடினின் பங்கேற்பு முறை இன்னும் தெளிவாகத் தெரியவில்லை என்று கூறினார்.",
        "\"தற்போது, ​​அவர்கள் நேரில் கலந்துகொள்ள அழைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர், ஆனால் அதற்கு நிறைய நேரம் உள்ளது. இந்த முக்கியமான மன்றத்தை நேருக்கு நேர் நடத்த தொற்றுநோய் அனுமதிக்கும் என்று நம்புகிறேன், ஊகங்களைத் தவிர்க்க விரும்புகிறேன்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "இந்தோனேசியா இந்த ஆண்டு G20 க்கு தலைமை தாங்குகிறது, மேலும் ரஷ்யாவை கூட்டத்தில் இருந்து விலக்குமாறு அமெரிக்காவிற்கு முக்கிய மேற்கத்திய நாடுகள் அழுத்தம் கொடுத்துள்ளன.",
        "எனினும், இந்தோனேசிய அதிபரும் G20 தலைவருமான ஜோகோ விடோடோ ரஷ்யாவுக்கான அழைப்பை ரத்து செய்யவில்லை. ஏப்ரல் தொடக்கத்தில், அவர் G20 உச்சிமாநாட்டில் விருந்தினராக உக்ரேனிய ஜனாதிபதி வோலோடிமிர் செலென்ஸ்கியை உரையாற்றுவதாகவும், உலகத் தலைவர்களுடன் இணைவதாகவும் அறிவித்தார்.",
        "விடோடோ ரஷ்யா மற்றும் உக்ரைன் ஆகிய நாடுகளுக்குச் சென்று அந்நாடுகளின் தலைவர்களைச் சந்தித்து இந்த வாரம் அமைதிப் பேச்சுவார்த்தைக்கு அழைப்பு விடுக்க திட்டமிட்டுள்ளதாக கூறப்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "புடின்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தோனேசியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிரெம்ளின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளாடிமிர் புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தோனேசியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 15 முதல் 16 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிரெம்ளின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யூரி உஷாகோவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தோனேசியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தோனேஷியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "G20",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜோகோ விடோடோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைனியன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வோலோடிமிர் செலென்ஸ்கி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}