{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/කොරෝනා-ගැන-ජනපතිගෙන්-විශේෂ-ප්‍රකාශයක්/1-617480",
  "time_ut": 1659449434,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කොරෝනා ගැන ජනපතිගෙන් විශේෂ ප්‍රකාශයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A special statement from the President about Corona",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickramasinghe made a special statement today (02) and requested the people to resort to vaccination as soon as possible as the risk of Covid is rising again.",
        "The Ministry of Health has issued health guidelines paying special attention to this and Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe, who requested the people to follow the instructions properly, emphasized that the spread of the Covid epidemic in the country should not be allowed again.",
        "President Ranil Wickramasinghe made a special statement regarding the Covid and Monkey Fox epidemic and said:",
        "“The number of Covid-19 cases and deaths is increasing again. 1731 Covid patients were reported in April. There were 26 Covid deaths. That situation decreased to 472 patients in May. 13 deaths were reported. The number of Covid patients in June is 283. 3 deaths. But in July, the number of Covid patients has increased to 1616. 35 deaths. 28 of these 35 deaths occurred after July 18. Looking at this, one more thing is visible. That is that the Covid vaccine should be given immediately.",
        "17 million were vaccinated in the first round. In the second round, it was reduced to 14 million. In the third round, 8 million people have received the Covid vaccine. Only 22,623 people have been vaccinated in the 4th round. The number of vaccinations for the third and fourth times has decreased, especially in the Western Province. Therefore, people should be re-directed for vaccination.",
        "There are currently 8 million vaccines in Sri Lanka. It can be used till October. Those 8 million vaccines cannot be finished in October. Therefore, a part has to be given to another country. The vaccine was brought for you. Therefore, I request all those who have not received the vaccine to get the vaccine as soon as possible.",
        "The Ministry of Health gives advice on this. Everyone should act according to that advice. In addition, the Ministry of Health has focused on the \"Monkey Fox\" epidemic. Currently it has not arrived in Sri Lanka. The first step has been taken to prevent the disease from coming to Sri Lanka.",
        "Plans are being made to provide treatment if needed. At this time think about health and act. I request all parties not to give another chance to the covid epidemic in this country\"."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Corona",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Covid",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Covid",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Covid",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monkey Fox",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1731",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "472",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "283",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1616",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Covid",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Covid",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Only 22,623",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "fourth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "8 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "October",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "October",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monkey Fox\"",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කොරෝනා ගැන ජනපතිගෙන් විශේෂ ප්‍රකාශයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොවිඩ් අවදානම යළි ඉහළ යමින් පවතින බැවින් කඩිනමින් එන්නත්කරණය සඳහා යොමු වන ලෙස ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අද (02) විශේෂ ප්‍රකාශයක් කරමින් ජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කළේය.",
        "සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය මේ පිළිබඳ විශේෂ අවධානයක් යොමු කරමින් සෞඛ්‍ය මාර්ගෝපදේශ නිකුත් කර ඇති බවත් එම උපදෙස් නියමාකාරයෙන් පිළිපදින ලෙස ජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටි ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා යළිත් රට තුළ කොවිඩ් වසංගතයේ ව්‍යාප්තියට ඉඩ නොතැබිය යුතු බවත් අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා කොවිඩ් සහ මන්කි ෆොක්ස් වසංගත තත්ත්වය සම්බන්ධව  විශේෂ ප්‍රකාශයක් කරමින්  මෙසේද කීය.",
        "“කොවිඩ් -19 රෝගීන් හා මරණ සංඛ්‍යාව යළිත් වැඩි වෙනවා. අප්‍රේල් මාසයේ කොවිඩ් රෝගීන් 1731ක් වාර්තා වුණා. කොවිඩ් මරණ 26ක් සිදු වුණා. එම තත්ත්වය මැයි මාසයේ දී රෝගීන් 472කට අඩු වුණා. මරණ වාර්තා වුණේ 13යි. ජුනි මාසයේ කොවිඩ් රෝගීන් සංඛ්‍යාව 283යි. මරණ 3යි. නමුත් ජූලි මාසයේ කොවිඩ් රෝගීන් 1616ක් දක්වා වැඩි වී තිබෙනවා. මරණ සංඛ්‍යාව 35ක්. මේ මරණ 35න් 28 ක් සිදු වුණේ ජූලි 18 වෙනිදායින් පසුවයි. මේ දෙස බැලූ විට තවත් එක කරුණක් පෙනෙනවා. ඒ කොවිඩ් එන්නත කඩිනමින් ලබා දීම කළ යුතු බවයි.",
        "පළමු වටයේ දී මිලියන 17ක් එන්නත ලබාගත්තා. දෙවන වටයේ දී එය මිලියන 14කට අඩු වුණා. තුන්වෙනි වටයේ දී කොවිඩ් එන්නත ලබාගෙන තිබෙන්නේ මිලියන 8යි. 4වන වටයේ දී  එන්නත ලබාගෙන තිබෙන්නේ පුද්ගලයන් 22,623 දෙනෙක් පමණයි. තුන්වෙනි වතාවෙත්, 4වන වතාවෙත් එන්නත ගත් ප්‍රමාණය විශේෂයෙන්ම බස්නාහිර පළාතේ අඩුවෙලා තිබෙනවා. ඒ නිසා එන්නත්කරණය සඳහා ජනතාව නැවත යොමු කළ යුතුයි.",
        "ලංකාවේ දැනට එන්නත් මිලියන 8ක් තිබෙනවා. එය ඔක්තෝම්බර් මාසය වෙනකම් පාවිච්චි කරන්න පුළුවන්. ඒ එන්නත් මිලියන 8 ඔක්තෝබර් මාසයේ දී අවසන් කරන්න බැරි වෙනවා. ඒ නිසා කොටසක් වෙන රටකට දෙන්න සිදුවෙනවා. එන්නත ගෙනාවේ ඔබ වෙනුවෙන්. ඒ නිසා එන්නත ලබානොගත් සියලු දෙනාගෙන් මම ඉල්ලීමක් කරනවා, ඉක්මණින් එන්නත ලබාගන්න කියලා.",
        "සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය මේ පිළිබඳ උපදෙස් දෙනවා. ඒ උපදෙස් අනුව සියලු දෙනාම කටයුතු කළ යුතුයි. ඊට අමතරව සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය “මන්කි ෆොක්ස්” වසංගතය පිළිබඳවත් අවධානය යොමු කරලා තිබෙනවා. දැනට එය ලංකාවට  පැමිණිලා නැහැ. ලංකාවට  එම රෝගය පැමිණීම වැළැක්වීමට පළමුවන පියවර ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "අවශ්‍ය වුණොත් ප්‍රතිකාර ලබාදෙන්න සැලසුම් සකස් කරගෙන යනවා. මේ අවස්ථාවේ දී සෞඛ්‍ය ගැන හිතලා ක්‍රියා කරන්න. මේ රට තුළ යළිත් කොවිඩ් වසංගතයට අවස්ථාවක් දෙන්න එපා කියා සියලු පාර්ශ්වයන්ගෙන් මම ඉල්ලා සිටිනවා”."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කොරෝනා",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොවිඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොවිඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොවිඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වඳුරු නරියා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1731",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "472",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "283",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1616",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොවිඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 17 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 14 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 8 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොවිඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22,623 ක් පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතරවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 8 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔක්තෝම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 8 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔක්තෝම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්ය අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වඳුරු නරියා\"",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கொரோனா தொடர்பில் ஜனாதிபதியின் விசேட அறிக்கை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இன்று (02) விசேட அறிக்கையொன்றை விடுத்ததுடன், கொவிட் தொற்று மீண்டும் அதிகரித்து வருவதால், கூடிய விரைவில் தடுப்பூசிகளை நாடுமாறு மக்களைக் கேட்டுக்கொண்டார்.",
        "சுகாதார அமைச்சு இது தொடர்பில் விசேட கவனம் செலுத்தி சுகாதார வழிகாட்டுதல்களை வெளியிட்டுள்ளதுடன், அறிவுறுத்தல்களை முறையாக பின்பற்றுமாறு மக்களைக் கேட்டுக்கொண்ட திரு.ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, நாட்டில் மீண்டும் கொவிட் தொற்று பரவுவதற்கு இடமளிக்கக் கூடாது என வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "கொவிட் மற்றும் குரங்கு நரி தொற்று நோய் தொடர்பில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க விசேட அறிக்கையொன்றை விடுத்து மேலும் கூறியதாவது:",
        "“கோவிட்-19 வழக்குகள் மற்றும் இறப்பு எண்ணிக்கை மீண்டும் அதிகரித்து வருகிறது. ஏப்ரல் மாதத்தில் 1731 கோவிட் நோயாளிகள் பதிவாகியுள்ளனர். 26 கோவிட் இறப்புகள் உள்ளன. அந்த நிலை மே மாதத்தில் 472 நோயாளிகளாக குறைந்துள்ளது. 13 இறப்புகள் பதிவாகியுள்ளன. ஜூன் மாதத்தில் கோவிட் நோயாளிகளின் எண்ணிக்கை 283 ஆக உள்ளது. 3 இறப்புகள். ஆனால் ஜூலை மாதத்தில், கோவிட் நோயாளிகளின் எண்ணிக்கை 1616 ஆக அதிகரித்துள்ளது. 35 இறப்புகள். இந்த 35 இறப்புகளில் 28 ஜூலை 18 க்குப் பிறகு நிகழ்ந்தன. இதைப் பார்க்கும்போது இன்னொரு விஷயமும் தெரிகிறது. அதாவது கோவிட் தடுப்பூசியை உடனடியாக போட வேண்டும்.",
        "முதல் சுற்றில் 17 மில்லியன் பேருக்கு தடுப்பூசி போடப்பட்டது. இரண்டாவது சுற்றில் அது 14 மில்லியனாகக் குறைக்கப்பட்டது. மூன்றாவது சுற்றில், 8 மில்லியன் மக்கள் கோவிட் தடுப்பூசியைப் பெற்றுள்ளனர். 4வது சுற்றில் மட்டும் 22,623 பேருக்கு தடுப்பூசி போடப்பட்டுள்ளது. குறிப்பாக மேல்மாகாணத்தில் மூன்றாவது மற்றும் நான்காவது தடவைகளுக்கு தடுப்பூசி போடும் எண்ணிக்கை குறைந்துள்ளது. எனவே, தடுப்பூசி போட மக்களை திசை திருப்ப வேண்டும்.",
        "இலங்கையில் தற்போது 8 மில்லியன் தடுப்பூசிகள் உள்ளன. இதை அக்டோபர் வரை பயன்படுத்தலாம். அந்த 8 மில்லியன் தடுப்பூசிகளை அக்டோபரில் முடிக்க முடியாது. எனவே, ஒரு பகுதியை வேறு நாட்டிற்கு வழங்க வேண்டும். தடுப்பூசி உங்களுக்காக கொண்டு வரப்பட்டது. எனவே தடுப்பூசி போடாத அனைவரும் விரைவில் தடுப்பூசி போட்டுக்கொள்ளுமாறு கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறேன்.",
        "சுகாதார அமைச்சகம் இதற்கான ஆலோசனைகளை வழங்குகிறது. அந்த அறிவுரைப்படி அனைவரும் செயல்பட வேண்டும். மேலும், “குரங்கு நரி” தொற்றுநோய் தொடர்பில் சுகாதார அமைச்சு கவனம் செலுத்தியுள்ளது. தற்போது அது இலங்கைக்கு வரவில்லை. இந்நோய் இலங்கைக்கு வராமல் தடுக்க முதல் நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "தேவைப்பட்டால் சிகிச்சை அளிக்க திட்டமிடப்பட்டு வருகிறது. இந்த நேரத்தில் ஆரோக்கியத்தைப் பற்றி சிந்தித்து செயல்படுங்கள். இந்த நாட்டில் கோவிட் தொற்றுநோய்க்கு மீண்டும் ஒரு வாய்ப்பு கொடுக்க வேண்டாம் என்று அனைத்து தரப்பினரையும் கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறேன்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கொரோனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவிட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவிட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவிட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குரங்கு நரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1731",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "472",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "283",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1616",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவிட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவிட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22,623 மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்காவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "8 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அக்டோபர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அக்டோபர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குரங்கு நரி\"",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}