{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/පොල්දූව-විරෝධයේ-අමු-විඩියෝ-සී-සී-ඩීයට-දෙන්නැයි-නියෝගයක්/101-616631",
  "time_ut": 1658144780,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පොල්දූව විරෝධයේ අමු විඩියෝ සී.සී.ඩීයට දෙන්නැයි නියෝගයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "An order to give the raw video of the Polduwa protest to the CCD",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Colombo Additional Magistrate Harshana Kekunawala ordered the heads of electronic media today (18) to hand over the footage related to the struggle that took place on the 13th at the Polduwa intersection leading to Parliament to the Colombo Crime Division.",
        "The Magistrate issued the orders in consideration of a request made by the Colombo Crimes Division in connection with the incident in which two army personnel were seriously injured during the protest and two ammunition magazines with 30 live rounds and two T56 firearms went missing.",
        "Colombo said that the investigation was initiated in connection with an incident in which two army soldiers were attacked and injured while being members of an illegal meeting on the road from the Polduwa intersection leading to the Parliament to the speaker's official residence and robbed of two ammunition bags with 30 rounds of live ammunition and two T56 type automatic firearms. The crime division had reported the matter to the court.",
        "Accordingly, the Colombo Crimes Division has requested the court to issue an order to provide the unedited videos recorded by the television channels at that time in relation to this investigation."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Polduwa",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        },
        {
          "text": "CCD",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo Additional Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harshana Kekunawala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 13th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polduwa",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Crime Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Crimes Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polduwa",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Crimes Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පොල්දූව විරෝධයේ අමු විඩියෝ සී.සී.ඩීයට දෙන්නැයි නියෝගයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පිවිසෙන පොල්දූව මංසන්ධියේ දී ඉකුත් 13 වැනිදා සිදුවූ අරගලයට අදාළ දර්ශන කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාසයට ලබා දෙන ලෙසට නියම කරමින් කොළඹ අතිරේක මහේස්ත්‍රාත් හර්ෂණ කැකුණාවල මහතා විද්‍යුත් මාධ්‍ය ආයතන ප්‍රධානීන්ට අද (18) නියෝග කළේය.",
        "මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා මෙලෙස නියෝග නිකුත් කළේ, මෙම උද්ඝෝෂණයේදී යුද හමුදා සාමාජිකයන් දෙදෙනකුට පරහදී බරපතල තුවාල සිදුකර ජීව උණ්ඩ 30ක් සහිත පතුරම් ගැබ් දෙකක් සහ ටී 56 ගිනි අවි දෙකක් අතුරුදන්වීමේ සිද්ධියට අදාළව කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාසය කළ ඉල්ලීමක් සැලකිල්ලට ගනිමිනි.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පිවිසෙන පොල්දූව මංසන්ධියේ සිට කතානායකවරයාගේ නිල නිවස දක්වා වූ මාර්ගයේ නිති විරෝධී රැස්වීමක සාමාජිකයන් වෙමින් යුද හමුදා සෙබලුන් දෙදෙනකුට පහරදී තුවාල සිදුකර ඔවුන් සතු ජීව උණ්ඩ 30ක් සහිත පතුරම් ගැබ් දෙකක් සහ ටී පනස් හය වර්ගයේ ස්වයංක්‍රීය ගිනි අවි දෙකක් කොල්ලකෑමේ සිද්ධියක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් මෙම පරීක්ෂණය ආරම්භ කළ බව කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ාසය අධිකරණයට කරුණු වාර්තා කර තිබිණී.",
        "ඒ අනුව මෙම විමර්ශනයට අදාළව එම අවස්ථාවේදී රූපවාහිණී නාලිකාවල පටිගත කළ සංස්කරණය නොකළ වීඩියෝ දර්ශන අවශ්‍යව ඇති බැවින් ඒවා ලබා දෙන ලෙසට නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කරන්නැයි කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාසය අධිකරණයෙන් ඉල්ලා තිබිණී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පොල්දූව",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        },
        {
          "text": "CCD",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අතිරේක මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂණ කැකුණවල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "13 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොල්දූව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොල්දූව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பொல்துவ போராட்டத்தின் மூல வீடியோவை சிசிடிக்கு வழங்க உத்தரவு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாராளுமன்றம் செல்லும் பொல்துவ சந்தியில் கடந்த 13 ஆம் திகதி இடம்பெற்ற போராட்டம் தொடர்பான காட்சிகளை கொழும்பு குற்றத்தடுப்பு பிரிவினரிடம் ஒப்படைக்குமாறு கொழும்பு மேலதிக நீதவான் ஹர்ஷன கெகுனாவல இலத்திரனியல் ஊடக பிரதானிகளுக்கு இன்று (18) உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தின் போது இராணுவத்தினர் இருவர் படுகாயமடைந்ததுடன் 30 துப்பாக்கிகள் மற்றும் இரண்டு T56 துப்பாக்கிகள் கொண்ட இரண்டு ரவைகள் காணாமல் போன சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் கொழும்பு குற்றத்தடுப்பு பிரிவினர் விடுத்த கோரிக்கையை கருத்திற்கொண்டு நீதவான் இந்த உத்தரவை பிறப்பித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பொல்துவ சந்தியில் இருந்து பாராளுமன்றம் செல்லும் வீதியில் சபாநாயகரின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ வாசஸ்தலத்திற்கு செல்லும் வீதியில் இராணுவ வீரர்கள் இருவர் தாக்கி காயப்படுத்தப்பட்ட சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் விசாரணைகள் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக கொழும்பு தெரிவித்துள்ளது. 30 தோட்டாக்கள் மற்றும் T56 ரக தானியங்கி துப்பாக்கிகள் இரண்டுடன், குற்றப்பிரிவு நீதிமன்றில் இது தொடர்பில் அறிக்கை செய்திருந்தது.",
        "இதன்படி, இந்த விசாரணை தொடர்பில் அப்போது தொலைக்காட்சி அலைவரிசைகள் பதிவு செய்த திருத்தப்படாத காணொளிகளை வழங்குமாறு உத்தரவு பிறப்பிக்குமாறு கொழும்பு குற்றத்தடுப்புப் பிரிவு நீதிமன்றில் கோரியுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பொல்துவா",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        },
        {
          "text": "சிசிடி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு மேலதிக நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷன கெகுனாவல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "13வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொல்துவா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு குற்றப்பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு குற்றப்பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொல்துவா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு குற்றப்பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}