{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-schedules-power-cuts-of-3-hours-on-august-29-99122/",
  "time_ut": 1661697120,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka schedules power cuts of 3 hours on August 29",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka schedules power cuts of 3 hours on August 29",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Power cuts of three hours of will be imposed around Sri Lanka on August 29, 2022 Public Utilities Commission (PUCSL) Chairman Janaka Ratnayake said amid fuel shortages.",
        "The Ceylon Electricity Board said that they were “compelled to take demand management measures due to inadequate generation as a result of fuel shortage.”",
        "Accordingly, all areas ABCDEFGHIJKLPQRSTUVW will have 1 hour and 40 minutes of power cuts in the daytime & 1 hour and 20 minutes during the night, Public Utilities Commission Chairman Janaka Ratnayake said.",
        "Group CC will have a power cut of 2 hours and 30 minutes from 6.00am to 8.30am.",
        "Groups MNOXYZ will have a 3 hour power cut from 5.30am to 8.30am.",
        "Download the power cut schedule for August 29, 2022 from here Power-cut-schedule-29-August-2022",
        "The PUCSL had requested the CEB to curtail power cut durations, which would depend on availability of hydropower and other generation sources, the CEB said.",
        "The Ceylon Petroleum Corporation previously released a statement saying that there was an adequate supply of all fuels both imported and refined within the country, after fuel queues were reported once again in some areas. (Colombo/Aug28/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3 hours",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "August 29",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "three hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 29, 2022 Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janaka Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ABCDEFGHIJKLPQRSTUVW",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 hour and 40 minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "daytime & 1 hour and 20 minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janaka Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Group CC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 hours and 30 minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.00am",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.30am",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Groups MNOXYZ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 hour",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.30am",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.30am",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August 29, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Aug28/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අගෝස්තු 29 වන දින පැය 3 ක විදුලි කප්පාදුවක් සැලසුම් කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - 2022 අගෝස්තු 29 වැනි දින ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පුරා පැය තුනක විදුලි කප්පාදුවක් පනවන බව මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාවේ (PUCSL) සභාපති ජනක රත්නායක මහතා ඉන්ධන හිඟයක් මධ්‍යයේ පැවසීය.",
        "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය පැවසුවේ \"ඉන්ධන හිඟයේ ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස ප්‍රමාණවත් නිෂ්පාදනයක් සිදු නොවීම හේතුවෙන් ඉල්ලුම කළමනාකරණ ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගැනීමට ඔවුන්ට බලකෙරුණු\" බවයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව ABCDEFGHIJKLPQRSTUVW හි සියලුම ප්‍රදේශවල දිවා කාලයේ පැය 1 විනාඩි 40 ක කාලයක් සහ රාත්‍රී කාලයේ පැය 1 යි විනාඩි 20 ක කාලයක් විදුලිය විසන්ධි වන බව මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාවේ සභාපති ජනක රත්නායක මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "CC කාණ්ඩයේ පෙරවරු 6.00 සිට 8.30 දක්වා පැය 2 යි විනාඩි 30 ක විදුලි කප්පාදුවක් සිදු කෙරේ.",
        "MNOXYZ කණ්ඩායම්වලට උදෑසන 5.30 සිට 8.30 දක්වා පැය 3ක විදුලි කප්පාදුවක් සිදුවේ.",
        "2022 අගෝස්තු 29 සඳහා වන විදුලි කප්පාදු කාලසටහන මෙතැනින් බාගන්න Power-cut-schedule-29-August-2022",
        "ජල විදුලිය සහ අනෙකුත් ජනන ප්‍රභවයන් මත රඳා පවතින විදුලි කප්පාදු කාල සීමාවන් සීමා කරන ලෙස මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයෙන් ඉල්ලා ඇති බව විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය පවසයි.",
        "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව මීට පෙර නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ ඇතැම් ප්‍රදේශවල නැවත වරක් ඉන්ධන පෝලිම් වාර්තා වීමත් සමඟ ආනයනය කරන ලද සහ පිරිපහදු කරන ලද සියලුම ඉන්ධන සඳහා ප්‍රමාණවත් සැපයුමක් රට තුළ පවතින බවයි. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 28/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "පැය 3",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "අගෝස්තු 29",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පැය තුනක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 29 මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජානක රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ABCDEFGHIJKLPQRSTUVW",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 1 යි විනාඩි 40 යි",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිවා කාලය සහ පැය 1 විනාඩි 20 යි",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජානක රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කණ්ඩායම CC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 2 යි විනාඩි 30 යි",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.00 පෙ.ව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙ.ව.8.30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කණ්ඩායම් MNOXYZ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 3 යි",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.30 ට",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙ.ව.8.30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 28/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஆகஸ்ட் 29 அன்று இலங்கையில் 3 மணி நேரம் மின்வெட்டு அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – 2022 ஆகஸ்ட் 29 அன்று இலங்கை முழுவதும் மூன்று மணிநேர மின்வெட்டு அமுல்படுத்தப்படும் என பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் (PUCSL) தலைவர் ஜனக ரத்நாயக்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"எரிபொருள் பற்றாக்குறையின் விளைவாக போதிய உற்பத்தி இல்லாததால் கோரிக்கை மேலாண்மை நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுக்க வேண்டிய கட்டாயத்தில் உள்ளோம்\" என்று இலங்கை மின்சார சபை கூறியது.",
        "இதன்படி, அனைத்து பகுதிகளிலும் ABCDEFGHIJKLPQRSTUVW பகலில் 1 மணித்தியாலம் 40 நிமிடங்களும் இரவில் 1 மணித்தியாலம் 20 நிமிடங்களும் மின்சாரம் தடைப்படும் என பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் தலைவர் ஜனக ரத்நாயக்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "குரூப் சிசியில் காலை 6.00 மணி முதல் 8.30 மணி வரை 2 மணி நேரம் 30 நிமிடங்கள் மின்வெட்டு இருக்கும்.",
        "MNOXYZ குழுக்களுக்கு காலை 5.30 மணி முதல் 8.30 மணி வரை 3 மணி நேரம் மின்வெட்டு இருக்கும்.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 29, 2022க்கான மின்வெட்டு அட்டவணையை இங்கிருந்து பதிவிறக்கம் செய்யவும் Power-cut-schedule-29-August-2022",
        "PUCSL மின்வெட்டு காலத்தை குறைக்குமாறு CEBயிடம் கோரியிருந்தது, இது நீர் மின்சாரம் மற்றும் பிற உற்பத்தி ஆதாரங்களின் கிடைக்கும் தன்மையைப் பொறுத்து இருக்கும் என்று CEB தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "சில பகுதிகளில் மீண்டும் எரிபொருள் வரிசைகள் பதிவாகியதையடுத்து, நாட்டிற்குள் இறக்குமதி செய்யப்பட்ட மற்றும் சுத்திகரிக்கப்பட்ட அனைத்து எரிபொருட்களுக்கும் போதுமான விநியோகம் இருப்பதாக இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் முன்னர் அறிக்கை ஒன்றை வெளியிட்டிருந்தது. (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்28/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3 மணி நேரம்",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 29",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று மணி நேரங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 29, 2022 பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனக ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ABCDEFGHIJKLPQRSTUVW",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 மணி நேரம் 40 நிமிடங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பகல்நேரம் & 1 மணி நேரம் 20 நிமிடங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனக ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குழு CC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 மணி 30 நிமிடங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 6.00 மணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 8.30 மணி",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குழுக்கள் MNOXYZ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 5.30 மணி",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 8.30 மணி",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 29, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்28/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}