{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Aragalaya-only-managed-to-send-elected-Prez-home-and-bring-in-defeated-Ranil-as-Prez-Wimal/342-241515",
  "time_ut": 1658401416,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Aragalaya only managed to send elected Prez home and bring in defeated Ranil as Prez: Wimal",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Aragalaya only managed to send elected Prez home and bring in defeated Ranil as Prez: Wimal",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "What the Aragalaya (struggle) has finally done was to send home President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, who was elected through an election, and elect Ranil Wickremesinghe, who was defeated in the election, as the President, National Freedom Front (NFF) leader Wimal Weerawansa said today.",
        "He told a news conference that as a result of the struggle on May 9, Ranil Wickremesinghe became the Prime Minister, subsequently became Acting President due to the June 9 struggle and now became the President.",
        "\"This is only what the Aragalaya has achieved now. That is why we did not endorse the slogan that the President should go home. I reiterated that such a move will only allow someone worse than him to come to the office of the President. But, these youth protesters were not wise enough to realize that,\" he said.",
        "Weerawansa said Ranil Wickremesinghe was able to secure 134 votes in Parliament due to the insecurity of parliamentarians created as a result of the struggle.",
        "He said the MPs thought it was Ranil Wickremesinghe who could suppress the struggle and secure their lives than Dullas Alahapperuma who is more democratic.",
        "\"That is why 134 MPs voted for him. As a result of the struggle which sans principle, strategy or purpose, the President who did not shoot at the protesters when they stormed into the President's House has been sent home and created the situation to elect a President who is going suppress them,\" he said.",
        "Weerawansa said they never believe that Ranil Wickremesinghe would be able to rescue the country from the current economic crisis. (Ajith Siriwardana)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Prez",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Aragalaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Freedom Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "May 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Aragalaya",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Siriwardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අරගලයා කළේ තේරී පත් වූ ජනාධිපති ගෙදර යවා පරාජිත රනිල් ජනාධිපති ලෙස ගෙන ඒමට පමණි: විමල්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අරගලය (අරගලය) අවසානයේ කර ඇත්තේ මැතිවරණයකින් තේරී පත් වූ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ගෙදර යවා මැතිවරණයෙන් පරාජය වූ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස පත් කිරීම බව ජාතික නිදහස් පෙරමුණේ නායක විමල් වීරවංශ මහතා පැවසීය. අද.",
        "මැයි 9 අරගලයේ ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරයට පත් වූ බවත්, පසුව ජූනි 9 අරගලය හේතුවෙන් වැඩ බලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා බවට පත් වූ බවත්, දැන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා බවට පත් වූ බවත් ඔහු ප්‍රවෘත්ති සාකච්ඡාවකදී පැවසීය.",
        "“දැන් අරගලයා කරලා තියෙන්නේ ඒකයි.ඒකයි අපි ජනාධිපතිතුමා ගෙදර යා යුතුයි කියන සටන් පාඨය අනුමත කළේ නැත්තේ.එහෙම ගියොත් වෙන්නේ ඔහුට වඩා නරක කෙනෙක්ට ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයට එන්න විතරයි කියලා මම නැවතත් කිව්වා.ඒත්. , ඒ බව අවබෝධ කර ගැනීමට තරම් මෙම තරුණ විරෝධතාකරුවන් ඥානාන්විත වූයේ නැත,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ඡන්ද 134ක් ලබා ගැනීමට හැකිවූයේ අරගලයේ ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස ඇති වූ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ අනාරක්ෂිතභාවය හේතුවෙන් බව වීරවංශ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාට වඩා රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට අරගලය යටපත් කර තම ජීවිතය සුරක්ෂිත කළ හැකි යැයි මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සිතූ බවද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "“ඒ නිසා තමයි මන්ත්‍රීවරු 134ක් එතුමාට ඡන්දය දුන්නේ. ප්‍රතිපත්තියක්, උපායක් හෝ අරමුණක් නැති අරගලයේ ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස විරෝධතාකරුවන් ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට කඩා වැදුණු විට වෙඩි නොතැබූ ජනාධිපතිවරයා ගෙදර යවා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමට තත්ත්වය නිර්මාණය කර තිබෙනවා. ඔවුන්ව මර්දනය කරන්න යන ජනාධිපතිවරයෙක්,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් රට ගොඩගැනීමට රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට හැකිවනු ඇතැයි තමන් කිසිවිටෙක විශ්වාස නොකරන බවද වීරවංශ මහතා පැවසීය. (අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජනාධිපති",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අරගලය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික නිදහස් පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැයි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අරගලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட அதிபரை வீட்டுக்கு அனுப்பவும், தோற்கடிக்கப்பட்ட ரணிலை அதிபராகக் கொண்டுவரவும் அரகலயாவால் முடிந்தது: விமல்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரகலய (போராட்டம்) இறுதியாக செய்தது தேர்தல் மூலம் தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை வீட்டுக்கு அனுப்பி தேர்தலில் தோற்கடிக்கப்பட்ட ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை ஜனாதிபதியாக தெரிவு செய்ததே என தேசிய சுதந்திர முன்னணியின் தலைவர் விமல் வீரவன்ச தெரிவித்துள்ளார். இன்று.",
        "கடந்த மே மாதம் 9ஆம் திகதி நடைபெற்ற போராட்டத்தின் பலனாக ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பிரதமரானார் என்றும், அதனைத் தொடர்ந்து ஜூன் 9ஆம் திகதி நடைபெற்ற போராட்டத்தினால் பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாகவும், தற்போது ஜனாதிபதியானார் எனவும் அவர் செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"இதுதான் இப்போது அரகலயா சாதித்துள்ளது. அதனால்தான் ஜனாதிபதி வீட்டிற்கு செல்ல வேண்டும் என்ற கோஷத்தை நாங்கள் ஆதரிக்கவில்லை. இதுபோன்ற நடவடிக்கை அவரை விட மோசமான ஒருவரை ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகத்திற்கு வர மட்டுமே அனுமதிக்கும் என்பதை நான் மீண்டும் வலியுறுத்தினேன். , இந்த இளைஞர் போராட்டக்காரர்கள் அதை உணரும் அளவுக்கு புத்திசாலித்தனமாக இல்லை,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "போராட்டத்தின் விளைவாக உருவான பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் பாதுகாப்பின்மை காரணமாகவே ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பாராளுமன்றத்தில் 134 வாக்குகளைப் பெற முடிந்ததாக வீரவன்ச தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜனநாயக ரீதியில் செயற்படும் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவை விட ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் போராட்டத்தை அடக்கி தமது உயிரைப் பாதுகாக்க முடியும் என பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் கருதுவதாக அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அதனால்தான் 134 எம்.பி.க்கள் அவருக்கு வாக்களித்தனர். கொள்கையோ, உத்தியோ, நோக்கமோ இல்லாத போராட்டத்தின் விளைவாக, குடியரசுத் தலைவர் மாளிகைக்குள் புகுந்து போராட்டக்காரர்கள் மீது துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தாத குடியரசுத் தலைவரை வீட்டுக்கு அனுப்பி, தேர்ந்தெடுக்கும் சூழ்நிலை உருவாகியுள்ளது. ஒரு ஜனாதிபதி அவர்களை அடக்கப் போகிறார்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் இருந்து நாட்டை மீட்பதற்கு ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவால் முடியும் என தாங்கள் ஒருபோதும் நம்பமாட்டோம் என வீரவன்ச தெரிவித்துள்ளார். (அஜித் சிறிவர்தன)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Prez",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அரகலயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய சுதந்திர முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மே 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரகலயா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}