{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ඉන්ධන-ගන්න-ටෝකන්-එකට-පිටින්-ආ-පොලිසියට-විරෝධයක්/101-615599",
  "time_ut": 1656490634,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඉන්ධන ගන්න ටෝකන් එකට පිටින් ආ පොලිසියට විරෝධයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Protest against the police from the token to buy fuel",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "While using fuel from the Tesbwa road on the Kesbwa road on the Kesbwa road, the police had objected to the tokens with the arrival of fuel to private motorcyclists and duties.",
        "It is said that these people have been waiting in queues for 5 days.",
        "About ten Bandaragama police officers had arrived with their motorbikes and duty motorbikes to refuel. There was strong opposition from the people at that time.",
        "Then the OIC came and tried to explain things to the group but they also objected to him.",
        "The agreement was completed on the agreement for the private keys to the private keys of the police."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Tesbwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kesbwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kesbwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bandaragama",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "OIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන ගන්න ටෝකන් එකට පිටින් ආ පොලිසියට විරෝධයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "බණ්ඩාරගම කැස්බෑව මාර්ගයේ ඉන්ධනහලින් ලබා දුන් ටෝකන්වලට ඉන්ධන නිකුත් කරමින් සිටින අතරතුර පොලිසිය පෞද්ගලික යතුරු පැදිවලට සහ රාජකාරී යතුරු පැදිවලට ඉන්ධන ලබාගැනීමට පැමිණීමත් සමග ටෝකන් ලබාගත් පිරිස ඊට දැඩි විරෝධයක් එල්ල කළහ.",
        "දින 5ක් තිස්සේ මෙම පිරිස පෝලිම්වල රැඳී සිට ඇතැයි ද පැවැසෙයි.",
        "බණ්ඩාරගම පොලිසියේ  නිලධාරීන් දස දෙනකු පමණ සිය පෞද්ගලික යතුරුපැදි ,සහ රාජකාරි යතුරුපැදි රැගෙන  ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා පැමිණ ඇත. ඒ අවස්ථාවේ ජනතාවගෙන් දැඩි විරෝධයක් එල්ල විය.",
        "අනතුරුව ස්ථානාධිපතිවරයා පැමිණ පිරිසට කරුණු පහදා දීමට උත්සාහ කිරීමේදී ඔහුට ද විරෝධය එල්ල කළහ.",
        "අනතුරුව පාරිභෝගිකයන්ට ලබා දෙන ඉන්ධන ප්‍රමාණයම පොලිසියේ පෞද්ගලික යතුරු සඳහා ලබාදීමට එකඟතාවය මත විරෝධය අවසන් කෙරිණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ටෙස්බ්වා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැස්බවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැස්බවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින 5 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්ථානාධිපති",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் வாங்க டோக்கனில் இருந்து காவல்துறைக்கு எதிராக போராட்டம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கெஸ்பவா வீதியில் உள்ள டெஸ்பவா வீதியில் இருந்து எரிபொருளை பயன்படுத்தும் போது, ​​தனியார் மோட்டார் சைக்கிள் ஓட்டுநர்கள் மற்றும் கடமைகளுக்கு எரிபொருள் வருகையுடன் டோக்கன்கள் வழங்கப்படுவதை பொலிஸார் எதிர்த்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இவர்கள் 5 நாட்களாக வரிசையில் காத்து கிடப்பதாக கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "சுமார் பத்து பண்டாரகம பொலிஸ் உத்தியோகத்தர்கள் தமது மோட்டார் சைக்கிள்கள் மற்றும் கடமையிலுள்ள மோட்டார் சைக்கிள்களுடன் எரிபொருள் நிரப்புவதற்காக வந்திருந்தனர். அப்போது மக்கள் மத்தியில் கடும் எதிர்ப்பு கிளம்பியது.",
        "பின்னர் OIC வந்து குழுவிடம் விஷயங்களை விளக்க முயன்றார், ஆனால் அவர்களும் அவரை எதிர்த்தனர்.",
        "காவல்துறையின் அந்தரங்க சாவிக்கான அந்தரங்க சாவிக்கான ஒப்பந்தத்தில் ஒப்பந்தம் முடிந்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "டெஸ்பவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேஸ்பவா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேஸ்பவா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரகம",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "OIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}