{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ජනපති-ජපානයෙන්-කළ-ඉල්ලීම/101-618363",
  "time_ut": 1660838805,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ජනපති ජපානයෙන් කළ ඉල්ලීම",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President's request from Japan",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickramasinghe said in an interview with Reuters yesterday (18) that he is asking Japan to invite the main countries that have given loans to Sri Lanka, including China and India, to come to bilateral debt restructuring talks with Sri Lanka.",
        "President Ranil Wickramasinghe said in the interview that someone should invite the main countries that have given bilateral loans to Sri Lanka to come to discuss the restructuring of the loans given to Sri Lanka and Sri Lanka is asking Japan to do so.",
        "President Ranil Wickramasinghe said that he will visit Japan in September to meet Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida.",
        "According to the reports of the International Monetary Fund, by the end of 2020, Sri Lanka's bilateral debt will be recorded at 6.2 billion US dollars.",
        "Analysts say that since Japan is a Quad country, apart from China, other major countries, including India, which have given bilateral loans to Sri Lanka, can be brought to one table.",
        "Reuters reported that President Ranil Wickramasinghe stated that Sri Lanka is negotiating with China and the responses received from China so far have been positive.",
        "Reuters reported that officials of the International Monetary Fund are scheduled to visit Sri Lanka at the end of August to discuss reaching an official-level agreement with Sri Lanka."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "September",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fumio Kishida",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.2 billion US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපති ජපානයෙන් කළ ඉල්ලීම",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ සාකච්ඡාවලට පැමිණෙන ලෙස චීනය සහ ඉන්දියාව ඇතුළු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ණය ලබා දුන් ප්‍රධාන රටවල්වලට ආරාධනා කරන්නැයි ජපානයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවය සමඟ පැවති සම්මුඛ සාකච්ඡාවකදී ඊයේ(18) ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබා දුන් ණය, ප්‍රතිව්‍යූහගත කිරීම සඳහා සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට පැමිණෙන්නැයි කවුරුන් හෝ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය ලබා දුන් ප්‍රධාන රටවලට ආරාධනා කළ යුතු බවත් එසේ සිදු කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජපානයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින බවත් එම සම්මුඛ සාකච්ඡාවේදී ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පැවසුවේය.",
        "තමන් ජපාන අගමැති ෆුමියෝ කිෂිඩා මහතා මුණගැසීම සඳහා සැප්තැම්බර් මස ජපානයේ සංචාරයක නිරත වන බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා එහිදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ වාර්තා වලට අනුව 2020 වසරේ අවසාන වන විට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය ඇමෙරිකා එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලර් බිලියන 6.2 ලෙස සටහන් වන බව රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවය පෙන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "ජපානය ක්වාඩ් රටක් වන නිසා චීනය හැර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය ලබා දුන් ඉන්දියාව ඇතුළු අනෙකුත් ප්‍රධාන රටවල් එක් මේසයකට රැගෙන ආ හැකි බව විශ්ලේෂකයෝ පවසති.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව චීනය සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කරමින් සිටින බවත් මේ දක්වා චීනයෙන් ලැබුණු ප්‍රතිචාර ධනාත්මක බවත් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළ බව රොයිටර්ස් පුවත් සේවය සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ නිලධාරී මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමකට එළඹීම සඳහා සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නිලධාරීන් අගෝස්තු මස අවසානයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට නියමිත බව රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවය වාර්තා කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fumio Kishida",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020 අවසානයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 6.2 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු අග",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜப்பான் ஜனாதிபதியின் வேண்டுகோள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சீனா, இந்தியா உள்ளிட்ட இலங்கைக்கு கடன் வழங்கிய பிரதான நாடுகளை இலங்கையுடன் இருதரப்பு கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு பேச்சுவார்த்தைக்கு வருமாறு ஜப்பானை அழைப்பதாக ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நேற்று (18) ரொய்ட்டர்ஸுக்கு வழங்கிய நேர்காணலில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கப்பட்ட கடன்களை மறுசீரமைப்பது தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாட வருமாறு இலங்கைக்கு இருதரப்புக் கடன்களை வழங்கிய பிரதான நாடுகளை வருமாறு யாராவது அழைக்க வேண்டும் எனவும் ஜப்பானிடம் இலங்கை அவ்வாறு கோருவதாகவும் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நேர்காணலில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "எதிர்வரும் செப்டெம்பர் மாதம் ஜப்பானுக்கு விஜயம் செய்து ஜப்பானிய பிரதமர் புமியோ கிஷிடாவை சந்திக்கவுள்ளதாக ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் அறிக்கையின்படி, 2020ஆம் ஆண்டு இறுதிக்குள் இலங்கையின் இருதரப்புக் கடன் 6.2 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களாக பதிவாகும்.",
        "ஜப்பான் ஒரு குவாட் நாடு என்பதால், சீனாவைத் தவிர, இலங்கைக்கு இருதரப்புக் கடன்களை வழங்கிய இந்தியா உள்ளிட்ட முக்கிய நாடுகளை ஒரு மேசைக்குக் கொண்டு வரலாம் என்று ஆய்வாளர்கள் கூறுகின்றனர்.",
        "சீனாவுடன் இலங்கை பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தி வருவதாகவும், சீனாவிடம் இருந்து இதுவரை கிடைத்த பதில்கள் சாதகமாக இருப்பதாகவும் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தெரிவித்ததாக ராய்ட்டர்ஸ் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் அதிகாரிகள் ஆகஸ்ட் மாத இறுதியில் இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்து இலங்கையுடன் உத்தியோகபூர்வ அளவிலான உடன்பாட்டை எட்டுவது குறித்து ஆலோசிக்க உள்ளதாக ராய்ட்டர்ஸ் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fumio Kishida",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020 இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.2 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}