{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/Green-Eco-Lodge--රෝහිිත-රාජපක්ෂට-අයත්-බවට-තහවුරු-වෙයි/11-396588",
  "time_ut": 1661357297,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "Green Eco Lodge  රෝහිිත රාජපක්ෂට අයත් බවට තහවුරු වෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "It is confirmed that Green Eco Lodge belongs to Rohitha Rajapaksa",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "It has been confirmed that the Green Eco Lodge luxury hotel complex located on the border of Sinharaja Forest in Kolonna Police Domain belongs to Mr. Rohitha Rajapaksa, the third son of former President Mahanda Rajapaksa.",
        "On May 10, some people set fire to this hotel complex and four suspects involved in it have been arrested by the Colonna Police.",
        "After this hotel complex was set on fire, it was reported that it belongs to Mr. Yoshita Rajapaksa, the second son of Mr. Mahanda Rajapaksa.",
        "However, he denied the reports but did not claim that it belonged to his brother.",
        "There are no information reports that Mr. Rohitha Rajapakse has been engaged in any kind of work till now."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Green Eco Lodge",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Rohitha Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Green Eco Lodge",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinharaja Forest",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kolonna",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rohitha Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahanda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "May 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colonna Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yoshita Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahanda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rohitha Rajapakse",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Green Eco Lodge  රෝහිිත රාජපක්ෂට අයත් බවට තහවුරු වෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොලොන්න පොලිස් වසමේ සිංහරාජ වනාන්තරයට මායිම්ව පිහිිටි Green Eco Lodge සුඛෝපභෝගී හෝටල් සංකීර්ණය හිටපු ජනපති මහන්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ තෙවැනි පුත් රෝහිත රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට අයත් බවට තහවුරු වී තිබේ.",
        "මෙම හෝටල් සංකීර්ණයට පසුගිය මැයිි 10 දා කිසියම් පිරිසක් ගිනි තබා විනාශ කළ අතර එයට සම්බන්ධ සැකකරුවන් සිව්දෙනෙක් කොලොන්න පොලීිසිිය විිසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "මෙම හෝටල් සංකීර්ණය ගිනි තැබීමෙන් පසුව තොරතුරු වාර්තා වූයේ එය මහන්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ දෙවැනි පුත් යෝෂිත රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට අයත් බවයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් ඔහු එම වාර්තා ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළ නමුත් එය තම සහෝදරයාට අයත් බවද ප්‍රකාශ නොකළේය.",
        "රෝහිත රාජපක්ෂ මහතා මේ දක්වා කිසියම් හෝ රැකියාවක නිරතව සිිටින බවට තොරතුරු වාර්තා නොවෙයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Green Eco Lodge",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රෝහිත රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Green Eco Lodge",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහරාජ වනාන්තරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොලොන්න",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෝහිත රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහන්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැයි 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොලොන්න පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yoshita Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහන්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රෝහිත රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "Green Eco Lodge ரோஹித ராஜபக்சவுக்கு சொந்தமானது என்பது உறுதி செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொலன்னாவை பொலிஸ் பிரிவில் சிங்கராஜா வன எல்லையில் அமைந்துள்ள Green Eco Lodge சொகுசு ஹோட்டல் வளாகம் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மஹந்த ராஜபக்சவின் மூன்றாவது மகன் திரு.ரோஹித ராஜபக்ஷவிற்கு சொந்தமானது என உறுதிப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "கடந்த மே மாதம் 10ஆம் திகதி இந்த ஹோட்டல் வளாகத்திற்கு சிலர் தீ வைத்ததுடன், இதில் தொடர்புடைய நான்கு சந்தேக நபர்களும் கொலன்னாவை பொலிஸாரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்த ஹோட்டல் வளாகம் தீ வைத்து எரிக்கப்பட்ட பின்னர், இது திரு.மஹந்த ராஜபக்சவின் இரண்டாவது மகன் திரு.யோஷித ராஜபக்ஷவுக்கு சொந்தமானது என்று தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இருப்பினும், அவர் அந்த செய்திகளை மறுத்தார், ஆனால் அது தனது சகோதரருக்கு சொந்தமானது என்று கூறவில்லை.",
        "திரு.ரோஹித ராஜபக்ஷ இதுவரை எந்த விதமான வேலைகளிலும் ஈடுபட்டதாக எந்த தகவலும் இல்லை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பசுமை சுற்றுச்சூழல் லாட்ஜ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரோஹித ராஜபக்ச",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பசுமை சுற்றுச்சூழல் லாட்ஜ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கராஜா காடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொலொன்னா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோஹித ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹாந்த ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மே 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொலோனா காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yoshita Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹாந்த ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரோஹித ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}