{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/speaker-may-consider-sri-lanka-president-vacated-post-if-no-letter-arrives-report-97410/",
  "time_ut": 1657776300,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Speaker may consider Sri Lanka president vacated post if no letter arrives: report",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Speaker may consider Sri Lanka president vacated post if no letter arrives: report",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has informed the Speaker of Parliament that he would send in his resignation letter very soon, failing which the possibility of him having vacated the position will be looked into, the privately owned NewsFirst network reported quoting Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena.",
        "NewsFirst reported that the president had told the speaker over the phone on Wednesday July 13 night that he would send the letter.",
        "Rajapaksa, who is currently in the Maldives, was originally supposed to resign on Wednesday.",
        "Speaker Abeywardena had told NewsFirst that he is currently under a lot of pressure.",
        "The president had informed him that he would make the letter available very soon.",
        "Since an acting president has been appointed, in the event Rajapaksa does not submit a resignation letter, legal previsions pertaining to considering him as having vacated the post will be looked into, NewsFirst said quoting the speaker.",
        "The news channel also said, citing a parliamentary spokesperson, that convening parliament on Friday July 15 as agreed to earlier is now uncertain as there is no letter from the president yet. (Colombo/Jul14/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NewsFirst",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wednesday July 13 night",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "NewsFirst",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Friday July 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලිපියක් නොලැබුණහොත් කථානායකවරයා ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයා පුරප්පාඩු වූ ධූරය ගැන සලකා බැලිය හැක: වාර්තාව",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "EconomyNext – ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය ඉතා ඉක්මනින් එවන බව කථානායකවරයාට දන්වා ඇති බවත් එසේ නොවුනහොත් එම ධූරයෙන් ඉවත් වීමට ඇති හැකියාව පිළිබඳව සොයා බලන බවත් කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන උපුටා දක්වමින් පුද්ගලිකව අයත් නිව්ස්ෆස්ට් ජාලය වාර්තා කළේය. .",
        "නිව්ස්ෆස්ට් වාර්තා කළේ ජූලි 13 බදාදා රාත්‍රියේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා දුරකථනයෙන් කථානායකවරයාට ලිපිය එවන බව පැවසූ බවයි.",
        "දැනට මාලදිවයිනේ සිටින රාජපක්ෂ බදාදා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට මුලින් නියමිතව තිබුණි.",
        "කතානායක අබේවර්ධන මහතා නිව්ස්ෆස්ට් වෙත ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබුණේ තමන් මේ වනවිට දැඩි පීඩනයකට ලක්ව සිටින බවයි.",
        "එම ලිපිය ඉතා ඉක්මනින් ලබාදීමට කටයුතු කරන බව ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඔහුට දන්වා තිබුණි.",
        "වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු පත් කර ඇති බැවින් රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපියක් ඉදිරිපත් නොකළහොත් ඔහු එම ධූරයෙන් ඉවත් වූවා සේ සැලකීමට අදාළ නීතිමය ප්‍රතිපාදන සොයා බලන බව කථානායකවරයා උපුටා දක්වමින් NewsFirst ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "මීට පෙර එකඟ වූ පරිදි ජූලි 15 සිකුරාදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කැඳවීම තවමත් ජනාධිපතිවරයාගෙන් ලිපියක් නොමැති බැවින් දැන් අවිනිශ්චිත බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු ප්‍රකාශකයෙකු උපුටා දක්වමින් ප්‍රවෘත්ති නාලිකාව පැවසීය. (කොළඹ/ජූලි14/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NewsFirst",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13 බදාදා රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "NewsFirst",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 15 සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கடிதம் வரவில்லை என்றால் இலங்கை அதிபர் பதவியை காலி செய்வது குறித்து சபாநாயகர் பரிசீலிக்கலாம்: அறிக்கை",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் – இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ, தனது இராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை விரைவில் அனுப்பவுள்ளதாக சபாநாயகருக்கு அறிவித்துள்ளதாகவும், தவறினால் அவர் பதவியை விட்டு விலகுவதற்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகள் ஆராயப்படும் என சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தனவை மேற்கோள்காட்டி தனியாருக்கு சொந்தமான நியூஸ் ஃபர்ஸ்ட் வலையமைப்பு தெரிவித்துள்ளது. .",
        "கடிதத்தை அனுப்புவதாக ஜனாதிபதி ஜூலை 13 புதன்கிழமை இரவு சபாநாயகருக்கு தொலைபேசியில் தெரிவித்ததாக நியூஸ் ஃபர்ஸ்ட் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "தற்போது மாலத்தீவில் இருக்கும் ராஜபக்சே, முதலில் புதன்கிழமை பதவி விலகுவதாக இருந்தது.",
        "சபாநாயகர் அபேவர்தன, தாம் தற்போது அதிக அழுத்தங்களுக்கு உள்ளாகியுள்ளதாக நியூஸ் ஃபர்ஸ்டிடம் தெரிவித்திருந்தார்.",
        "இதற்கான கடிதத்தை விரைவில் கிடைக்கச் செய்வதாக ஜனாதிபதி அவருக்கு அறிவித்திருந்தார்.",
        "செயல் தலைவர் ஒருவர் நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதால், ராஜபக்ச ராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை சமர்ப்பிக்காத பட்சத்தில், அவர் பதவியில் இருந்து விலகியதாக கருதுவது தொடர்பான சட்ட விதிகள் ஆராயப்படும் என சபாநாயகரை மேற்கோள் காட்டி நியூஸ் ஃபர்ஸ்ட் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "முன்னதாக ஒப்புக்கொண்டபடி ஜூலை 15 வெள்ளிக்கிழமை பாராளுமன்றத்தை கூட்டுவது இப்போது நிச்சயமற்றது, ஜனாதிபதியிடமிருந்து இன்னும் கடிதம் வரவில்லை என்று நாடாளுமன்ற செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் ஒருவரை மேற்கோள் காட்டி செய்தி சேனல் கூறியது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை 14/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நியூஸ்ஃபர்ஸ்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புதன்கிழமை ஜூலை 13 இரவு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நியூஸ்ஃபர்ஸ்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 15 வெள்ளிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}