{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/02/it-s-a-good-budget-mahinda-rajapaksa-on-budget-amendment-2022/",
  "time_ut": 1662128640,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "It’s a good budget – Mahinda Rajapaksa on Budget Amendment 2022",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "It’s a good budget – Mahinda Rajapaksa on Budget Amendment 2022",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Former Sri Lankan President and the Leader of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna Mahinda Rajapaksa said the Budget Amendment 2022 was a positive one.",
        "He also told reporters while leaving the Parliament that he was informed of a possible return to Sri Lanka by his brother Gotabaya Rajapaksa, and has no idea if the latter would be joining politics.",
        "It's a good budget – Mahinda Rajapaksa on Budget Amendment 2022, & more.#lka #SriLanka #SLnews #News1st #Budget #Amendment #MahindaRajapaksa #SLPP pic.twitter.com/iNqCT1DGV0",
        "It’s a good budget – Mahinda Rajapaksa on Budget Amendment 2022",
        "Chinese Fertilizer: Auditor General recommends to recover losses; prosecute those responsible"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Budget Amendment 2022",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "MahindaRajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඒක හොඳ අයවැයක් - මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ 2022 අයවැය සංශෝධනය ගැන",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 2022 අයවැය සංශෝධනය ධනාත්මක එකක් බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා හිටපු ජනාධිපති සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ නායක මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ඔහු පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් පිටව යන අතරතුර මාධ්‍යවේදීන් අමතමින් කියා සිටියේ තම සොහොයුරු ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ විසින් නැවත ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණිය හැකි බව තමාට දන්වා ඇති බවත්, ඔහු දේශපාලනයට සම්බන්ධ වන්නේ දැයි නොදන්නා බවත්ය.",
        "එය හොඳ අයවැයක් - 2022 අයවැය සංශෝධනය පිළිබඳ මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ, සහ තවත්.#lka #SriLanka #SLnews #News1st #Budget #Amendment #MahindaRajapaksa #SLPP pic.twitter.com/iNqCT1DGV0",
        "ඒක හොඳ අයවැයක් - මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ 2022 අයවැය සංශෝධනය ගැන",
        "චීන පොහොර: පාඩු අයකර ගැනීමට විගණකාධිපති නිර්දේශ කරයි; වගකිව යුත්තන්ට නඩු පවරන්න"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අයවැය සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இது ஒரு நல்ல வரவு செலவுத் திட்டம் - வரவு செலவுத் திருத்தம் 2022 இல் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); வரவு செலவுத் திருத்தம் 2022 சாதகமான ஒன்று என இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் தலைவருமான மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் இருந்து வெளியேறும் போது செய்தியாளர்களிடம் பேசிய அவர், தனது சகோதரர் கோத்தபய ராஜபக்ச இலங்கைக்கு திரும்புவது சாத்தியம் என தனக்குத் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டதாகவும், அவர் அரசியலில் சேருவது குறித்து எனக்கு எதுவும் தெரியாது என்றும் கூறினார்.",
        "இது ஒரு நல்ல வரவு செலவுத் திட்டம் – மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ வரவு செலவுத் திருத்தம் 2022, மேலும் பல.#lka #SriLanka #SLnews #News1st #Budget #Amendment #MahindaRajapaksa #SLPP pic.twitter.com/iNqCT1DGV0",
        "இது ஒரு நல்ல வரவு செலவுத் திட்டம் - வரவு செலவுத் திருத்தம் 2022 இல் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
        "சீன உரம்: ஆடிட்டர் ஜெனரல் இழப்புகளை மீட்டெடுக்க பரிந்துரைக்கிறார்; பொறுப்பானவர்கள் மீது வழக்குத் தொடரவும்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பட்ஜெட் திருத்தம் 2022",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}