{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/நான்-குற்றவாளி-அல்ல/175-299804",
  "time_ut": 1657053186,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "’நான் குற்றவாளி அல்ல’",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "'I am not guilty'",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former President Maithripala Sirisena has said in the House that he is not going to accept that he is guilty of the Easter Sunday attack and that he rejects the allegations related to it.",
        "Addressing the Parliament yesterday (5), in the report of the Presidential Commission on the Manusha Nanayakkara Sunday attack incident,",
        "The former President said this while responding to the comment made by the opposition leader Sajith Premadasa about how he had held a meeting with the accused person and how he was going to cooperate with him.",
        "Since 6 months ago, the Sri Lanka Freedom Party had discussed with the President and demanded the formation of an all-party government. It was also said that we are ready to take responsibility in that government.",
        "Meanwhile, if the case is to be prosecuted according to the report of the commission regarding the Easter Sunday attack, the Attorney General's Department can do so. There are already 8 human rights cases pending against me in the High Court. Similarly, there are up to 400 cases filed by the affected parties against me, the former Prime Minister and the Defense Secretary.",
        "In this case, I set up a commission regarding the Easter Sunday attack. They said they thought they knew the attack was going to happen in that suggestion.",
        "According to this, the commission should file a case. But no case was filed in this regard. Therefore, I am not going to admit that I am guilty anywhere. He said he rejects it."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Easter",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manusha Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6 months ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Easter",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "up to 400",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defense",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Easter",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "'මම වැරදිකරුවෙක් නෙවෙයි'",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාස්කු ඉරිදා ප්‍රහාරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් තමන් වැරදිකරු බව පිළිනොගන්නා බවත් ඊට අදාළ චෝදනා ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන බවත් හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා සභාවේදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ඊයේ (5) පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අමතමින් මනූෂ නානායක්කාර ඉරිදා ප්‍රහාරයේ සිද්ධිය පිළිබඳ ජනාධිපති කොමිෂන් සභා වාර්තාවේ මෙසේද සඳහන් වේ.",
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා චූදිතයා සමඟ හමුවක් පැවැත්වූ ආකාරය සහ ඔහු සමඟ සහයෝගයෙන් කටයුතු කරන ආකාරය පිළිබඳව කළ ප්‍රකාශයට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා මේ බව සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මීට මාස 6කට පෙර සිට ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය ජනාධිපතිවරයා සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කර සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටියා. ඒ ආණ්ඩුවේ වගකීම ගන්න අපි ලෑස්තියි කියලත් කිව්වා.",
        "මේ අතර පාස්කු ඉරිදා ප්‍රහාරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් කොමිෂන් සභා වාර්තාවට අනුව නඩුව විභාග කරන්නේ නම් නීතිපති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට එය කළ හැකියි. මට විරුද්ධව මානව හිමිකම් නඩු 8ක් දැනටමත් මහාධිකරණයේ විභාග වෙනවා. ඒ වගේ ම මට, හිටපු අගමැතිතුමාට, ආරක්‍ෂක ලේකම්තුමාට විරුද්ධව විපතට පත් පාර්ශ්ව විසින් පවරා ඇති නඩු සංඛ්‍යාව 400ක් දක්වා තිබෙනවා.",
        "මේ අවස්ථාවේ දී පාස්කු ඉරිදා ප්‍රහාරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් මම කොමිසමක් පත් කළා. එම යෝජනාව තුළ ප්‍රහාරය සිදුවනු ඇතැයි තමන් දන්නා බව ඔවුන් සිතූ බව ඔවුහු පැවසූහ.",
        "මේ අනුව කොමිසම නඩු පැවරිය යුතුයි. නමුත් මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් කිසිම නඩුවක් ගොනු කළේ නැහැ. ඒ නිසා මම කොතනකවත් වැරදිකාරයෙක් කියලා පිළිගන්න යන්නේ නැහැ. ඔහු එය ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන බව පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනූෂ නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාස 6කට කලින්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "400 දක්වා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "’நான் குற்றவாளி அல்ல’",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "உயிர்த்த ஞாயிறு தாக்குதல் சம்பவத்தில் நான் குற்றவாளி என்பதனை எங்கேயும் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப் போவதில்லை என்றும், அது தொடர்பான குற்றச்சாட்டுகளை தான்  நிராகரிக்கின்றேன் என்றும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன சபையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நேற்று (5)  உரையாற்றும் போது, மனுஷ நாணயக்கார உயிர்த்த ஞாயிறு தாக்குதல் சம்பவம் தொடர்பான ஜனாதிபதி ஆணைக்குழுவின் அறிக்கையில்,",
        "குற்றவாளி என்று குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ள நபருடன் எப்படி எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச சந்திப்பை நடத்தியுள்ளார் என்றும், அவருடன் எப்படி இணைந்து செயற்படப் போகின்றார் என்று வெளியிட்ட கருத்து தொடர்பில் பதிலளித்து உரையாற்றும் போதே முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி இவ்வாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நாங்கள் 6 மாதங்களுக்கு முன்னர் இருந்தே ஜனாதிபதியுடன் ஶ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி கலந்துரையாடி சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்குமாறு கோரிக்கை விடுத்தோம். அந்த அரசாங்கத்தில் பொறுப்பை ஏற்க நாங்கள் தயார் என்றும் கூறப்பட்டது.",
        "இதேவேளை உயிர்த்த ஞாயிறு தாக்குதல் தொடர்பான ஆணைக்குழுவினர் அறிக்கையின்படி வழக்கு தொடர்வதென்றால் சட்டமா அதிபர் திணைக்களத்தினால் அதனை செய்ய முடியும். எனக்கு எதிராக ஏற்கனவே 8 மனித உரிமைகள் வழகுகள் உயர்நீதிமன்றத்தில் உள்ளன. அதேபோன்று பாதிக்கப்பட்ட தரப்பினரால் என்னிடமும், முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மற்றும் பாதுகாப்பு செயலாளர் உள்ளிட்டோரிடம் நஷ்ட ஈடுகோரி 400 வரையிலான வழக்குகளும் உள்ளன.",
        "இந்நிலையில் உயிர்த்த ஞாயிறு தாக்குதல் தொடர்பான ஆணைக்குழுவை நானே அமைத்தேன். அந்த பரிந்துரையில் அந்த தாக்குதல் நடக்கும் என்று எனக்கு தெரியும் என்று நினைப்பதாகவே அவர்கள் கூறியுள்ளனர்.",
        "இதன்படி அந்த ஆணைக்குழுவினால் வழக்கு தொடுக்க வேண்டும். ஆனால் அது தொடர்பில் வழக்கு தொடுக்கவில்லை. இதனால் இதில் நான் குற்றவாளி என்பதனை எங்கேயும் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப் போவதில்லை. அதனை நிராகரிக்கின்றேன் என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனுஷ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6 மாதங்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "400 வரை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}