{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/28/parliament-prorogue-with-effect-from-today-28-next-session-on-3rd-august/",
  "time_ut": 1659022320,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Parliament prorogued with effect from today (28); Next session on 3rd August",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Parliament prorogued with effect from today (28); Next session on 3rd August",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); President Ranil Wickremesinghe has decided to prorogue Parliament with effect from midnight today (28).",
        "According to the extraordinary gazette issued this evening, the next session will commence at 10:30 AM on 3rd August 2022.",
        "A prorogation which is a temporary recess of Parliament, should not extend to a period of more than two months, However, such date for summoning Parliament may be advanced by another Presidential Proclamation provided it is summoned for a date not less than three days from the date of such fresh proclamation.",
        "When Parliament is prorogued, the Proclamation should notify the date for the commencement of the new Session of Parliament under Paragraph (3) of Article 70 of the Constitution.",
        "During the prorogation the Speaker continues to function and the Members retain their membership even though they do not attend meetings of Parliament.",
        "The effect of a prorogation is to suspend all current Business before the House and all proceedings pending at the time are quashed except impeachments.",
        "A Bill, motion or question of the same substance cannot be introduced for a second time during the same Session.  However, it could be carried forward at a subsequent Session after a prorogation.",
        "“All matters which having been duly brought before Parliament, have not been disposed of at the time of the prorogation of Parliament, may be proceeded with during the next Session,” states the Paragraph (4) of Article 70 of the Constitution.",
        "In the light of this constitutional provision, a prorogation does not put an end to pending Business.  Thus, a pending matter may be proceeded with from that stage onwards after the commencement of the new Session.  At the beginning of a new Session all items of Business which were in the Order Paper of Parliament need to be re-listed, if it is desired to continue with them.",
        "At the end of a prorogation a new Session begins and is ceremonially declared open by the President.  He is empowered under the Constitution to make a Statement of Government Policy in Parliament at the commencement of each Session of Parliament and to preside at ceremonial sittings of Parliament in terms of the provisions stipulated in Paragraph (2) of Article 33 of the Constitution.",
        "The President is empowered to make a statement of Government Policy at the commencement of each new Session.  In the past, it was known as the Throne Speech which was delivered by the Governor-General.",
        "Parliament prorogued with effect from today (28); Next session on 3rd August",
        "NO split in the SLPP, but there is a conspiracy: Kariyawasam"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "28",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Next",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "3rd",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "August",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "midnight today",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "this evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "10:30 AM on",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than two months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Presidential Proclamation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "less than three days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Proclamation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Session",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 70 of the Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Session",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Session",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Session",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 70 of the Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Session",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Session",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Session",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 33 of the Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Session",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Governor-General",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Next",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3rd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අද (28) සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කල්දමයි; මීළඟ සැසිය අගෝස්තු 3 වැනිදා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); අද (28) මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කල් තැබීමට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා තීරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "අද සවස නිකුත් කරන ලද අතිවිශේෂ ගැසට් පත්‍රයට අනුව, මීළඟ සැසිවාරය 2022 අගෝස්තු 3 වැනි දින පෙරවරු 10:30 ට ආරම්භ වේ.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ තාවකාලික විරාමයක් වන කල් තැබීමක් මාස දෙකකට වඩා වැඩි කාලයක් දක්වා දීර්ඝ නොකළ යුතුය, කෙසේ වෙතත්, පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කැඳවීමේ එවැනි දිනයක් දින තුනකට නොඅඩු දිනයකට කැඳවනු ලැබුවහොත් වෙනත් ජනාධිපති ප්‍රකාශයක් මගින් එය කල් දැමිය හැකිය. එවැනි නැවුම් ප්‍රකාශයක දිනය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කල් තබන විට, ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 70 වැනි ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ (3) ඡේදය යටතේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ නව සැසිවාරය ආරම්භ වන දිනය ප්‍රකාශය මගින් දැනුම් දිය යුතුය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු වාර අවසන් කිරීමේදී කථානායකවරයා දිගටම කටයුතු කරන අතර මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු රැස්වීම්වලට නොපැමිණි නමුත් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සිය සාමාජිකත්වය රඳවා ගනී.",
        "කල් දැමීමක ප්‍රතිඵලය වන්නේ සභාව ඉදිරියේ පවතින සියලුම කටයුතු අත්හිටුවීම සහ දෝෂාභියෝග හැර එම අවස්ථාවේ පවතින සියලුම කටයුතු අවලංගු කිරීමයි.",
        "එම සැසියේදීම එම ද්‍රව්‍යයේම පනත් කෙටුම්පතක්, යෝජනාවක් හෝ ප්‍රශ්නයක් දෙවන වරටත් ඉදිරිපත් කළ නොහැක. කෙසේ වෙතත්, එය කල්දැමීමෙන් පසු ඊළඟ සැසිවාරයකදී ඉදිරියට ගෙන යා හැකිය.",
        "\"පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කල් තබන අවස්ථාවේ නිසි පරිදි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කර නොමැති සියලු කරුණු ඊළඟ සැසිවාරයේදී ඉදිරියට ගෙන යා හැකිය\" යනුවෙන් ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 70 වැනි ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ (4) ඡේදයේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "මෙම ව්‍යවස්ථාමය ප්‍රතිපාදනය අනුව, කල් දැමීමක් පොරොත්තු ව්‍යාපාරවලට තිත තබන්නේ නැත. මේ අනුව, නව සැසිවාරය ආරම්භ වූ පසු එම අදියරේ සිට ඉදිරියට යාමට නියමිත කරුණක් ඉදිරියට ගෙන යා හැකිය. නව සැසිවාරයක ආරම්භයේ දී පාර්ලිමේන්තු න්‍යාය පත්‍රයේ තිබූ සියලුම ව්‍යාපාර අයිතම දිගටම කරගෙන යාමට අවශ්‍ය නම් ඒවා නැවත ලැයිස්තුගත කළ යුතුය.",
        "කල් දැමීමක් අවසානයේ නව සැසිවාරයක් ආරම්භ වන අතර එය ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් උත්සවාකාරයෙන් විවෘත කරනු ලැබේ. ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 33 වැනි ඡේදයේ (2) ඡේදයේ දක්වා ඇති විධිවිධානවලට අනුව සෑම පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසිවාරයක්ම ආරම්භයේදී පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ රජයේ ප්‍රතිපත්ති ප්‍රකාශයක් කිරීමට සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ උත්සව සභා රැස්වීම්වල මුලසුන දැරීමට ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව යටතේ ඔහුට බලය ඇත.",
        "සෑම නව සැසිවාරයක්ම ආරම්භයේදීම රජයේ ප්‍රතිපත්ති ප්‍රකාශයක් කිරීමට ජනාධිපතිවරයාට බලය ඇත. අතීතයේ එය හැඳින්වූයේ ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයා විසින් කරන ලද රාජාසන කතාව ලෙසිනි.",
        "අද (28) සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කල්දමයි; මීළඟ සැසිය අගෝස්තු 3 වැනිදා",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ බෙදීමක් නැහැ, නමුත් කුමන්ත්‍රණයක් තියෙනවා: කාරියවසම්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "28",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඊළඟ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "3 වැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "අගෝස්තු",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "10:30 පෙ.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස දෙකකට වඩා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ප්‍රකාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින තුනකට වඩා අඩුය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රකාශනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාරය",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 70 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාරය",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාරය",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාරය",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 70 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වාරය",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාරය",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වාරය",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාවේ 33 වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වාරය",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුකාර ජනරාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாராளுமன்றம் இன்று (28) முதல் அமுலுக்கு வரும் வகையில் ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்டது; அடுத்த அமர்வு ஆகஸ்ட் 3ஆம் தேதி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இன்று (28) நள்ளிரவு முதல் அமுலுக்கு வரும் வகையில் நாடாளுமன்றத்தை ஒத்திவைக்க ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தீர்மானித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இன்று மாலை வெளியிடப்பட்ட அசாதாரண வர்த்தமானியின்படி, அடுத்த அமர்வு 2022 ஆகஸ்ட் 3 ஆம் தேதி காலை 10:30 மணிக்கு தொடங்கும்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தின் தற்காலிக இடைநிறுத்தம், இரண்டு மாதங்களுக்கு மேல் நீட்டிக்கப்படக்கூடாது, இருப்பினும், பாராளுமன்றத்தை அழைப்பதற்கான அத்தகைய தேதி மற்றொரு ஜனாதிபதியின் பிரகடனத்தின் மூலம் முன்னெடுக்கப்படலாம். அத்தகைய புதிய அறிவிப்பு தேதி.",
        "பாராளுமன்றம் ஒத்திவைக்கப்படும் போது, ​​அரசியலமைப்பின் 70வது பிரிவின் பத்தி (3)ன் கீழ் புதிய பாராளுமன்ற கூட்டத்தொடர் தொடங்கும் தேதியை பிரகடனம் அறிவிக்க வேண்டும்.",
        "இடைநீக்கத்தின் போது சபாநாயகர் தொடர்ந்து செயல்படுகிறார் மற்றும் உறுப்பினர்கள் நாடாளுமன்றக் கூட்டங்களில் கலந்து கொள்ளாவிட்டாலும் தங்கள் உறுப்பினர்களைத் தக்க வைத்துக் கொள்கிறார்கள்.",
        "பதவிநீக்கத்தின் விளைவு, சபைக்கு முன்பாக நடப்பு அனைத்து அலுவல்களையும் இடைநிறுத்துவது மற்றும் அந்த நேரத்தில் நிலுவையில் உள்ள அனைத்து நடவடிக்கைகளும் குற்றஞ்சாட்டுதல்களைத் தவிர ரத்து செய்யப்படும்.",
        "அதே அமர்வின் போது அதே பொருளின் மசோதா, இயக்கம் அல்லது கேள்வியை இரண்டாவது முறையாக அறிமுகப்படுத்த முடியாது. இருப்பினும், இது ஒரு ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்ட பிறகு அடுத்த அமர்வில் முன்னோக்கி கொண்டு செல்லப்படலாம்.",
        "\"பாராளுமன்றம் ஒத்திவைக்கப்படும் நேரத்தில் உரிய முறையில் தீர்வு காணப்படாத அனைத்து விஷயங்களும் அடுத்த அமர்வின் போது தொடரப்படலாம்\" என்று அரசியலமைப்பின் 70வது பிரிவின் பத்தி (4) கூறுகிறது.",
        "இந்த அரசியலமைப்புச் சட்டத்தின் வெளிச்சத்தில், நிலுவையில் உள்ள வணிகத்திற்கு ஒரு ஒத்திவைப்பு முற்றுப்புள்ளி வைக்காது. எனவே, நிலுவையில் உள்ள ஒரு விஷயத்தை புதிய அமர்வு தொடங்கிய பிறகு அந்த நிலையிலிருந்து தொடரலாம். புதிய அமர்வின் தொடக்கத்தில், நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் ஒழுங்குப் பத்திரத்தில் இருந்த அனைத்து வணிகப் பொருட்களையும் தொடர விரும்பினால், அவை மீண்டும் பட்டியலிடப்பட வேண்டும்.",
        "ஒரு ஒத்திவைப்பு முடிவில் ஒரு புதிய அமர்வு தொடங்குகிறது மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதியால் சம்பிரதாயபூர்வமாக திறக்கப்படும். பாராளுமன்றத்தின் ஒவ்வொரு கூட்டத் தொடரின் தொடக்கத்திலும் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் அரசாங்கக் கொள்கை அறிக்கையை வெளியிடுவதற்கும் அரசியலமைப்பின் 33 வது பிரிவின் பத்தி (2) இல் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ள விதிகளின்படி பாராளுமன்றத்தின் சம்பிரதாய அமர்வுகளுக்குத் தலைமை தாங்குவதற்கும் அரசியலமைப்பின் கீழ் அவருக்கு அதிகாரம் உள்ளது.",
        "ஒவ்வொரு புதிய அமர்வின் தொடக்கத்திலும் அரசாங்க கொள்கை அறிக்கையை வெளியிட ஜனாதிபதிக்கு அதிகாரம் உள்ளது. கடந்த காலங்களில் கவர்னர் ஜெனரலால் ஆற்றப்படும் சிம்மாசன உரை என்று அழைக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "பாராளுமன்றம் இன்று (28) முதல் அமுலுக்கு வரும் வகையில் ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்டது; அடுத்த அமர்வு ஆகஸ்ட் 3ஆம் தேதி",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவில் பிளவு இல்லை, ஆனால் சதி உள்ளது: காரியவசம்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "28",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "அடுத்தது",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "3வது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று நள்ளிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "10:30 AM அன்று",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு மாதங்களுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி பிரகடனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று நாட்களுக்கு குறைவாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரகடனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமர்வு",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பின் பிரிவு 70",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமர்வு",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமர்வு",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமர்வு",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பின் பிரிவு 70",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமர்வு",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமர்வு",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமர்வு",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பின் பிரிவு 33",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமர்வு",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கவர்னர் ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்தது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}