{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-paddy-cultivation-hit-record-in-yala-minister-98967/",
  "time_ut": 1661338320,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka paddy cultivation hit record in Yala: Minister",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka paddy cultivation hit record in Yala: Minister",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka farmers are estimated to have sown a record 512,000 hectares of paddy in the minor Yala 2022 season spurred by rising rise prices and a food shortage scare, Agriculture Minister Mahinda Amaraweera said.",
        "Sri Lanka was originally expecting only 275,000 hectares of rice to be cultivated despite a chemical fertilizer ban imposed by ousted President Gotabaya Rajapaksa being lifted as forex shortages from a broken soft-peg blocked imports, he said.",
        "Sri Lanka usually sees about 400,000 hectares of rice cultivated in the Yala season yielding about 1.5 million tonnes of paddy and 800,000 cultivated in the Main Maha season.",
        "If 500,000 hectares of rice was cultivated over 2.0 million tonnes of paddy would be harvested provided fertilizer was given on time could be milled into 1.36 million tonnes of rice, enough to feed the country for more than 6 months.",
        "However farmers have said fields cultivated with organic fertilizer produce about 30 to 40 percent less yield.",
        "“We do not know exactly how much paddy would be produced,” Minister Amaraweera said. “Some of the farmers who cultivated early did not get chemical fertilizer. Some of them got fertilizer. So we cannot make the forecasts accurately as we did before.",
        "“However because the extent cultivated was high we think there will be a considerable harvest.”",
        "Tests carried out by Sri Lanka’s rice research stations have shown that 70/30 mix of chemical and organic fertilizer produced the best, results, Minister Amaraweera said.",
        "Authorities were at first expecting rice to be imported from around September, but now it is expected that stocks will last till late December he said.",
        "Minister Amaraweera said earlier that over 230,000 tonnes of rice had been imported to Sri Lanka this year. Sri Lanka consumes about 200,000MT of rice a month.",
        "Due to money printing, and a ban on open account imports there were fears of food shortages.",
        "However President Ranil Wickremesinghe has also liberalized rice imports preventing a shortage.",
        "Sri Lanka had good rains late in the Yala season in 2022 allowing farmers to go to the field.",
        "Paddy prices soared above 120 to 150 during the season as food shortage scare was spread mainly by politicians giving them an incentive to cultivate despite tractor fees for tiling land jumping from around 12,000 rupees to over 20,000 an acre and there being diesel shortages.",
        "“Some people went to Hambantota and bought paddy at 200 rupees a kilogram, and bought all the rice in supermarkets,” Minister Gunewardene said. “Now they have weevils.”",
        "Despite better harvests, the broken soft-peg with the rupee falling to 360 to the US dollar from 182 over two years had driven rice to over 220 rupee a kilogram, and proteins even higher, putting food out of the reach of the less affluent.",
        "Minister Amaraweera said his main task was now to make sure diesel was available for framers , with complaints that fuel was not readily available for harvesting equipment due to forex shortages from a broken soft-peg.",
        "Sri Lanka also raised 110 million dollars World Bank credit to import urea for the next season but the first tender for 150,000MT had only resulted in a 12,500MT order. (Colombo/Aug24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "512,000 hectares",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 season",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "275,000 hectares",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 400,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "season",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 1.5 million tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "800,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Main Maha",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "500,000 hectares",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.0 million tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.36 million tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 6 months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "September",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "late December",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "season",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "above 120 to 150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the season",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20,000 an acre",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunewardene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "360",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "182",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "220",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "110 million dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next season",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12,500MT",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා වී වගාව යාල ප්‍රදේශයේ වාර්තාවක් තබයි: ඇමති",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආර්ථිකය - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ගොවීන් 2022 යල කන්නයේ වාර්තාගත වී හෙක්ටයාර 512,000ක් වපුරනු ඇතැයි ගණන් බලා ඇති බව කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුලින් අපේක්ෂා කළේ සහල් හෙක්ටයාර් 275,000ක් පමණක් වගා කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වූ නමුත්, බලයෙන් පහකළ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ විසින් පනවන ලද රසායනික පොහොර තහනම නිසා විදේශ විනිමය හිඟය ඉවත් කළද ආනයනය අවහිර වී ඇති බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සාමාන්‍යයෙන් යල කන්නයේ හෙක්ටයාර් 400,000 ක් පමණ වී වගා කරන අතර වී ටොන් මිලියන 1.5 ක් පමණ අස්වැන්නක් ලබා දෙන අතර ප්‍රධාන මහ කන්නයේ 800,000 ක් වගා කෙරේ.",
        "සහල් හෙක්ටයාර් ලක්ෂ 5ක් වගා කළහොත් වී ටොන් මිලියන 2.0කට වඩා වැඩි අස්වැන්නක් ලබා ගත හැකි වන්නේ නියමිත වේලාවට පොහොර ලබා දුන්නේ නම් සහල් ටොන් මිලියන 1.36ක් බවට පත් කළ හැකි අතර එය මාස 6කට වඩා වැඩි කාලයක් රට පෝෂණය කිරීමට ප්‍රමාණවත් වේ.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් ගොවීන් පවසා ඇත්තේ කාබනික පොහොර යොදා වගා කරන කෙත්වලින් සියයට 30ත් 40ත් අතර අස්වැන්නක් අඩු බවයි.",
        "වී ප්‍රමාණය කොපමණ ප්‍රමාණයක් නිෂ්පාදනය කරයිද යන්න අපි හරියටම නොදනිමු යැයි අමාත්‍ය අමරවීර මහතා පැවසීය. “කලින් වගා කළ සමහර ගොවීන්ට රසායනික පොහොර ලැබුණේ නැහැ. සමහරුන්ට පොහොර ලැබුණා. ඒ නිසා අපිට කලින් කළා වගේ අනාවැකි නිවැරදිව කරන්න බැහැ.",
        "\"කෙසේ වෙතත් වගා කරන ලද ප්‍රමාණය ඉහළ බැවින් සැලකිය යුතු අස්වැන්නක් ලැබෙනු ඇතැයි අපි සිතමු.\"",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සහල් පර්යේෂණ මධ්‍යස්ථාන විසින් සිදු කරන ලද පරීක්ෂණවලින් හෙළි වී ඇත්තේ රසායනික හා කාබනික පොහොර මිශ්‍ර 70/30 හොඳම ප්‍රතිඵලය නිපදවා ඇති බව බව අමාත්‍ය අමරවීර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "සැප්තැම්බර් මාසයේ සිට සහල් ආනයනය කිරීමට බලධාරීන් මුලදී අපේක්ෂා කළ නමුත් දැන් දෙසැම්බර් අග දක්වා සහල් තොග පවතිනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කරන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මේ වසරේ සහල් ටොන් දෙලක්ෂ තිස් දහසකට අධික ප්‍රමාණයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ආනයනය කර ඇති බව අමාත්‍ය අමරවීර මීට පෙර ප්‍රකාශ කළා. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මසකට සහල් මෙ.ටොන් 200,000ක් පමණ පරිභෝජනය කරයි.",
        "මුදල් මුද්‍රණය කිරීම සහ විවෘත ගිණුම් ආනයනය තහනම් කිරීම හේතුවෙන් ආහාර හිඟයක් ඇති වේ යැයි බියක් ඇති විය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, සහල් හිඟයක් ඇතිවීම වළක්වාලමින් සහල් ආනයනය ලිහිල් කිරීමට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා කටයුතු කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "2022 යල කන්නයේ ප්‍රමාද වී ගොවීන්ට කෙතට යාමට ඉඩ සලසමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හොඳ වර්ෂාපතනයක් ලැබුණි.",
        "කන්නයේ වී මිල 120 සිට 150 දක්වා ඉහළ ගියේ ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන්ම දේශපාලකයින් විසින් වගා කිරීමට දිරිගැන්වීමක් ලබා දීම නිසා ආහාර හිඟ බිය පැතිරීම නිසා ඉඩම් අක්කරයක් රුපියල් 12,000 සිට 20,000 දක්වා පනිමින් ට්‍රැක්ටර් ගාස්තුව තිබියදීත්, ඩීසල් හිඟයක් පැවතීමත්ය.",
        "“සමහර අය හම්බන්තොට ගිහින් වී කිලෝවක් රුපියල් 200ට අරගෙන, සුපිරි වෙළෙඳසල්වලින් සහල් ඔක්කොම ගත්තා,” යැයි ගුණවර්ධන ඇමැතිවරයා කීවේය. \"දැන් ඔවුන්ට කුරුමිණියන් ඇත.\"",
        "වඩා හොඳ අස්වැන්නක් ලැබුවද, වසර දෙකක කාලයක් තුළ රුපියල 182 සිට එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලරයට 360 දක්වා පහත වැටීමත් සමඟ කැඩුණු සොෆ්ට්-පීග් සහල් කිලෝග්‍රෑමයක් රුපියල් 220 ඉක්මවා ගොස් ඇති අතර ප්‍රෝටීන් ඊටත් වඩා ඉහළ ගොස් ඇති අතර, අඩු ධනවතුන්ට ආහාර ලබා ගත නොහැකි විය.",
        "කැඩී බිඳී ගිය සොෆ්ට් පෙග් එකකින් විදේශ විනිමය හිඟය හේතුවෙන් අස්වනු නෙලීමේ උපකරණ සඳහා ඉන්ධන පහසුවෙන් ලබා ගත නොහැකි බවට මැසිවිලි නැඟීමත් සමඟ දැන් තමාගේ ප්‍රධාන කාර්යය වන්නේ රාමුකරුවන් සඳහා ඩීසල් ලබා දීම බව අමාත්‍ය අමරවීර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "මීළඟ කන්නය සඳහා යූරියා ආනයනය කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ද ඩොලර් මිලියන 110 ක් ලෝක බැංකු ණය රැස් කර ඇති නමුත් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 150,000 ක් සඳහා වූ පළමු ටෙන්ඩරයේ ප්‍රතිඵලය වූයේ මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 12,500 ක ඇණවුමක් පමණි. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙක්ටයාර 512,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 වාරය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙක්ටයාර 275,000",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "400,000 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් මිලියන 1.5 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "800,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රධාන මහා",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙක්ටයාර 500,000",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් මිලියන 2.0 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් මිලියන 1.36 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස 6 කට වඩා වැඩි කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙසැම්බර් අග",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "120 සිට 150 දක්වා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අක්කර 20,000 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "360",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "182",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "220",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 110 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ කන්නය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12,500MT",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "யாலத்தில் இலங்கை நெல் சாகுபடி சாதனை: அமைச்சர்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கை விவசாயிகள் 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு சிறு யாலப் பருவத்தில் 512,000 ஹெக்டேர் நெல் விதைப்பு செய்துள்ளதாக மதிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது, இது விலைவாசி உயர்வு மற்றும் உணவுப் பற்றாக்குறை அச்சத்தால் தூண்டப்பட்டது என்று விவசாய அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பதவி நீக்கம் செய்யப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவினால் விதிக்கப்பட்ட இரசாயன உரத்தடை நீக்கப்பட்ட போதிலும் 275,000 ஹெக்டேர் நெல் மட்டுமே பயிரிடப்படும் என இலங்கை முதலில் எதிர்பார்த்தது.",
        "இலங்கை பொதுவாக யாலா பருவத்தில் சுமார் 400,000 ஹெக்டேர் நெல் பயிரிடப்பட்டு 1.5 மில்லியன் டன் நெல் மற்றும் 800,000 பிரதான மஹா பருவத்தில் பயிரிடப்படுகிறது.",
        "500,000 ஹெக்டேர் நெல் பயிரிடப்பட்டால் 2.0 மில்லியன் டன் நெல் அறுவடை செய்யப்படும், சரியான நேரத்தில் உரம் வழங்கப்பட்டால், 1.36 மில்லியன் டன் அரிசியை அரைத்து, 6 மாதங்களுக்கும் மேலாக நாட்டிற்கு உணவளிக்க போதுமானது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், கரிம உரங்கள் மூலம் பயிரிடப்பட்ட வயல்களில் 30 முதல் 40 சதவீதம் குறைவான மகசூல் கிடைக்கும் என விவசாயிகள் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "\"எவ்வளவு நெல் உற்பத்தி செய்யப்படும் என்பது எங்களுக்கு சரியாகத் தெரியாது\" என அமைச்சர் அமரவீர தெரிவித்தார். “முன்பு சாகுபடி செய்த சில விவசாயிகளுக்கு ரசாயன உரம் கிடைக்கவில்லை. சிலருக்கு உரம் கிடைத்தது. எனவே முன்னறிவிப்புகளைச் சரியாகச் செய்ய முடியாது.",
        "\"இருப்பினும் பயிரிடப்பட்ட அளவு அதிகமாக இருந்ததால், கணிசமான அறுவடை இருக்கும் என்று நாங்கள் நினைக்கிறோம்.\"",
        "இலங்கையின் அரிசி ஆராய்ச்சி நிலையங்களினால் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட சோதனைகளில் 70/30 இரசாயன மற்றும் கரிம உரங்கள் சிறந்த முறையில் உற்பத்தி செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தெரியவந்துள்ளதாக அமைச்சர் அமரவீர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அதிகாரிகள் முதலில் செப்டம்பர் மாதத்திலிருந்து அரிசி இறக்குமதி செய்யப்படும் என்று எதிர்பார்த்தனர், ஆனால் இப்போது டிசம்பர் இறுதி வரை கையிருப்பு இருக்கும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இந்த வருடம் இலங்கைக்கு 230,000 தொன் அரிசி இறக்குமதி செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அமைச்சர் அமரவீர சற்றுமுன் தெரிவித்தார். இலங்கை ஒரு மாதத்திற்கு சுமார் 200,000MT அரிசியை பயன்படுத்துகிறது.",
        "பணம் அச்சிடுதல் மற்றும் திறந்த கணக்கு இறக்குமதிக்கு தடை விதிக்கப்பட்டதால் உணவு தட்டுப்பாடு அச்சம் ஏற்பட்டது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க அரிசி இறக்குமதியை தாராளமயமாக்கி பற்றாக்குறையைத் தடுக்கிறார்.",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு யாலா பருவத்தில் இலங்கையில் நல்ல மழை பெய்து விவசாயிகள் வயலுக்குச் செல்ல அனுமதித்தது.",
        "உணவுப்பற்றாக்குறை பீதியை அரசியல்வாதிகள் பரப்பியதால் நெல் விலை சீசனில் 120 முதல் 150 வரை உயர்ந்தது, நிலத்தை டைல்ஸ் செய்வதற்கு டிராக்டர் கட்டணம் ஏக்கருக்கு சுமார் 12,000 ரூபாயில் இருந்து 20,000 ரூபாயாக உயர்ந்து, டீசல் தட்டுப்பாடு நிலவுகிறது.",
        "“சிலர் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டைக்குச் சென்று ஒரு கிலோகிராம் 200 ரூபாவுக்கு நெல்லைக் கொள்வனவு செய்தனர், மேலும் அனைத்து அரிசிகளையும் பல்பொருள் அங்காடிகளில் கொள்வனவு செய்தனர்” என்று அமைச்சர் குணவர்தன கூறினார். \"இப்போது அவர்களுக்கு அந்துப்பூச்சிகள் உள்ளன.\"",
        "சிறந்த விளைச்சல் இருந்தபோதிலும், உடைந்த சாஃப்ட்-பெக் மற்றும் அமெரிக்க டாலருக்கு ரூபாய் மதிப்பு 360 ஆக வீழ்ச்சியடைந்தது, இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளில் 182 இல் இருந்து அரிசி ஒரு கிலோகிராம் 220 ரூபாய்க்கும் அதிகமாகவும், புரதங்கள் இன்னும் அதிகமாகவும், குறைந்த வசதி படைத்தவர்களுக்கு உணவு கிடைக்காமல் போய்விட்டது.",
        "உடைந்த சாஃப்ட்-பெக்கில் இருந்து அந்நிய செலாவணி பற்றாக்குறையால் அறுவடை உபகரணங்களுக்கு எரிபொருள் உடனடியாக கிடைக்கவில்லை என்ற புகார்களுடன், பிரேம் செய்பவர்களுக்கு டீசல் கிடைப்பதை உறுதி செய்வதே தனது முக்கிய பணியாகும் என்று அமைச்சர் அமரவீர கூறினார்.",
        "அடுத்த பருவத்தில் யூரியாவை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்காக 110 மில்லியன் டாலர் உலக வங்கிக் கடனை இலங்கை திரட்டியது, ஆனால் 150,000MTக்கான முதல் டெண்டரில் 12,500MT ஆர்டர் மட்டுமே கிடைத்தது. (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "512,000 ஹெக்டேர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 சீசன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "275,000 ஹெக்டேர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 400,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யால",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பருவம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 1.5 மில்லியன் டன்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "800,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முக்கிய மகா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "500,000 ஹெக்டேர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.0 மில்லியன் டன்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.36 மில்லியன் டன்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 மாதங்களுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிசம்பர் பிற்பகுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பருவம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "120 முதல் 150 வரை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பருவம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு ஏக்கருக்கு 20,000",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "360",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "182",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளுக்கு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "220",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "110 மில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த பருவம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12,500MT",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}