{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84317/four-more-arrested-over-fuel-racketeering-9200-litres-of-petrol-seized",
  "time_ut": 1660560840,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Four more arrested over fuel racketeering; 9,200 litres of petrol seized",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Four more arrested over fuel racketeering; 9,200 litres of petrol seized",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Four suspects have been arrested with 9,200 litres of petrol being illegally transported in the Anamaduwa area for fuel racketeering.",
        "According to Ada Derana reporter, the suspects were arrested while attempting to load the petrol consignment into a lorry from a bowser truck.",
        "During the police inquiries, it has been revealed that the stock of petrol was slated to be sold to fishermen in Mannar to be used instead of kerosene.",
        "Meanwhile, Puttalam Police seized 4,000 litres of petrol being illegally transported in a freezer truck in the Kalladiya area on the Puttalam-Kurunegala road.",
        "This large consignment of petrol was found in a lorry en route to Mannar from Anamaduwa.",
        "The driver of the lorry is reportedly a 32-year-old resident of the Mannar area. The bowser truck that supplied this petrol stock has also been taken into police custody in the area of Anamaduwa.",
        "Accordingly, the police have taken a total of 13,200 litres of petrol into custody, Ada Derana reporter said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Four",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "9,200",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9,200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anamaduwa",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ada Derana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Puttalam Police",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalladiya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mannar from Anamaduwa",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "32-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anamaduwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13,200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ada Derana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන ජාවාරමේ තවත් හතරක් අත්අඩංගුවට පෙට්‍රල් ලීටර් 9200ක් අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්ධන ජාවාරම් සඳහා නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස ප්‍රවාහනය කරමින් තිබූ පෙට්‍රල් ලීටර් 9200ක් සමඟ සැකකරුවන් 4 දෙනෙකු ආණමඩුව ප්‍රදේශයේදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "බවුසර් රථයකින් පෙට්‍රල් තොගය ලොරි රථයකට පටවා ගැනීමට යාමේදී සැකකරුවන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව අද දෙරණ වාර්තාකරු පවසයි.",
        "මෙම පෙට්‍රල් තොගය මන්නාරම ප්‍රදේශයේ ධීවරයින්ට භූමිතෙල් වෙනුවට භාවිත කිරීම සඳහා අලෙවි කිරීමට සැලසුම් කර තිබූ බව පොලිස් පරීක්ෂණවලදී අනාවරණ වී තිබෙනවා.",
        "මේ අතර, පුත්තලම - කුරුණෑගල මාර්ගයේ කල්අඩිය ප්‍රදේශයේ දී අධිශීතකරණ ලොරි රථයකින් නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස ප්‍රවාහනය කරමින් තිබූ පෙට්‍රල් ලීටර් 4000ක් පුත්තලම පොලිසිය භාරයට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "ආණමඩුවේ සිට මන්නාරම දෙසට ගමන් කරමින් තිබූ ලොරි රථයක තිබී මෙම විශාල පෙට්‍රල් තොගය සොයාගෙන තිබේ.",
        "ලොරි රථයේ රියදුරු මන්නාරම ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 32 හැවිරිදි අයෙක් බවයි වාර්තා වන්නේ. මෙම පෙට්‍රල් තොගයට සැපයූ බවුසර් රථයද ආණමඩුව ප්‍රදේශයේදී පොලිස් භාරයට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "ඒ අනුව පෙට්‍රල් ලීටර් 13,200ක් පොලිස් භාරයට ගෙන ඇති බව අද දෙරණ වාර්තාකරු සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හතර",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "9,200 කි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9,200 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණමඩුව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද දෙරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම පොලිසිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කල්අඩිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම ආණමඩුවෙන්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "32 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණමඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13,200 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද දෙරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் கடத்தலில் ஈடுபட்ட மேலும் நால்வர் கைது; 9,200 லிட்டர் பெட்ரோல் பறிமுதல் செய்யப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஆனமடுவ பிரதேசத்தில் எரிபொருள் கடத்தலுக்காக சட்டவிரோதமான முறையில் கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்ட 9,200 லீற்றர் பெற்றோலுடன் நான்கு சந்தேகநபர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "பௌசர் ட்ரக் வண்டியில் இருந்து பெற்றோல் பொருட்களை லொறியில் ஏற்றிச் செல்ல முற்பட்ட போதே சந்தேகநபர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக அத தெரண செய்தியாளர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பொலிஸாரின் விசாரணைகளின் போது, ​​மண்ணெண்ணெய்க்கு பதிலாக மன்னாரில் உள்ள மீனவர்களுக்கு விற்பனை செய்ய குறித்த பெற்றோல் கையிருப்பு வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்தமை தெரியவந்துள்ளது.",
        "இதேவேளை, புத்தளம் குருநாகல் வீதியின் கல்லடிய பிரதேசத்தில் சட்ட விரோதமாக பிரீசர் ட்ரக் ஒன்றில் கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்ட 4,000 லீற்றர் பெற்றோலை புத்தளம் பொலிஸார் கைப்பற்றியுள்ளனர்.",
        "ஆனமடுவையில் இருந்து மன்னார் நோக்கி பயணித்த லொறி ஒன்றில் இருந்து இந்த பாரிய பெற்றோல் கண்டெடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "லொறியின் சாரதி மன்னார் பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த 32 வயதுடையவர் என தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது. இந்த பெற்றோல் பங்குக்கு விநியோகித்த பவுசர் ட்ரக் வண்டியும் ஆனமடுவ பகுதியில் வைத்து பொலிஸாரால் கைப்பற்றப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அதன்படி, மொத்தம் 13,200 லீற்றர் பெற்றோல் பொலிஸாரால் கைப்பற்றப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அத தெரண செய்தியாளர் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நான்கு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "9,200",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9,200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆனமடுவ",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அட தெரண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம் பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்லடியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆனமடுவையிலிருந்து மன்னார்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "32 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆனமடுவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13,200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அட தெரண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}