{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/‘‘වත්මන්-ආණ්ඩුව-ගුරුවරයාගේ-බඩට-ගහලා‘‘/101-600996",
  "time_ut": 1634189199,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "‘‘වත්මන් ආණ්ඩුව ගුරුවරයාගේ බඩට ගහලා‘‘",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "\"The current government has hit the teacher in the stomach\"",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former Education Minister and United National Party Vice Leader Mr. Akila Viraj Kariyawasam said that the good governance government took initial steps to solve the teacher's salary issue by taking VAT from profit-making institutions, but as soon as the current government came in, it slashed the VAT and protected big men and hit the teacher in the stomach.",
        "Mr. Kariyawasam said that the government is attacking the public servants and the teachers who voted to bring them to power today. Since the education of the children in this country has been set back by one and a half to two years, both parties should come to a middle ground and solve the problem.",
        "\"A government that has come to power should provide the basic needs of the few people to be fed and clothed. But this government has not been able to pour it. Today, every sector is collapsing,\" said Mr. Kariyawasam."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Akila Viraj Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "VAT",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one and a half to two years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘‘වත්මන් ආණ්ඩුව ගුරුවරයාගේ බඩට ගහලා‘‘",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "යහපාලන ආණ්ඩුව ලාභ ලබන ආයතන වලින්  වැට් බදු ලබාගෙන ගුරුවරුන්ගේ වැටුප් ප්‍රශ්නය විසඳීමට මූලික පියවර තැබූ නමුත් වත්මන් ආණ්ඩුව පැමිණි සැනින් වැට් බද්ද කප්පාදුකර ලොකු මිනිසුන් ආරක්ෂා කොට ගුරුවරයාගේ බඩට ගසා ඇතැයි හිටපු අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍ය සහ එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ උප නායක අකිල විරාජ් කාරියවසම් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ආණ්ඩුව අද පහර පිට පහර ගසන්නේ ඔවුන් බලයට ගෙන ඒමට මූලික වී ඡන්දය දුන් රාජ්‍ය සේවකයන්ට මෙන්ම ගුරුවරුන්ට බව කී කාරියවසම් මහතා  අද මෙරට දරු පරපුරේ අධ්‍යාපනය වසර එකහමාරකින් දෙකකින් පමණ ආපස්සට හරවා තිබෙන හෙයින් දෙපාර්ශවයම මැද තැනකට පැමිණ ප්‍රශ්නය විසඳාගත යුතු බවද සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "“බලයට පත්වූ ආන්ඩුවක් අඩුගණනේ ජනතාවට කාලා ඇඳලා ජීවත් වී ඉන්න වත් මූලික අවශ්‍යතා සම්පාදනය කළ යුතුයි. නමුත් මේ ආණ්ඩුවට එය වත් කරන්නට නොහැකි වී තිබෙනවා.අද සෑම ක්ෂේත්‍රයක්ම කඩා වැටීමට ලක්ව තිබෙනවා” යනුවෙන්ද කාරියවසම් මහතා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අකිල විරාජ් කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැට් බද්ද",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු එකහමාරක් හෝ දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"தற்போதைய அரசு ஆசிரியர் வயிற்றில் அடித்துவிட்டது\"",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நல்லாட்சி அரசாங்கம் இலாபம் ஈட்டும் நிறுவனங்களில் இருந்து VAT வசூலித்து ஆசிரியர்களின் சம்பளப் பிரச்சினையைத் தீர்ப்பதற்கான ஆரம்ப நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுத்ததாகவும், ஆனால் தற்போதைய அரசாங்கம் வந்தவுடன் அதனை குறைத்ததாகவும் முன்னாள் கல்வி அமைச்சரும் ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் உப தலைவருமான திரு.அகிலவிராஜ் காரியவசம் தெரிவித்தார். VAT மற்றும் பெரிய மனிதர்களைப் பாதுகாத்தது.",
        "ஆட்சிக்கு வருவதற்கு வாக்களித்த அரச ஊழியர்களையும் ஆசிரியர்களையும் இன்று அரசு தாக்குகிறது.இந்நாட்டில் பிள்ளைகளின் கல்வி ஒன்றரை இரண்டு வருடங்கள் பின்னடைவைச் சந்தித்துள்ள நிலையில் இரு தரப்பினரும் வரவேண்டும் என்றார் திரு காரியவசம். ஒரு நடுத்தர நிலத்திற்கு சென்று சிக்கலை தீர்க்கவும்.",
        "“அதிகாரத்திற்கு வந்த அரசாங்கம் ஒரு சிலருக்கு உணவு மற்றும் உடுத்துவதற்கான அடிப்படைத் தேவைகளை வழங்க வேண்டும். ஆனால், இந்த அரசால் அதைக் கொட்ட முடியவில்லை.இன்று ஒவ்வொரு துறையும் வீழ்ச்சியடைந்து வருகிறது\" என்றார் திரு. காரியவசம்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அகில விராஜ் காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "VAT",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்றரை முதல் இரண்டு ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}