{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/ranil-wickremesinghe-wins-sri-lankas-crucial-presidential-vote-97710/",
  "time_ut": 1658301000,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ranil Wickremesinghe wins Sri Lanka’s crucial presidential vote",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ranil Wickremesinghe wins Sri Lanka’s crucial presidential vote",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s parliament elected Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe as the 8th Executive President on Wednesday (20) with 134 lawmakers in the 225-member parliament voting in favour of the government-backed candidate.",
        "The new vote came after the former leader Gotabaya Rajapaksa fled the country and resigned last week from Singapore, plunging the country into deep political crisis after months-long protests against him.",
        "The protests came after Rajapaksa’s wrong economic and agricultural policies hit the country with dollar shortages following the Central Bank printing of trillions of rupees while maintaining a soft peg against the currency.",
        "The country is still facing shortages of fuel, cooking gas, and medicines while it is also facing a looming food shortage.",
        "Wickremesinghe was appointed as a PM of the country for the 6th time in May although he had only one seat in the parliament. He came to parliament on a residual vote total after his party had a humiliating defeat in 2019 Presidential elections.",
        "At the election, 223 MPs cast their votes with two abstaining making the total count of valid votes at 219.",
        "Candidates Dallas Alhahepperuma got 82 votes and Anura Kumara Dissanayake got only three votes."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "months-long",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "trillions",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "6th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "219",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alhahepperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "only three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තීරණාත්මක ජනාධිපතිවරණ ඡන්දයෙන් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ජය ගනී",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව 8 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා බදාදා (20) දින තේරී පත් වූ අතර මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 225 දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 134 දෙනෙකු රජයට සහාය දක්වන අපේක්ෂකයාට පක්ෂව ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළහ.",
        "හිටපු නායක ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා රටින් පලා ගොස් සිංගප්පූරුවෙන් පසුගිය සතියේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු නව ඡන්දය ලැබුණේ ඔහුට එරෙහිව මාස ගණනාවක් පුරා පැවති විරෝධතාවලින් පසුව රට ගැඹුරු දේශපාලන අර්බුදයකට ඇද දමමිනි.",
        "රාජපක්ෂගේ වැරදි ආර්ථික හා කෘෂිකාර්මික ප්‍රතිපත්ති නිසා මහ බැංකුව විසින් රුපියල් ට්‍රිලියන ගණනින් මුදල් මුද්‍රණය කිරීමත් සමඟ මුදල් ඒකකයට එරෙහිව මෘදු ස්ථාවරයක් පවත්වාගෙන යාමත් සමඟ ඩොලර් හිඟයක් රට තුළ ඇති වූ පසු මෙම විරෝධතා මතු විය.",
        "රට තවමත් ඉන්ධන, ඉවුම් පිහුම් ගෑස් සහ ඖෂධ හිඟයකට මුහුණ දෙන අතරම ආහාර හිඟයකටද මුහුණ දී සිටී.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ එක් ආසනයක් පමණක් තිබුණද 6 වැනි වරටත් අගමැති ධුරයට පත් වූයේ මැයි මාසයේදීය. 2019 ජනාධිපතිවරණයේදී තම පක්ෂය නින්දිත පරාජයක් ලැබීමෙන් පසු ඔහු පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණියේ ඉතිරි ඡන්ද එකතුවෙනි.",
        "මැතිවරණයේදී මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 223 දෙනෙකු ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළ අතර දෙදෙනෙකු ඡන්දය දීමෙන් වැළකී සිටීමෙන් වලංගු ඡන්ද සංඛ්‍යාව 219 ක් විය.",
        "අපේක්ෂකයින් වන ඩලස් අල්හාහෙප්පෙරුම මහතාට ඡන්ද 82ක් හිමි වූ අතර අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක මහතාට ලැබුණේ ඡන්ද තුනක් පමණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස-දිග",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්රිලියන",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "6 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "219",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අල්හාහෙප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුනක් පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் அதிபர் தேர்தலில் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கே வெற்றி பெற்றார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையின் பாராளுமன்றம் புதன்கிழமை (20) 8 வது நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியாக செயல் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவைத் தேர்ந்தெடுத்தது, 225 உறுப்பினர்களைக் கொண்ட பாராளுமன்றத்தில் 134 சட்டமியற்றுபவர்கள் அரசாங்க ஆதரவு வேட்பாளருக்கு ஆதரவாக வாக்களித்தனர்.",
        "முன்னாள் தலைவர் கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறி சிங்கப்பூரில் இருந்து கடந்த வாரம் ராஜினாமா செய்ததை அடுத்து, அவருக்கு எதிரான பல மாத போராட்டங்களுக்குப் பிறகு நாட்டை ஆழ்ந்த அரசியல் நெருக்கடியில் ஆழ்த்தியதை அடுத்து புதிய வாக்கெடுப்பு வந்தது.",
        "ராஜபக்சேவின் தவறான பொருளாதார மற்றும் விவசாயக் கொள்கைகள், நாணயத்திற்கு எதிராக மென்மையான ஆப்பைப் பராமரிக்கும் அதே வேளையில், மத்திய வங்கி டிரில்லியன் கணக்கான ரூபாய்களை அச்சடித்ததைத் தொடர்ந்து டாலர் தட்டுப்பாட்டால் நாட்டைத் தாக்கியதை அடுத்து எதிர்ப்புகள் வந்தன.",
        "நாடு இன்னும் எரிபொருள், சமையல் எரிவாயு மற்றும் மருந்துகள் பற்றாக்குறையை எதிர்கொள்கிறது, அதே நேரத்தில் அது உணவுப் பற்றாக்குறையை எதிர்கொள்கிறது.",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு பாராளுமன்றத்தில் ஒரே ஒரு ஆசனம் இருந்த போதிலும் மே மாதம் 6வது முறையாக நாட்டின் பிரதமராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டார். 2019 ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் அவரது கட்சி அவமானகரமான தோல்வியை சந்தித்ததை அடுத்து அவர் எஞ்சிய வாக்குகளை பெற்று பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு வந்தார்.",
        "தேர்தலில், 223 எம்.பி.க்கள் வாக்களித்தனர், இருவர் வாக்களிக்கவில்லை. மொத்த வாக்குகளின் எண்ணிக்கை 219 ஆக இருந்தது.",
        "வேட்பாளர்களான டலஸ் அல்ஹாஹெப்பெரும 82 வாக்குகளையும் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க 3 வாக்குகளையும் பெற்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள் நீடித்தது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிரில்லியன்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "6வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "219",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அல்ஹாஹெப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}