{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ඉන්ධනහලේ-සිට-ගෙදර-යද්දී-වැටී-මරුට/1-616409",
  "time_ut": 1657789072,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඉන්ධනහලේ සිට ගෙදර යද්දී වැටී මරුට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "He fell and died on his way home from the gas station",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Halawatha Police say that a mechanic who was returning to his home after waiting in a fuel queue in Halawatha area for several days suddenly fell ill and died in Munneswaram area of ​​Halawatha Kurunagala road.",
        "A 37-year-old father of two named Prasanna Fernando, resident of Halawata, Rambepitiya, has died.",
        "Police say that on the 12th, on the news that fuel was coming to Halawata, he rode his motorcycle for over 10 kilometers and spent the long queue at the fuel station, but fell down and died on the side of the road in Munneswaram area due to lack of fuel."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Halawatha Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Halawatha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "several days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Munneswaram",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunagala",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "37-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Halawata, Rambepitiya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 12th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Halawata",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධනහලේ සිට ගෙදර යද්දී වැටී මරුට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "දින කීපයක් හලාවත ප‍්‍රදේශයේ ඉන්ධන පෝලිමක  රැදීසිට නැවත සිය නිවස කරා යමින් සිටි කාර්මිකයකු හදිසියේ රෝගාතුර වී හලාවත කුරුණැගල මාර්ගයේ මුන්නේස්වරම ප‍්‍රදේශයේදී ඇද වැටී මරණයට පත්ව ඇති බව හලාවත පොලීසිය පවසයි.",
        "මෙසේ මරණයට පත්ව ඇත්තේ හලාවත, රඹේපිටිය,  පදිංචි  ප‍්‍රසන්න ප‍්‍රනාන්දු නැමති 37 හැවිරිදි දෙදරු පියෙකි.",
        "හලාවතට ඉන්ධන එන බවට ලැබුන ආරංචියක් මත 12දා කිලෝමීටර් 10ට අධික දුරක්  යතුරුපැදියේ තෙල් ටැංකිය පාපැදියක බැද ඉන්ධනහලේ දිගු පෝලිමේ ගත කළත් ඉන්ධන නොලැබීම හේතුවෙන් නැවත නිවස කරා යමින් සිටියදී මුන්නේස්වරම ප‍්‍රදේශයේදී මාර්ගය අයිනේ වැටී මිය ගොස් ඇතැයි පොලිසිය කියයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හලවත පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හලවත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුන්නේෂ්වරම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "37 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හලවත, රඹේපිටිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හලවත",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பெட்ரோல் பங்கில் இருந்து வீட்டிற்கு வரும் வழியில் தவறி விழுந்து இறந்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஹலவத்தை பிரதேசத்தில் பல நாட்களாக எரிபொருள் வரிசையில் காத்திருந்து வீடு திரும்பிய இயந்திரவியலாளர் ஒருவர் ஹலவத்தை குருநாகல் வீதியின் முன்னேஸ்வரம் பகுதியில் திடீரென சுகவீனமடைந்து உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக ஹலவத்தை பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "ஹலவத்த, ரம்பேபிட்டிய பிரதேசத்தை சேர்ந்த பிரசன்ன பெர்னாண்டோ என்ற 37 வயதுடைய இரண்டு பிள்ளைகளின் தந்தையே இவ்வாறு உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "கடந்த 12ஆம் திகதி ஹலவத்தைக்கு எரிபொருள் வருவதாகக் கிடைத்த தகவலின் பேரில் மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் 10 கிலோமீற்றருக்கு மேல் பயணித்து எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையத்தில் நீண்ட வரிசையில் காத்திருந்த போதும் முன்னேஸ்வரம் பகுதியில் வீதியோரத்தில் தவறி விழுந்து உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர். எரிபொருள் பற்றாக்குறைக்கு."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹலவத்த போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹலவதா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முன்னேஸ்வரம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "37 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்னா பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹலவத்த, ரம்பேபிட்டிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹலவதா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}