{
  "newspaper_id": "b-b-c-com-sinhala",
  "url": "https://www.bbc.com/sinhala/sri-lanka-62249809",
  "time_ut": 1658369086,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ: දැඩි ආරක්ෂක රැකවල් මැද ජනපති ලෙස දිවුරුම් දෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ranil Wickremesinghe: Swearing in as President amid tight security",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe was sworn in as the eighth Executive President of Sri Lanka today (July 21) amid heavy security.",
        "He became the Prime Minister of Sri Lanka on six occasions and came to the 09th Parliament on 23 June 2021 for the only member of parliament that was won by the United National Party from the national list in the 2020 general election.",
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe, as a member of a party that has only one member of Parliament, has been given the prime ministership and the president of the country has been receiving a lot of attention worldwide."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "eighth",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 09th Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "23 June 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "only one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ: දැඩි ආරක්ෂක රැකවල් මැද ජනපති ලෙස දිවුරුම් දෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අටවැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ දැඩි ආරක්ෂක රැකවල් මැද අද (ජූලි 21) පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "අවස්ථා හයකදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධූරයට පත් වූ ඔහු 2020 මහ මැතිවරණයේදී එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයට ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවෙන් හිමි වූ එකම මන්ත්‍රී ධූරය සඳහා 2021 වර්ෂයේ ජුනි මස 23 දින 09 වැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණියේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ එකම මන්ත්‍රීධුරයක් හිමි පක්ෂයක සාමාජිකයෙකු ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධූරය හිමි කර ගැනීම සහ රටේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා බවට පත්වීම ගැන ලොවපුරා දැඩි අවධානයක් යොමුව තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අටවැනි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "09 වැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 ජූනි 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එකක් පමණයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க: பலத்த பாதுகாப்புக்கு மத்தியில் ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியேற்பு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் எட்டாவது நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரம் கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இன்று (ஜூலை 21) பலத்த பாதுகாப்புக்கு மத்தியில் பதவியேற்றார்.",
        "அவர் ஆறு தடவைகள் இலங்கையின் பிரதமரானார் மற்றும் 2020 ஆம் ஆண்டு பொதுத் தேர்தலில் ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சி தேசியப் பட்டியலில் இருந்து வெற்றி பெற்ற ஒரேயொரு நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருக்காக 2021 ஜூன் 23 ஆம் திகதி 09 ஆவது பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு வந்தார்.",
        "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு ஒரேயொரு நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினரைக் கொண்ட கட்சியின் உறுப்பினர் என்ற வகையில் பிரதமர் பதவி வழங்கப்பட்டு நாட்டின் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு உலகளவில் பெரும் வரவேற்பு கிடைத்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டாவது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "09வது பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "23 ஜூன் 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}