{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/நிமல்-மீதான-விசாரணை-அறிக்கை-ஜனாதிபதியிடம்/175-301445",
  "time_ut": 1659289125,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "நிமல் மீதான விசாரணை அறிக்கை ஜனாதிபதியிடம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Inquiry report on Nimal to President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The inquiry report on former Minister Nimal Siripala de Silva has been handed over to the President's Secretary.",
        "A report has been handed over to the President's Secretary at the President's Secretariat this afternoon (31).",
        "There were reports on various social networking sites that a cabinet minister had demanded a bribe from a Japanese company.",
        "Former minister Nimal Siripala de Silva had demanded an inquiry into the matter.",
        "It is noteworthy that President Ranil Wickremesinghe had appointed a three-member investigation team on the 22nd of last year as per the request made by Nimal Siripala de Silva. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Nimal",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Secretariat",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 22nd of last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නිමල් ගැන පරීක්ෂණ වාර්තාව ජනපතිට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු අමාත්‍ය නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමර්ශන වාර්තාව ජනාධිපති ලේකම්වරයා වෙත භාරදී තිබෙනවා.",
        "අද (31) පස්වරුවේ ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේදී ජනාධිපති ලේකම්වරයා වෙත වාර්තාවක් භාරදී තිබේ.",
        "කැබිනට් අමාත්‍යවරයෙකු ජපන් සමාගමකින් අල්ලසක් ඉල්ලා ඇති බවට විවිධ සමාජ ජාල වෙබ් අඩවි ඔස්සේ වාර්තා පළ වුණා.",
        "හිටපු අමාත්‍ය නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා තිබුණා.",
        "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා මහතා කළ ඉල්ලීමකට අනුව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් පසුගිය 22 වැනිදා ත්‍රිපුද්ගල විමර්ශන කණ්ඩායමක් පත් කර තිබීම විශේෂත්වයකි. (ඒ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නිමල්",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසරේ 22 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நிமல் மீதான விசாரணை அறிக்கை ஜனாதிபதியிடம்",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா மீதான விசாரணை அறிக்கை ஜனாதிபதி செயலாளரிடம் கையளிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்தில் வைத்து ஜனாதிபதி செயலாளரிடம் இன்று (31) பிற்பகல் குறித்த அறிக்கை கையளிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அமைச்சரவை அமைச்சர் ஒருவர், ஜப்பானிய நிறுவனமொன்றில இருந்து இலஞ்சம் கோரியதாக பல்வேறு சமூக வலைததளங்களில் தகவல்கள் வெளியாகியிருந்தன.",
        "இந்த விடயம் தொடரபில் விசாரணை மேற்கொள்ளுமாறு முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா கோரிக்கை விடுத்திருந்தார்.",
        "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா விடுத்த கோரிக்கைக்கு அமைய, ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க, மூவரடங்கிய விசாரணைக் குழுவை கடந்த 22ஆம் திகதி நியமித்திருந்தார் என்பது குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நிமல்",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செயலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு 22ம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}