{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Lawyer-files-contempt-of-court-case-against-Sanath-Nishantha/342-243936",
  "time_ut": 1661768958,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Lawyer files contempt of court case against Sanath Nishantha",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Lawyer files contempt of court case against Sanath Nishantha",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A lawyer today filed a contempt of court application in Court of Appeal seeking an order directing the Attorney General to draft charges against Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) parliamentarian Sanath Nishantha for committing the offence of contempt of court.",
        "The petitioner Priyalal Sirisena, an Attorney-at-law by profession filed this application naming Puttalam District Parliamentarian Sanath Nishantha, the Bar Association of Sri Lanka and the Attorney General as respondents.",
        "The petitioner is seeking an order to impose sentence on Sanath Nishantha for committing the offence of contempt of court punishable under Article 105(3) of the constitution. (Lakmal Sooriyagoda)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sanath Nishantha",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanath Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Priyalal Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam District Parliamentarian Sanath Nishantha",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bar Association of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sanath Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 105(3",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakmal Sooriyagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සනත් නිශාන්තට එරෙහිව නීතිඥවරයා අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමේ නඩුවක් ගොනු කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සනත් නිශාන්තට අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමේ වරද සම්බන්ධයෙන් චෝදනා කෙටුම්පත් කරන ලෙස නීතිපතිවරයාට නියෝග කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා නීතීඥයෙකු අද අභියාචනාධිකරණයට අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමේ පෙත්සමක් ගොනු කළේය.",
        "පුත්තලම දිස්ත්‍රික් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සනත් නිශාන්ත, ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතීඥ සංගමය සහ නීතිපති වගඋත්තරකරුවන් කරමින් මෙම පෙත්සම ගොනු කළේ වෘත්තියෙන් නීතිඥ ප්‍රියලාල් සිරිසේන මහතා විසිනි.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 105(3) වගන්තිය යටතේ දඬුවම් ලැබිය හැකි අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමේ වරද සම්බන්ධයෙන් සනත් නිශාන්තට දඬුවම් නියම කරන ලෙස නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කරන ලෙස පෙත්සම්කරු ඉල්ලා සිටියි. (ලක්මාල් සූරියගොඩ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සනත් නිශාන්ත",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සනත් නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රියලාල් සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම දිස්ත්‍රික් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සනත් නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සනත් නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වගන්තිය 105(3",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්මාල් සූරියගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சனத் நிஷாந்தவுக்கு எதிராக சட்டத்தரணி நீதிமன்ற அவமதிப்பு வழக்கை தாக்கல் செய்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் (SLPP) பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சனத் நிஷாந்தவிற்கு எதிராக நீதிமன்ற அவமதிப்பு குற்றத்தை செய்தமைக்காக சட்டமா அதிபருக்கு எதிராக குற்றச்சாட்டை முன்வைக்குமாறு உத்தரவிடுமாறு கோரி சட்டத்தரணி ஒருவர் இன்று மேன்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றத்தில் நீதிமன்ற அவமதிப்பு மனுவை தாக்கல் செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "மனுதாரர் சட்டத்தரணியான பிரியலால் சிறிசேன, புத்தளம் மாவட்ட நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சனத் நிஷாந்த, இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் மற்றும் சட்டமா அதிபர் ஆகியோரை பிரதிவாதிகளாக பெயரிட்டு இந்த மனுவை தாக்கல் செய்தார்.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் 105(3) பிரிவின் கீழ் தண்டனைக்குரிய நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதித்த குற்றத்திற்காக சனத் நிஷாந்தவுக்கு தண்டனை விதிக்க உத்தரவிடுமாறு மனுதாரர் கோரியுள்ளார். (லக்மால் சூரியகொட)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சனத் நிஷாந்த",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனத் நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரியலால் சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம் மாவட்ட பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சனத் நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சனத் நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுரை 105(3",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்மால் சூரியகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}