{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Take-action-against-those-responsible-before-privatising-loss-making-state-entities-AKD/108-244207",
  "time_ut": 1662114583,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Take action against those responsible before privatising loss-making state entities: AKD",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Take action against those responsible before privatising loss-making state entities: AKD",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Claiming that the state institutions are running at huge loss due to decisions taken by politicians, National People's Power (NPP) MP Anura Kumara Dissanayake said today that those who were responsible for plunging the state institutions into loss making entities, should be dealt with before privatising them.",
        "He told Parliament that state institutions such as SriLankan Airlines and Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC) were found to have been loss making bodies due to actions of the politicians.",
        "\"SriLankan incurred huge losses due to Airbus deal and fraudulent actions of its officials. Onetime Chairman of the SriLankan, a close relative of former President Mahinda Rajapaksa brought down a SriLankan flight to Singapore without waiting for a scheduled flight. SriLankan is recording heavy loss due to such arbitrary actions. CPC is incurring huge losses due to actions such as the Hedging deal,\" he said.",
        "The MP said President Ranil Wickremesinghe said in his budget speech that state institutions are overcrowded and added that those institutions are unnecessarily filled by politicians through political appointments.",
        "He said the politicians who are responsible for these evil actions would never find solutions to the present crisis and said a new government should be formed with new mandate. (Ajith Siriwardana)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "National People's Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Airbus",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Onetime",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hedging",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ajith Siriwardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාඩු ලබන රාජ්‍ය ආයතන පෞද්ගලීකරණය කිරීමට පෙර වගකිවයුත්තන්ට එරෙහිව පියවර ගන්න: AKD",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දේශපාලනඥයින් ගන්නා තීන්දු තීරණ හේතුවෙන් රාජ්‍ය ආයතන විශාල වශයෙන් පාඩු ලබන බව පවසන ජාතික ජන බලවේගයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක මහතා අද ප්‍රකාශ කළේ රාජ්‍ය ආයතන පාඩු ලබන ආයතනවලට ඇද දැමීමට වගකිවයුත්තන්ට පෞද්ගලීකරණය කිරීමට පෙර කටයුතු කළ යුතු බවයි. ඔවුන්ට.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය, ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව වැනි රාජ්‍ය ආයතන දේශපාලකයන්ගේ ක්‍රියාකලාපය හේතුවෙන් පාඩු ලබන ආයතන බවට පත්ව ඇති බව ඔහු පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැවසීය.",
        "\"එයාර්බස් ගනුදෙනුව සහ එහි නිලධාරීන්ගේ වංචනික ක්‍රියා හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රීලංකන් සමාගමට විශාල පාඩුවක් සිදුවුණා. හිටපු ජනාධිපති මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ සමීපතම ඥාතියෙකු වන හිටපු ජනාධිපති මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ සමීපතම ඥාතියෙකු විසින් නියමිත ගුවන් ගමනක් එනතෙක් නොසිට සිංගප්පූරුවට ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් යානයක් ගෙන්වා ගත්තා. මෙවැනි අත්තනෝමතික ක්‍රියාවලට හෙජින් ගනුදෙනුව වැනි ක්‍රියා හේතුවෙන් ඛනිජ තෙල් සංස්ථාවට විශාල පාඩුවක් සිදුවෙනවා.",
        "රාජ්‍ය ආයතන පිරී ඉතිරී යන බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අයවැය කතාවේදී ප්‍රකාශ කළ බවත්, දේශපාලන පත්වීම් හරහා එම ආයතන අනවශ්‍ය ලෙස දේශපාලනඥයන් විසින් පුරවන බවත් මන්ත්‍රීවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "මෙම දුෂ්ට ක්‍රියාවලට වගකිව යුතු දේශපාලනඥයින්ට කිසිවිටෙකත් වත්මන් අර්බුදයට විසඳුම් නොලැබෙන බවත්, නව ජනවරමක් සහිත නව රජයක් පිහිටුවිය යුතු බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය. (අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජන බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එයාර් බස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක වරක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙජිං",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நஷ்டத்தில் இயங்கும் அரசு நிறுவனங்களை தனியார்மயமாக்கும் முன் பொறுப்பானவர்கள் மீது நடவடிக்கை எடுங்கள்: ஏகேடி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசியல்வாதிகளின் தீர்மானங்களினால் அரச நிறுவனங்கள் பாரிய நட்டத்தில் இயங்குவதாகக் கூறும் தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தியின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க, அரச நிறுவனங்களை நஷ்டமடையும் நிறுவனங்களுக்குள் தள்ளுவதற்கு காரணமானவர்களை தனியார் மயமாக்குவதற்கு முன்னர் நடவடிக்கை எடுக்க வேண்டும் என தெரிவித்துள்ளார். அவர்களுக்கு.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் எயார்லைன்ஸ் மற்றும் சிலோன் பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் (CPC) போன்ற அரச நிறுவனங்கள் அரசியல்வாதிகளின் செயற்பாடுகளால் நஷ்டமடைந்து காணப்பட்டதாக அவர் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"ஏர்பஸ் ஒப்பந்தம் மற்றும் அதன் அதிகாரிகளின் மோசடி நடவடிக்கைகளால் ஸ்ரீலங்கன் பெரும் நஷ்டத்தை சந்தித்துள்ளது. ஒரு காலத்தில் ஸ்ரீலங்கன் தலைவரும், முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷவின் நெருங்கிய உறவினருமான ஸ்ரீலங்கன் விமானத்தை, திட்டமிடப்பட்ட விமானத்திற்காக காத்திருக்காமல் சிங்கப்பூருக்கு இறக்கிவிட்டார். இது போன்ற தன்னிச்சையான நடவடிக்கைகளால், ஹெட்ஜிங் ஒப்பந்தம் போன்ற நடவடிக்கைகளால் CPC பெரும் இழப்பை சந்திக்கிறது,\" என்றார்.",
        "அரச நிறுவனங்கள் நிரம்பி வழிகின்றன என ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தனது வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட உரையில் தெரிவித்ததாகவும், அரசியல் நியமனங்கள் மூலம் அந்த நிறுவனங்கள் தேவையில்லாமல் அரசியல்வாதிகளால் நிரப்பப்படுவதாகவும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த தீய செயல்களுக்கு காரணமான அரசியல்வாதிகள் தற்போதைய நெருக்கடிக்கு ஒரு போதும் தீர்வைக் காணமாட்டார்கள் என்று கூறிய அவர், புதிய ஆணையுடன் புதிய அரசாங்கம் அமைக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்றார். (அஜித் சிறிவர்தன)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏர்பஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு முறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹெட்ஜிங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அஜித் சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}