{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/සංචාරක-සමාගම-හිමිකරු-පැහැරගෙන-මුදල්-කොල්ල-කෑ-අයෙක්-මාට්ටු/1-618480",
  "time_ut": 1661074412,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "සංචාරක සමාගම හිමිකරු පැහැරගෙන මුදල් කොල්ල කෑ අයෙක් මාට්ටු",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A person who kidnapped the owner of the travel company and robbed money was caught",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Borella police say that a group of three including two brothers who kidnapped the owner and assistant accountant of a travel company near the Bandaragama Bolgoda Bridge and robbed them of several hundred thousand rupees, posing as police officers, were arrested in Borella Vanathamulla area.",
        "According to the police, the suspects took away the credit cards of the two and robbed them of nearly 8 lakh rupees and a silver necklace.",
        "It has been revealed in the initial investigations conducted by the police that the owner of the travel agency and the assistant accountant, who was abducted on the 17th of last year, was brought near the Bolgoda bridge in Bandaragama, saying that he needed a luxury car to provide transportation facilities from Katunayake airport to a doctor coming to Sri Lanka from abroad.",
        "The police say that the three robbers who had come in a Thiroda car crossed the road to the car and pretended to be from the police and put them both in the back seat of the car and took them to a house in Vanathamulla on the pretext of taking them to the Bandaragama police.",
        "The police said that after threatening the two of them, they took the credit cards in their wallets and took two hundred thousand rupees first, then the assistant accountant took the remaining amount to Borella and took four hundred fifty eight thousand eight thousand three hundred rupees from a private bank.",
        "A police officer said that after complaining to Chief Inspector AJMR Samarasinghe, Station Commander of Borella Police regarding the robbery, the Station Commander, who acted immediately, went to a house in Borella Vanathamulla on the direction of the complainants and managed to arrest one of the suspects there.",
        "Police say that the arrested suspect was also wearing the silver necklace that had been stolen that day"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Borella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bandaragama Bolgoda Bridge",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "several hundred thousand",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Borella Vanathamulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 17th of last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bolgoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandaragama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vanathamulla",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandaragama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two hundred thousand rupees first",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Borella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "four hundred fifty eight thousand eight thousand three hundred",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Borella Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Borella Vanathamulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සංචාරක සමාගම හිමිකරු පැහැරගෙන මුදල් කොල්ල කෑ අයෙක් මාට්ටු",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් ලෙස පෙනී සිටිමින් සංචාරක සමාගමක හිමිකරු සහ සහකාර ගණකාධිකාරීවරයා බණ්ඩාරගම බොල්ගොඩ පාලම අසලදී පැහැරගෙන ඔවුන් සතු රුපියල් ලක්ෂ ගණනාවක මුදල් කොල්ලකෑ සහෝදරයන් දෙදෙනකු ඇතුළු තිදෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් කණ්ඩායමක අයකු බොරැල්ල වනාතමුල්ල ප්‍රදේශයේ දී අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව බොරැල්ල පොලිසිය කියයි",
        "ඔවුන් දෙදෙනාගේ සන්තකයේ තිබූ කෙඩිට් කාඩ්පත් පැහැරගෙන රුපියල් ලක්ෂ 8 කට ආසන්න මුදලක් හා රිදී මාලයක් සැකකරුවන් විසින් කොල්ල කා තිබූ බව පොලිසිය කියයි",
        "විදේශගතව සිට මෙරටට පැමිණෙන වෛද්‍යවරයකුට කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපොළේ සිට ප්‍රවාහන පහසුකම් ලබාදීමට සුඛෝපභෝගී මෝටර් රථයක් අවශ්‍ය බවට පවසමින් පැහැරගැනීමට ලක්වූ සංචාරක ආයතන හිමිකරු සහ සහකාර ගණකාධිකාරීවරයා ව ඉකුත් 17 වෙනි දින බණ්ඩාරගම බොල්ගොඩ පාලම අසලට ගෙන්වා ගෙන තිබූ බව පොලිසිය සිදුකළ මූලික විමර්ශනවලදී අනාවරණය වී ඇත",
        "එහිදී තීරෝද රථයකින් පැමිණ තිබූ කොල්ලකරුවන් තිදෙනා මෝටර් රථයට මඟ හරස් කර තමන් පොලිසියේ බව හඟවා ඔවුන් දෙදෙනාම මෝටර් රථයේ පිටුපස අසුනට දමා බණ්ඩාරගම පොලිසියට රැගෙන යන මුවාවෙන් වනාතමුල්ල නිවසකට රැගෙන ගොස් තිබූ බව පොලිසිය කියයි",
        "එහිදී ඔවුන් දෙදෙනාට තර්ජනය කර මුදල් පසුම්බියවල තිබූ කෙඩිට් කාඩ් පත් රැගෙන ගොස් රුපියල් ලක්ෂ දෙකක මුදලක් ප්‍රථමයෙන් ලබාගැනීමෙන් අනතුරුව ඉතිරි මුදල සහකාර ගණකාධිකාරීවරයා  බොරැල්ලට රැගෙන ගොස් පෞද්ගලික බැංකුවකින් රුපියල් හාරලක්ෂ පනස් අට දහස් අටදහස් තුන්සියයක මුදලක් ලබාගෙන තිබූ බව පොලිසිය කියයි",
        "එම කොල්ලකෑම සම්බන්ධයෙන් බොරැල්ල පොලිසියේ ස්ථානාධිපති ප්‍රධාන පොලිස් පරීක්ෂක ඒ ජේ එම් ආර් සමරසිංහ මහතාට පැමිණිලි කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුව වහා ක්‍රියාත්මක වූ ස්ථානාධිපතිවරයා පැමිණිලිකරුවන් ගේ මඟපෙන්වීම ඔස්සේ බොරැල්ල වනාතමුල්ල නිවසක් වෙත ගොස් එහි සිටි එක් සැකකරුවකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට සමත්වූ බව පොලිස් නිලධාරියකු පැවැසීය",
        "එලෙස අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරු එදින කොල්ලකා තිබූ රිදී මාලය ද පැළඳ සිටි බව පොලිසිය කියයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බොරැල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරගම බොල්ගොඩ පාලම",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිය දහස් ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරැල්ල වනාතමුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසරේ 17 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොල්ගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වනාතමුල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුලින්ම රුපියල් ලක්ෂ දෙකක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරැල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හාරලක්ෂ පනස් අට දහස් අට දහස් තුන්සියයක්",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බොරැල්ල පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරැල්ල වනාතමුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டிராவல்ஸ் நிறுவனத்தின் உரிமையாளரை கடத்திச் சென்று பணத்தை கொள்ளையடித்த நபர் பிடிபட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பண்டாரகம பொல்கொட பாலத்திற்கு அருகில் உள்ள பயண நிறுவனம் ஒன்றின் உரிமையாளரையும் உதவி கணக்காளரையும் கடத்திச் சென்று பொலிஸ் உத்தியோகத்தர்கள் போல் வேடமணிந்து பல இலட்சம் ரூபா பணத்தை கொள்ளையடித்த சகோதரர்கள் இருவர் உள்ளிட்ட மூவர் அடங்கிய குழுவினர் பொரளை வனாத்தமுல்ல பிரதேசத்தில் வைத்து கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக பொரளை பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்கள் இருவரின் கடன் அட்டைகளையும் எடுத்துச் சென்று அவர்களிடம் இருந்து சுமார் 8 இலட்சம் ரூபா பணம் மற்றும் வெள்ளி நகையை கொள்ளையடித்துச் சென்றுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "கடந்த 17ஆம் திகதி கடத்தப்பட்ட டிராவல்ஸ் ஏஜென்சியின் உரிமையாளரும், உதவி கணக்காளரும் சொகுசு கார் தேவை எனக் கூறி பண்டாரகம பொல்கொட பாலத்திற்கு அருகில் அழைத்து வரப்பட்டதாக பொலிஸார் மேற்கொண்ட ஆரம்பகட்ட விசாரணைகளில் தெரியவந்துள்ளது. வெளிநாட்டில் இருந்து இலங்கை வரும் வைத்தியர் ஒருவருக்கு கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையத்திலிருந்து போக்குவரத்து வசதிகளை ஏற்படுத்திக் கொடுப்பதற்காக.",
        "திரோட காரில் வந்த மூன்று கொள்ளையர்கள் வீதியைக் கடந்து காருக்குச் சென்று பொலிஸாரைப் போல் நடித்து இருவரையும் காரின் பின் இருக்கையில் அமர வைத்து வனத்தமுல்லையில் உள்ள வீடொன்றுக்கு அழைத்துச் சென்றதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர். அவர்களை பண்டாரகம பொலிஸாரிடம் அழைத்துச் சென்றுள்ளனர்.",
        "இருவரையும் மிரட்டி பணப்பையில் இருந்த கிரெடிட் கார்டுகளை எடுத்து முதலில் இரண்டு லட்சம் ரூபாயை எடுத்ததாகவும், பின்னர் உதவி கணக்காளர் எஞ்சிய தொகையை பொரளைக்கு எடுத்துச் சென்று நானூறு ஐம்பத்தெட்டாயிரத்து எட்டாயிரத்து முந்நூறு ரூபாவை எடுத்ததாகவும் பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர். ஒரு தனியார் வங்கி.",
        "இந்த கொள்ளைச் சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் பொரளை பொலிஸ் நிலைய கட்டளைத் தளபதி பிரதம பொலிஸ் பரிசோதகர் ஏ.ஜே.எம்.ஆர் சமரசிங்கவிடம் முறைப்பாடு செய்ததையடுத்து, உடனடியாக செயற்பட்ட நிலையத் தளபதி, முறைப்பாட்டாளர்களின் அறிவுறுத்தலின் பேரில் பொரளை வனாத்தமுல்லையில் உள்ள வீடொன்றுக்குச் சென்று, அவர்களில் ஒருவரைக் கைது செய்ததாக பொலிஸ் அதிகாரி ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார். அங்கு சந்தேகிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேகநபர் அன்றைய தினம் திருடப்பட்ட வெள்ளி நகையையும் அணிந்திருந்ததாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொரளை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரகம போல்கொட பாலம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல நூறு ஆயிரம்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொரளை வனாத்தமுல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு 17ம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "போல்கொடா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வனத்தமுல்லை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரகம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில் இரண்டு லட்சம் ரூபாய்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொரளை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நானூற்று ஐம்பத்தெட்டாயிரத்து எட்டாயிரத்து முந்நூறு",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொரளை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொரளை வனாத்தமுல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}