{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/27/high-level-us-delegation-meets-president-to-discuss-economic-crisis/",
  "time_ut": 1656316680,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "High-Level US delegation meets President to discuss economic crisis",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "High-Level US delegation meets President to discuss economic crisis",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The High-level US Delegation that visited Sri Lanka to explore ways that the US can support the island nation’s economy called on President Gotabaya Rajapaksa in Colombo on Monday (27) morning.",
        "Ambassador Kelly Keiderling, Deputy Assistant Secretary of the US Department of State, and Robert Kaproth, Deputy Assistant Secretary of the US Treasury accompanied by Ambassador to Sri Lanka Julie J Chung met the President to discuss Sri Lanka’s economic crisis.",
        "“It’s a challenging time, but we continue to deliver assistance & long-term partnership to help SL achieve a prosperous, secure & democratic future,” tweeted the Ambassador.",
        "G7 aims to raise $600 billion to counter China’s Belt and Road",
        "Green Light from Defence Ministry for Cargo Ferry Service between KKS and Tamil Nadu"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "US Delegation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27) morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kelly Keiderling",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the US Department of State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Robert Kaproth",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the US Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SL",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$600 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Defence Ministry for Cargo Ferry Service",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "KKS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ආර්ථික අර්බුදය ගැන සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට ඉහළ පෙළේ ඇමෙරිකානු නියෝජිත පිරිසක් ජනපති හමුවෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); දිවයිනේ ආර්ථිකයට අමෙරිකාවට සහය විය හැකි මාර්ග සොයා බැලීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණි ඇමෙරිකානු ඉහළ පෙළේ නියෝජිත පිරිස සඳුදා (27) පෙරවරුවේ කොළඹදී ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා හමුවිය.",
        "එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ නියෝජ්‍ය සහකාර ලේකම් තානාපති Kelly Keiderling සහ එක්සත් ජනපද භාණ්ඩාගාරයේ නියෝජ්‍ය සහකාර ලේකම් Robert Kaproth සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තානාපති Julie J Chung යන මහත්වරු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා ජනාධිපතිතුමා හමුවූහ.",
        "\"එය අභියෝගාත්මක කාලයකි, නමුත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සමෘද්ධිමත්, ආරක්ෂිත සහ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී අනාගතයක් ළඟා කර ගැනීමට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා අපි අඛණ්ඩව සහය සහ දිගුකාලීන හවුල්කාරිත්වය ලබා දෙන්නෙමු\" යනුවෙන් තානාපතිවරයා ට්වීට් කළේය.",
        "G7 චීනයේ තීරය සහ මාර්ගයට එරෙහිව ඩොලර් බිලියන 600 ක් රැස් කිරීමට ඉලක්ක කරයි",
        "KKS සහ තමිල්නාඩු අතර භාණ්ඩ ප්‍රවාහනය සඳහා ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයෙන් හරිත එළිය"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද නියෝජිත කණ්ඩායම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27) උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෙලී කීඩර්ලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොබට් කප්රොත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද භාණ්ඩාගාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.එල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 600 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩ යාත්‍රා සේවය සඳහා ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේ.කේ.එස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி குறித்து விவாதிக்க அமெரிக்க உயர்மட்ட குழு ஜனாதிபதியை சந்தித்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); தீவு நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரத்திற்கு அமெரிக்கா ஆதரவளிப்பதற்கான வழிகளை ஆராய்வதற்காக இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்த அமெரிக்க உயர்மட்டக் குழு திங்கட்கிழமை (27) காலை கொழும்பில் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை சந்தித்தது.",
        "அமெரிக்க இராஜாங்கத் திணைக்களத்தின் பிரதி உதவிச் செயலாளர் தூதுவர் கெல்லி கெய்டர்லிங் மற்றும் அமெரிக்கத் திறைசேரியின் பிரதி உதவிச் செயலாளர் ரொபேர்ட் கப்ரோத் மற்றும் இலங்கைக்கான தூதுவர் ஜூலி ஜே சுங் ஆகியோருடன் இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி குறித்து ஜனாதிபதியை சந்தித்தனர்.",
        "\"இது ஒரு சவாலான நேரம், ஆனால் இலங்கைக்கு வளமான, பாதுகாப்பான மற்றும் ஜனநாயக எதிர்காலத்தை அடைய உதவும் வகையில் நாங்கள் தொடர்ந்து உதவி மற்றும் நீண்ட கால பங்காளித்துவத்தை வழங்குகிறோம்\" என்று தூதுவர் ட்வீட் செய்தார்.",
        "சீனாவின் பெல்ட் அண்ட் ரோடுக்கு எதிராக 600 பில்லியன் டாலர் திரட்ட G7 இலக்கு கொண்டுள்ளது",
        "KKS மற்றும் தமிழ்நாடு இடையே சரக்கு படகு சேவைக்கு பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகத்தின் பச்சை விளக்கு"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க பிரதிநிதிகள் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27) காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கெல்லி கெய்டர்லிங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க வெளியுறவுத்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராபர்ட் கப்ரோத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$600 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சரக்கு படகு சேவைக்கான பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கே.கே.எஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}