{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132170",
  "time_ut": 1658674298,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "3 மாதங்களின் பின் திறக்கப்படும் ஜனாதிபதி செயலக கதவுகள் : பாதுகாப்புச் செயலர், இராணுவ தளபதி மேற்பார்வை !",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Presidential Secretariat doors to be opened after 3 months : Defense Secretary, Army Chief Supervised !",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "Colombo - The operations of the Fort Presidential Secretariat will resume to normal from today, Monday, the 25th.",
        "Since last April 9, the main entrance of the Presidential Secretariat (Gate Zero) has been blocked and vandalized by the empty-faced Kota Ko Kama protesters, and it has been announced that the secretariat activities are limited.",
        "In this situation, after the seizure of the Presidential Secretariat by millions of people who gathered in Colombo on July 9, the activities of the Secretariat were completely paralyzed.",
        "In this situation, on the morning of Friday 22nd, the armed forces attacked and chased the protestors in front of the presidential secretariat and brought the secretariat under their control.",
        "While the damaged doors and windows of the Secretariat were reconstructed on the afternoon of the 24th, a senior official of the Presidential Secretariat said that it is planned to resume normal operations from today.",
        "On the afternoon of the 24th, Defense Secretary General Kamal Gunaratna and Army Commander Lt. Gen. Vikum Lienake visited the Presidential Secretariat and personally confirmed all matters including the security situation. In this situation, the secretariat activities will be carried out as usual from today."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3 months",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Defense",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Army",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Fort Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "today, Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 25th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last April 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kota Ko Kama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "millions",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Secretariat",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday 22nd",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Secretariat",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the afternoon of the 24th",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the afternoon of the 24th",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defense",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kamal Gunaratna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vikum Lienake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මාස 3කට පසු ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේ දොරටු විවෘත කෙරේ : ආරක්‍ෂක ලේකම්, යුද හමුදාපතිගේ අධීක්ෂණය !",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොළඹ - කොටුව ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේ කටයුතු අද (25) සඳුදා සිට සාමාන්‍ය තත්ත්වයට පත් වේ.",
        "පසුගිය අපේ‍්‍රල් 9 වැනිදා සිට ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේ ප‍්‍රධාන දොරටුව (ගේට් සීරෝ) අවහිර කරමින් හිස් කොට කෝ කමා විරෝධතාකරුවන් විසින් කඩාකප්පල් කර ඇති අතර, ලේකම් කාර්යාල කටයුතු සීමා කර ඇති බව ප‍්‍රකාශ කර ඇත.",
        "මේ තත්ත්වය තුළ ජුලි 9 වැනිදා කොළඹට රැස්ව සිටි මිලියන සංඛ්‍යාත ජනතාවක් විසින් ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය අල්ලාගැනීමෙන් පසු ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේ කටයුතු සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම අඩාල විය.",
        "මේ තත්ත්වය තුළ 22 සිකුරාදා අලුයම ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය ඉදිරිපිට විරෝධතාවයේ නිරත වූවන්ට ප්‍රහාර එල්ල කර ලුහුබැඳ ගොස් ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාව විසින් ලේකම් කාර්යාලය සිය පාලනයට නතු කර ගත්හ.",
        "හානියට පත් ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේ දොර ජනෙල් පෙරේදා (24) පස්වරුවේ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණය කළ අතර, අද සිට සාමාන්‍ය පරිදි කටයුතු ආරම්භ කිරීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති බව ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරියෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "24 වැනිදා පස්වරුවේ ආරක්‍ෂක ලේකම් ජනරාල් කමල් ගුණරත්න සහ යුද හමුදාපති ලුතිනන් ජෙනරාල් විකුම් ලීනකේ ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයට පැමිණ ආරක්‍ෂක තත්ත්වය ඇතුළු සියලු කරුණු පෞද්ගලිකව තහවුරු කළහ. මේ තත්ත්වය තුළ අද සිට සාමාන්‍ය පරිදි ලේකම් කාර්යාල කටයුතු සිදු කෙරෙනු ඇති."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මාස 3 යි",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "හමුදා",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොටුව ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද, සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය අප්‍රේල් 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොට කෝ කාමා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 වැනිදා පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "24 වැනිදා පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමල් ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විකුම් ලියනකේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "3 மாதங்களின் பின் திறக்கப்படும் ஜனாதிபதி செயலக கதவுகள் : பாதுகாப்புச் செயலர், இராணுவ தளபதி மேற்பார்வை !",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பு - கோட்டை ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்தின்  நடவடிக்கைகள் இன்று 25 ஆம் திகதி திங்கட்கிழமை முதல் மீண்டும்  வழமைக்கு திரும்பவுள்ளது.",
        "கடந்த ஏப்ரல் 9 ஆம் திகதி முதல் காலி முகத்திடல் கோட்டா கோ கம போராட்டக்காரர்களால், ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்தின் பிரதான நுழைவாயில் (கேட் சீரோ) மறிக்கப்பட்டு ஆர்ப்பட்டம் செய்யப்பட்ட நிலையில், செயலக நடவடிக்கைகள் மட்டுப்படுத்தப்பட்டதாக அறிவிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இவ்வாறான நிலையில் கடந்த ஜூலை 9 ஆம் திகதி கொழும்பில் திரண்ட இலட்சக்காணக்கான மக்களால்  ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம் கைப்பற்றப்பட்டதை அடுத்து அச்செயலகத்தின் நடவடிக்கைகல் முற்றாக செயலிழந்தன.",
        "இந் நிலையில் கடந்த 22 ஆம் திகதி வெள்ளிக்கிழமை அதிகாலை ஆயுதப் படையினர், ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்துக்கு முன்பாக போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டவர்களை தாக்கி துரத்தி, செயலகத்தை தமது கட்டுப்பாட்டுக்குள் கொண்டுவந்தனர்.",
        "இந் நிலையில் செயலகத்தின் சேதமாக்கப்பட்டிருந்த கதவுகள், ஜன்னல்கள் 24 ஆம் திகதி நண்பகலகும் போது புனரமைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த நிலையில், இன்று முதல் வழமையான நடவடிக்கைகளை முன்னெடுக்க திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளதாக ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்தின் உயரதிகாரி ஒருவர் கூறினார்.",
        "24 ஆம் திகதி பிற்பகல் பாதுகாப்பு செயலாளர் ஜெனரல் கமல் குனரத்னவும் இராணுவ தளபதி லெப்டினன் ஜெனரால் விக்கும் லியனகேயும் ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்துக்கு சென்று, அதன் பாதுகபபு நிலவரம் உள்ளிட்ட அனைத்து விடயங்களையும் நேரில் உறுதி செய்துள்ளனர். இந் நிலையிலேயே இன்று முதல் செயலக  நடவடிக்கைகள் வழமை போல நடை பெறவுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3 மாதங்கள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இராணுவம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று, திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஏப்ரல் 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டா கோ காமா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மில்லியன்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செயலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளிக்கிழமை 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செயலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "24ம் தேதி மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "24ம் தேதி மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கமல் குணரத்னா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கும் லீனகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}