{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Community-Kitchen-hosted-by-Rotary-Club-of-Colombo-Mid-Town-and-Meal-Care/56-738550",
  "time_ut": 1660178785,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Community Kitchen hosted by Rotary Club of Colombo Mid Town and Meal Care",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Community Kitchen hosted by Rotary Club of Colombo Mid Town and Meal Care",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Rotary Club of Colombo Mid Town, together with Meal Care, recently distributed 400 lunch packs amongst the community in Rajaguru Sri Subuthi Road and Veluwanarama Road in Wellawatta. Beneficiaries of the project included economically deprived families who are affected by the current economic crisis. Rotarians and their families from the Rotary Club of Colombo Mid Town and volunteers from Meal Care participated in the distribution with the aim of uplifting the community during this challenging time period. The project was funded by attune Lanka Ltd. and the well-wishers."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Rotary Club of Colombo Mid Town and Meal Care",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Rotary Club of Colombo Mid Town",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "400",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajaguru Sri Subuthi Road",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wellawatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rotarians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Rotary Club of Colombo Mid Town",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Meal Care",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "attune Lanka Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කොළඹ මිඩ් ටවුන් හි රොටරි සමාජය සහ ආහාර සත්කාරය මගින් සත්කාරකත්වය සපයන ප්‍රජා කුස්සිය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොළඹ මිඩ් ටවුන් රොටරි සමාජය, මීල් කෙයාර් සමඟ එක්ව පසුගියදා වැල්ලවත්ත රාජගුරු ශ්‍රී සුබුති පාරේ සහ වේළුවනාරාම පාරේ ප්‍රජාව අතරට දිවා ආහාර පැකට් 400ක් බෙදා දෙන ලදී. ව්‍යාපෘතියේ ප්‍රතිලාභීන් අතර වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් පීඩාවට පත් වූ ආර්ථික වශයෙන් අසරණ වූ පවුල් ඇතුළත් විය. මෙම අභියෝගාත්මක කාලසීමාව තුළ ප්‍රජාව නඟා සිටුවීමේ අරමුණින් කොළඹ මිඩ් ටවුන් හි රොටරි සමාජයේ රොටේරියන් සහ ඔවුන්ගේ පවුල්වල සාමාජිකයින් සහ මීල් කෙයාර් හි ස්වේච්ඡා සේවකයන් බෙදා හැරීම සඳහා සහභාගී විය. මෙම ව්‍යාපෘතිය සඳහා අරමුදල් සපයන ලද්දේ attune Lanka Ltd සහ හිතවතුන් විසිනි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Rotary Club of Colombo Mid Town සහ Meal Care",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ මිඩ් ටවුන් රොටරි සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "400",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජගුරු ශ්‍රී සුබුති පාර",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැල්ලවත්ත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොටේරියන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ මැද නගරයේ රොටරි සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආහාර සත්කාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "attune Lanka Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரோட்டரி கிளப் ஆஃப் கொழும்பு மிட் டவுன் மற்றும் மீல் கேர் மூலம் சமூக சமையலறை நடத்தப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "Rotary Club of Colombo Mid Town, Meal Care உடன் இணைந்து அண்மையில் 400 மதிய உணவுப் பொதிகளை இராஜகுரு ஸ்ரீ சுபுதி வீதி மற்றும் வெள்ளவத்தையில் உள்ள வேலுவனாராம வீதியில் உள்ள சமூகத்தினருக்கு வழங்கியது. இத்திட்டத்தின் பயனாளிகளில் தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பொருளாதாரத்தில் பின்தங்கிய குடும்பங்களும் அடங்குவர். இந்த சவாலான காலப்பகுதியில் சமூகத்தை மேம்படுத்தும் நோக்கில் கொழும்பு மிட் டவுன் ரோட்டரி கழகத்தைச் சேர்ந்த ரோட்டரியர்கள் மற்றும் அவர்களது குடும்பத்தினர் மற்றும் மீல் கேர் தன்னார்வ தொண்டர்கள் இந்த விநியோகத்தில் கலந்து கொண்டனர். அட்யூன் லங்கா லிமிடெட் மற்றும் நலன் விரும்பிகளால் இந்த திட்டம் நிதியளிக்கப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரோட்டரி கிளப் ஆஃப் கொழும்பு மிட் டவுன் மற்றும் மீல் கேர்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு மிட் டவுன் ரோட்டரி கிளப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "400",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜகுரு ஸ்ரீ சுபுதி சாலை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளவத்தை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோட்டரியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோட்டரி கிளப் ஆஃப் கொழும்பு மிட் டவுன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உணவு பராமரிப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அட்யூன் லங்கா லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}