{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/02/power-outages-from-3rd-to-5th-sept-announced/",
  "time_ut": 1662119460,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Power Outages from 3rd to 5th Sept. announced",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Power Outages from 3rd to 5th Sept. announced",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka (PUCSL) approved power cuts from 03rd – 05th September as follows;",
        "Money printing fueling inflation; CBSL autonomy paramount – IMF Mission Chief",
        "UKs DCTS to benefit Sri Lanka on duty-free access – PM Boris Johnson",
        "Political instability will pose risks to implement reforms, and distribution of IMF funding – Fitch"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3rd",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sept.",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "03rd – 05th September",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boris Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සැප්තැම්බර් 3 සිට 5 දක්වා විදුලිය විසන්ධි කරන බව නිවේදනය කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව (PUCSL) පහත සඳහන් පරිදි සැප්තැම්බර් 03 සිට 05 දක්වා විදුලිය විසන්ධි කිරීම අනුමත කරන ලදී.",
        "මුදල් මුද්‍රණය උද්ධමනය වැඩි කරයි; CBSL ස්වයං පාලනය අතිමහත් - IMF දූත මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානියා",
        "තීරුබදු රහිත ප්‍රවේශය සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ප්‍රතිලාභ ලබා දෙන එක්සත් රාජධානියේ DCTS - අගමැති බොරිස් ජොන්සන්",
        "දේශපාලන අස්ථාවරත්වය ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ ක්‍රියාවට නැංවීමට සහ ජාමූඅ අරමුදල් බෙදා හැරීමට අවදානමක් ඇති කරයි - ෆිච්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3 වැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "සැප්.",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 03 - 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරිස් ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "செப்., 3ம் தேதி முதல் 5ம் தேதி வரை மின்தடை அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழு (PUCSL) செப்டெம்பர் 03 முதல் 05 வரை மின்வெட்டுகளை பின்வருமாறு அங்கீகரித்துள்ளது.",
        "பணம் அச்சிடுதல் பணவீக்கத்தைத் தூண்டுகிறது; CBSL தன்னாட்சி மிக முக்கியமானது - IMF மிஷன் தலைவர்",
        "ஐக்கிய இராச்சியத்தின் டி.சி.டி.எஸ்., இலங்கைக்கு வரியற்ற அணுகலில் பயனளிக்கும் - பிரதமர் போரிஸ் ஜோன்சன்",
        "அரசியல் ஸ்திரமின்மை சீர்திருத்தங்களைச் செயல்படுத்தவும், IMF நிதியை விநியோகிக்கவும் ஆபத்துகளை ஏற்படுத்தும் - ஃபிட்ச்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3வது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "செப்.",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "03 - 05 செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "போரிஸ் ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}