{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Celebration-of-75-glorious-years-of-India-s-independence-in-Sri-Lanka/56-738718",
  "time_ut": 1660593750,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Celebration of 75 glorious years of India’s independence in Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Celebration of 75 glorious years of India’s independence in Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "75 years of India’s Independence was celebrated with great fervour in different parts of Sri Lanka yesterday.",
        "The celebrations this year are a part of the ‘Azadi Ka Amrit Mahotsav’ initiative, a global campaign to commemorate 75 years of a progressive and self-reliant India through numerous activities and events.",
        "The main event in Colombo was held at ‘India House’, the official residence of High Commissioner of India. High Commissioner Gopal Baglay hoisted India’s national flag and inspected the guard of honour. He also read excerpts of the President of India’s message on the occasion.",
        "Several cultural events added flavour to the milestone celebrations. Sri Lanka Navy Band played melodious tunes, symbolic of valour and patriotism. Students of Guru Sadara Supathum performed a dance to the music of ‘Bharat ko Salaam’. There was another ‘Garba’ dance performance in honour of Goddess Durga, who epitomises strength, protection and motherhood. The event was telecast live and was attended virtually by friends of India and members of the Indian community in Sri Lanka.",
        "High Commissioner and officers of High Commission of India also paid homage at the Indian Peace Keeping Force (IPKF) Memorial to the memory of the Indian soldiers of IPKF who made the supreme sacrifice defending peace and unity of Sri Lanka.",
        "Special events were organised by the Assistant High Commission in Kandy, Consulate General in Jaffna and Consulate General in Hambantota as well on the momentous occasion. It needs emphasis that the celebrations in Jaffna were held at the iconic Jaffna Cultural Centre, a state of the art and one of its kind facility in the city which was built with grant assistance by Government of India.",
        "A highlight of this year’s celebration was the enthusiastic participation of members of the Indian community in the ‘Har Ghar Tiranga’ campaign wherein they showcased their love and respect for the Indian tri-coloured flag in various innovative ways."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "75 glorious years",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "75 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gopal Baglay",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Guru Sadara Supathum",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ko Salaam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Goddess Durga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Indian Peace Keeping Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "IPKF",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the supreme sacrifice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Assistant High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna Cultural Centre",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the ‘Har Ghar Tiranga’",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්දීය නිදහසේ අභිමානවත් වසර 75 සැමරීම",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දීය නිදහසේ 75 වැනි සංවත්සරය ඊයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විවිධ ප්‍රදේශවල මහත් උද්යෝගයෙන් සමරනු ලැබීය.",
        "මෙම වසරේ සැමරුම් බොහෝ ක්‍රියාකාරකම් සහ සිදුවීම් හරහා ප්‍රගතිශීලී සහ ස්වයංපෝෂිත ඉන්දියාවේ 75 වසර සැමරීමේ ගෝලීය ව්‍යාපාරයක් වන ‘Azadi Ka Amrit Mahotsav’ වැඩසටහනේ කොටසකි.",
        "කොළඹ ප්‍රධාන උත්සවය ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයාගේ නිල නිවස වන ‘ඉන්දියා හවුස්’ හිදී පැවැත්විණි. මහ කොමසාරිස් ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ ඉන්දීය ජාතික ධජය ඔසවමින් ගෞරවනීය ආචාර පෙළපාලිය නිරීක්ෂණය කළේය. එම අවස්ථාවේදී ඉන්දීය ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ පණිවිඩයේ කොටස්ද ඔහු කියෙව්වා.",
        "සංස්කෘතිකාංග කිහිපයක්ම උත්සව අවස්ථාවට රසය එක් කළේය. ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාවේ තූර්ය වාදක කණ්ඩායම ධෛර්යය සහ දේශප්‍රේමය සංකේතවත් කරමින් මධුර නාද වාදනය කළේය. ගුරු සාදර සුපතුම් හි සිසුන් ‘භාරත් කෝ සලාම්’ සංගීතයට නර්තනයක් ඉදිරිපත් කළහ. ශක්තිය, ආරක්ෂාව සහ මාතෘත්වය සංකේතවත් කරන දුර්ගා දේවියට ගෞරවයක් වශයෙන් තවත් ‘ගර්බා’ නැටුම් සංදර්ශනයක් පැවැත්විණි. මෙම අවස්ථාව සජීවීව විකාශය වූ අතර ඉන්දියාවේ මිතුරන් සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්දියානු ප්‍රජාවේ සාමාජිකයින් පාහේ එයට සහභාගී විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සාමය සහ සමගිය ආරක්ෂා කිරීම සඳහා උත්තරීතර පරිත්‍යාගයක් කළ IPKF හි ඉන්දියානු සොල්දාදුවන් සිහිපත් කිරීම සඳහා ඉන්දීය සාම සාධක හමුදාවේ (IPKF) ස්මාරකය වෙත ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයා සහ නිලධාරීන් ද උපහාර දැක්වීය.",
        "මහනුවර සහකාර මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය, යාපනයේ කොන්සල් ජනරාල් කාර්යාලය සහ හම්බන්තොට කොන්සල් ජනරාල් කාර්යාලය විසින් විශේෂ උත්සව සංවිධානය කරන ලදී. යාපනයේ සැමරුම් ඉන්දීය රජයේ ප්‍රදාන ආධාර මත ඉදිකරන ලද නවීනතම සහ නවීනතම පහසුකම් සහිත යාපනය සංස්කෘතික මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ දී පැවැත් වූ බව අවධාරණය කළ යුතුය.",
        "මෙවර සැමරුම් උත්සවයේ විශේෂත්වයක් වූයේ ඉන්දීය ත්‍රි-වර්ණ ධජයට ඔවුන්ගේ ආදරය හා ගෞරවය විවිධ නව්‍ය ආකාරයෙන් ප්‍රදර්ශනය කළ ‘හර් ඝර් ටිරංගා’ ප්‍රචාරණ ව්‍යාපාරයට ඉන්දීය ප්‍රජාවේ සාමාජිකයන් උද්යෝගයෙන් සහභාගි වීමයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තේජාන්විත වසර 75 ක්",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 75 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 75 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුරු සාදර සුපතුම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ko සලාම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුර්ගා දේවිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු සාම සාධක හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "IPKF",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "උත්තරීතර පූජාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සහකාර මහ කොමසාරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය සංස්කෘතික මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "'හර් ඝර් තිරංග'",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையில் இந்தியா சுதந்திரம் அடைந்து 75வது ஆண்டு விழா கொண்டாடப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்தியாவின் 75வது சுதந்திர தின விழா நேற்று இலங்கையின் பல்வேறு பகுதிகளில் கோலாகலமாக கொண்டாடப்பட்டது.",
        "இந்த ஆண்டு கொண்டாட்டங்கள் 'ஆசாதி கா அம்ரித் மஹோத்சவ்' முன்முயற்சியின் ஒரு பகுதியாகும், இது பல்வேறு நடவடிக்கைகள் மற்றும் நிகழ்வுகள் மூலம் முற்போக்கான மற்றும் தன்னம்பிக்கை கொண்ட இந்தியாவின் 75 ஆண்டுகளை நினைவுகூரும் உலகளாவிய பிரச்சாரமாகும்.",
        "கொழும்பில் முக்கிய நிகழ்வு இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகரின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லமான ‘இந்தியா ஹவுஸில்’ நடைபெற்றது. உயர் ஆணையர் கோபால் பாக்லே இந்தியாவின் தேசியக் கொடியை ஏற்றி வைத்து மரியாதையை பார்வையிட்டார். இந்த நிகழ்வில் இந்திய ஜனாதிபதியின் செய்தியின் சில பகுதிகளையும் அவர் வாசித்தார்.",
        "பல கலாச்சார நிகழ்வுகள் மைல்கல் கொண்டாட்டங்களுக்கு சுவை சேர்த்தன. வீரம் மற்றும் தேசபக்தியின் அடையாளமாக இலங்கை கடற்படை இசைக்குழு மெல்லிசை இசையை இசைத்தது. குரு சடார சுபத்தின் மாணவர்கள் ‘பாரத் கோ சலாம்’ இசைக்கு நடனமாடினர். வலிமை, பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் தாய்மையின் உருவகமான துர்கா தேவியின் நினைவாக மற்றொரு ‘கர்பா’ நடன நிகழ்ச்சி நடைபெற்றது. இந்நிகழ்வு நேரடியாக ஒளிபரப்பப்பட்டதுடன், இந்திய நண்பர்கள் மற்றும் இலங்கையில் உள்ள இந்திய சமூகத்தை சேர்ந்தவர்கள் இதில் கலந்து கொண்டனர்.",
        "இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் மற்றும் இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயத்தின் அதிகாரிகளும், இலங்கையின் அமைதி மற்றும் ஒற்றுமையைப் பாதுகாப்பதற்காக உச்சபட்ச தியாகம் செய்த IPKF இன் இந்திய வீரர்களின் நினைவாக இந்திய அமைதி காக்கும் படை (IPKF) நினைவிடத்தில் மரியாதை செலுத்தினர்.",
        "கண்டியில் உள்ள உதவி உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம், யாழ்ப்பாணத்தில் உள்ள துணைத் தூதரகம் மற்றும் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டையில் உள்ள துணைத் தூதரகத்தினால் விசேட நிகழ்வுகள் ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்டிருந்தன. யாழ்ப்பாணத்தில் கொண்டாட்டங்கள் இந்திய அரசின் மானிய உதவியுடன் கட்டப்பட்ட நகரத்தில் உள்ள நவீன மற்றும் அதன் வகையான வசதிகளில் ஒன்றான யாழ் கலாச்சார மையத்தில் நடைபெற்றது என்பதை வலியுறுத்த வேண்டும்.",
        "இந்த ஆண்டு கொண்டாட்டத்தின் சிறப்பம்சமாக, ‘ஹர் கர் திரங்கா’ பிரச்சாரத்தில் இந்திய சமூகத்தைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள் ஆர்வத்துடன் பங்கேற்று, பல்வேறு புதுமையான வழிகளில் இந்திய மூவர்ணக் கொடியின் மீதான தங்கள் அன்பையும் மரியாதையையும் வெளிப்படுத்தினர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "75 புகழ்பெற்ற ஆண்டுகள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "75 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோபால் பாக்லே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குரு சாதார சுபத்தும்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோ சலாம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "துர்கா தேவி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய அமைதி காக்கும் படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "IPKF",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "உயர்ந்த தியாகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உதவி உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாணம் கலாச்சார மையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "'ஹர் கர் திரங்கா'",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}