{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Dinesh-to-be-sworn-in-today/108-241549",
  "time_ut": 1658460445,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Dinesh to be sworn in today",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dinesh to be sworn in today",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The previous cabinet of ministers who functioned under Gotabaya Rajapaksa and Ranil Wickremesinghe will be sworn in today after the Prime Minister takes oaths",
        "Following the appointment of Ranil Wickremesinghe as the President, his national list seat in Parliament has fallen vacant and discussions are now ongoing as to who will be appointed to fill the vacant seat",
        "Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna Parliamentarian Dinesh Gunawardena will take oaths as the Prime Minister today morning along with the previous cabinet of ministers, a senior SLPP source told Daily Mirror last night.",
        "Gunawardena will be sworn in as the Prime Minister before President Ranil Wickremesinghe following many discussions within the SLPP party yesterday.",
        "Sources said that while time was short, the previous cabinet of ministers who functioned under Gotabaya Rajapaksa and Ranil Wickremesinghe will be sworn in today after the Prime Minister takes oaths, in order to restart the stalled work but once Parliament convenes on July 27th, discussions on a national government will take place.",
        "Once political parties agree to join a national government, the cabinet will be reshuffled and a new cabinet of ministers will take oaths, sources said.",
        "\"Right now there are a lot of papers that need to be submitted to cabinet and the ministries have just stopped functioning. So the previous government will take oaths today and restart their work,\" senior sources said.",
        "Following the appointment of Ranil Wickremesinghe as the President, his national list seat in Parliament has fallen vacant and discussions are now ongoing within the UNP camp as to who will be appointed to fill the vacant seat.",
        "The names shortlisted as of yesterday was Ruwan Wijewardena, Sagala Ratnayaka, Akila Viraj Kariyawasam or Vajira Abeywardena. (JAMILA HUSAIN)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna Parliamentarian",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gunawardena",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 27th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ruwan Wijewardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sagala Ratnayaka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Akila",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Viraj Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vajira Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "JAMILA HUSAIN",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දිනේෂ් අද දිවුරුම් දෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ සහ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ යන මහත්වරුන් යටතේ මීට පෙර කටයුතු කළ අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා දිවුරුම් දීමෙන් අනතුරුව අද දිවුරුම් දීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපති ධූරයට පත්වීමත් සමග ඔහුගේ ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධුරය පුරප්පාඩු වී ඇති අතර පුරප්පාඩු වූ මන්ත්‍රී ධුරය සඳහා පත් කරන්නේ කවුරුන්ද යන්න පිළිබඳව මේ වන විට සාකච්ඡා වෙමින් පවතිනවා.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පෙර කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය සමඟ අද පෙරවරුවේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දෙන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ මූලාශ්‍රයක් ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ තුළ ඊයේ පැවති සාකච්ඡා රැසකින් අනතුරුව ගුණවර්ධන මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "කාලය මද වූවත්, ඇනහිට තිබූ වැඩකටයුතු යළි ආරම්භ කිරීම සඳහා, ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ සහ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ යටතේ ක්‍රියාත්මක වූ හිටපු අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය අද දින අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා දිවුරුම් දීමෙන් පසු දිවුරුම් දෙනු ඇති බව ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි. නමුත් ජූලි 27 පාර්ලිමේන්තුව රැස් වූ පසු සාකච්ඡා ජාතික ආණ්ඩුවක් ඇති වෙනවා.",
        "ජාතික ආණ්ඩුවකට එක්වීමට දේශපාලන පක්ෂ එකඟ වූ පසු අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය සංශෝධනය කර නව අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලයක් දිවුරුම් දීමට නියමිත බව ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "\"මේ වන විට කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය ලිපි ලේඛන රාශියක් ඇති අතර අමාත්‍යාංශවල ක්‍රියාකාරිත්වය නවතා දමා ඇත. ඒ නිසා පසුගිය රජය අද දිවුරුම් දී නැවත වැඩ අරඹයි,\" ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ ආරංචි මාර්ග පවසයි.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපති ධූරයට පත්වීමත් සමග ඔහුගේ ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධුරය පුරප්පාඩු වී ඇති අතර පුරප්පාඩු වූ මන්ත්‍රී ධුරය සඳහා පත් කරන්නේ කවුරුන්ද යන්න පිළිබඳව මේ වනවිට එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ කඳවුර තුළ සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වෙමින් තිබේ.",
        "ඊයේ වන විට කෙටි ලැයිස්තුගත කර තිබුණේ රුවන් විජේවර්ධන, සාගල රත්නායක, අකිල විරාජ් කාරියවසම් හෝ වජිර අබේවර්ධන යන නම් ය. (ජමිලා හුසේන්)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුවන් විජේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගල රත්නායක",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අකිල",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "විරාජ් කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වජිර අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජමිලා හුසේන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தினேஷ் இன்று பதவியேற்க உள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச மற்றும் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் கீழ் செயற்பட்ட முன்னைய அமைச்சரவை பிரதமர் பதவிப்பிரமாணம் செய்து கொண்டதன் பின்னர் இன்று பதவியேற்கவுள்ளது.",
        "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமிக்கப்பட்டதையடுத்து, நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் அவரது தேசியப் பட்டியல் ஆசனம் வெற்றிடமாகியுள்ள நிலையில், அந்த வெற்றிடத்திற்கு யாரை நியமிப்பது என்பது தொடர்பில் தற்போது கலந்துரையாடல்கள் இடம்பெற்று வருகின்றன.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் தினேஸ் குணவர்தன, முன்னைய அமைச்சரவையுடன் இணைந்து இன்று காலை பிரதமராக பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்து கொள்வார் என ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் சிரேஷ்ட வட்டாரம் ஒன்று நேற்று இரவு டெய்லி மிரருக்கு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன கட்சிக்குள் நேற்று இடம்பெற்ற பல கலந்துரையாடலின் பின்னர் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க முன்னிலையில் குணவர்தன பிரதமராக பதவியேற்கவுள்ளார்.",
        "கால அவகாசம் குறைவாக இருந்தபோதிலும், கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச மற்றும் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் கீழ் செயற்பட்ட முன்னைய அமைச்சரவை, பிரதமர் பதவிப்பிரமாணம் செய்து கொண்டதன் பின்னர், முடங்கிய பணிகளை மீள ஆரம்பிக்கும் நோக்கிலும், ஜூலை 27ஆம் திகதி பாராளுமன்றம் கூடியதும், இன்று பதவிப்பிரமாணம் செய்து கொள்வதாக வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன. தேசிய அரசாங்கம் அமையும்.",
        "தேசிய அரசாங்கத்தில் இணைவதற்கு அரசியல் கட்சிகள் இணக்கம் தெரிவித்தவுடன், அமைச்சரவை மாற்றியமைக்கப்பட்டு புதிய அமைச்சரவை பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்து கொள்ளப்படும் என தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "\"இப்போது அமைச்சரவைக்கு சமர்ப்பிக்க வேண்டிய ஆவணங்கள் நிறைய உள்ளன, மேலும் அமைச்சகங்கள் செயல்படுவதை நிறுத்திவிட்டன. எனவே முந்தைய அரசாங்கம் இன்று சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்து தங்கள் பணிகளை மீண்டும் தொடங்கும்\" என்று மூத்த வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன.",
        "ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமிக்கப்பட்டதையடுத்து, நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் அவருக்கு இருந்த தேசியப் பட்டியல் ஆசனம் வெற்றிடமாகியுள்ள நிலையில், அந்த வெற்றிடத்திற்கு யாரை நியமிப்பது என்பது தொடர்பில் ஐ.தே.கட்சியில் தற்போது கலந்துரையாடல்கள் இடம்பெற்று வருகின்றன.",
        "நேற்றைய நிலவரப்படி ருவான் விஜேவர்தன, சாகல ரத்நாயக்க, அகில விராஜ் காரியவசம் அல்லது வஜிர அபேவர்தன ஆகிய பெயர்கள் தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டன. (ஜமிலா ஹுசைன்)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.பி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.பி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ருவான் விஜேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகல ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அகிலா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "விராஜ் காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜமிலா ஹுசைன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}