{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/රනිල්ගේ-ගෙට-ගිනි-තැබූ-සජබ-සංවිධායකගේ-පුතා-රට-පනී-/1-616554",
  "time_ut": 1658056868,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රනිල්ගේ ගෙට ගිනි තැබූ සජබ සංවිධායකගේ පුතා රට පනී?",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ranil's house was set on fire by the son of a Sahaba organizer.",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Criminal investigation department sources say that a son of a former deputy minister who was wanted for arrest after setting fire to the private house of Acting President Ranil Wickramasinghe last night has fled the country.",
        "Sources of the Criminal Investigation Department say that the son of this Deputy Minister has left for Dubai last night (10).",
        "According to the report, the father of the fugitive suspect is a deputy minister in the Mahinda Rajapaksa government, and later he left the party and joined the Samagi Jana Balawega, and currently he is working as a constituency organizer in an area near Colombo.",
        "After occupying the President's House for the last (9) days, the activists went to the house of Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe, the politician's son, and released a video on social media saying, \"We are going to raid Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe's house just as we raided the President's House, and to inform the people who value the country to come for it.\" Ranil Wickramasinghe's house was raided and he requested through the video not to leave the house until he received the letter of resignation from the post of Prime Minister.",
        "Police sources say that investigations have been started regarding a woman who recorded this video from there, and the woman has been in contact with a politician who was engaged in struggles in many areas including Colombo and engaged in struggles with her on several occasions.",
        "According to sources of the Criminal Investigation Department, the Criminal Investigation Department has taken over all the videos and photographs related to these incidents and started investigations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sahaba",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9) days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රනිල්ගේ ගෙට ගිනි තැබූ සජබ සංවිධායකගේ පුතා රට පනී?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ඉකුත් 09 දින රාත්‍රියේ ගිනි තබා හානි කිරීමට මුල්ව , අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට සොයමින් සිටි හිටපු නියෝජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරයකුගේ පුතකු රටින් පලාගොස් ඇති බව අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තු ආරංචි මාර්ග පවසයි.",
        "මෙම නියෝජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරයාගේ පුතා ඉකුත් (10) දින රාත්‍රියේ ඩුබායි රාජ්‍ය බලා පිටත්ව ගොස් ඇති බවද අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තු ආරංචි මාර්ග කියයි.",
        "පලාගිය සැකකරුගේ පියා මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ රජයේ  නියෝජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරයකු බවත්, පසුව ඔහු එම පක්ෂයෙන් ඉවත්ව සමගි ජන බලවේගයට එක්ව ඇති අතර, දැනට ඔහු කොළඹට ආසන්න ප්‍රදේශයක ආසන සංවිධායකවරයකු වශයෙක් කටයුතු කරමින් සිටින බව වාර්තාවේ.",
        "අරගලකරුවන් ඉකුත් (9) දින ජනාධිපති මන්දිය අත්පත්කර ගැනීමෙන් පසු මෙම දේශපානඥයාගේ පුතා රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ නිවස ආසන්නයට ගොස් “අපි ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය වැටලුවා සේම රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ නිවසට වැටලීමට යන බවත්,  රට වටින් පිරිසට ඒ සදහා පැමිණෙන ලෙසටත්,” දන්වා සමාජ මාධ්‍ය වෙත වීඩියෝවක් මුදා හැරිමින් ඉල්ලා සිටි ඇති අතර, රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ නිවස වටලා අගමැති ධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලිපිය අතට ලබාගන්නා තෙක් එම නිවසින් පිටව නොයන බවට ද ඔහු වීඩියෝව හරහා ඉල්ලීම් කර තිබුණි.",
        "මේ සදහා ආධාර අනුබල ලබා දෙමින් මෙම වීඩියෝ පටය එහි සිට පටිගත කළ කාන්තාවක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමර්ශන ආරම්භ කර ඇති බවත්, එම කාන්තාව අවස්ථා කිහිපයක් ම කොළඹ ඇතුලු ප්‍රදේශ රැසක අරගලවල නිරත සිටි දේශපාලනඥවරියක් සමග සම්බන්ධවෙමින් ඇය සමග අරගල වන නිරත වී ඇති බවද පොලිස් ආරංචි මාර්ග පවසයි.",
        "මෙම සිදුවීම්වලට අදාල සියලු වීඩියෝ සහ ඡායාරූප රැසක් අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව බාරයට ගෙන විමර්ශන ආරම්භ කර ඇති බවද අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තු ආරංචි මර්ග කියයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "සහබා",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9) දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சஹாபா அமைப்பாளரின் மகனால் ரணிலின் வீடு தீக்கிரையாக்கப்பட்டது.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட வீட்டிற்கு நேற்றிரவு தீ வைத்த பின்னர் கைது செய்ய தேடப்பட்டு வந்த முன்னாள் பிரதி அமைச்சர் ஒருவரின் மகன் நாட்டை விட்டு தப்பிச் சென்றுள்ளதாக குற்றப் புலனாய்வு திணைக்கள வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "இந்த பிரதி அமைச்சரின் மகன் நேற்று (10) இரவு டுபாய் சென்றுள்ளதாக குற்றப் புலனாய்வு திணைக்கள வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "தப்பியோடிய சந்தேக நபரின் தந்தை மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ அரசாங்கத்தில் பிரதி அமைச்சராகவும், பின்னர் அக்கட்சியில் இருந்து விலகி சமகி ஜன பலவேகவில் இணைந்து கொண்டதாகவும், தற்போது கொழும்பிற்கு அருகில் உள்ள பிரதேசத்தில் தொகுதி அமைப்பாளராக கடமையாற்றி வருவதாகவும் அந்த செய்தியில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "கடந்த (9) நாட்களாக ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையை ஆக்கிரமித்திருந்த செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள், அரசியல்வாதியின் மகன் திரு.ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் வீட்டிற்குச் சென்று சமூக ஊடகங்களில் காணொளி ஒன்றை வெளியிட்டு, “நாங்கள் திரு. நாங்கள் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையை சோதனையிட்டோம், அதற்காக நாட்டை மதிக்கும் மக்களை வருமாறு அறிவிக்க வேண்டும்” என ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் வீடு சோதனையிடப்பட்டதுடன், பிரதமர் பதவியில் இருந்து விலகுவதற்கான கடிதம் கிடைக்கும் வரை வீட்டை விட்டு வெளியே வரவேண்டாம் என வீடியோ மூலம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார். அமைச்சர்.",
        "அங்கிருந்து இந்த காணொளியை பதிவு செய்த பெண் ஒருவர் தொடர்பில் விசாரணைகள் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும், கொழும்பு உள்ளிட்ட பல பிரதேசங்களில் போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டு அவருடன் பல தடவை போராட்டங்களில் ஈடுபட்ட அரசியல்வாதி ஒருவருடன் குறித்த பெண் தொடர்பு கொண்டுள்ளதாகவும் பொலிஸ் வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "இந்த சம்பவங்கள் தொடர்பான அனைத்து வீடியோக்கள் மற்றும் புகைப்படங்களை குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களம் கைப்பற்றி விசாரணைகளை ஆரம்பித்துள்ளதாக குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களத் தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சஹாபா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9) நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}