{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/President-Wickremesinghe-discharged-from-court-proceedings/342-241890",
  "time_ut": 1658911965,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President Wickremesinghe discharged from court proceedings",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President Wickremesinghe discharged from court proceedings",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Supreme Court today ordered to discharge President Ranil Wickremesinghe from the court proceedings pertaining to the Fundamental Rights petitions filed over economic crisis in the country.",
        "These petitions had been filed seeking an order to take legal action against those responsible for financial irregularities and mismanagement of the economy.",
        "Meanwhile, the Supreme Court decided to name former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa as a respondent in the petitions since presidential immunity does not applicable to him following his resignation from the post of President. Accordingly, the registrar of the Supreme Court was ordered to issue notice on former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, returnable for August 1.",
        "Three university academics, Sri Lankan swimmer and coach Julian Bolling, former Chairman of the Ceylon Chamber of Commerce Chandra Jayaratne, Transparency International and  Jehan Canaga Retna filed these petitions urging authorities to take legal action against the main culprits responsible for the current economic crisis.",
        "The petitioners had named 39 individuals including then Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa, former Finance Minister Basil Rajapaksa, former Secretary to the President P.B. Jayasundara, former Governors of the Central Bank Ajith Nivard Cabraal and W.D. Lakshman and former Ministry of Finance Secretary S.R. Atygalle as respondents.",
        "President's Counsel Chandaka Jayasundere appearing on behalf of the petitioners informed court that the petitioners are not expecting to seek a relief against President Ranil Wickremesinghe although he had been named as a respondent in the petition. Accordingly he moved Supreme Court to release President Ranil Wickremesinghe from the court proceedings.",
        "Taking into consideration the facts, the Supreme Court five-judge-bench headed by Chief Justice Jayantha Jayasuriya decided to terminate court proceedings against President Wickremesinghe and he was discharged from the case proceedings pertaining to these Fundamental Rights petitions.",
        "President's Counsel Ronald Perera with Senior Counsel Eraj de Silva appeared on behalf of President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Additional Solicitor General Nerin Pulle appeared for the Attorney General. (Lakmal Sooriyagoda)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julian Bolling",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Chamber of Commerce Chandra Jayaratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Transparency International",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jehan Canaga Retna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "39",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "P.B. Jayasundara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank Ajith Nivard Cabraal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "W.D. Lakshman",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "S.R. Atygalle",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chandaka Jayasundere",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayantha Jayasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ronald Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nerin Pulle",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakmal Sooriyagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ අධිකරණ කටයුතුවලින් නිදහස් විය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රටේ පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ගොනු කර ඇති මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් පෙත්සම්වලට අදාළ අධිකරණ කටයුතුවලින් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ නිදහස් කිරීමට ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය අද නියෝග කළා.",
        "මූල්‍ය අක්‍රමිකතා සහ ආර්ථිකයේ අයහපත් කළමනාකරණය සම්බන්ධයෙන් වගකිව යුත්තන්ට එරෙහිව නීතිමය පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස නියෝග කරන්නැයි ඉල්ලා මෙම පෙත්සම් ගොනු කර තිබුණි.",
        "මේ අතර, හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ජනාධිපති ධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු ඔහුට හිමි ජනාධිපති මුක්තිය අදාළ නොවන බැවින් එම පෙත්සම්වල වගඋත්තරකරුවෙකු ලෙස නම් කිරීමට ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය තීරණය කළේය. ඒ අනුව, හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට අගෝස්තු 01 වැනිදාට නැවත ඉදිරිපත් කළ හැකි නොතීසි නිකුත් කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයේ රෙජිස්ට්‍රාර්වරයාට නියෝග කෙරිණි.",
        "වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට වගකිව යුතු ප්‍රධාන වැරදිකරුවන්ට එරෙහිව නීතිමය පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස බලධාරීන්ට බලකරමින් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල විද්වතුන් තිදෙනෙකු, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පිහිනුම් ක්‍රීඩක සහ පුහුණුකරු ජූලියන් බෝලින්, ලංකා වාණිජ මණ්ඩලයේ හිටපු සභාපති චන්ද්‍රා ජයරත්න, ට්‍රාන්ස්පේරන්සි ඉන්ටර්නැෂනල් සහ  ජෙහාන් කැනග රෙට්නා මෙම පෙත්සම් ගොනු කළහ.",
        "පෙත්සම්කරුවන් විසින් එවකට අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ, හිටපු මුදල් අමාත්‍ය බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ, හිටපු ජනාධිපති ලේකම් පී.බී. ජයසුන්දර, මහ බැංකුවේ හිටපු අධිපතිවරුන් වන අජිත් නිවාඩ් කබ්රාල් සහ ඩබ්ලිව්.ඩී.ලක්ෂ්මන් සහ හිටපු මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම් එස්.ආර්. ආටිගල වගඋත්තරකරුවන් ලෙස.",
        "පෙත්සම්කරුවන් වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි ජනාධිපති නීතීඥ චන්දක ජයසුන්දර මහතා අධිකරණයට දන්වා සිටියේ මෙම පෙත්සමේ වගඋත්තරකරුවෙකු ලෙස නම් කර තිබුණද ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට එරෙහිව සහනයක් ලබාගැනීමට පෙත්සම්කරුවන් අපේක්ෂා නොකරන බවයි. ඒ අනුව ඔහු ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අධිකරණ ක්‍රියාවලියෙන් නිදහස් කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය හමුවට ගියේය.",
        "කරුණු සැලකිල්ලට ගත් අගවිනිසුරු ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය ප්‍රමුඛ පංච පුද්ගල ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ විනිසුරු මඩුල්ල ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට එරෙහි අධිකරණ ක්‍රියාමාර්ග අවසන් කිරීමට තීරණය කළ අතර, මෙම මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් පෙත්සම්වලට අදාළ නඩු කටයුතුවලින් ඔහු නිදහස් කෙරිණි.",
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වෙනුවෙන් ජනාධිපති නීතීඥ රොනල්ඩ් පෙරේරා මහතා සහ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නීතිඥ එරාජ් ද සිල්වා මහතා පෙනී සිටියේය.",
        "නීතිපතිවරයා වෙනුවෙන් අතිරේක සොලිසිටර් ජනරාල් නෙරින් පුල්ලේ මහතා පෙනී සිටියේය. (ලක්මාල් සූරියගොඩ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලියන් බොලිං",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා වාණිජ මණ්ඩලය චන්ද්‍රා ජයරත්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්‍රාන්ස්පේරන්සි ඉන්ටර්නැෂනල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෙහාන් කැනගා රෙට්නා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "39",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පී.බී. ජයසුන්දර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව අජිත් නිවාඩ් කබ්රාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩබ්ලිව්.ඩී.ලක්ෂ්මන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ආර්. ආටිගල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චන්දක ජයසුන්දර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොනල්ඩ් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නෙරින් පුල්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්මාල් සූරියගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க நீதிமன்ற நடவடிக்கைகளில் இருந்து விடுவிக்கப்பட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி தொடர்பில் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ள அடிப்படை உரிமை மீறல் மனுக்கள் தொடர்பான நீதிமன்ற நடவடிக்கைகளில் இருந்து ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவை விடுவிக்குமாறு உயர் நீதிமன்றம் இன்று உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "நிதி முறைகேடுகள் மற்றும் தவறான பொருளாதார மேலாண்மைக்கு காரணமானவர்களுக்கு எதிராக சட்ட நடவடிக்கை எடுக்க உத்தரவிடக் கோரி இந்த மனுக்கள் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டிருந்தன.",
        "இதேவேளை, முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச ஜனாதிபதி பதவியை இராஜினாமா செய்ததையடுத்து, அவருக்கு ஜனாதிபதி விதிவிலக்கு பொருந்தாது என்பதால், இந்த மனுக்களில் பிரதிவாதியாக பெயரிட உயர் நீதிமன்றம் தீர்மானித்துள்ளது. இதன்படி, முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவை எதிர்வரும் ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் முதலாம் திகதிக்கு திருப்பி அனுப்புமாறு நோட்டீஸ் வழங்குமாறு உயர் நீதிமன்ற பதிவாளருக்கு உத்தரவிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையின் நீச்சல் வீரரும் பயிற்சியாளருமான ஜூலியன் பொலிங், இலங்கை வர்த்தக சம்மேளனத்தின் முன்னாள் தலைவர் சந்திர ஜயரத்ன, ட்ரான்ஸ்பரன்சி இன்டர்நேஷனல் மற்றும்  ஜெஹான் கனக ரெட்னா ஆகிய மூன்று பல்கலைக்கழக கல்வியாளர்கள், தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு காரணமான முக்கிய குற்றவாளிகளுக்கு எதிராக சட்ட நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு அதிகாரிகளை வலியுறுத்தி இந்த மனுக்களை தாக்கல் செய்தனர்.",
        "அப்போது பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க, முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ, முன்னாள் நிதி அமைச்சர் பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ, முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியின் செயலாளர் பி.பி. ஜயசுந்தர, மத்திய வங்கியின் முன்னாள் ஆளுநர்களான அஜித் நிவார்ட் கப்ரால் மற்றும் டபிள்யூ.டி.லக்ஷ்மன் மற்றும் நிதி அமைச்சின் முன்னாள் செயலாளர் எஸ்.ஆர். ஆட்டிகல பிரதிவாதிகள்.",
        "மனுவில் பிரதிவாதியாக ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பெயரிடப்பட்டுள்ள போதிலும், அவருக்கு எதிராக நிவாரணம் கோருவதற்கு மனுதாரர்கள் எதிர்பார்க்கவில்லை என மனுதாரர்கள் சார்பில் ஆஜரான ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி சாந்தக ஜயசுந்தர நீதிமன்றில் அறிவித்தார். இதன்படி நீதிமன்ற நடவடிக்கைகளில் இருந்து ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை விடுவிக்குமாறு அவர் உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தில் மனுத்தாக்கல் செய்தார்.",
        "உண்மைகளை கருத்திற்கொண்டு, பிரதம நீதியரசர் ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய தலைமையிலான ஐவரடங்கிய நீதியரசர்கள் குழாம், ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு எதிரான நீதிமன்ற நடவடிக்கைகளை நிறுத்த தீர்மானித்ததுடன், இந்த அடிப்படை உரிமை மனுக்கள் தொடர்பான வழக்கு நடவடிக்கைகளில் இருந்து அவர் விடுவிக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க சார்பில் ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி ரொனால்ட் பெரேரா மற்றும் சிரேஷ்ட சட்டத்தரணி எராஜ் டி சில்வா ஆகியோர் ஆஜராகினர்.",
        "அட்டர்னி ஜெனரல் சார்பில் கூடுதல் சொலிசிட்டர் ஜெனரல் நெரின் புல்லே ஆஜரானார். (லக்மால் சூரியகொட)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலியன் பொலிங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை வர்த்தக சம்மேளனம் சந்திரா ஜயரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிரான்ஸ்பரன்சி இன்டர்நேஷனல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெஹான் கனகா ரெட்னா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "39",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பி.பி. ஜெயசுந்தர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி அஜித் நிவார்ட் கப்ரால்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டபிள்யூ.டி.லக்ஷ்மன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஆர். ஆடிகல்லே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சந்தக ஜயசுந்தரே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரொனால்ட் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேரின் புள்ளே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்மால் சூரியகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}