{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/27/rs-911-mn-received-for-x-press-pearl-compensation/",
  "time_ut": 1661585460,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Rs. 911 Mn received for X-Press Pearl compensation",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Rs. 911 Mn received for X-Press Pearl compensation",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Ministry of Fisheries says that another Rs. 911 Mn was received as  compensation to be awarded to the Sri Lankan fishermen who were affected by the fire that broke out on board the X-Press Pearl Cargo Vessel in the seas off Colombo.",
        "The Ministry of Fisheries said X-Press pearl insurers made the compensation payment.",
        "Accordingly, the Ministry said that arrangements will be made to distribute this money among 15,032 fishermen identified in Gampaha, Colombo, and Kalutara districts.",
        "Earlier on two occasions, Rs. 348 Mn and Rs. 335 Mn given by the X-Press pearl insurers were distributed to the fishermen as interim compensation through the Divisional Secretariats in the respective localities of the affected fishermen.",
        "All fishermen affected by the X-Press Pearl Maritime Disaster, depending on their type of vessel, method of fishing, and loss of income, received Rs. 80,000 to Rs. 240,000 as compensation so far.",
        "Earlier, Sri Lanka authorites imposed a ban on fishing on the sea area from Negombo to Panadura due to the affects of the X-Press Pearl Maritime Disaster, and this ban directly affected over 15,000 Sri Lankan fishermen.",
        "The X-Press Pearl incident is the worst maritime disaster to have struck Sri Lanka. It has had a significant impact on Sri Lanka’s sensitive coastal environment, local communities and the economy.",
        "Moreover, the event continues to unfold, and its active pollution generation phase will only come to closure with the elimination of the risks from the wreck and containers lost at sea.",
        "Along with uncertainties of cascading environmental damage, the incident’s complexity stems from the range of pollutants involved – oil, hazardous chemicals and plastics – and the lack of clarity regarding the nature and status of a substantial part of the vessel’s cargo.",
        "Moreover, the growing geographic extent of the plastic spill – the largest on record – is expected to have transboundary impacts further compounding the problem."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "911",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mn",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "X-Press Pearl",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Fisheries",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "911",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Fisheries",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "X-Press",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15,032",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalutara",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "335",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "X-Press",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Divisional Secretariats",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the X-Press",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pearl Maritime Disaster",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "80,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "240,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Negombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Panadura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pearl Maritime Disaster",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රුපියල්. X-Press පර්ල් වන්දි සඳහා මිලියන 911 ක් ලැබිණි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ධීවර අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසන්නේ තවත් රුපියල් කෝටි 100ක මුදලක් ලබා දෙන බවයි. කොළඹට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ මුහුදේදී එක්ස් ප්‍රෙස් පර්ල් භාණ්ඩ යාත්‍රාවේ ඇති වූ ගින්නෙන් විපතට පත් ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ධීවරයින් සඳහා වන්දි වශයෙන් රුපියල් මිලියන 911ක් ලැබිණි.",
        "ධීවර අමාත්‍යාංශය පැවසුවේ එක්ස් ප්‍රෙස් මුතු රක්‍ෂණ සමාගම් විසින් වන්දි ගෙවීම සිදු කළ බවයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව ගම්පහ, කොළඹ සහ කළුතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවල හඳුනාගත් ධීවරයින් 15,032ක් අතර මෙම මුදල් බෙදාදීමට කටයුතු කරන බව එම අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි.",
        "මීට පෙර අවස්ථා දෙකකදී රු. මිලියන 348 ක් සහ රු. X-Press මුතු රක්‍ෂණකරුවන් විසින් ලබාදුන් රුපියල් මිලියන 335 ක මුදල විපතට පත් ධීවරයන්ගේ අදාළ ප්‍රදේශවල ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කාර්යාල හරහා අතුරු වන්දි වශයෙන් ධීවරයන් වෙත බෙදා දෙන ලදී.",
        "X-Press Pearl සමුද්‍රීය ව්‍යසනයෙන් විපතට පත් සියලුම ධීවරයින්ට ඔවුන්ගේ යාත්‍රා වර්ගය, මසුන් ඇල්ලීමේ ක්‍රමය සහ ආදායම් අහිමි වීම මත රු. 80,000 සිට රු. මේ වන විට 240,000 වන්දි වශයෙන්.",
        "මීට පෙර එක්ස් ප්‍රෙස් පර්ල් සමුද්‍ර ව්‍යසනයේ බලපෑම හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලධාරීන් මීගමුව සිට පානදුර දක්වා මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයේ මසුන් ඇල්ලීම තහනම් කළ අතර මෙම තහනම ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ධීවරයින් 15,000 කට වැඩි පිරිසකට සෘජුවම බලපෑවේය.",
        "එක්ස් ප්‍රෙස් පර්ල් සිද්ධිය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට බලපෑ දරුණුතම සමුද්‍ර ව්‍යසනයයි. එය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංවේදී වෙරළබඩ පරිසරයට, ප්‍රාදේශීය ප්‍රජාවන්ට සහ ආර්ථිකයට සැලකිය යුතු බලපෑමක් ඇති කර ඇත.",
        "එපමණක් නොව, මෙම සිදුවීම දිගින් දිගටම දිග හැරෙන අතර, එහි සක්‍රීය පරිසර දූෂණය උත්පාදනය කිරීමේ අදියර අවසන් වනු ඇත්තේ මුහුදේ නැතිවූ සුන්බුන් සහ බහාලුම්වල අවදානම ඉවත් කිරීමත් සමඟ පමණි.",
        "කඳුරැල්ල පාරිසරික හානිය පිළිබඳ අවිනිශ්චිතතාවයන් සමඟින්, සිද්ධියේ සංකීර්ණත්වය පැන නගින්නේ දූෂක - තෙල්, අන්තරායකර රසායනික ද්‍රව්‍ය සහ ප්ලාස්ටික් - සහ යාත්‍රාවේ භාණ්ඩවල සැලකිය යුතු කොටසක ස්වභාවය සහ තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳ පැහැදිලිකම නොමැතිකම සම්බන්ධ දූෂක පරාසයෙනි.",
        "තවද, ප්ලාස්ටික් කාන්දුවේ වර්ධනය වන භූගෝලීය ප්‍රමාණය - වාර්තාගත විශාලතම - ප්‍රශ්නය තව දුරටත් උග්‍ර කරමින් දේශසීමා බලපෑම් ඇති කරනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "911",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mn",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "X-Press පර්ල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධීවර අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "911",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධීවර අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "X-Press",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15,032 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුතර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "335",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "X-Press",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කාර්යාල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "X-Press",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පර්ල් සමුද්‍ර ව්‍යසනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "80,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "240,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පානදුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පර්ල් සමුද්‍ර ව්‍යසනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரூ. X-Press Pearl இழப்பீட்டிற்காக 911 Mn பெறப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); கடற்றொழில் அமைச்சு மேலும் ஒரு இலட்சம் ரூபாவை வழங்குவதாகக் கூறுகிறது. கொழும்பு கடற்பகுதியில் எக்ஸ்-பிரஸ் பெர்ல் சரக்கு கப்பலில் ஏற்பட்ட தீ விபத்தில் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட இலங்கை மீனவர்களுக்கு இழப்பீடாக 911 மில்லியன் ரூபாய் பெறப்பட்டது.",
        "X-Press முத்து காப்பீட்டாளர்கள் இழப்பீடு தொகையை செலுத்தியதாக மீன்பிடி அமைச்சகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி, கம்பஹா, கொழும்பு மற்றும் களுத்துறை மாவட்டங்களில் இனங்காணப்பட்டுள்ள 15,032 மீனவர்களுக்கு இந்தப் பணத்தை விநியோகிக்க ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்படும் என அமைச்சு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "முன்னதாக இரண்டு முறை ரூ. 348 மில்லியன் மற்றும் ரூ. X-Press முத்து காப்பீட்டாளர்களால் வழங்கப்பட்ட 335 மில்லியன் மீனவர்களுக்கு இடைக்கால இழப்பீடாக பாதிக்கப்பட்ட மீனவர்களின் பிரதேச செயலகங்கள் மூலம் விநியோகிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "X-Press Pearl கடல்சார் பேரிடரால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட அனைத்து மீனவர்களுக்கும், அவர்களின் கப்பல் வகை, மீன்பிடிக்கும் முறை மற்றும் வருவாய் இழப்பு ஆகியவற்றைப் பொறுத்து, ரூ. 80,000 முதல் ரூ. இதுவரை இழப்பீடாக 240,000.",
        "முன்னதாக, X-Press Pearl கடல்சார் பேரழிவின் பாதிப்புகள் காரணமாக நீர்கொழும்பு முதல் பாணந்துறை வரையிலான கடல் பகுதியில் மீன்பிடிக்க இலங்கை அதிகாரிகள் தடை விதித்தனர், மேலும் இந்த தடை 15,000 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட இலங்கை மீனவர்களை நேரடியாகப் பாதித்தது.",
        "X-Press Pearl சம்பவம் இலங்கையை தாக்கிய மிக மோசமான கடல்சார் பேரழிவாகும். இது இலங்கையின் உணர்திறன் வாய்ந்த கரையோர சூழல், உள்ளூர் சமூகங்கள் மற்றும் பொருளாதாரம் ஆகியவற்றில் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க தாக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "மேலும், நிகழ்வு தொடர்ந்து வெளிவருகிறது, மேலும் அதன் செயலில் உள்ள மாசு உருவாக்கும் கட்டம் கடலில் இழந்த சிதைவுகள் மற்றும் கொள்கலன்களின் அபாயங்களை நீக்குவதன் மூலம் மட்டுமே மூடப்படும்.",
        "சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதிப்புகளின் நிச்சயமற்ற தன்மையுடன், இந்த சம்பவத்தின் சிக்கலானது சம்பந்தப்பட்ட மாசுபாடுகள் - எண்ணெய், அபாயகரமான இரசாயனங்கள் மற்றும் பிளாஸ்டிக்குகள் - மற்றும் கப்பலின் சரக்குகளின் கணிசமான பகுதியின் தன்மை மற்றும் நிலை குறித்த தெளிவின்மை ஆகியவற்றிலிருந்து உருவாகிறது.",
        "மேலும், பிளாஸ்டிக் கசிவின் வளர்ந்து வரும் புவியியல் அளவு - பதிவில் மிகப்பெரியது - எல்லை தாண்டிய தாக்கங்கள் சிக்கலை மேலும் அதிகரிக்கும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "911",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mn",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "எக்ஸ்-பிரஸ் பேர்ல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்றொழில் அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "911",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்றொழில் அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எக்ஸ்-பிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15,032",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "335",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எக்ஸ்-பிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரதேச செயலகங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எக்ஸ்-பிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முத்து கடல்சார் பேரழிவு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "80,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "240,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீர்கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாணந்துறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முத்து கடல்சார் பேரழிவு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}