{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Sajith-calls-on-President-to-issue-unconditional-pardon-for-Ranjan/56-739169",
  "time_ut": 1661539779,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sajith calls on President to issue unconditional pardon for Ranjan",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sajith calls on President to issue unconditional pardon for Ranjan",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa, while thanking the President for pardoning former Samagi Jana Balawegaya MP Ranjan Ramanayake, called on President Ranil Wickremesinghe to pardon him unconditionally.",
        "“I thank the President for pardoning Ranjan Ramanayake who is a humanitarian and a true representative of the people. However, he has only received a conditional pardon,” Premadasa said.",
        "President Wickremesinghe has granted pardon on the condition that Ramanayake should not make any statement critical or derogatory of the entire Judiciary in future, a release from the President’s Media Division said.",
        "The popular actor and politician was convicted over contempt of court charges and sentenced to four years of rigorous imprisonment in January 2021 over a statement made about the country’s Judiciary.",
        "Ramanayake received a conditional pardon from President Ranil Wickremesinghe yesterday and was released from the Welikada Prison. Large crowds, as well as friends and acquaintances of the politician turned actor, were seen gathered to welcome him. Ramanayake was led out from the prison premises amidst chants of ‘Ranja! Ranja!’ by those gathered.",
        "“Today we, along with the whole country, are ecstatic about his release. But we ask the President to grant him an unconditional pardon allowing him to once again serve the country as a representative of the people,” Premadasa said.",
        "Following his release, Ramanayake visited the Gangaramaya Temple to evoke the blessings of the triple gem and then held a press briefing along with Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa at the latter’s office in Colombo where he said he intends to remain independent."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranjan",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "January 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Welikada Prison",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රන්ජන්ට කොන්දේසි විරහිත සමාවක් දෙන්නැයි සජිත් ජනපතිගෙන් ඉල්ලයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතාට සමාව ලබාදීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජනාධිපතිවරයාට ස්තූතිය පළ කරමින් ඔහුට කොන්දේසි විරහිතව සමාව දෙන ලෙස ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "“මනුෂ්‍යවාදී සැබෑ ජනතා නියෝජිතයකු වන රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතාට සමාව දීම ගැන මම ජනාධිපතිතුමාට ස්තූතිවන්ත වෙනවා. නමුත් ඔහුට ලැබී තිබෙන්නේ කොන්දේසි සහිත සමාවක් පමණයි” ප්‍රේමදාස පැවසීය.",
        "මින් ඉදිරියට රාමනායක මහතා සමස්ත අධිකරණයටම විවේචනාත්මක හෝ අවමන් සහගත ප්‍රකාශයක් නොකළ යුතුය යන කොන්දේසිය මත ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සමාව ලබාදී ඇති බව ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය නිකුත් කළ නිවේදනයක දැක්වේ.",
        "ජනප්‍රිය නළුවා සහ දේශපාලනඥයා අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමේ චෝදනාවකට වරදකරු වූ අතර රටේ අධිකරණය පිළිබඳව කළ ප්‍රකාශයක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් 2021 ජනවාරි මාසයේදී වසර හතරක බරපතල සිරදඬුවම් නියම කරන ලදී.",
        "රාමනායක මහතා ඊයේ ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අතින් කොන්දේසි සහිත සමාව ලබා වැලිකඩ බන්ධනාගාරයෙන් නිදහස් විය. ඔහු පිළිගැනීමට විශාල ජනකායක් මෙන්ම නළුවකු බවට පත් වූ දේශපාලනඥයාගේ හිතවතුන් සහ හිතවතුන් ද රැස්ව සිටිනු දක්නට ලැබිණි. රාමනායක බන්ධනාගාර පරිශ්‍රයෙන් පිටතට ගෙන යන ලද්දේ ‘රංජා! රන්ජා!’ රැස්ව සිටි අය විසිනි.",
        "“අද අපි, මුළු රටම ඔහුව නිදහස් කිරීම ගැන සතුටු වෙනවා. නමුත් අපි ජනාධිපතිතුමාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින්නේ ඔහුට නැවත වරක් ජනතා නියෝජිතයෙකු ලෙස රට වෙනුවෙන් සේවය කිරීමට ඉඩ සලසමින් ඔහුට කොන්දේසි විරහිත සමාවක් ලබා දෙන ලෙසයි” ප්‍රේමදාස පැවසීය.",
        "නිදහස ලැබීමෙන් අනතුරුව රාමනායක මහතා ගංගාරාම විහාරස්ථානයට ගොස් තෙරුවන් සරණයි. අනතුරුව විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතාගේ කොළඹ පිහිටි කාර්යාලයේ දී මාධ්‍ය හමුවක් ද පැවැත්වූ අතර එහිදී ඔහු කියා සිටියේ ස්වාධීනව සිටීමට අදහස් කරන බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රන්ජන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 ජනවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩ බන්ධනාගාරය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரஞ்சனுக்கு நிபந்தனையற்ற மன்னிப்பு வழங்குமாறு சஜித் ஜனாதிபதியிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச, முன்னாள் சமகி ஜன பலவேகய நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு மன்னிப்பு வழங்கியமைக்காக ஜனாதிபதிக்கு நன்றி தெரிவிக்கும் அதேவேளை, நிபந்தனையற்ற மன்னிப்பு வழங்குமாறு ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "“மனிதாபிமானமும் உண்மையான மக்களின் பிரதிநிதியுமான ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு மன்னிப்பு வழங்கியதற்காக ஜனாதிபதிக்கு நான் நன்றி கூறுகிறேன். எனினும் அவருக்கு நிபந்தனையுடன் கூடிய மன்னிப்பு மாத்திரமே கிடைத்துள்ளது” என பிரேமதாச தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "எதிர்காலத்தில் முழு நீதித்துறையையும் விமர்சிக்கும் வகையில் அல்லது இழிவுபடுத்தும் வகையிலான எந்தவொரு அறிக்கையையும் ராமநாயக்க வெளியிடக்கூடாது என்ற நிபந்தனையுடன் ஜனாதிபதி விக்ரமசிங்க மன்னிப்பு வழங்கியுள்ளார் என ஜனாதிபதி ஊடகப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "பிரபல நடிகரும் அரசியல்வாதியும் நீதிமன்ற அவமதிப்புக் குற்றச்சாட்டின் பேரில் குற்றவாளி என நிரூபிக்கப்பட்டு, நாட்டின் நீதித்துறை பற்றி வெளியிட்ட அறிக்கைக்காக ஜனவரி 2021 இல் நான்கு ஆண்டுகள் கடுங்காவல் சிறைத்தண்டனை விதிக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "ராமநாயக்க நேற்று ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம் நிபந்தனைகளுடன் கூடிய மன்னிப்பை பெற்று வெலிக்கடை சிறைச்சாலையில் இருந்து விடுவிக்கப்பட்டார். நடிகராக மாறிய அரசியல்வாதியின் நண்பர்கள் மற்றும் தெரிந்தவர்கள் என ஏராளமானோர் அவரை வரவேற்க திரண்டிருந்தனர். ‘ரஞ்சா! ரஞ்சா!’ என்று கூடியிருந்தவர்களால்.",
        "“இன்று முழு நாட்டோடு சேர்ந்து நாமும் அவரது விடுதலை குறித்து மகிழ்ச்சியில் இருக்கிறோம். ஆனால் அவருக்கு மீண்டும் ஒருமுறை மக்கள் பிரதிநிதியாக நாட்டுக்கு சேவையாற்றுவதற்கு அவருக்கு நிபந்தனையற்ற மன்னிப்பு வழங்குமாறு ஜனாதிபதியிடம் கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறோம் என பிரேமதாச தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "விடுதலை செய்யப்பட்டதைத் தொடர்ந்து, கங்காராமய கோவிலுக்குச் சென்ற ராமநாயக்க, மும்மூர்த்திகளின் ஆசிர்வாதத்தைப் பெறுவதற்காக, கொழும்பில் உள்ள சஜித் பிரேமதாசவுடன் இணைந்து ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பொன்றை நடத்தினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரஞ்சன்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு வருடங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிக்கடை சிறைச்சாலை",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}