{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Cabinet-nod-for-freight-service-between-KKS-and-Tamil-Nadu-soon-Devananda/108-239945",
  "time_ut": 1656376387,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Cabinet nod for freight service between KKS and Tamil Nadu soon: Devananda",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Cabinet nod for freight service between KKS and Tamil Nadu soon: Devananda",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Cabinet has given the nod to begin a freight transportation service between Kankesanthurai and Tamil Nadu, Minister of Fisheries Douglas Devananda said yesterday.",
        "Minister Devananda said he will make arrangements to begin initial work on the service soon.",
        "He said this service will pave the way for the transportation of fuel, medicine and fertilizer between the two destinations.",
        "“It will be possible to transport these goods at a lower cost,” the Minister said.",
        "The Minister said that air transportation between Palali, Trichi and Chennai will begin on July 1 this year. (Kelum Bandara)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "KKS",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tamil Nadu",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Devananda",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kankesanthurai and Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Douglas Devananda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Devananda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Palali",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chennai",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 1 this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelum Bandara",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "KKS සහ තමිල්නාඩුව අතර භාණ්ඩ ප්‍රවාහන සේවයට කැබිනට් අනුමැතිය ළඟදීම: දේවානන්ද",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "කන්කසන්තුරේ සහ තමිල්නාඩුව අතර භාණ්ඩ ප්‍රවාහන සේවාවක් ආරම්භ කිරීමට කැබිනට් අනුමැතිය හිමිව ඇති බව ධීවර අමාත්‍ය ඩග්ලස් දේවානන්ද මහතා ඊයේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "එම සේවාවේ මූලික කටයුතු කඩිනමින් ආරම්භ කිරීමට කටයුතු කරන බව අමාත්‍ය දේවානන්ද මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ගමනාන්ත දෙක අතර ඉන්ධන, ඖෂධ සහ පොහොර ප්‍රවාහනය සඳහා මෙම සේවාව මගපාදන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "අඩු මුදලකට මේ භාණ්ඩ ප්‍රවාහනය කරන්න පුළුවන් වේවි යැයි අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "පලාලි, ට්‍රිචි සහ චෙන්නායි අතර ගුවන් ප්‍රවාහනය මේ වසරේ ජූලි 01 වැනිදා ආරම්භ කරන බව අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය. (කැළුම් බණ්ඩාර)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කේ.කේ.එස්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "දේවානන්දයි",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කන්කසන්තුරේ සහ තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩග්ලස් දේවානන්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දේවානන්දයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පලාලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චෙන්නායි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ ජූලි 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැළුම් බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "KKS மற்றும் தமிழ்நாடு இடையே சரக்கு போக்குவரத்து சேவைக்கு விரைவில் அமைச்சரவை ஒப்புதல்: தேவானந்தா",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "காங்கேசன்துறைக்கும் தமிழகத்துக்கும் இடையில் சரக்கு போக்குவரத்து சேவையை ஆரம்பிப்பதற்கு அமைச்சரவை அங்கீகாரம் வழங்கியுள்ளதாக கடற்றொழில் அமைச்சர் டக்ளஸ் தேவானந்தா நேற்று தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த சேவைக்கான முதற்கட்ட பணிகளை விரைவில் தொடங்க ஏற்பாடு செய்வதாக அமைச்சர் தேவானந்தா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்தச் சேவையானது இரண்டு இடங்களுக்கு இடையே எரிபொருள், மருந்து மற்றும் உரப் போக்குவரத்துக்கு வழி வகுக்கும் என்றார்.",
        "\"குறைந்த விலையில் இந்த பொருட்களை கொண்டு செல்ல முடியும்\" என்று அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "பலாலி, திருச்சி மற்றும் சென்னை இடையே விமான போக்குவரத்து இந்த ஆண்டு ஜூலை 1 ஆம் தேதி தொடங்கும் என்று அமைச்சர் கூறினார். (கெலும் பண்டார)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கே.கே.எஸ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "தேவானந்தா",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காங்கேசன்துறை மற்றும் தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டக்ளஸ் தேவானந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேவானந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பலாலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சென்னை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு ஜூலை 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெலும் பண்டார",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}