{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/சட்டத்தின்-ஆட்சி-நிலைநாட்டப்பட-வேண்டும்-ஜுலி-சங்/175-300392",
  "time_ut": 1657735107,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "சட்டத்தின் ஆட்சி நிலைநாட்டப்பட வேண்டும்: ஜுலி சங்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Rule of law must be upheld: Juli Sangh",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The US ambassador to Sri Lanka, Julie Singh, said that the rule of law should be established.",
        "He also noted that a peaceful transfer of power is necessary within Sri Lanka's democratic and constitutional framework.",
        "According to this, the people's demands for accountability, transparency, democratic governance and a better future can be fulfilled, said Julie Sung, the US Ambassador to Sri Lanka. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Juli Sangh",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Singh",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Julie Sung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නීතියේ ආධිපත්‍යය තහවුරු කළ යුතුය: ජූලි සංග්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "නීතියේ ආධිපත්‍යය ස්ථාපිත කළ යුතු බව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අමෙරිකානු තානාපතිනි ජුලී සිං මහත්මිය පැවසුවාය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී සහ ව්‍යවස්ථාමය රාමුව තුළ සාමකාමී බල හුවමාරුවක් අවශ්‍ය බව ද ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මේ අනුව වගවීම, විනිවිදභාවය, ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී පාලනයක් සහ යහපත් අනාගතයක් සඳහා වූ ජනතා ඉල්ලීම් ඉටු කළ හැකි බව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඇමෙරිකානු තානාපතිනි ජුලී සන්ග් මහත්මිය ප්‍රකාශ කළාය. (ඒ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජූලි සංග්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි සිං",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි සන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சட்டத்தின் ஆட்சி நிலைநாட்டப்பட வேண்டும்: ஜுலி சங்",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "சட்டத்தின் ஆட்சி நிலைநாட்டப்பட வேண்டும் என இலங்கைக்கான அமெரிக்க துரதுவர் ஜுலி சங் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் ஜனநாயக மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு கட்டமைப்பிற்குள் அமைதியான அதிகார பரிமாற்றம் அவசியமானது எனவும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "இதன்படி பொறுப்புக்கூறல், வெளிப்படைத்தன்மை, ஜனநாயக ஆட்சி மற்றும் சிறந்த எதிர்காலத்திற்கான மக்களின் கோரிக்கைகளை நிறைவேற்ற முடியும் எனவும் இலங்கைக்கான அமெரிக்க துரதுவர் ஜுலி சங் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜூலி சங்கம்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சிங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}