{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Man-killed-two-year-old-child-and-woman-injured-in-shooting-in-Peliyagoda/108-239819",
  "time_ut": 1656262627,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Man killed, two year old child and woman injured in shooting in Peliyagoda",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Man killed, two year old child and woman injured in shooting in Peliyagoda",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A 32 year old man was killed and his 2-year-old son and another woman were hospitalised following a shooting incident at Pattiya Junction in Peliyagoda tonight.",
        "Police said the victim was traveling with his wife and 2-year-old son on a motorbike when two men arrived on a motorcycle and opened fire and fled.",
        "They said another woman who was passing by at the time of the shooting was also injured and was admitted to the National Hospital in Colombo.",
        "The 2-year-old boy is being treated at the Lady Ridgeway Children's Hospital.",
        "The deceased has been identified as a resident of Minuwangoda.",
        "The motive for the murder has not been revealed yet. The suspects had fled the scene and the Peliyagoda Police are conducting further investigations under the supervision of the SSP in charge of the Kelaniya Division."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "two year old",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Peliyagoda",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "32 year old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pattiya Junction",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tonight",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the National Hospital in Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Lady Ridgeway Children's Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Minuwangoda",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SSP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kelaniya Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පෑලියගොඩ වෙඩි තැබීමකින් පුද්ගලයෙක් මරුට, දෙහැවිරිදි කුඩා දරුවෙකු සහ කාන්තාවක් තුවාල ලබයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පෑලියගොඩ, පට්ටිය හන්දියේදී අද රාත්‍රියේ සිදුවූ වෙඩි තැබීමකින් 32 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයෙකු මියගොස් ඔහුගේ 2 හැවිරිදි පුත්‍රයා සහ තවත් කාන්තාවක් රෝහල් ගත කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "පොලීසිය පැවසුවේ, මියගිය පුද්ගලයා සිය බිරිඳ සහ අවුරුදු 2ක පිරිමි දරුවා සමඟ යතුරුපැදියකින් ගමන් කරමින් සිටියදී යතුරුපැදියකින් පැමිණි පුද්ගලයින් දෙදෙනෙකු වෙඩි තබා පළා ගොස් ඇති බව ය.",
        "වෙඩි තැබීම සිදුවන අවස්ථාවේ ඒ අසලින් ගමන් කළ තවත් කාන්තාවක් ද තුවාල ලබා කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කර ඇති බවයි ඔවුන් පැවසුවේ.",
        "අවුරුදු 2ක පිරිමි ළමයා රිජ්වේ ආර්යා ළමා රෝහලේ ප්‍රතිකාර ලබනවා.",
        "මියගොස් ඇත්තේ මිනුවන්ගොඩ ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිකරුවෙකි.",
        "ඝාතනයට හේතුව මෙතෙක් අනාවරණ වී නැහැ. සැකකරුවන් එම ස්ථානයෙන් පලාගොස් ඇති අතර කැලණිය කොට්ඨාස භාර ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරීවරයාගේ අධීක්‍ෂණය යටතේ පෑලියගොඩ පොලිසිය වැඩිදුර විමර්ශන සිදුකරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අවුරුදු දෙකයි",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "පෑලියගොඩ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "32 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 2 ක් වයසැති",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පට්ටිය හන්දිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 2 ක් වයසැති",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 2 ක් වයසැති",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිජ්වේ ආර්යා ළමා රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිනුවන්ගොඩ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැලණිය කොට්ඨාසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பேலியகொடவில் இடம்பெற்ற துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டில் ஆண் பலி, இரண்டு வயது குழந்தை மற்றும் பெண் காயமடைந்துள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பேலியகொட, பட்டிய சந்தியில் இன்று இரவு இடம்பெற்ற துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டு சம்பவத்தில் 32 வயதான ஆண் ஒருவர் கொல்லப்பட்டதுடன், அவரது 2 வயது மகனும் மற்றுமொரு பெண்ணும் வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "பாதிக்கப்பட்ட நபர் தனது மனைவி மற்றும் 2 வயது மகனுடன் மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் பயணித்த போது மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் வந்த இருவர் துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்திவிட்டு தப்பிச் சென்றுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டின் போது அவ்வழியாகச் சென்ற மற்றுமொரு பெண்ணும் காயமடைந்து கொழும்பில் உள்ள தேசிய வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அவர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "2 வயது சிறுவனுக்கு லேடி ரிட்ஜ்வே குழந்தைகள் மருத்துவமனையில் சிகிச்சை அளிக்கப்பட்டு வருகிறது.",
        "உயிரிழந்தவர் மினுவாங்கொடை பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்தவர் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "கொலைக்கான காரணம் இதுவரை வெளியாகவில்லை. சந்தேகநபர்கள் சம்பவ இடத்திலிருந்து தப்பிச் சென்றுள்ளதுடன், களனி பிரிவுக்கு பொறுப்பான சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகரின் மேற்பார்வையில் பேலியகொட பொலிஸார் மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு வயது",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "பேலியகொட",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "32 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பட்டியா சந்திப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்றிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் உள்ள தேசிய வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லேடி ரிட்ஜ்வே குழந்தைகள் மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மினுவாங்கொட",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எஸ்.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "களனி பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}