{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/international/ෂී-ලෝක-තරුණ-සංවර්ධන-සංසදයට-සුබපැතුම්-යවයි/3-395649",
  "time_ut": 1658471486,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ෂී ලෝක තරුණ සංවර්ධන සංසදයට සුබපැතුම් යවයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Xi sends greetings to the World Youth Development Forum",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "While young people represent hope, they are the creators of the future, says Chinese President Xi Jinping.",
        "In a letter to the World Youth Development Forum, Xi said China always views youth as the driving force of social development and encourages them to release their youthful energy as they participate in community building and promote a shared future for mankind.",
        "Xi expressed his belief that the forum will become an important platform for young people from all over the world to contribute to global development. He also called for global efforts to promote youth development.",
        "Young people around the world should stand up for the common values ​​of humanity, such as peace, development, equality, justice, democracy and freedom, Xi said.",
        "He urged the youth to facilitate the implementation of the United Nations 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development and promote the global development initiative with concrete actions.",
        "The forum will be held online and offline from July 21 to 23, and is said to be attended by nearly 2,000 youth delegates from over 100 countries."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Xi",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "the World Youth Development Forum",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi Jinping",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the World Youth Development Forum",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Xi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "​​of",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sustainable Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 21 to 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly 2,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ෂී ලෝක තරුණ සංවර්ධන සංසදයට සුබපැතුම් යවයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "යෞවනයන් බලාපොරොත්තුව නියෝජනය කරන අතරම, ඔවුන් අනාගතයේ නිර්මාණකරුවන් වන බව චීන ජනාධිපති ෂී ජින්පිං පවසයි.",
        "චීනය සැමවිටම තරුණයින් සමාජ සංවර්ධනයේ ගාමක බලවේගය ලෙස සලකන බවත් ප්‍රජාවක් ගොඩනැගීමට සහභාගී වනවිට සහ මානව වර්ගයා සඳහා හවුල් අනාගතයක් ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමේදී ඔවුන්ගේ තරුණ ශක්තිය මුදා හැරීමට ඔවුන් දිරිමත් කරන බවත් ෂී පවසා සිටියේ ලෝක තරුණ සංවර්ධන සංසදයට ලිපියක් යවමිනි.",
        "මෙම සංසදය ලොව පුරා සිටින තරුණ තරුණියන්ට ගෝලීය සංවර්ධනයට දායක විය හැකි වැදගත් වේදිකාවක් බවට පත්වනු ඇතැයි ෂී සිය විශ්වාසය පළ කළේය. තරුණ සංවර්ධනය ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීම සඳහා ගෝලීය උත්සාහයන්ද ඔහු ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "ලොවපුරා සිටින තරුණයින් මනුෂ්‍යත්වයේ පොදු වටිනාකම් වන සාමය, සංවර්ධනය, සමානාත්මතාවය, යුක්තිය, ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය සහ නිදහස වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටිය යුතු බව ෂී පැවසීය.",
        "තිරසාර සංවර්ධනය සඳහා වූ එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ 2030 න්‍යාය පත්‍රය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට පහසුකම් සැලසීමට සහ සංයුක්ත ක්‍රියාමාර්ග සමඟ ගෝලීය සංවර්ධන මුලපිරීම ප්‍රවර්ධනය කරන ලෙස ඔහු තරුණයන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "මෙම සංසදය ජූලි 21දා සිට 23දා දක්වා මාර්ගගතව සහ නොබැඳි ලෙස පවත්වනු ලබන අතර, රටවල් 100කට අධික සංඛ්‍යාවක තරුණ නියෝජිතයින් 2,000කට ආසන්න සංඛ්‍යාවක් සහභාගී වන බව පැවසෙයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Xi",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ලෝක තරුණ සංවර්ධන සංසදය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi Jinping",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක තරුණ සංවර්ධන සංසදය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Xi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තිරසාර සංවර්ධනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 21 සිට 23 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2000කට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "உலக இளைஞர் மேம்பாட்டு மன்றத்திற்கு Xi வாழ்த்துக்களை அனுப்புகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இளைஞர்கள் நம்பிக்கையை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் அதே வேளையில், அவர்கள் எதிர்காலத்தை உருவாக்குபவர்கள் என்று சீன அதிபர் ஜி ஜின்பிங் கூறுகிறார்.",
        "உலக இளைஞர் மேம்பாட்டு மன்றத்திற்கு எழுதிய கடிதத்தில், சீனா எப்போதும் இளைஞர்களை சமூக வளர்ச்சியின் உந்து சக்தியாகக் கருதுவதாகவும், சமூகக் கட்டமைப்பில் பங்கேற்பதன் மூலமும், மனித குலத்திற்கான பகிரப்பட்ட எதிர்காலத்தை மேம்படுத்துவதன் மூலமும் அவர்களின் இளமை ஆற்றலை வெளியிட ஊக்குவிப்பதாக ஷி கூறினார்.",
        "உலகெங்கிலும் உள்ள இளைஞர்கள் உலகளாவிய வளர்ச்சிக்கு பங்களிப்பதற்கு மன்றம் ஒரு முக்கியமான தளமாக மாறும் என்று ஜி தனது நம்பிக்கையை வெளிப்படுத்தினார். இளைஞர்களின் வளர்ச்சியை ஊக்குவிக்க உலகளாவிய முயற்சிகளுக்கு அவர் அழைப்பு விடுத்தார்.",
        "உலகெங்கிலும் உள்ள இளைஞர்கள் அமைதி, வளர்ச்சி, சமத்துவம், நீதி, ஜனநாயகம் மற்றும் சுதந்திரம் போன்ற மனிதகுலத்தின் பொதுவான விழுமியங்களுக்காக நிற்க வேண்டும் என்று ஜி கூறினார்.",
        "நிலையான வளர்ச்சிக்கான ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் 2030 நிகழ்ச்சி நிரலை செயல்படுத்தவும், உறுதியான நடவடிக்கைகளுடன் உலகளாவிய வளர்ச்சி முயற்சியை ஊக்குவிக்கவும் இளைஞர்களை அவர் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "இந்த மன்றம் ஜூலை 21 முதல் 23 வரை ஆன்லைனில் மற்றும் ஆஃப்லைனில் நடைபெறும், மேலும் 100 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட நாடுகளில் இருந்து கிட்டத்தட்ட 2,000 இளைஞர் பிரதிநிதிகள் கலந்து கொள்வார்கள் என்று கூறப்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Xi",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "உலக இளைஞர் மேம்பாட்டு மன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi Jinping",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உலக இளைஞர் மேம்பாட்டு மன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Xi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிலையான அபிவிருத்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 21 முதல் 23 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 2,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}