{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131581",
  "time_ut": 1657962247,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "கர்மவினையோ - காலச் சுழற்சியோ ?",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Karma - the cycle of time?",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "Ajit Dharmapala, a former police officer, posted a video on social media last Tuesday when there were reports that Gotabaya Rajapaksa was trying to flee the country.",
        "In it, he had stated that Gotabaya Rajapaksa was staying at the private residence of Air Marshal Sudarsana Pathirana, Chief of the Air Force. Air Force Headquarters immediately denied the information.",
        "Air Force Spokesperson Group Captain Dushan Wijesinghe had said that there is no truth behind these reports and it is propaganda that tarnishes the reputation of the Air Force and its Commander.",
        "Gotabaya Rajapaksa did not resign then. He was the President of the country. In such a situation, the Air Force spokesperson says that his stay at the Air Force Commander's private residence is a conspiracy to cause trouble for the Air Force and its Commander-in-Chief.",
        "Because he is the commander in command of the entire army. Even if he had been sheltered in his house in a crisis, it cannot be held to be wrong in law.",
        "But the Air Force spokesman's statement meant that the president would be tarnished if he stayed.",
        "As a former army officer, Gotabaya Rajapaksa, a key factor in winning the three-decade war, is viewed by the Air Force as a disgrace. There is no other disgrace like this.",
        "Gotabaya Rajapaksa and his family tried twice to leave the country last Monday night, but officials from the Department of Immigration did not cooperate.",
        "When they tried to flee on their way to the important dignitaries, the immigration officials had notified them to accompany their fellow passengers. They refused.",
        "That is, Gotabaya Rajapaksa was not ready to stand in line with his fellow passengers. The man who was elected by the votes of 69 lakh people and claimed to hold their mandate, hesitated to face a few hundred passengers on the flight deck.",
        "After the end of the war on May 18, 2009, Gotabaya Rajapaksa had said that LTTE leader Prabhakaran had run away and his forces were looking for him.",
        "The next day, Prabhakaran fought to the last and embraced death. The same Gotabaya Rajapaksa is now on the run, unable to face the people.",
        "If brave, he should have stayed in the country till the end. He should have fought against the charges against him. But he could not be. He turned his back and ran away.",
        "Gotabaya Rajapaksa's departure from the country has been a complicated affair, up until the end. All three forces were determined to protect him.",
        "First with military escort from the President's House, he was taken aboard a naval vessel and taken to the Trincomalee Naval Base.",
        "From there, he was brought to Katunayake Airport. He stayed at the Air Force base near the airport until he could fly.",
        "He also reached Maldives by air force flight. The Air Force has also confirmed it.",
        "The three forces did not abandon him till the end. Although they offered to provide him with lasting protection, he did not trust them.",
        "After the protests on 9th May, Mahinda Rajapaksa was rescued from Colombo by the army and was kept and guarded at the Trincomalee Naval Base for almost a week.",
        "However, he did not intend to leave the country. Mahinda Rajapaksa believed that he could ensure his security as long as Gotabaya Rajapaksa was in office as President.",
        "Defense Secretary General Kamal Gunaratne had said then that it was their duty to protect him as a former president and former prime minister.",
        "But when Gotabaya Rajapaksa was chased out of the presidential palace and was wandering around for four days - unable to stay in one place, neither the defense secretary, the chief of the three forces, nor the commanders of the three forces openly said that he is the president of the country and it is our responsibility to protect him.",
        "The reason for that is the fear of incurring the wrath of the people. By the time Gotabaya Rajapaksa left the country, he had lost everything and had reached a point of despair where he could trust no one.",
        "Sitting in a guest room at the airport, officials refused to stamp the passports Kota's aides took to the immigration screening center for prominent figures.",
        "It was only after a couple of times that happened that he escaped to the Maldives on a military plane. Immigration officials do not have the power to prevent a sitting president from leaving the country.",
        "Immigration officials have clarified it in a report. Immigration officials were not prepared to stamp Kota's passport without the President in person.",
        "Earlier, he would have made such a mark by staying in the Presidential Palace. In the end, his power did not help him.",
        "To this extent, Kota was the most powerful executive president in the country.",
        "That executive power was not enough to secure Kota's position. It took a lot of effort to get his family out of the country safely.",
        "Even though Kota was a former US citizen, the US refused to grant him a visa. India did not allow the military aircraft carrying him to land at a South Indian airport.",
        "This is the plight of someone who came to power with the mandate of 69 lakh people. If Kota had not aspired to politics, this would not have happened.",
        "He is desperate for power and has finally reached the point where he is running with his clothes on. Is it karma or the cycle of time?"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ajit Dharmapala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Marshal Sudarsana Pathirana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Force Headquarters",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Air Force Spokesperson Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dushan Wijesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Air Force Commander's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three-decade",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Immigration",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "a few hundred",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "May 18, 2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "LTTE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prabhakaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The next day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prabhakaran",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "First",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Katunayake Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9th May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "almost a week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Defense",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kamal Gunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "four days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kota",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kota",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Palace",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kota",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kota",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kota",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Indian airport",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kota",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කර්මය - කාල චක්‍රය?",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "පසුගිය අඟහරුවාදා ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ රටින් පැන යාමට උත්සාහ කරන බවට වාර්තා පළවෙමින් තිබියදී හිටපු පොලිස් නිලධාරියෙකු වන අජිත් ධර්මපාල විසින් සමාජ මාධ්‍ය වෙත වීඩියෝවක් පළ කළේය.",
        "එහි ඔහු සඳහන් කර තිබුණේ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ ගුවන් හමුදාපති එයාර් මාර්ෂල් සුදර්ශන පතිරණ මහතාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසේ රැඳී සිටින බවයි. ගුවන් හමුදා මූලස්ථානය වහාම එම තොරතුරු ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය.",
        "ගුවන් හමුදා මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක ගෲප් කපිතාන් දුෂාන් විජේසිංහ කියා සිටියේ මෙම වාර්තා පිටුපස කිසිදු සත්‍යතාවක් නොමැති බවත් එය ගුවන් හමුදාවේ සහ එහි අණදෙන නිලධාරියාගේ කීර්ති නාමයට කැළලක් වන ප්‍රචාර බවත්ය.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ එදා ඉල්ලා අස් වුණේ නැහැ. ඔහු රටේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා විය. එවැනි තත්ත්වයක් තුළ ඔහු ගුවන් හමුදාපතිවරයාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසේ රැඳී සිටීම ගුවන් හමුදාවට සහ එහි ප්‍රධානියාට කරදරයක් කිරීමේ කුමන්ත්‍රණයක් බව ගුවන් හමුදා මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශකවරයා පවසයි.",
        "මක්නිසාද යත් ඔහු මුළු හමුදාවටම අණ දෙන නිලධාරියා වන බැවිනි. අර්බුදකාරී අවස්ථාවක ඔහු තම නිවසේ නවාතැන් ගෙන සිටියද එය නීතියෙන් වරදක් ලෙස සැලකිය නොහැකිය.",
        "එහෙත් ගුවන් හමුදා මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශකවරයාගේ ප්‍රකාශයෙන් කියැවුණේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා රැඳී සිටියහොත් ඔහුට කැළලක් වන බවයි.",
        "දශක තුනක යුද්ධය ජයග්‍රහණය කිරීමේ ප්‍රධාන සාධකයක් වූ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ හිටපු හමුදා නිලධාරියෙකු ලෙස ගුවන් හමුදාව සලකන්නේ අපකීර්තියක් ලෙසය. මේ වගේ අපකීර්තියක් තවත් නැහැ.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ සහ ඔහුගේ පවුලේ අය පසුගිය සඳුදා රාත්‍රියේ රටින් පිටවීමට දෙවරක් උත්සාහ කළ නමුත් ආගමන විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ නිලධාරීන් ඊට සහයෝගය දැක්වූයේ නැත.",
        "ඔවුන් වැදගත් ප්‍රභූවරුන් වෙත යමින් සිටියදී පලා යාමට උත්සාහ කළ විට, ආගමන විගමන නිලධාරීන් ඔවුන්ට තම සෙසු මගීන් සමඟ යන ලෙස දන්වා ඇත. ඔවුන් ප්රතික්ෂේප කළා.",
        "එනම් ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ තම සහෝදර මගීන් සමඟ එක පෙළට හිට ගැනීමට සූදානම් නොවීය. 69 ලක්ෂයක ජනතාවගේ ඡන්දයෙන් තේරී පත් වූ සහ ඔවුන්ගේ ජනවරම ලබා දෙන බව පැවසූ පුද්ගලයා, ගුවන් යානා තට්ටුවේ සිටි මගීන් සිය ගණනකට මුහුණ දීමට පසුබට විය.",
        "2009 මැයි 18 වැනිදා යුද්ධය අවසන් වීමෙන් පසු ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ පවසා තිබුණේ කොටි නායක ප්‍රභාකරන් පැන ගිය බවත් තම හමුදාව ඔහු සොයමින් සිටින බවත්ය.",
        "ඊළඟ දවසේ ප්‍රභාකරන් අන්තිම වෙනකම් සටන් කරලා මරණය වැළඳ ගත්තා. එම ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂම දැන් ජනතාවට මුහුණ දීමට නොහැකිව පලා යමින් සිටී.",
        "නිර්භීත නම්, ඔහු අවසානය දක්වා රට තුළ සිටිය යුතුය. ඔහුට එල්ල වී තිබෙන චෝදනාවලට එරෙහිව සටන් කළ යුතුව තිබුණා. නමුත් ඔහු විය නොහැකි විය. ඔහු පිටුපස හැරී දිව ගියේය.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ රටින් පිටවීම අවසානය දක්වාම සංකීර්ණ කටයුත්තක් විය. ඔහු ආරක්ෂා කිරීමට ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාවම අධිෂ්ඨාන කර ගත්හ.",
        "ප්‍රථමයෙන් ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ සිට හමුදා පිරිවරාගෙන නාවික යාත්‍රාවක නංවාගෙන ත්‍රිකුණාමලය නාවික හමුදා කඳවුර වෙත රැගෙන යන ලදී.",
        "එතැනින් කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළට ගෙන ආවා. ඔහු ගුවන් තොටුපළ අසල ගුවන් හමුදා කඳවුරේ පියාසර කිරීමට හැකි වන තෙක් රැඳී සිටියේය.",
        "ඔහු මාලදිවයිනට ද පැමිණියේ ගුවන් හමුදා යානයකිනි. ගුවන් හමුදාවද එය තහවුරු කර ඇත.",
        "ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාව ඔහුව අවසානය දක්වාම අත්හැරියේ නැහැ. ඔහුට සදාකාලික ආරක්ෂාව ලබා දීමට ඔවුන් ඉදිරිපත් වුවද, ඔහු ඔවුන්ව විශ්වාස කළේ නැත.",
        "මැයි 9 වැනිදා විරෝධතාවලින් පසුව හමුදාව විසින් කොළඹින් මුදාගත් මහින්ද රාජපක්‍ෂ සතියකට ආසන්න කාලයක් ත්‍රිකුණාමලය නාවික හමුදා කඳවුරේ රඳවා තබාගෙන ආරක්‍ෂා කළේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ඔහු රට හැර යාමට අදහස් කළේ නැත. ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ජනාධිපති ධූරයේ සිටින තුරු තමාගේ ආරක්ෂාව තහවුරු කළ හැකි බව මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ විශ්වාස කළේය.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු සහ හිටපු අගමැතිවරයෙකු ලෙස ඔහුව ආරක්ෂා කිරීම ඔවුන්ගේ යුතුකමක් බව ආරක්ෂක ලේකම් මහලේකම් කමල් ගුණරත්න එහිදී කියා තිබුණා.",
        "නමුත් ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයෙන් එළවා දමා දින හතරක් එක තැනක සිටීමට නොහැකිව එහා මෙහා යද්දී ආරක්ෂක ලේකම්වරයා හෝ ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදා ප්‍රධානියා හෝ ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාපතිවරුන් ඔහු බව ප්‍රසිද්ධියේ කීවේ නැත. රටේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ ඔහු ආරක්ෂා කිරීම අපගේ වගකීමයි.",
        "ඒකට හේතුව ජනතා උදහසට ලක්වෙයි කියන බයයි. ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ රට හැර යන මොහොත වන විට සියල්ල අහිමිව කිසිවකු විශ්වාස කළ නොහැකි මංමුලා සහගත තත්ත්වයකට පැමිණ සිටියේය.",
        "ගුවන් තොටුපළේ අමුත්තන්ගේ කාමරයක වාඩි වී සිටි අතර, කෝටාගේ සහායකයින් ප්‍රමුඛ පුද්ගලයින් සඳහා ආගමන පරීක්ෂණ මධ්‍යස්ථානය වෙත ගෙන ගිය විදේශ ගමන් බලපත්‍ර මුද්‍රා තැබීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළහ.",
        "හමුදා ගුවන් යානයකින් මාලදිවයිනට පැන ගියේ දෙතුන් වතාවක් සිදු වූ පසුවය. බලයේ සිටින ජනාධිපතිවරයකු රට හැර යාම වැළැක්වීමට ආගමන විගමන නිලධාරීන්ට බලයක් නැත.",
        "ආගමන විගමන නිලධාරීන් වාර්තාවකින් ඒ බව පැහැදිලි කර ඇත. ජනාධිපතිවරයා පෞද්ගලිකව නොමැතිව කොටාගේ විදේශ ගමන් බලපත්‍රයේ මුද්‍රා තැබීමට ආගමන විගමන නිලධාරීන් සූදානම් නොවීය.",
        "මීට පෙර ඔහු ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ නැවතී සිට එවැනි සලකුණක් තබා ඇත.අවසානයේ ඔහුගේ බලය ඔහුට උදව් කළේ නැත.",
        "මේ තරමටම රටේ බලවත්ම විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා වූයේ කොටාය.",
        "එම විධායක බලය කොටා ගේ තනතුර තහවුරු කිරීමට ප්‍රමාණවත් නොවීය. ඔහුගේ පවුල නිරුපද්‍රිතව රටින් පිට කිරීමට මහත් පරිශ්‍රමයක් දැරීමට සිදු විය.",
        "කොටා හිටපු ඇමෙරිකානු පුරවැසියෙක් වුවද ඔහුට වීසා ලබාදීම ඇමෙරිකාව ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය. ඔහු රැගත් හමුදා ගුවන් යානයට දකුණු ඉන්දීය ගුවන් තොටුපළකට ගොඩබෑමට ඉන්දියාව ඉඩ දුන්නේ නැත.",
        "ලක්ෂ 69ක ජනවරම ලබාගෙන බලයට ආපු එකෙකුගේ අවාසනාව. කොටා දේශපාලනයට ආසා නොකළා නම් මෙහෙම වෙන්නේ නැහැ.",
        "බලය සඳහා මංමුලා සහගතව සිටින ඔහු අවසානයේ ඇඳුම් ඇඳගෙන දුවන තැනට පැමිණ ඇත. එය කර්මයද කාල චක්‍රයද?"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අජිත් ධර්මපාල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එයාර් මාර්ෂල් සුදර්ශන පතිරණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා මූලස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා මාධ්ය ප්රකාශක කණ්ඩායම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dushan Wijesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදාපතිවරයාගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දශක තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිය ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2009 මැයි 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්ටීටීඊය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රභාකරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රභාකරන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9 මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතියකට ආසන්න කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමල් ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොටා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොටා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොටා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොටා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොටා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ඉන්දීය ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கர்மவினையோ - காலச் சுழற்சியோ ?",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ நாட்டை விட்டுத் தப்பிச் செல்ல முயன்று கொண்டிருப்பதாக பரபரப்பாக தகவல்கள் வெளியாகி கொண்டிருந்த போது, கடந்த செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை முன்னாள் பொலிஸ் அதிகாரி அஜித் தர்மபால ஒரு வீடியோவை சமூக ஊடகங்களில் பதிவிட்டிருந்தார்.",
        "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ,விமானப்படைத் தளபதி எயர் மார்ஷல் சுதர்சன பத்திரனவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்தில் தங்கியிருக்கிறார் என்று அவர் அதில் கூறியிருந்தார். உடனடியாக விமானப்படைத் தலைமையகம், அந்த தகவலை மறுத்தது.",
        "இந்த செய்திகளுக்குப் பின்னால் எந்த உண்மையும் இல்லை என்றும், விமானப்படை மற்றும் அதன் தளபதியின் நற்பெயருக்கு களங்கம் ஏற்படுத்தும் பிரசாரம் இது என்றும், விமானப்படைப் பேச்சாளர் குறூப் கப்டன் டுஷான் விஜேசிங்க தெரிவித்திருந்தார்.",
        "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ அப்போது பதவி விலகவில்லை. நாட்டின் ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியில் இருந்தார். அவ்வாறான நிலையில், விமானப்படைத் தளபதியின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்தில் அவர் தங்கியிருப்பதை, விமானப்படைக்கும், அதன் தளபதிக்கும் களங்களத்தை ஏற்படுத்தும் சதி என்று விமானப்படைப் பேச்சாளர் கூறுகிறார்.",
        "ஏனென்றால், ஒட்டுமொத்தப் படைகளுக்கும் அவர் தான் கட்டளையிடும் தளபதி. நெருக்கடி ஒன்றில் அவரை, தனது வீட்டில் தங்க வைத்துப் பாதுகாத்திருந்தால், கூட சட்டப்படி அது தவறானது எனக் கொள்ள முடியாது.",
        "ஆனால், விமானப்படைப் பேச்சாளரின் கூற்று, ஜனாதிபதியை தங்க வைத்திருந்தால் அது களங்கப்படுத்தும் செயலாக அர்த்தப்படுத்தியிருக்கிறது.",
        "ஒரு முன்னாள் இராணுவ அதிகாரியாக, மூன்று தசாப்த போரை வெல்வதற்கு, முக்கிய காரணியான, கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை தங்கவைத்திருப்பது, களங்கத்துக்குரிய செயலாக விமானப்படை பார்க்கிறது. இதைப் போன்றதொரு அவமானம் வேறேதும் இல்லை.",
        "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ தனது குடும்பத்துடன் கடந்த திங்கட்கிழமை இரவு நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறுவதற்கு இரண்டு முறை முயற்சித்த போதும், குடியல்வுத் திணைக்கள அதிகாரிகள் அதற்கு ஒத்துழைக்கவில்லை.",
        "அவர்கள் முக்கிய பிரமுகர்களுக்கான வழியில், தப்பியோட முனைந்த போது, அவர்களை சக பயணிகளுடன் வருமாறு குடியகல்வு அதிகாரிகள் அறிவித்திருந்தனர். அதற்கு அவர்கள் மறுத்து விட்டனர்.",
        "அதாவது, சக பயணிகளுடன் இணைந்து வரிசையில் நிற்க கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ தயாராக இருக்கவில்லை. 69 இலட்சம் மக்களின் வாக்குகளால் தெரிவானவர், அவர்களின் ஆணையை வைத்திருப்பதாக கூறிக் கொண்டவர், விமான நிலையில் சில நூறு பயணிகளை எதிர்கொள்ள தயங்கினார்.",
        "2009 மே 18ஆம் திகதி போர் முடிவுக்கு வந்த பின்னர், விடுதலைப் புலிகளின் தலைவர் பிரபாகரன் ஓடி ஒளித்து விட்டதாகவும், அவரை தமது படைகளை தேடி வருவதாகவும், கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ கூறியிருந்தார்.",
        "மறுநாள், கடைசி வரை சண்டையிட்டு, மரணத்தை தழுவினார் பிரபாகரன். அதே கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ இப்போது, மக்களை எதிர்கொள்ள முடியாமல், தப்பியோடியிருக்கிறார்.",
        "துணிச்சல் கொண்டவராக இருந்தால், அவர் கடைசி வரை நாட்டில் இருந்திருக்க வேண்டும். தன் மீதான குற்றச்சாட்டுகளை எதிர்த்து, போராடியிருக்க வேண்டும். ஆனால் அவரால், அவ்வாறு இருக்க முடியவில்லை. புறமுதுகிட்டுத் தப்பியோடியிருக்கிறார்.",
        "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறுவது கடைசி வரையில், சிக்கலானதொரு காரியமாகவே இருந்திருக்கிறது. அவரைப் பாதுகாப்பதில் முப்படைகளும் உறுதியாக இருந்தன.",
        "முதலில் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் இருந்து இராணுவப் பாதுகாப்புடன், அவர் கடற்படை கப்பலில் ஏற்றப்பட்டு, திருகோணமலை கடற்படைத் தளத்க்கு கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்டார்.",
        "அங்கிருந்து, கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையத்துக்கு அழைத்து வரப்பட்டார். விமானத்தில் பயணம் செய்யும் வரை அவர் விமான நிலையத்துக்கு அருகில் உள்ள விமானப்படைத் தளத்திலேயே தங்கியிருந்தார்.",
        "விமானப்படை விமானத்தின் மூலமே அவர் மாலைதீவுக்கும் சென்றடைந்தார். அதனை விமானப்படை உறுதிப்படுத்தியும் உள்ளது.",
        "அவரை முப்படையினரும் கடைசி வரை கைவிடவில்லை. நீடித்த பாதுகாப்பை அவருக்கு வழங்க முன்வந்தாலும், அவர் அவர்களை நம்பவில்லை.",
        "மே-9ஆம் திகதி போராட்டங்களை அடுத்து, கொழும்பில் இருந்து மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ, இராணுவத்தினரால் மீட்கப்பட்டு, திருகோணமலை கடற்படைத் தளத்தில் கிட்டத்தட்ட ஒரு வாரம் தங்க வைக்கப்பட்டு பாதுகாக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "ஆனாலும், அவர் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேற முனையவில்லை. ஜனாதிபதியாக கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ பதவியில் இருக்கும் வரை, தனது பாதுகாப்பை உறுதிப்படுத்த முடியும் என்று, மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ நம்பினார்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி, முன்னாள் பிரதமர் என்ற வகையில், அவரைப் பாதுகாக்க வேண்டியது தங்களின் கடமை என்று, பாதுகாப்புச் செயலாளர் ஜெனரல் கமல் குணரத்ன அப்போது கூறியிருந்தார்.",
        "ஆனால், கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் இருந்து துரத்தப்பட்டு, நான்கு நாட்களாக அங்குமிங்குமாக – ஒரேயிடத்தில் தங்கியிருக்க முடியாமல் அலைந்து கொண்டிருந்த போது, அவர் நாட்டின் ஜனாதிபதி, அவரைப் பாதுகாக்க வேண்டியது எங்கள் பொறுப்பு என்று பாதுகாப்பு செயலரோ, முப்படைகளின் பிரதானியோ, முப்படைகளின் தளபதிகளோ வாய்திறந்து கூறவில்லை.",
        "மக்களின் கோபத்துக்கு தாங்களும் உள்ளாக வேண்டிய நிலை ஏற்படும் என்ற அச்சமே அதற்குக் காரணம். கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறும் போது, எல்லாவற்றையும் இழந்து – யாரையும் நம்ப முடியாத விரக்தி நிலையை அடைந்திருந்தார்.",
        "விமான நிலையத்தில் விருந்தினர் அறையில் அமர்ந்திருந்து கொண்டு, முக்கிய பிரமுகர்களுக்கான குடியகல்வு சோதனை மையத்துக்கு கோட்டாவின் உதவியாளர்கள் கொண்டு சென்ற கடவுச்சீட்டுகளுக்கு அதிகாரிகள் சீல் வைக்க மறுத்திருக்கின்றனர்.",
        "ஒன்றுக்கு இரண்டு முறை அவ்வாறு நடந்த பின்னர் தான், இராணுவ விமானத்தில், மாலைதீவுக்கு தப்பிச் செல்லும் நிலை ஏற்பட்டது. அதிகாரத்தில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதியை நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறுவதை தடுக்கும் அதிகாரம் குடியல்வு அதிகாரிகளுக்கு கிடையாது.",
        "அதனை குடிவரவு குடியல்வு அதிகாரிகள் அறிக்கை ஒன்றில் தெளிவுபடுத்தியிருந்தனர். ஜனாதிபதி நேரில் வராமல், கோட்டாவின் கடவுச்சீட்டுக்கு முத்திரையிட குடிவரவு அதிகாரிகள் தயாராக இருக்கவில்லை.",
        "முன்னரென்றால், ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் இருந்து கொண்டே அவர் அவ்வாறான முத்திரையை குத்தியிருந்திருப்பார்.கடைசி நேரத்தில் அவரது அதிகாரம், அவருக்கே உதவாமல் போனது.",
        "இந்தளவுக்கும் நாட்டில் இதுவரை அதிகாரத்தில் இருந்த நிறைவேற்று அதிகார ஜனாதிபதிகளில் அதி உச்ச அதிகாரங்களைக் கொண்டவராக கோட்டாவே விளங்கினார்.",
        "அந்த நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரம் கோட்டாவின் பதவியை பாதுகாக்க போதுமானதாக இருக்கவில்லை. அவரது குடும்பத்தினரை பாதுகாப்பாக நாட்டை விட்டு கொண்டு செல்வதற்கு படாத பாடு படவேண்டிய நிலை ஏற்பட்டது.",
        "கோட்டா முன்னைய அமெரிக்க குடிமகனாக இருந்த போதும், அவருக்கு வீசா வழங்க அமெரிக்க மறுத்தது.   அவரை ஏற்றி வரும் இராணுவ விமானத்தை தென்னிந்திய விமான நிலையம் ஒன்றில் தரையிறக்க இந்தியா அனுமதிக்ககவில்லை.",
        "69 இலட்சம் மக்களின் ஆணையுடன் அதிகாரத்துக்கு வந்தவருக்கு ஏற்பட்ட அவல நிலை இது. கோட்டா அரசியலுக்கு ஆசைப்படாமல் இருந்திருந்தால் இந்த நிலை வந்திருக்காது.",
        "அவர் அதிகாரத்துக்கு ஆசைப்பட்டு, கடைசியில் கட்டிய துணியுடன் ஓடும் நிலை வந்திருக்கிறது. இது தான் கர்மவினையோ அல்லது காலத்தின் சுழற்சியோ?"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அஜித் தர்மபால",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எயார் மார்ஷல் சுதர்சன பத்திரன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை தலைமையகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை செய்தி தொடர்பாளர் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dushan Wijesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை தளபதியின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று தசாப்தங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவு திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சில நூறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மே 18, 2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விடுதலைப் புலிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரபாகரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரபாகரன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9 மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட ஒரு வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கமல் குணரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்னிந்திய விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}