{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/27/six-men-nabbed-for-hoarding-fuel/",
  "time_ut": 1656317100,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Six men nabbed for hoarding fuel",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Six men nabbed for hoarding fuel",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Six suspects have been arrested for stockpiling fuel without licenses and selling it at high prices in several areas.",
        "Four suspects were arrested in Mawathagama, Paragahadeniya, Maswewa, We-Uda, and Welikumbura areas for illegally stockpiling fuel and selling it at exorbitant prices.",
        "Police said that 315L of diesel were seized from their possession.",
        "At the same time, Police arrested a suspect who was illegally stockpiling fuel in the Sandiveli area in Batticaloa and seized 550L of diesel and 258L of kerosene in his possession.",
        "Meanwhile, a suspect was arrested with 1100L of diesel in the Kotagala area in Dimbulapathana.",
        "The arrested suspects are due to be produced to the court on Monday (27).",
        "G7 aims to raise $600 billion to counter China’s Belt and Road"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Six",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mawathagama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paragahadeniya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maswewa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welikumbura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sandiveli",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Batticaloa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "550L",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1100L",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kotagala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dimbulapathana",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$600 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන රැස්කරමින් සිටි පුද්ගලයින් 6 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); බලපත්‍ර නොමැතිව ඉන්ධන තොග ගබඩා කර ප්‍රදේශ කිහිපයක අධික මිලට අලෙවි කළ සැකකරුවන් 6 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "මාවතගම, පරගහදෙණිය, මාස්වැව, වෑඋඩ, වැලිකුඹුර යන ප්‍රදේශවලදී නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස ඉන්ධන තොග ගබඩා කර අධික මිලට අලෙවි කළ සැකකරුවන් 4 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "ඔවුන් සන්තකයේ තිබී ඩීසල් ලීටර් 315ක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බවයි පොලිසිය පැවසුවේ.",
        "ඒ සමගම මඩකලපුව, සන්දිවේලි ප්‍රදේශයේ නීති විරෝධී ලෙස ඉන්ධන තොග ගබඩා කරමින් සිටි සැකකරුවෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් පොලීසිය ඔහු සන්තකයේ තිබී ඩීසල් ලීටර් 550ක් සහ භූමිතෙල් ලීටර් 258ක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "මේ අතර දිඹුලපතන, කොටගල ප්‍රදේශයේදී ඩීසල් ලීටර් 1100ක් සමඟ සැකකරුවෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරුවන් සඳුදා (27) අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිතය.",
        "G7 චීනයේ තීරය සහ මාර්ගයට එරෙහිව ඩොලර් බිලියන 600 ක් රැස් කිරීමට ඉලක්ක කරයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හය",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාවතගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පරගහදෙණිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මස්වැව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිකුඹුර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සන්දිවේලි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මඩකලපුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "550L",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1100L",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිඹුලපතන",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 600 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருளை பதுக்கி வைத்திருந்த 6 பேர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பல பகுதிகளில் அனுமதிப்பத்திரம் இன்றி எரிபொருளை பதுக்கி வைத்து அதிக விலைக்கு விற்பனை செய்த 6 சந்தேக நபர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "மாவத்தகம, பரகஹதெனிய, மஸ்வெவ, வெ-உட, வெலிகும்புர ஆகிய பகுதிகளில் சட்டவிரோதமான முறையில் எரிபொருளை குவித்து அதிக விலைக்கு விற்பனை செய்த நான்கு சந்தேகநபர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "அவர்களிடம் இருந்து 315 லிட்டர் டீசல் கைப்பற்றப்பட்டதாக போலீசார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இதேவேளை, மட்டக்களப்பு, சந்திவெளி பகுதியில் சட்டவிரோதமான முறையில் எரிபொருளை பதுக்கி வைத்திருந்த சந்தேக நபர் ஒருவரைக் கைது செய்த பொலிஸார், அவரிடமிருந்த 550L டீசல் மற்றும் 258L மண்ணெண்ணெய் ஆகியவற்றைக் கைப்பற்றியுள்ளனர்.",
        "இதேவேளை, திம்புலபத்தனை, கொட்டகலை பிரதேசத்தில் 1100 எல் டீசலுடன் சந்தேகநபர் ஒருவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேகநபர்கள் எதிர்வரும் திங்கட்கிழமை (27) நீதிமன்றத்தில் ஆஜர்படுத்தப்படவுள்ளனர்.",
        "சீனாவின் பெல்ட் அண்ட் ரோடுக்கு எதிராக 600 பில்லியன் டாலர் திரட்ட G7 இலக்கு கொண்டுள்ளது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஆறு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாவத்தகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பரகஹதெனிய",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஸ்வேவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிகும்புர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சண்டிவெளி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மட்டக்களப்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "550லி",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1100லி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொட்டகலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திம்புலபதன",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$600 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}