{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84413/interpol-confirms-arrest-of-harak-kata-by-dubai-police",
  "time_ut": 1660934220,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Interpol confirms arrest of ‘Harak Kata’ by Dubai Police",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Interpol confirms arrest of ‘Harak Kata’ by Dubai Police",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Interpol has officially informed Sri Lanka’s Criminal Investigation Department on Friday that wanted criminal and notorious drug trafficker Nadun Chinthaka alias ‘Harak Kata’ has been arrested by the Dubai Police.",
        "The Criminal Investigation Department (CID) said that the suspect is to be brought to Sri Lanka within 30 days under the Extradition Act.",
        "It was reported on August 12, that notorious drug kingpin and the leader of an organized criminal gang in Sri Lanka, Nadun Chinthaka alias ‘Harak Kata’ had been arrested during a covert operation in Dubai.",
        "According to reports, the raid was conducted by the Police Narcotics Bureau in coordination with the international police. The arrest was made when the suspect tried to flee to Malaysia with a woman who is said to be his wife.",
        "As per reports, it has been discovered that ‘Harak Kata’ had been involved in drug distribution activities in association with other drug traffickers operating in many countries including Malaysia, Singapore, Seychelles and the Maldives."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Interpol",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dubai",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Interpol",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nadun Chinthaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harak Kata’",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Dubai Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Extradition Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nadun Chinthaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harak Kata’",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Police Narcotics Bureau",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malaysia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Harak Kata’",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malaysia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seychelles",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "'හරක් කට' ඩුබායි පොලිසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව ජාත්‍යන්තර පොලිසිය තහවුරු කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අපරාධකාර සහ කුප්‍රකට මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය ජාවාරම්කරුවෙකු වන නදුන් චින්තක හෙවත් ‘හරක් කටා’ ඩුබායි පොලිසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති බව ඉන්ටර්පෝල් විසින් සිකුරාදා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට නිල වශයෙන් දැනුම් දී තිබේ.",
        "උදර්පන පනත යටතේ සැකකරු දින 30ක් ඇතුළත ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ගෙන්වා ගැනීමට නියමිත බව අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව (CID) පැවසීය.",
        "කුප්‍රකට මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය ජාවාරම්කරුවෙකු සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංවිධානාත්මක අපරාධ කල්ලි නායකයෙකු වන නදුන් චින්තක හෙවත් ‘හරක් කටා’ ඩුබායිහිදී රහසිගත මෙහෙයුමකදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව පසුගිය අගෝස්තු 12 වැනිදා වාර්තා විය.",
        "වාර්තාවන්ට අනුව ජාත්‍යන්තර පොලිසිය සමඟ සම්බන්ධීකරණයෙන් පොලිස් මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය නාශක කාර්යාංශය මෙම වැටලීම සිදුකර ඇත. සැකකරු ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ බව කියන කාන්තාවක් සමඟ මැලේසියාවට පලා යාමට උත්සාහ කිරීමේදී මෙම අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම සිදු කර ඇත.",
        "මැලේසියාව, සිංගප්පූරුව, සීෂෙල්ස් සහ මාලදිවයින ඇතුළු රටවල් රැසක ක්‍රියාත්මක වන මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය ජාවාරම්කරුවන් සමඟ එක්ව ‘හරක් කටා’ මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය බෙදාහැරීමේ කටයුතුවල නිරත වී ඇති බවට තොරතුරු අනාවරණය වී තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර පොලිසිය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඩුබායි",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නදුන් චින්තක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරක් කට'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිටුවහල් කිරීමේ පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නදුන් චින්තක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරක් කට'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය නාශක කාර්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැලේසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හරක් කට'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැලේසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීෂෙල්ස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "'ஹரக் கட்டா' துபாய் காவல்துறையால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதை இன்டர்போல் உறுதிப்படுத்துகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தேடப்படும் குற்றவாளியும் பிரபல போதைப்பொருள் கடத்தல்காரரும் 'ஹரக் கட்டா' என அழைக்கப்படும் நடுன் சிந்தக டுபாய் பொலிஸாரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக இன்டர்போல் இலங்கையின் குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களத்திற்கு வெள்ளிக்கிழமை உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களம் (CID) கூறியது: சந்தேக நபரை 30 நாட்களுக்குள் நாடு கடத்தல் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் இலங்கைக்கு அழைத்து வர நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "கடந்த ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் 12ஆம் திகதி, பிரபல போதைப்பொருள் மன்னனும், இலங்கையின் ஒழுங்கமைக்கப்பட்ட குற்றக் கும்பலின் தலைவனுமான, 'ஹரக் கட்டா' என அழைக்கப்படும் நடுன் சிந்தக, துபாயில் இரகசிய நடவடிக்கையின் போது கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாகத் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "சர்வதேச பொலிஸாருடன் இணைந்து பொலிஸ் போதைப்பொருள் ஒழிப்புப் பிரிவினரால் இந்தச் சுற்றிவளைப்பு மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன. சந்தேக நபர் தனது மனைவி என கூறப்படும் பெண் ஒருவருடன் மலேசியாவிற்கு தப்பிச் செல்ல முற்பட்ட போதே கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "மலேசியா, சிங்கப்பூர், சீஷெல்ஸ், மாலத்தீவு உள்ளிட்ட பல நாடுகளில் இயங்கி வரும் போதைப்பொருள் கடத்தல்காரர்களுடன் இணைந்து ‘ஹரக் கட்டா’ போதைப்பொருள் விநியோக நடவடிக்கைகளில் ஈடுபட்டு வந்தது கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்டர்போல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "துபாய்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்டர்போல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றவியல் புலனாய்வு திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நடுன் சிந்தனை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹரக் கட்டா’",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய் போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாடு கடத்தல் சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நடுன் சிந்தனை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹரக் கட்டா’",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொலிஸ் போதைப்பொருள் தடுப்புப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலேசியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹரக் கட்டா’",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலேசியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீஷெல்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}