{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/stock-investors-turn-nervous-turnover-dips-below-rs-1-billion-level/",
  "time_ut": 1658503860,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Stock investors turn nervous; turnover dips below Rs. 1 billion level",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Stock investors turn nervous; turnover dips below Rs. 1 billion level",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "The CSE was somewhat volatile yesterday following the previous day’s operation by the security forces in close proximity to the Presidential Secretariat. Stock market investors were considerably panicky and profit- takings were noted consequentially, stock market analysts said. Sri Lanka’s nation-wide inflation rose 58.9 per cent in the 12-months to June 2022; the worst so far in the history of the country. However, Central Bank Governor Dr Nandalal Weerasinghe told the international media that the current high inflation is expected to come down in the next few months.",
        "Trading activities slowed down and the turnover level touched below the Rs one billion level. Both indices moved downwards. The All -Share Price Index went down by 14.6 points and S and P SL20 declined by 14.6 points. Turnover stood at Rs 866 million with a single crossing. The crossing was reported in Sunshine Holdings, which crossed 1.7 million shares to the tune of Rs 61.2 million; its shares traded at Rs 36.",
        "In the retail market top seven companies that mainly contributed to the turnover were; Lanka IOC Rs 173.5 million (2.1 million shares traded), Browns Investments Rs 152.7 million (19.6 million shares traded), Sunshine Holdings Rs 107.2 million (2.9 million shares traded), Expolanka Rs 47.2 million (265,000 shares traded), Hayleys Rs 32.1 million (437,000 shares traded), hZenid Rs 20.5 million (925,000 shares traded) and JKH Rs 18.7 million (155,000 shares traded). During the day 52.8 million share volumes changed hands in 13000 transactions.Yesterday, the US dollar parity rate stood at Rs 368.49.",
        "CCC calls for strong multi-party administration acceptable to all sections of public",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "1 billion",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the previous day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "58.9 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "12-months to June 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next few months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "one billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14.6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14.6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunshine Holdings",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.7 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "61.2 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka IOC Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "173.5 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.1 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Browns Investments Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "152.7 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19.6 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunshine Holdings Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "107.2 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.9 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "47.2 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "265,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "32.1 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "437,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "hZenid Rs 20.5 million",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "925,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "JKH Rs 18.7 million",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "155,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "52.8 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "13000",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "368.49",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CCC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කොටස් ආයෝජකයෝ නොසන්සුන් වෙති; පිරිවැටුම රු. බිලියන 1 මට්ටම",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයට ආසන්නයේ ආරක්ෂක අංශ විසින් පෙරේදා සිදු කළ මෙහෙයුමෙන් පසු කොළඹ කොටස් වෙළෙඳපොළ ඊයේ තරමක් අස්ථාවර විය. කොටස් වෙලඳපොල ආයෝජකයින් සැලකිය යුතු ලෙස භීතියට පත් වූ අතර ලාභ ලැබීම් එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස සටහන් වූ බව කොටස් වෙළඳපල විශ්ලේෂකයෝ පවසති. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාතික මට්ටමේ උද්ධමනය 2022 ජූනි දක්වා මාස 12 තුළ සියයට 58.9කින් ඉහළ ගියේය. මෙතෙක් රටේ ඉතිහාසයේ නරකම. කෙසේ වෙතත්, මහ බැංකු අධිපති ආචාර්ය නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ ජාත්‍යන්තර මාධ්‍ය වෙත ප්‍රකාශ කළේ දැනට පවතින ඉහළ උද්ධමනය ඉදිරි මාස කිහිපය තුළ පහළ යනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කරන බවයි.",
        "වෙළෙඳ කටයුතු මන්දගාමී වූ අතර පිරිවැටුම් මට්ටම රුපියල් බිලියනයක මට්ටමට පහළට ළඟා විය. දර්ශක දෙකම පහළට ගමන් කළේය. සියලුම කොටස් මිල දර්ශකය ඒකක 14.6 කින් පහළ ගිය අතර S සහ P SL20 ඒකක 14.6 කින් පහළ ගියේය. එක් හරස් මාර්ගයකින් පිරිවැටුම රුපියල් මිලියන 866 ක් විය. සන්ෂයින් හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් හි මෙම හරස් කිරීම වාර්තා වූ අතර එය කොටස් මිලියන 1.7 ඉක්මවා ගොස් රුපියල් මිලියන 61.2 ක් විය. එහි කොටස් රුපියල් 36 ට ගනුදෙනු විය.",
        "සිල්ලර වෙළඳපොලේ පිරිවැටුම සඳහා ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් දායක වූ සමාගම් හත වූයේ; ලංකා IOC රුපියල් මිලියන 173.5 (කොටස් මිලියන 2.1 ක් ගනුදෙනු), බ්‍රවුන්ස් ඉන්වෙස්ට්මන්ට් රුපියල් මිලියන 152.7 (කොටස් මිලියන 19.6 ක් ගනුදෙනු), සන්ෂයින් හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් රුපියල් මිලියන 107.2 (කොටස් මිලියන 2.9 ක්), එක්ස්පෝලංකා රුපියල් මිලියන 47.2 ක් (කොටස් මිලියන 265,000 ක් ගනුදෙනු), හේලි. (කොටස් 437,000ක් වෙළඳාම් කර ඇත), hZenid රුපියල් මිලියන 20.5 (කොටස් 925,000ක් ගනුදෙනු කර ඇත) සහ JKH රුපියල් මිලියන 18.7 (කොටස් 155,000ක් ගනුදෙනු කර ඇත). දවස තුළ ගනුදෙනු 13000 කදී කොටස් වෙළුම් මිලියන 52.8 ක් වෙනස් විය. ඊයේ, එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලරයේ සමානාත්මතා අනුපාතය රුපියල් 368.49 ක් විය.",
        "සියලුම මහජන කොටස්වලට පිළිගත හැකි ශක්තිමත් බහු-පක්ෂ පරිපාලනයක් සඳහා CCC ඉල්ලා සිටී",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බිලියන 1 කි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙර දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 58.9 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූනි සිට මාස 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි මාස කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියනයක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14.6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14.6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්ෂයින් හෝල්ඩින්ග්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.7 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 61.2 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා IOC රු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 173.5 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 2.1 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Browns Investments රු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 152.7 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 19.6 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්ෂයින් හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් රු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 107.2 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 2.9 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 47.2 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "265,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 32.1 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "437,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "hZenid රුපියල් මිලියන 20.5 කි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "925,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "JKH රුපියල් මිලියන 18.7 කි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "155,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 52.8 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "13000",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "368.49 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CCC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பங்கு முதலீட்டாளர்கள் பதற்றமடைகின்றனர்; விற்றுமுதல் ரூ.க்கு கீழே குறைந்தது. 1 பில்லியன் நிலை",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்திற்கு அருகாமையில் பாதுகாப்புப் படையினரின் முந்தைய நாள் நடவடிக்கையைத் தொடர்ந்து நேற்று CSE சற்று ஏற்ற இறக்கமாக இருந்தது. பங்குச் சந்தை முதலீட்டாளர்கள் கணிசமான பீதியில் இருந்தனர் மற்றும் அதன் விளைவாக லாபம் ஈட்டப்பட்டது என்று பங்குச் சந்தை ஆய்வாளர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர். இலங்கையின் நாடு தழுவிய பணவீக்கம் 2022 ஜூன் வரையிலான 12 மாதங்களில் 58.9 சதவீதம் அதிகரித்தது; நாட்டின் வரலாற்றில் இதுவரை மோசமானது. எவ்வாறாயினும், தற்போதைய உயர் பணவீக்கம் அடுத்த சில மாதங்களில் குறையும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுவதாக மத்திய வங்கியின் ஆளுநர் கலாநிதி நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க சர்வதேச ஊடகங்களுக்கு தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "வர்த்தக நடவடிக்கைகள் மந்தமாகி, விற்றுமுதல் அளவு ரூ. ஒரு பில்லியன் அளவைத் தொட்டது. இரண்டு குறியீடுகளும் கீழ்நோக்கி நகர்ந்தன. அனைத்துப் பங்கு விலைச் சுட்டெண் 14.6 புள்ளிகளாலும், S மற்றும் P SL20 14.6 புள்ளிகளாலும் சரிந்தன. விற்றுமுதல் ஒருமுறை கடக்க ரூ.866 மில்லியனாக இருந்தது. சன்ஷைன் ஹோல்டிங்ஸில் கிராசிங் அறிவிக்கப்பட்டது, இது 1.7 மில்லியன் பங்குகளை ரூ. 61.2 மில்லியனுக்குத் தாண்டியது; அதன் பங்குகள் 36 ரூபாய்க்கு வர்த்தகம் செய்யப்பட்டது.",
        "சில்லறை விற்பனைச் சந்தையில் முதன்மையான ஏழு நிறுவனங்கள் விற்றுமுதல் பங்களித்தன; லங்கா ஐஓசி ரூ 173.5 மில்லியன் (2.1 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), பிரவுன்ஸ் இன்வெஸ்ட்மென்ட்ஸ் ரூ 152.7 மில்லியன் (19.6 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), சன்ஷைன் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் ரூ 107.2 மில்லியன் (2.9 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ரூ 47.2 மில்லியன் (265,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), 32.1 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் (437,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), hZenid ரூ 20.5 மில்லியன் (925,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்) மற்றும் JKH ரூ 18.7 மில்லியன் (155,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்). நாளின் போது 13000 பரிவர்த்தனைகளில் 52.8 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் கைமாறின.நேற்று அமெரிக்க டாலர் சமநிலை விகிதம் ரூ.368.49 ஆக இருந்தது.",
        "அனைத்துப் பிரிவினரும் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளக்கூடிய வலுவான பல கட்சி நிர்வாகத்திற்கு CCC அழைப்பு விடுக்கிறது",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "1 பில்லியன்",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "58.9 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 2022 முதல் 12 மாதங்கள் வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த சில மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14.6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14.6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சன்ஷைன் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.7 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "61.2 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கா ஐஓசி ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "173.5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.1 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரவுன்ஸ் முதலீடுகள் ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "152.7 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19.6 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சன்ஷைன் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "107.2 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.9 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "47.2 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "265,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "32.1 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "437,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "hZenid ரூ 20.5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "925,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "JKH ரூ 18.7 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "155,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "52.8 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "13000",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "368.49",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CCC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}