{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/headline/Brathwaite-Lewis-among-the-overseas-players-selected-in-LPL-draft/419-240421",
  "time_ut": 1657075133,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Brathwaite, Lewis among the overseas players selected in LPL draft",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Brathwaite, Lewis among the overseas players selected in LPL draft",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "West Indians Carlos Brathwaite and Evin Lewis were among the overseas players who secured top dollar at the Player Draft for the third season of the Lanka Premier League (LPL) which starts later this month.",
        "Pakistan’s Imad Wasim, South African Dwaine Pretorius and Australian D’Arcy Short were also selected in the International Ruby category, where overseas players will earn US dollars 60,000 each.",
        "Cashing in on an equivalent pay day were Sri Lanka limited overs captain Dasun Shanaka, all-rounders Wanindu Hasaranga, Thisara Perera and Angelo Mathews, along with Danushka Gunathilaka, all signed in the Sri Lankan Ruby salary bracket.",
        "Brathwaite and Hasaranga will form a formidable partnership for the Kandy Falcons franchise, which has had the most significant upgrades among the respective squads, following two disappointing seasons.",
        "Having retained just one player from last year’s squad, Kandy have drafted another West Indian all-rounder in Fabian Allen, and the young exciting talent Dewald Brevis of South Africa.",
        "Hasaranga was a key part in the Jaffna franchise winning both LPL tournaments, and his departure will be a big loss to the Kings, but having retained Maheesh Theekshana they also signed all-rounder Dunith Wellalage.",
        "Jaffna have invested heavily in South African veteran Hardus Viljeon, drafting him in the second highest catergory for international players -- a similar figure being splashed for all-rounder Dhananjaya de Silva.",
        "Twice beaten finalists the Galle Gladiators and their captain at both those finals Bhanuka Rajapaksa have parted ways, with the batsman joining the Dambulla Giants under the leadership of Shanaka.",
        "Australians Short and Ben Cutting, and Nepalese leg-spinner Sandeep Lamichhane securing the franchises' top three slots for overseas players in the Dambulla franchise.",
        "The Gladiators continue to have a strong presence of Pakistani players, with Faheem Ashraf, Azam Khan and Sharfraz Ahmed teaming up with Wasim, with the other two overseas player slots going to Janneman Malan and Qais Ahmed.",
        "The Gladiators have also signed fast-bowler Dushmantha Chameera, bringing back Gunathilaka, Kusal Mendis, Lakshan Sandakan, Nuwan Thushara and Pulina Tharanga.",
        "With the departure of Chameera, the Colombo Kings franchise have expended significant resources on fast bowlers, using five of their six overseas player slots on Pretorius, West Indian Dominic Drakes, and Afghanistan's Fazalhaq Farooqi, Naveen-ul-Haq and Karim Janat."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "LPL",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "West Indians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Carlos Brathwaite",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Evin Lewis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Player Draft",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the third season",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LPL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "later this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Imad Wasim",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "South African",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "International Ruby",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "60,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dasun Shanaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wanindu Hasaranga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thisara Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Angelo Mathews",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Danushka Gunathilaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Brathwaite",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hasaranga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "last year’s",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fabian Allen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dewald Brevis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Africa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hasaranga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "LPL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Theekshana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dunith Wellalage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "South African",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hardus Viljeon",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhananjaya de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Galle Gladiators",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bhanuka Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Dambulla Giants",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shanaka",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ben Cutting",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nepalese",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sandeep Lamichhane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dambulla",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gladiators",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistani",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Faheem Ashraf",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Azam Khan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sharfraz Ahmed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wasim",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janneman Malan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qais Ahmed",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gladiators",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dushmantha Chameera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunathilaka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kusal Mendis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakshan Sandakan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwan Thushara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pulina",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chameera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pretorius",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "West Indian Dominic Drakes",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Afghanistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fazalhaq Farooqi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karim Janat",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "LPL කෙටුම්පතේ තෝරාගත් විදේශීය ක්‍රීඩකයින් අතර Brathwaite, Lewis",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මේ මස අගදී ආරම්භ වන Lanka Premier League (LPL) තුන්වන වාරයේ Player Draft හි ඉහළම ඩොලරය ලබා ගත් විදේශීය ක්‍රීඩකයින් අතර බටහිර ඉන්දීය ක්‍රීඩකයන් වන Carlos Bratwaite සහ Evin Lewis ද විය.",
        "පකිස්තානයේ ඉමාඩ් වසීම්, දකුණු අප්‍රිකානු ක්‍රීඩක ඩ්වේන් ප්‍රිටෝරියස් සහ ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු ජාතික ඩී ආර්සි ෂෝට් ජාත්‍යන්තර රූබි කාණ්ඩයට ද තේරී පත් වූ අතර එහිදී විදේශීය ක්‍රීඩකයින්ට ඩොලර් 60,000 බැගින් හිමි වේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සීමිත ඕවර නායක දසුන් ශානක, තුන් ඉරියව් ක්‍රීඩකයන් වන වනිඳු හසරංග, තිසර පෙරේරා සහ ඇන්ජලෝ මැතිව්ස්, ධනුෂ්ක ගුණතිලක සමඟ සමාන වැටුප් දිනයක් සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා රූබි වැටුප් තලයට අත්සන් කර ඇත.",
        "බලාපොරොත්තු සුන් කරවන වාර දෙකකින් පසුව, අදාළ සංචිත අතර වඩාත් කැපී පෙනෙන වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම් ඇති Kandy Falcons ෆ්‍රැන්චයිස් සඳහා බ්‍රැත්වේට් සහ හසරංග බලවත් හවුල්කාරිත්වයක් ගොඩනඟනු ඇත.",
        "පසුගිය වසරේ සංචිතයෙන් එක් ක්‍රීඩකයෙකු පමණක් රඳවාගෙන සිටින මහනුවර, ෆේබියන් ඇලන් සහ දකුණු අප්‍රිකාවේ තරුණ උද්යෝගිමත් දක්ෂතා ඇති ඩෙවල්ඩ් බ්‍රෙවිස් තුළ තවත් බටහිර ඉන්දීය තුන් ඉරියව් ක්‍රීඩකයෙකු කෙටුම්පත් කර ඇත.",
        "හසරංග LPL තරඟාවලි දෙකම ජයග්‍රහණය කිරීමේ යාපනයේ ප්‍රධාන කොටස්කරුවෙකු වූ අතර, ඔහුගේ ඉවත්වීම කිංග්ස් කණ්ඩායමට විශාල පාඩුවක් වනු ඇත, නමුත් මහේෂ් තීක්ෂණ රඳවා ගැනීමෙන් ඔවුන් තුන් ඉරියව් ක්‍රීඩක දුනිත් වෙල්ලාලගේ ද ගිවිසුම්ගත කර ඇත.",
        "යාපනය දකුණු අප්‍රිකානු ප්‍රවීණ ක්‍රීඩක Hardus Viljeon සඳහා විශාල වශයෙන් ආයෝජනය කර ඇති අතර, ඔහු ජාත්‍යන්තර ක්‍රීඩකයින් සඳහා දෙවන ඉහළම කාණ්ඩයට ඇතුළත් කර ඇත -- තුන් ඉරියව් ක්‍රීඩක ධනංජය ද සිල්වා සඳහා ද එවැනිම අගයක් නිකුත් විය.",
        "එම අවසන් තරග දෙකේදීම දෙවතාවක් පරාජයට පත් වූ ගාලු ග්ලැඩියේටර්ස් පිල සහ එහි නායකයා වූ භානුක රාජපක්ෂ වෙන්ව ගිය අතර පිතිකරු ශානකගේ නායකත්වයෙන් දඹුල්ල ජයන්ට් පිලට එක්විය.",
        "ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානුවන්ගේ කෙටි සහ බෙන් කටිං සහ නේපාල පා දඟ පන්දු යවන ක්‍රීඩක සන්දීප් ලැමිචානේ දඹුල්ල ෆ්‍රැන්චයිස් හි විදේශීය ක්‍රීඩකයින් සඳහා පළමු ස්ථාන තුන ලබාගෙන ඇත.",
        "ග්ලැඩියේටර්ස් කණ්ඩායමට පකිස්තාන ක්‍රීඩකයන්ගේ ප්‍රබල පැවැත්මක් ඇති අතර, වසීම් සමඟ ෆහීම් අෂ්රෆ්, අසාම් ඛාන් සහ ෂර්ෆ්‍රාස් අහමඩ් එක්වන අතර අනෙක් විදේශීය ක්‍රීඩක ස්ථාන දෙක ජැනෙමන් මාලන් සහ කයිස් අහමඩ් වෙත හිමිවේ.",
        "ගුණතිලක, කුසල් මෙන්ඩිස්, ලක්ෂාන් සඳකැන්, නුවන් තුෂාර සහ පුලින තරංග යළි කණ්ඩායමට කැඳවා Gladiators කණ්ඩායම වේග පන්දු යවන ක්‍රීඩක දුෂ්මන්ත චමීර ද ගිවිසුම්ගත කර ඇත.",
        "චමීරගේ ඉවත්වීමත් සමඟ කලම්බු කිංග්ස් කණ්ඩායම වේගපන්දු යවන්නන් සඳහා සැලකිය යුතු සම්පත් වැය කර ඇති අතර, ඔවුන්ගේ විදේශීය ක්‍රීඩකයින් හය දෙනාගෙන් පහක්ම ප්‍රිටෝරියස්, බටහිර ඉන්දීය ඩොමිනික් ඩ්‍රේක්ස් සහ ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානයේ ෆසාල්හක් ෆාරුකි, නවීන්-උල්-හක් සහ කරීම් ජනත් වෙත යොදාගෙන ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "LPL",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බටහිර ඉන්දියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාලෝස් බ්‍රැත්වේට්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එවින් ලුවිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්‍රීඩක කෙටුම්පත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්වන වාරය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LPL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම මාසයේ පසුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉමාඩ් වසීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු අප්රිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්යන්තර රූබි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "60,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දසුන් ශානක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වනිඳු හසරංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිසර පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇන්ජලෝ මැතිව්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධනුෂ්ක ගුණතිලක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්‍රැත්වේට්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හසරංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆේබියන් ඇලන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩෙවල්ඩ් බ්‍රෙවිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු අප්රිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හසරංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "LPL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තීක්ෂණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුනිත් වෙල්ලාලගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු අප්රිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hardus Viljeon",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධනංජය ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාලු ග්ලැඩියේටර්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භානුක රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දඹුල්ල යෝධයෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශානක",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෙන් කැපීම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නේපාල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්දීප් ලමිච්චනේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දඹුල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ග්ලැඩියේටර්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆහීම් අෂ්රෆ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අසාම් ඛාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂර්ෆ්රාස් අහමඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසීම් ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනෙමන් මාලන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කයිස් අහමඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ග්ලැඩියේටර්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුෂ්මන්ත චමීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුණතිලකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුසල් මෙන්ඩිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂාන් සඳකැන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුවන් තුෂාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුලිනා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චමීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රිටෝරියස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර ඉන්දීය ඩොමිනික් ඩ්‍රේක්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆසාල්හක් ෆාරුකි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කරීම් ජනත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "LPL வரைவில் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட வெளிநாட்டு வீரர்களில் பிராத்வைட், லூயிஸ்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்த மாத இறுதியில் தொடங்கும் லங்கா பிரீமியர் லீக்கின் (LPL) மூன்றாவது சீசனுக்கான பிளேயர் டிராப்டில் டாலரைப் பெற்ற வெளிநாட்டு வீரர்களில் மேற்கிந்திய வீரர்களான கார்லோஸ் பிராத்வைட் மற்றும் எவின் லூயிஸ் ஆகியோர் அடங்குவர்.",
        "சர்வதேச ரூபி பிரிவில் பாகிஸ்தானின் இமாத் வாசிம், தென்னாப்பிரிக்காவின் டுவைன் பிரிட்டோரியஸ் மற்றும் ஆஸ்திரேலிய டி'ஆர்சி ஷார்ட் ஆகியோரும் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டனர், அங்கு வெளிநாட்டு வீரர்கள் தலா 60,000 அமெரிக்க டாலர்களைப் பெறுவார்கள்.",
        "இலங்கை மட்டுப்படுத்தப்பட்ட ஓவர்கள் அணித்தலைவர் தசுன் ஷனக, சகலதுறை ஆட்டக்காரர்களான வனிந்து ஹசரங்க, திசர பெரேரா மற்றும் ஏஞ்சலோ மேத்யூஸ் மற்றும் தனுஷ்க குணதிலக்க ஆகியோர் இலங்கையின் ரூபி சம்பள வரம்பில் கையெழுத்திட்டனர்.",
        "பிரத்வைட் மற்றும் ஹசரங்க ஆகியோர் கண்டி ஃபால்கன்ஸ் உரிமைக்காக ஒரு வல்லமைமிக்க கூட்டாண்மையை உருவாக்குவார்கள், இது இரண்டு ஏமாற்றமான பருவங்களைத் தொடர்ந்து அந்தந்த அணிகளில் மிகவும் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க மேம்படுத்தல்களைக் கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "கடந்த ஆண்டு அணியில் இருந்து ஒரு வீரரை மட்டும் தக்கவைத்துக் கொண்ட கண்டி, ஃபேபியன் ஆலனில் மற்றொரு மேற்கிந்திய ஆல்-ரவுண்டரையும், தென்னாப்பிரிக்காவின் இளம் அற்புதமான திறமையான டெவால்ட் ப்ரீவிஸையும் உருவாக்கியுள்ளார்.",
        "இரண்டு எல்பிஎல் போட்டிகளிலும் ஹசரங்க யாழ்ப்பாண அணியில் முக்கிய பங்கு வகித்தார், மேலும் அவரது விலகல் கிங்ஸ் அணிக்கு பெரும் இழப்பாக இருக்கும், ஆனால் மஹீஷ் தீக்ஷனாவை தக்கவைத்துக்கொண்ட அவர்கள் சகலதுறை ஆட்டக்காரர் துனித் வெல்லலகேவையும் ஒப்பந்தம் செய்தனர்.",
        "யாழ்ப்பாணம் தென்னாப்பிரிக்காவின் மூத்த வீரர் ஹர்டஸ் வில்ஜியோனிடம் அதிக முதலீடு செய்து, சர்வதேச வீரர்களுக்கான இரண்டாவது மிக உயர்ந்த தரவரிசையில் அவரை உருவாக்கியது -- சகலதுறை ஆட்டக்காரர் தனஞ்சய டி சில்வாவுக்கும் இதேபோன்ற எண்ணிக்கை தெறிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "அந்த இரண்டு இறுதிப் போட்டிகளிலும் இரண்டு முறை தோற்கடிக்கப்பட்ட காலி கிளாடியேட்டர்ஸ் மற்றும் அவர்களது அணித்தலைவர் பானுக ராஜபக்ஷ பிரிந்துவிட்டனர், பேட்ஸ்மேன் ஷனகவின் தலைமையில் தம்புள்ளை ஜெயண்ட்ஸ் அணியுடன் இணைந்தார்.",
        "ஆஸ்திரேலியர்கள் ஷார்ட் மற்றும் பென் கட்டிங், மற்றும் நேபாள லெக்-ஸ்பின்னர் சந்தீப் லாமிச்சானே ஆகியோர் தம்புள்ளை அணியில் வெளிநாட்டு வீரர்களுக்கான முதல் மூன்று இடங்களைப் பெற்றனர்.",
        "கிளாடியேட்டர்ஸ் தொடர்ந்து பாக்கிஸ்தான் வீரர்களின் வலுவான இருப்பைக் கொண்டுள்ளது, ஃபஹீம் அஷ்ரஃப், அசம் கான் மற்றும் ஷர்ஃப்ராஸ் அகமது ஆகியோர் வாசிமுடன் இணைந்துள்ளனர், மற்ற இரண்டு வெளிநாட்டு வீரர்களுக்கான இடங்கள் ஜன்னெமன் மலான் மற்றும் கைஸ் அஹ்மத் ஆகியோருக்குச் செல்கின்றன.",
        "குணதிலகா, குசல் மெண்டிஸ், லக்ஷான் சந்தகன், நுவான் துஷார மற்றும் புலின தரங்கா ஆகியோரை மீண்டும் இணைத்து, வேகப்பந்து வீச்சாளர் துஷ்மந்த சமீரவையும் கிளாடியேட்டர்ஸ் ஒப்பந்தம் செய்துள்ளது.",
        "சமீராவின் விலகலுடன், கொழும்பு கிங்ஸ் அணியானது வேகப்பந்து வீச்சாளர்களுக்கு கணிசமான வளங்களை செலவழித்தது, பிரிட்டோரியஸ், மேற்கிந்திய டொமினிக் டிரேக்ஸ் மற்றும் ஆப்கானிஸ்தானின் ஃபசல்ஹக் ஃபாரூக்கி, நவீன்-உல்-ஹக் மற்றும் கரீம் ஜனத் ஆகியோரின் ஆறு வெளிநாட்டு வீரர்களுக்கான இடங்களைப் பயன்படுத்தி ஐந்தை பயன்படுத்தியது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "LPL",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு இந்தியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கார்லோஸ் பிராத்வைட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எவின் லூயிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரர் வரைவு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது சீசன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LPL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாதத்தின் பிற்பகுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இமாத் வாசிம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்னாப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச ரூபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "60,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தசுன் ஷனக",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வனிந்து ஹசரங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திசர பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏஞ்சலோ மேத்யூஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனுஷ்க குணதிலக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிராத்வைட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹசரங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபேபியன் ஆலன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெவால்ட் ப்ரீவிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்னாப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹசரங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "LPL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தீக்ஷனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "துனித் வெல்லலகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்னாப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹார்டஸ் வில்ஜியோன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனஞ்சய டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி கிளாடியேட்டர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பானுகா ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்புள்ளை ஜயண்ட்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷனகா",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பென் கட்டிங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேபாளியர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்தீப் லமிச்சனே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்புள்ளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிளாடியேட்டர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபஹீம் அஷ்ரப்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசம் கான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷர்ஃப்ராஸ் அகமது",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாசிம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனனிமான் மாலன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கைஸ் அகமது",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிளாடியேட்டர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துஷ்மந்த சமீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குணதிலக",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குசல் மெண்டிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்ஷன் சண்டகன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுவன் துஷாரா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புலினா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமீரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டோரியஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு இந்திய டொமினிக் டிரேக்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்கானிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபசல்ஹக் பாரூக்கி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கரீம் ஜனத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}