{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83633/president-rajapaksa-fails-to-board-singapore-based-flight-reports",
  "time_ut": 1657766640,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President Rajapaksa fails to board Singapore-based flight: reports",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President Rajapaksa fails to board Singapore-based flight: reports",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, who departed for the Maldives amidst the ongoing economic crisis and growing protests demanding his resignation, has not headed to Singapore, foreign media revealed.",
        "As per reports, he was set to board SQ437 flight belonging to Singapore Airlines, however, he was a no-show at the Changi Airport due to security reasons.",
        "He was expected to depart for Singapore and send his resignation to the Speaker of Parliament after landing there.",
        "According to media reports, President Rajapaksa is now in talks with the Maldivian government to secure a private jet for his departure.",
        "He flew out of Sri Lanka to the Maldives with his wife Ioma Rajapaksa and two security officers in the early hours of Wednesday.",
        "Sri Lanka Air Force (SLAF), later confirmed that it provided a military plane to President Rajapaksa upon a request made by the incumbent government."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Singapore",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SQ437",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Changi Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldivian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ioma Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the early hours of Wednesday",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සිංගප්පූරුවේ ගුවන් යානයට ගොඩවීමට ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ අපොහොසත් වෙයි: වාර්තාවේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සහ ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බලකරමින් වැඩෙන විරෝධතා මධ්‍යයේ මාලදිවයින බලා පිටත්ව ගිය ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සිංගප්පූරුව බලා ගොස් නොමැති බව විදෙස් මාධ්‍ය අනාවරණය කරයි.",
        "වාර්තා වන පරිදි, ඔහු සිංගප්පූරු ගුවන් සේවයට අයත් SQ437 ගුවන් යානයට ගොඩවීමට සූදානම්ව සිටි නමුත්, ආරක්ෂක හේතූන් මත ඔහු චැංගි ගුවන් තොටුපළට නොපැමිණියේය.",
        "ඔහු සිංගප්පූරුව බලා පිටත්ව ගොස් එහි ගොඩබෑමෙන් පසු සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය කථානායකවරයා වෙත යැවීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන ලදී.",
        "මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා වලට අනුව, ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ දැන් මාලදිවයින් රජය සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කරමින් සිටින්නේ ඔහුගේ පිටවීම සඳහා පුද්ගලික ජෙට් යානයක් ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා ය.",
        "ඔහු බදාදා අලුයම සිය බිරිඳ අයෝමා රාජපක්ෂ සහ ආරක්ෂක නිලධාරීන් දෙදෙනෙකු සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් මාලදිවයිනට පියාසර කළේය.",
        "වත්මන් රජය විසින් කරන ලද ඉල්ලීමකට අනුව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව (ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව) ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂට හමුදා ගුවන් යානයක් ලබා දුන් බව පසුව තහවුරු කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SQ437",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරු ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චැංගි ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයෝමා රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා හිමිදිරියේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சிங்கப்பூர் விமானத்தில் ஏறத் தவறிய அதிபர் ராஜபக்சே: தகவல்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மாலத்தீவுக்குப் புறப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச, தற்போது நிலவும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி மற்றும் பதவி விலகக் கோரி அதிகரித்து வரும் போராட்டங்களுக்கு மத்தியில் சிங்கப்பூர் செல்லவில்லை என வெளிநாட்டு ஊடகங்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளன.",
        "அறிக்கைகளின்படி, அவர் சிங்கப்பூர் ஏர்லைன்ஸுக்குச் சொந்தமான SQ437 விமானத்தில் ஏறத் தயாராக இருந்தார், இருப்பினும், பாதுகாப்பு காரணங்களால் அவர் சாங்கி விமான நிலையத்தில் காட்டப்படவில்லை.",
        "அவர் சிங்கப்பூர் புறப்பட்டு, அங்கு வந்திறங்கிய பின்னர் தனது ராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை நாடாளுமன்ற சபாநாயகருக்கு அனுப்புவார் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்பட்டது.",
        "ஊடகச் செய்திகளின்படி, ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ இப்போது மாலத்தீவு அரசாங்கத்துடன் தனது புறப்படுவதற்கு ஒரு தனிப்பட்ட ஜெட் விமானத்தைப் பெற பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தி வருகிறார்.",
        "அவர் புதன்கிழமை அதிகாலை தனது மனைவி அயோமா ராஜபக்ச மற்றும் இரண்டு பாதுகாப்பு அதிகாரிகளுடன் இலங்கையில் இருந்து மாலத்தீவுக்கு சென்றார்.",
        "இலங்கை விமானப்படை (SLAF), பின்னர் தற்போதைய அரசாங்கத்தின் கோரிக்கையின் பேரில் ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்சேவுக்கு இராணுவ விமானத்தை வழங்கியதை உறுதிப்படுத்தியது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SQ437",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாங்கி விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவு",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அயோமா ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்கிழமை அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}