{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/cinema/பிரபல-இசையமைப்பாளர்-திடீர்-மரணம்/54-303331",
  "time_ut": 1661947097,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "பிரபல இசையமைப்பாளர் திடீர் மரணம்..!",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Famous music composer died suddenly..!",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The sudden death of the famous music composer has shocked the Malayalam film industry and fans alike.",
        "52-year-old John B Vargi, a popular music composer, has captured the hearts of thousands of Malayalam fans with his music. His death due to sudden illness is shocking.",
        "He has composed music for some popular Malayalam films like Kammattipadam, Neithukaran, Penkodi, Unnam etc. released in Malayalam. Vargi, who was living in her house in Mullakara, Kerala state, is said to have fainted at her house due to a sudden decline in her health. Following this, he was admitted to the hospital and died due to treatment. His death has left the entire film industry and fans in mourning.",
        "Apart from composing music for Malayalam films and songs, Vargi has also worked in some Hindi, Kannada and Tamil films. He composed difficult songs for a Malayalam rock band named Avyal.",
        "He was a key member of the band Jigsaw Puzzle. In 2007, Vargi was adjudged Best Music Composer for the drama film Frozen at the Madrid Imagine India Film Festival.",
        "A guitarist, he studied guitar at London's Trinity College of Music. He rose to fame after releasing three albums with his band, Jigsaw Puzzle.",
        "Celebrities and fans are paying their tributes to him as the most talented music composer of Malayalam film industry, his loss is irreparable. Notably, Vargie has two children with his wife, Baby John, and Job and Joseph John."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Malayalam",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "52-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "John B Vargi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malayalam",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Malayalam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kammattipadam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Neithukaran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Penkodi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Unnam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malayalam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vargi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mullakara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Malayalam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vargi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kannada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malayalam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Avyal",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jigsaw Puzzle",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2007",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vargi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Best Music Composer",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Frozen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Madrid Imagine India Film Festival",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "London",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trinity College of Music",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jigsaw Puzzle",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Malayalam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vargie",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Baby John",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Job",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joseph John",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ප්‍රසිද්ධ සංගීත නිර්මාපකයෙකු හදිසියේ මියයයි..!",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සුප්‍රසිද්ධ සංගීත නිර්මාපකයාගේ හදිසි අභාවය මලයාලම් සිනමා ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ මෙන්ම රසික රසිකාවියන්ද කම්පාවට පත් කර ඇත.",
        "ජනප්‍රිය සංගීත නිර්මාපකයෙකු වන 52 හැවිරිදි ජෝන් බී වර්ගී සිය සංගීතයෙන් දහස් සංඛ්‍යාත මලයාලම් රසික රසිකාවියන්ගේ හදවත් පැහැරගෙන ඇත. හදිසි රෝගාබාධයක් හේතුවෙන් ඔහුගේ මරණය කම්පනයකි.",
        "ඔහු මලයාලම් භාෂාවෙන් නිකුත් වූ කම්මට්ටිපදම්, නීතුකරන්, පෙන්කොඩි, උන්නම් ආදී ජනප්‍රිය මලයාලම් චිත්‍රපට කිහිපයකට සංගීතය නිර්මාණය කර ඇත. කේරල ප්‍රාන්තයේ මුල්ලකර ප්‍රදේශයේ පිහිටි සිය නිවසේ වාසය කළ වර්ගීගේ සෞඛ්‍ය තත්ත්වය හදිසියේ පිරිහීම හේතුවෙන් ඇයගේ නිවස තුළදී ක්ලාන්ත වී ඇති බව පැවසේ. ඉන් අනතුරුව ඔහු රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කර ප්‍රතිකාර ලබමින් සිටියදී මියගොස් තිබේ. ඔහුගේ වියෝව සමස්ත සිනමා කර්මාන්තයේ සහ රසික රසිකාවියන්ගේ ශෝකයට පත් කර ඇත.",
        "වර්ගි මලයාලම් චිත්‍රපට සහ ගීත සඳහා සංගීතය රචනා කිරීමට අමතරව හින්දි, කන්නඩ සහ දෙමළ චිත්‍රපට කිහිපයකම ද සේවය කර ඇත. ඔහු Avyal නම් මලයාලම් රොක් සංගීත කණ්ඩායමක් සඳහා දුෂ්කර ගීත රචනා කළේය.",
        "ඔහු Jigsaw Puzzle සංගීත කණ්ඩායමේ ප්‍රධාන සාමාජිකයෙක් විය. 2007 දී Madrid Imagine India චිත්‍රපට උළෙලේ Frozen නාට්‍ය චිත්‍රපටය සඳහා Vargi හොඳම සංගීත නිර්මාපකයා ලෙස සම්මාන ලැබීය.",
        "ගිටාර් වාදකයෙකු වන ඔහු ලන්ඩනයේ ත්‍රිත්ව සංගීත විද්‍යාලයේ ගිටාර් හැදෑරීය. ඔහුගේ සංගීත කණ්ඩායම වන ජිග්සෝ ප්‍රහේලිකාව සමඟ ඇල්බම තුනක් නිකුත් කිරීමෙන් පසු ඔහු ප්‍රසිද්ධියට පත් විය.",
        "මලයාලම් චිත්‍රපට ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ දක්ෂතම සංගීත නිර්මාපකයා ලෙස ප්‍රසිද්ධ පුද්ගලයින් සහ රසිකයින් ඔහුට උපහාර පුද කරති, ඔහුගේ වියෝව පිරිමැසිය නොහැක. කැපී පෙනෙන ලෙස, වර්ජිට ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ බේබි ජෝන් සහ ජොබ් සහ ජෝසප් ජෝන් සමඟ දරුවන් දෙදෙනෙක් සිටී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මලයාලම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "52 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝන් බී වර්ගී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මලයාලම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මලයාලම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කම්මට්ටිපදම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නීතුකරන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙන්කොඩි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උන්නම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මලයාලම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වර්ගී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුල්ලකරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මලයාලම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වර්ගී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කන්නඩ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මලයාලම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවියල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජිග්සෝ ප්‍රහේලිකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2007",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වර්ගී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හොඳම සංගීත නිර්මාපකයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශීත කළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Madrid Imagine India Film Festival",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලන්ඩන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රිත්ව සංගීත විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිග්සෝ ප්‍රහේලිකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මලයාලම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වර්ගී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බේබි ජෝන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රැකියා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝසප් ජෝන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரபல இசையமைப்பாளர் திடீர் மரணம்..!",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிரபல இசையமைப்பாளரின் திடீர் மரணம், மலையாள திரையுலகினர் மற்றும் ரசிகர்கள் மத்தியில் அதிர்ச்சியை ஏற்படுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான மலையாள ரசிகர்களின் மனதை தன்னுடைய இசையால் தன்வசப்படுத்தியவர்,  பிரபல இசையமைப்பாளர் 52 வயதான ஜான் பி வர்கி. இவர் திடீர் உடல்நலக்குறைவு காரணமாக உயிரிழந்துள்ளது அதிர்ச்சியை ஏற்படுத்தியுளளது.",
        "இவர் மலையாளத்தில் வெளியான கம்மட்டிப்படம், நெய்துக்காரன், பெண்கொடி, உன்னம் போன்ற சில பிரபலமான மலையாளப் படங்களுக்கு இசையமைத்தவர்.  கேரளா மாநிலம், முல்லக்கராவில் உள்ள தன்னுடைய வீட்டில் வசித்து வந்த வர்கி, திடீர் என ஏற்பட்ட உடல்நல குறைவு காரணமாக தனது வீட்டில் மயங்கி விழுந்ததாக கூறப்படுகிறது. இதை தொடர்ந்து மருத்துவமனையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்ட  இவர் சிகிச்சை பலனின்றி உயிரிழந்தார். இவரது மரணம் ஒட்டுமொத்த திரையுலகினர் மற்றும் ரசிகர்களை சோகத்தில் ஆழ்த்தியுள்ளது.",
        "மலையாளப் படங்கள் மற்றும் பாடல்களுக்கு இசையமைத்துள்ளது மட்டுமல்லாமல், சில இந்தி, கன்னடம் மற்றும் தமிழ் படங்களிலும் வர்கி பணியாற்றியுள்ளார்.  மலையாள ராக் இசைக்குழுவிற்கு அவியல் என்று பெயரிடப்பட்ட கடினமான பாடல்களை இயற்றினார்.",
        "ஜிக்சா புதிர் இசைக்குழுவின் முக்கிய அங்கமாக இருந்தார். மாட்ரிட் இமேஜின் இந்தியா திரைப்பட விழாவில் 2007 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஃப்ரோசன் என்ற நாடகத் திரைப்படத்திற்கு இசையமைத்ததற்காக வர்கி சிறந்த இசையமைப்பாளராக அறிவிக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "கிதார் கலைஞரான இவர், லண்டனின் டிரினிட்டி காலேஜ் ஆஃப் மியூசிக்கில் கிட்டார் வாசிப்பதில் தேர்ச்சி பெற்றார். அவரது இசைக்குழு, ஜிக்சா புதிர் என்ற பெயரில் மூன்று ஆல்பங்களை வெளியிட்ட பிறகு அவர் புகழ் பெற்றார்.",
        "மலையாள திரையுலகின் மிக திறமையான இசையமைப்பாளரான இவரது இழப்பு ஈடுசெய்ய முடியாதது என பிரபலங்கள் மற்றும் ரசிகர்கள் இவருக்கு தங்களது அஞ்சலியை செலுத்தி வருகிறார்கள். வர்கிக்கு அவரது மனைவி பேபி ஜான் மற்றும் ஜாப் மற்றும் ஜோசப் ஜான் என்ற இரண்டு குழந்தைகள் உள்ளனர் என்பது குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மலையாளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "52 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான் பி வர்கி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலையாளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மலையாளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்மட்டிபாடம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நெய்துகாரன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெண்கொடி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உன்னம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலையாளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வர்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முல்லகர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மலையாளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வர்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹிந்தி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கன்னடம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலையாளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அவயல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜிக்சா புதிர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2007",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வர்கி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறந்த இசையமைப்பாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உறைந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாட்ரிட் இமேஜின் இந்தியா திரைப்பட விழா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லண்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிரினிட்டி இசைக் கல்லூரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜிக்சா புதிர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மலையாளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வர்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழந்தை ஜான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வேலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜோசப் ஜான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}