{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Ceylon-tea-increases-footprint-in-largest-retail-chains-in-Poland/34-739224",
  "time_ut": 1661730556,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ceylon tea increases footprint in largest retail chains in Poland",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ceylon tea increases footprint in largest retail chains in Poland",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Auchan is a French multinational retail group headquartered in Croix, France, and has continued its commercial activities in Poland for over 22 years (since 1996)",
        "In a significant breakthrough, Sri Lanka’s tea exports to the Polish retail market will increase from 2022 onwards with the expanded supply of Ceylon tea to Poland’s largest retail chains Biedronka (Ladybird) and Auchan.",
        "Biedronka has already sourced a total of 109,699 kilos of Ceylon tea, valued at $ 754,641.12 from the new Sri Lankan export partner between February and July 2022. This is an important opportunity for further expanding the Ceylon tea footprint in the Polish retail market, while increasing the appreciation for Sri Lanka’s premium tea among the largely tea-drinking Polish consumers. Tea comprised 31.60% of Sri Lanka’s exports to Poland in 2020.",
        "Biedronka sources its products mainly from Polish suppliers. However, the retail chain offers opportunities for a range of high quality consumer products from foreign suppliers to be sold at its stores. Compliance with EU quality/standards, uninterrupted delivery and the CSR (Corporate Social Responsibility) profile, are essential for Biedronka, when sourcing items from foreign buyers.",
        "The new supplies of Ceylon tea, fully produced in Sri Lanka, will be sold under Briedronka’s Lion logo branded private label, “REMSEY”, at the retailer’s 3,154 stores across 1,100 towns and cities in Poland. It is estimated that the sale of Ceylon tea in this supermarket chain alone, will reach at least $ 10 million by the end of 2022 and, increase to $ 15 million in 2023. At present, the worth of its private label Ceylon tea, primarily comprising Earl Grey and black tea, is around $ 4 million. With the entry of new Sri Lankan export partners, the Ceylon tea shelves in Biedronka and Auchan will be diversified with flavoured and iced tea, including regional varieties.",
        "The sale of private label teas by the retail chains is estimated to be about 50% of the total Polish tea market, and has grown significantly given the emerging market opportunities, reasonable costs and the high profit margins it yields. Biedronka alone, as the largest retail chain, controls almost half of the Polish FMCG market. Further, as the wellness and organic market categories continue to flourish, key retailers are expanding their private label premium tea brands to appeal to sustainable and healthy lifestyles.",
        "The Embassy of Sri Lanka in Warsaw, combining tea and tourism promotion activities, showcased an array of premium Ceylon tea, generously donated by the Empire Teas Ltd., Quest Ceylon Tea LLC and Mabroc Teas Ltd., at the November 2021 International Charity Bazaar in Warsaw. The Elpitiya Plantations PLC also joined the Sri Lanka Embassy’s promotion events with tea and cinnamon gift packs. It was during the charity event that the Embassy succeeded in partnering with the Krakow based FMCG company, LIVEE POLSKA Sp., a regular supplier to Biedronka and Auchan, to seek to expand the portfolio of Ceylon tea in the supermarket chains.",
        "The Sri Lanka Mission arranged B2B meetings for LIVEE POLSKA Sp. with the identified Sri Lankan tea companies in Cologne, Germany, during their participation at the Anuga 2021 food trade fair.",
        "Ambassador Dhammika Kumari Semasinghe was invited to join LIVEE in the discussions and negotiations with Biedronka last year, to secure the increased and direct supply of Ceylon tea.",
        "With the right product, and sustained promotional activities, LIVEE’s goal is to double the export of Ceylon tea and other products to Poland by 2023. LIVEE will also access the Ukrainian market with smaller quantities of Ceylon tea, sourced directly from its new partners.",
        "Discussions are already underway to source dried fruits, canned pineapples, iced teas for the two retail chains, and golden and silver tips premium Ceylon teas, etc. for luxury tea houses in Warsaw and Krakow. In the coming months, these business leads will be formalised between the Sri Lankan and Polish partners.",
        "The successful entry of Ceylon tea into the Polish retail market, is also an important market diversification, since Sri Lanka’s export partners in the European region are primarily France, Germany, Belgium, Italy, Netherlands and the UK. As the retail chains/markets are connected and aligned across Europe, value added Ceylon teas and other items, for instance, in Auchan Poland, will be offered in the Auchan stores in Hungary, Romania, Portugal, or within the EU. At present, the Central/Eastern European markets continue to remain woefully underutilised by Sri Lanka. However, Sri Lanka could be optimistic about its long-term growth prospects for a number of export products by increasing its commercial engagement with Central/Eastern Europe through Poland, the largest emerging economy in the region with a population exceeding 38 million.",
        "The Polish tea market, estimated to be worth $ 630 million a year, is growing steadily. As the fourth largest tea market in the European region (next to Ireland, UK and Russia), Poland’s yearly tea imports are around 31, 000 metric tons worth $ 120 million. Specialising in value added teas, Poland imports a bulk of its products mainly from India and Kenya.",
        "Biedronka, owned by the Jerónimo Martins Group of Portugal, has investments valued over PLN 14 billion in Poland since 1995. The supermarket chain with 3,154 stores across the country, is the largest private employer in Poland (70,000 workforce) and sources its products mainly from Polish suppliers.",
        "Display and sale of Ceylon Tea at the International Charity Bazaar 2021 (sales proceeds channelled to a designated Polish charity)",
        "Sri Lanka tea display at the 7th edition of the Wrocław Tea Festival “Czaisz?” 2022"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Poland",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Auchan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "French",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Croix",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "France",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 22 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "since 1996",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polish",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ladybird",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Auchan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "109,699",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "754,641.12",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "between February and July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polish",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polish",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "31.60%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Polish",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSR",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ceylon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Briedronka’s Lion",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "REMSEY",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,154",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "at least $ 10 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 15 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Earl Grey",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "around $ 4 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Auchan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 50%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polish",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "almost half",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polish",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Embassy of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Warsaw",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Empire Teas Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Quest Ceylon Tea LLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mabroc Teas Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "November 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "International Charity",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Warsaw",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Elpitiya Plantations PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Embassy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Krakow",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LIVEE POLSKA Sp.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Auchan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LIVEE POLSKA Sp",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cologne",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Kumari Semasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LIVEE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LIVEE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukrainian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Warsaw",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Krakow",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coming months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polish",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ceylon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polish",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "European",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "France",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Belgium",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Italy",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Netherlands",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Europe",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Auchan Poland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Auchan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hungary",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Romania",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Portugal",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central/Eastern European",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central/Eastern Europe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "38 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Polish",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 630 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "fourth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "European",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ireland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "around 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 120 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kenya",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Jerónimo Martins Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Portugal",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PLN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1995",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,154",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polish",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Tea",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Charity Bazaar",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polish",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Wrocław Tea Festival “Czaisz",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සිලෝන් ටී පෝලන්තයේ විශාලතම සිල්ලර වෙළඳ ජාලයේ අඩිපාර වැඩි කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "Auchan යනු ප්‍රංශයේ Croix හි මූලස්ථානය වන ප්‍රංශ බහුජාතික සිල්ලර වෙළඳ කණ්ඩායමක් වන අතර, වසර 22 කට වැඩි කාලයක් (1996 සිට) පෝලන්තයේ සිය වාණිජ ක්‍රියාකාරකම් දිගටම කරගෙන ගොස් ඇත.",
        "සැලකිය යුතු ප්‍රගතියක් ලෙස, පෝලන්තයේ විශාලතම සිල්ලර වෙළඳ ජාලයන් වන Biedronka (Ladybird) සහ Auchan වෙත ලංකා තේ සැපයීම පුළුල් කිරීමත් සමඟ 2022 සිට පෝලන්ත සිල්ලර වෙළඳපොළට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තේ අපනයනය ඉහළ යනු ඇත.",
        "Biedronka විසින් 2022 පෙබරවාරි සිට ජූලි දක්වා කාලය තුළ නව ශ්‍රී ලංකා අපනයන සහකරු වෙතින් ඩොලර් 754,641.12 ක වටිනාකමකින් යුත් ලංකා තේ කිලෝ 109,699 ක් ලබාගෙන ඇත. මෙය පෝලන්ත සිල්ලර වෙළඳපොලේ ලංකා තේ අඩිපාර තවදුරටත් ව්‍යාප්ත කිරීම සඳහා වැදගත් අවස්ථාවක් වන අතර එය වැඩි වේ. විශාල වශයෙන් තේ පානය කරන පෝලන්ත පාරිභෝගිකයින් අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රිමියම් තේ සඳහා වූ අගය කිරීම. 2020 වසරේ පෝලන්තයට කරන ලද ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අපනයනවලින් 31.60% තේ සමන්විත විය.",
        "Biedronka සිය නිෂ්පාදන ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් පෝලන්ත සැපයුම්කරුවන්ගෙන් ලබා ගනී. කෙසේ වෙතත්, සිල්ලර වෙළඳ ජාලය විදේශීය සැපයුම්කරුවන්ගෙන් උසස් තත්ත්වයේ පාරිභෝගික නිෂ්පාදන රාශියක් එහි ගබඩාවල අලෙවි කිරීමට අවස්ථාව ලබා දෙයි. EU තත්ත්ව/ප්‍රමිතීන්ට අනුකූල වීම, බාධාවකින් තොරව බෙදා හැරීම සහ CSR (ආයතනික සමාජ වගකීම්) පැතිකඩ, Biedronka සඳහා විදේශීය ගැනුම්කරුවන්ගෙන් භාණ්ඩ ලබා ගැනීමේදී අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වේ.",
        "සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නිෂ්පාදනය කරන ලද ලංකා තේ නව සැපයුම් Briedronka's Lion ලාංඡනය සහිත පුද්ගලික ලේබලය \"REMSEY\" යටතේ, පෝලන්තයේ නගර සහ නගර 1,100 ක සිල්ලර වෙළෙන්දාගේ වෙළඳසැල් 3,154 කදී අලෙවි කෙරේ. මෙම සුපිරි වෙළඳසැල් ජාලය තුළ පමණක් ලංකා තේ අලෙවිය 2022 වසර අවසන් වන විට අවම වශයෙන් ඩොලර් මිලියන 10 දක්වා ළඟා වනු ඇතැයි ගණන් බලා ඇති අතර, 2023 දී එය ඩොලර් මිලියන 15 දක්වා ඉහළ යනු ඇතැයි ගණන් බලා ඇත. අර්ල් ග්‍රේ සහ කළු තේ වලින් සමන්විත වන අතර එය ඩොලර් මිලියන 4 ක් පමණ වේ. නව ශ්‍රී ලංකා අපනයන හවුල්කරුවන්ගේ ප්‍රවේශයත් සමඟ Biedronka සහ Auchan හි ලංකා තේ රාක්ක කලාපීය ප්‍රභේද ඇතුළුව රස කළ සහ අයිස් තේවලින් විවිධාංගීකරණය වනු ඇත.",
        "සිල්ලර දාමයන් විසින් පුද්ගලික ලේබල් තේ විකිණීම සමස්ත පෝලන්ත තේ වෙළඳපොලෙන් 50% ක් පමණ වන බවට ඇස්තමේන්තු කර ඇති අතර, නැගී එන වෙළඳපල අවස්ථා, සාධාරණ පිරිවැය සහ එයින් ලැබෙන ඉහළ ලාභ ආන්තික මත සැලකිය යුතු ලෙස වර්ධනය වී ඇත. Biedronka පමණක්, විශාලතම සිල්ලර වෙළඳ ජාලය ලෙස, පෝලන්ත FMCG වෙළඳපොළෙන් අඩක් පමණ පාලනය කරයි. තවද, සුවතා සහ කාබනික වෙළඳපල කාණ්ඩ අඛණ්ඩව වර්ධනය වන බැවින්, ප්‍රධාන සිල්ලර වෙළෙන්දෝ තිරසාර සහ සෞඛ්‍ය සම්පන්න ජීවන රටාවකට ආයාචනා කිරීම සඳහා ඔවුන්ගේ පුද්ගලික ලේබල් වාරික තේ සන්නාම පුළුල් කරති.",
        "වෝර්සෝ හි ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති කාර්යාලය, තේ සහ සංචාරක ප්‍රවර්ධන ක්‍රියාකාරකම් ඒකාබද්ධ කරමින්, සීමාසහිත එම්පයර් ටීස්, ක්වෙස්ට් සිලෝන් ටී එල්එල්සී සහ මැබ්‍රොක් ටීස් ලිමිටඩ් විසින් නොමසුරුව පරිත්‍යාග කරන ලද ප්‍රිමියම් සිලෝන් තේ පෙළක් 2021 නොවැම්බර් 2021 ජාත්‍යන්තර පුණ්‍ය බසාර්හිදී ප්‍රදර්ශනය කරන ලදී. වෝර්සෝ. ඇල්පිටිය ප්ලාන්ටේෂන් පීඑල්සී ද ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති කාර්යාලයේ ප්‍රවර්ධන වැඩසටහන් සඳහා තේ සහ කුරුඳු තෑගි ඇසුරුම් සමඟ එක් විය. සුපිරි වෙළඳසැල් ජාලයන්හි ලංකා තේ කළඹ පුළුල් කිරීමට උත්සාහ කිරීම සඳහා Biedronka සහ Auchan සඳහා නිත්‍ය සැපයුම්කරුවෙකු වන Krakow පදනම් කරගත් FMCG සමාගමක් වන LIVEE POLSKA Sp. සමඟ හවුල් වීමට තානාපති කාර්යාලය සමත් වූයේ පුණ්‍ය උත්සවය අතරතුරදීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දූත මණ්ඩලය LIVEE POLSKA Sp සඳහා B2B රැස්වීම් සංවිධානය කළේය. Anuga 2021 ආහාර වෙළඳ ප්‍රදර්ශනයට ඔවුන්ගේ සහභාගීත්වය අතරතුර ජර්මනියේ කොලෝන් හි හඳුනාගත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා තේ සමාගම් සමඟ.",
        "පසුගිය වසරේ Biedronka සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡා සහ සාකච්ඡා සඳහා LIVEE සමඟ සම්බන්ධ වන ලෙස තානාපතිනී ධම්මිකා කුමාරි සේමසිංහ මහත්මියට ආරාධනා කරන ලදී, ලංකා තේ වැඩි කිරීම සහ සෘජු සැපයුම සුරක්ෂිත කිරීම සඳහා.",
        "නිවැරදි නිෂ්පාදනයක් සහ තිරසාර ප්‍රවර්ධන ක්‍රියාකාරකම් සමඟින්, LIVEE හි අරමුණ වන්නේ 2023 වන විට පෝලන්තයට ලංකා තේ සහ අනෙකුත් නිෂ්පාදන අපනයනය දෙගුණ කිරීම ය. LIVEE විසින් සිය නව හවුල්කරුවන්ගෙන් සෘජුවම ලබා ගන්නා කුඩා ප්‍රමාණයේ ලංකා තේ සමඟ යුක්රේන වෙළඳපොළට පිවිසෙනු ඇත.",
        "වියළි පලතුරු, ටින් අන්නාසි, සිල්ලර දාම දෙක සඳහා අයිස් තේ සහ Warsaw සහ Krakow හි සුඛෝපභෝගී තේ නිවාස සඳහා රන් සහ රිදී ඉඟි වාරික ලංකා තේ ආදිය ලබා ගැනීමට දැනටමත් සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වෙමින් තිබේ. ඉදිරි මාසවලදී, ශ්‍රී ලංකා සහ පෝලන්ත හවුල්කරුවන් අතර මෙම ව්‍යාපාරික මඟපෙන්වීම් විධිමත් වනු ඇත.",
        "යුරෝපීය කලාපයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අපනයන හවුල්කරුවන් මූලික වශයෙන් ප්‍රංශය, ජර්මනිය, බෙල්ජියම, ඉතාලිය, නෙදර්ලන්තය සහ එක්සත් රාජධානිය වන බැවින්, පෝලන්ත සිල්ලර වෙළඳපොළට ලංකා තේ සාර්ථක ලෙස ඇතුළුවීම ද වැදගත් වෙළඳපල විවිධාංගීකරණයකි. සිල්ලර දාමයන්/වෙළඳපොල යුරෝපය පුරා සම්බන්ධ වී පෙළගැසී ඇති බැවින්, අගය එකතු කළ ලංකා තේ සහ අනෙකුත් අයිතම, උදාහරණයක් ලෙස, Auchan පෝලන්තයේ, හංගේරියාවේ, රුමේනියාවේ, පෘතුගාලයේ හෝ EU තුළ Auchan ගබඩාවල පිරිනමනු ලැබේ. වර්තමානයේදී, මධ්‍යම/නැගෙනහිර යුරෝපීය වෙලඳපොලවල් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව විසින් අවභාවිතයට ලක්ව දුක්ඛිත ලෙස දිගටම පවතී. කෙසේ වෙතත්, මිලියන 38 ඉක්මවන ජනගහනයක් සහිත කලාපයේ විශාලතම නැඟී එන ආර්ථිකය වන පෝලන්තය හරහා මධ්‍යම/නැගෙනහිර යුරෝපය සමඟ වාණිජමය සම්බන්ධය වැඩි කිරීමෙන් අපනයන නිෂ්පාදන ගණනාවක් සඳහා එහි දිගුකාලීන වර්ධන අපේක්ෂාවන් පිළිබඳව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සුබවාදී විය හැකිය.",
        "වසරකට ඩොලර් මිලියන 630 ක් ලෙස ඇස්තමේන්තු කර ඇති පෝලන්ත තේ වෙළඳපොළ ක්‍රමයෙන් වර්ධනය වෙමින් පවතී. යුරෝපීය කලාපයේ සිව්වන විශාලතම තේ වෙළඳපොල ලෙස (අයර්ලන්තය, එක්සත් රාජධානිය සහ රුසියාවට යාබදව), පෝලන්තයේ වාර්ෂික තේ ආනයනය ඩොලර් මිලියන 120 ක් වටිනා මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 31,000 ක් පමණ වේ. අගය එකතු කළ තේ සඳහා විශේෂිත වූ පෝලන්තය සිය නිෂ්පාදනවලින් වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් ඉන්දියාවෙන් සහ කෙන්යාවෙන් ආනයනය කරයි.",
        "පෘතුගාලයේ Jerónimo Martins සමූහයට අයත් Biedronka, 1995 සිට පෝලන්තයේ PLN බිලියන 14 කට වඩා වැඩි ආයෝජනයක් කර ඇත. රට පුරා වෙළඳසැල් 3,154 ක් සහිත සුපිරි වෙළඳසැල් ජාලය පෝලන්තයේ විශාලතම පුද්ගලික සේවා යෝජකයා වන අතර (ශ්‍රම බලකාය 70,000) සහ එහි නිෂ්පාදන ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් මූලාශ්‍ර කරයි. පෝලන්ත සැපයුම්කරුවන්.",
        "2021 ජාත්‍යන්තර පුණ්‍ය බසාර් හි ලංකා තේ ප්‍රදර්ශනය සහ විකිණීම (විකුණුම් ආදායම නම් කරන ලද පෝලන්ත පුණ්‍යායතනයකට යොමු කෙරේ)",
        "Wrocław Tea Festival \"Czaisz?\" හි 7 වන සංස්කරණයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා තේ ප්‍රදර්ශනය 2022"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පෝලන්තය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුචන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රංශ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්රොයික්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රංශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 22 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1996 සිට",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලේඩිබර්ඩ්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුචන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "109,699 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "754,641.12 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 පෙබරවාරි සහ ජූලි අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "31.60%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSR",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්‍රිඩ්‍රොන්කාගේ සිංහයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "REMSEY",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,154 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,100 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් ඩොලර් මිලියන 10 ක්",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අවසානයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 15 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අර්ල් ග්රේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 4 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුචන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50% පමණ",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඩකට ආසන්න",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෝර්සෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත එම්පයර් ටීස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Quest Ceylon Tea LLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mabroc Teas Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොවැම්බර් 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර පුණ්‍යායතනය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෝර්සෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇල්පිටිය වැවිලි පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්රැකෝව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LIVEE POLSKA Sp.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුචන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LIVEE POLSKA Sp",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොලෝන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුගා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධම්මිකා කුමාරි සේමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය අවුරුද්දේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජීවී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජීවී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෝර්සෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්රැකෝව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයා",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රංශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෙල්ජියම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉතාලිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෙදර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුචන් පෝලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුචන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හංගේරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුමේනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෘතුගාලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්‍යම/නැගෙනහිර යුරෝපීය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්‍යම/නැගෙනහිර යුරෝපය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 38 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 630 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතරවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "31 පමණ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 120 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙන්යාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජෙරොනිමෝ මාටින්ස් සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෘතුගාලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PLN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1995",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,154 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා තේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර පුණ්‍ය බසාර්",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wrocław තේ උත්සවය \"Czaisz",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சிலோன் தேயிலை போலந்தின் மிகப்பெரிய சில்லறை விற்பனைச் சங்கிலிகளில் தடம் அதிகரிக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "Auchan என்பது பிரான்சின் Croix ஐ தலைமையிடமாகக் கொண்ட ஒரு பிரெஞ்சு பன்னாட்டு சில்லறை வணிகக் குழுவாகும், மேலும் போலந்தில் 22 ஆண்டுகளுக்கும் மேலாக (1996 முதல்) வணிக நடவடிக்கைகளைத் தொடர்கிறது.",
        "ஒரு குறிப்பிடத்தக்க திருப்புமுனையாக, போலந்தின் மிகப்பெரிய சில்லறை வர்த்தக நிறுவனங்களான Biedronka (Ladybird) மற்றும் Auchan ஆகியவற்றிற்கு இலங்கை தேயிலையை விரிவுபடுத்துவதன் மூலம் போலந்து சில்லறை சந்தைக்கான இலங்கையின் தேயிலை ஏற்றுமதி 2022 முதல் அதிகரிக்கும்.",
        "பெப்ரவரி மற்றும் ஜூலை 2022 க்கு இடையில் புதிய இலங்கை ஏற்றுமதி பங்காளியிடமிருந்து 754,641.12 டாலர் மதிப்புள்ள 109,699 கிலோ சிலோன் தேயிலையை Biedronka ஏற்கனவே பெற்றுள்ளது. போலந்து சில்லறை விற்பனை சந்தையில் சிலோன் தேயிலை தடத்தை மேலும் விரிவுபடுத்துவதற்கு இது ஒரு முக்கியமான வாய்ப்பாகும். பெருமளவில் தேநீர் அருந்தும் போலந்து நுகர்வோர் மத்தியில் இலங்கையின் பிரீமியம் தேயிலைக்கான பாராட்டு. 2020 இல் போலந்திற்கான இலங்கையின் ஏற்றுமதியில் தேயிலை 31.60% ஆகும்.",
        "Biedronka அதன் தயாரிப்புகளை முக்கியமாக போலந்து சப்ளையர்களிடமிருந்து பெறுகிறது. எவ்வாறாயினும், சில்லறை விற்பனைச் சங்கிலியானது வெளிநாட்டு சப்ளையர்களிடமிருந்து உயர்தர நுகர்வோர் தயாரிப்புகளை அதன் கடைகளில் விற்பனை செய்வதற்கான வாய்ப்புகளை வழங்குகிறது. ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியத்தின் தரம்/தரநிலைகளுடன் இணங்குதல், தடையில்லா விநியோகம் மற்றும் CSR (கார்ப்பரேட் சமூகப் பொறுப்பு) சுயவிவரம், வெளிநாட்டு வாங்குபவர்களிடமிருந்து பொருட்களைப் பெறும்போது Biedronka க்கு அவசியம்.",
        "இலங்கையில் முழுமையாக உற்பத்தி செய்யப்படும் சிலோன் தேயிலையின் புதிய விநியோகங்கள், போலந்தில் உள்ள 1,100 நகரங்கள் மற்றும் நகரங்களில் உள்ள சில்லறை விற்பனையாளரின் 3,154 கடைகளில் Briedronka இன் லயன் லோகோ பிராண்டட் தனியார் லேபிள் \"REMSEY\" கீழ் விற்கப்படும். இந்த பல்பொருள் அங்காடி சங்கிலியில் மட்டும் சிலோன் தேயிலை விற்பனையானது, 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் இறுதிக்குள் குறைந்தபட்சம் $10 மில்லியனை எட்டும் என்றும், 2023ல் $15 மில்லியனாக அதிகரிக்கும் என்றும் மதிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது. தற்போது, ​​அதன் தனியார் லேபிள் சிலோன் டீயின் மதிப்பு, முதன்மை ஏர்ல் கிரே மற்றும் ப்ளாக் டீ ஆகியவை சுமார் $4 மில்லியன் ஆகும். புதிய இலங்கை ஏற்றுமதி பங்காளிகளின் நுழைவுடன், Biedronka மற்றும் Auchan இல் உள்ள சிலோன் தேயிலை அலமாரிகள் பிராந்திய வகைகள் உட்பட சுவை மற்றும் குளிர்ந்த தேயிலை மூலம் பன்முகப்படுத்தப்படும்.",
        "சில்லறை விற்பனை சங்கிலிகளால் தனியார் லேபிள் தேயிலைகளின் விற்பனை மொத்த போலந்து தேயிலை சந்தையில் சுமார் 50% என மதிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது, மேலும் வளர்ந்து வரும் சந்தை வாய்ப்புகள், நியாயமான செலவுகள் மற்றும் அதிக லாப வரம்புகள் ஆகியவற்றால் கணிசமாக வளர்ந்துள்ளது. Biedronka மட்டும், மிகப்பெரிய சில்லறை வணிகச் சங்கிலியாக, போலந்து FMCG சந்தையில் கிட்டத்தட்ட பாதியைக் கட்டுப்படுத்துகிறது. மேலும், ஆரோக்கியம் மற்றும் கரிம சந்தை வகைகள் தொடர்ந்து செழித்து வருவதால், முக்கிய சில்லறை விற்பனையாளர்கள் நிலையான மற்றும் ஆரோக்கியமான வாழ்க்கை முறைகளை ஈர்க்க தங்கள் தனியார் லேபிள் பிரீமியம் தேயிலை பிராண்டுகளை விரிவுபடுத்துகின்றனர்.",
        "வார்சாவில் உள்ள இலங்கை தூதரகம், தேயிலை மற்றும் சுற்றுலா ஊக்குவிப்பு நடவடிக்கைகளை ஒன்றிணைத்து, எம்பயர் டீஸ் லிமிடெட், குவெஸ்ட் சிலோன் டீ எல்எல்சி மற்றும் மப்ரோக் டீஸ் லிமிடெட் ஆகியவற்றால் தாராளமாக நன்கொடையாக வழங்கப்பட்ட பிரீமியம் சிலோன் தேயிலை வரிசையை நவம்பர் 2021 இன் சர்வதேச அறக்கட்டளை பஜாரில் காட்சிப்படுத்தியது. வார்சா. தேயிலை மற்றும் இலவங்கப்பட்டை பரிசுப் பொதிகளுடன் இலங்கை தூதரகத்தின் ஊக்குவிப்பு நிகழ்வுகளில் எல்பிட்டிய பிளான்டேஷன்ஸ் பிஎல்சியும் இணைந்து கொண்டது. தொண்டு நிகழ்வின் போது, ​​தூதரகம் கிராகோவை தளமாகக் கொண்ட FMCG நிறுவனமான LIVEE POLSKA Sp. உடன் கைகோர்த்து வெற்றி பெற்றது.",
        "LIVEE POLSKA Sp க்கான B2B சந்திப்புகளை இலங்கை தூதரகம் ஏற்பாடு செய்தது. ஜேர்மனியின் கொலோன் நகரில் அடையாளம் காணப்பட்ட இலங்கை தேயிலை நிறுவனங்களுடன், அனுகா 2021 உணவு வர்த்தக கண்காட்சியில் பங்குபற்றிய போது.",
        "சிலோன் தேயிலையின் அதிகரித்த மற்றும் நேரடி விநியோகத்தைப் பாதுகாப்பதற்காக கடந்த ஆண்டு Biedronka உடனான கலந்துரையாடல்கள் மற்றும் பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளில் LIVEE இல் இணையுமாறு தூதுவர் தம்மிக்க குமாரி சேமசிங்க அழைக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "சரியான தயாரிப்பு மற்றும் நீடித்த ஊக்குவிப்பு நடவடிக்கைகளுடன், 2023 ஆம் ஆண்டளவில் போலந்திற்கு சிலோன் தேயிலை மற்றும் பிற தயாரிப்புகளின் ஏற்றுமதியை இரட்டிப்பாக்குவது LIVEE இன் இலக்காகும். LIVEE அதன் புதிய பங்காளிகளிடமிருந்து நேரடியாக பெறப்படும் சிறிய அளவிலான சிலோன் தேயிலையுடன் உக்ரேனிய சந்தையையும் அணுகும்.",
        "உலர்ந்த பழங்கள், பதிவு செய்யப்பட்ட அன்னாசிப்பழங்கள், இரண்டு சில்லறை சங்கிலிகளுக்கான ஐஸ்கட் டீகள் மற்றும் வார்சா மற்றும் கிராகோவில் உள்ள ஆடம்பர தேயிலை வீடுகளுக்கு தங்க மற்றும் வெள்ளி டிப்ஸ் பிரீமியம் சிலோன் டீகள் போன்றவற்றை வழங்குவதற்கான விவாதங்கள் ஏற்கனவே நடந்து வருகின்றன. எதிர்வரும் மாதங்களில், இலங்கை மற்றும் போலந்து பங்காளிகளுக்கு இடையில் இந்த வர்த்தக வழிகள் முறைப்படுத்தப்படும்.",
        "போலந்து சில்லறை விற்பனை சந்தையில் சிலோன் தேயிலை வெற்றிகரமான நுழைவு, ஒரு முக்கியமான சந்தை பல்வகைப்படுத்தல் ஆகும், ஏனெனில் ஐரோப்பிய பிராந்தியத்தில் இலங்கையின் ஏற்றுமதி பங்காளிகள் முதன்மையாக பிரான்ஸ், ஜெர்மனி, பெல்ஜியம், இத்தாலி, நெதர்லாந்து மற்றும் இங்கிலாந்து. ஐரோப்பா முழுவதும் சில்லறை விற்பனைச் சங்கிலிகள்/சந்தைகள் இணைக்கப்பட்டு சீரமைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதால், மதிப்பு கூட்டப்பட்ட சிலோன் தேநீர் மற்றும் பிற பொருட்கள், உதாரணமாக, ஆச்சான் போலந்தில், ஹங்கேரி, ருமேனியா, போர்ச்சுகல் அல்லது ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியத்தில் உள்ள ஆச்சான் கடைகளில் வழங்கப்படும். தற்போது, ​​மத்திய/கிழக்கு ஐரோப்பிய சந்தைகள், இலங்கையால் தொடர்ந்து மோசமாகப் பயன்படுத்தப்படுகின்றன. எவ்வாறாயினும், 38 மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான மக்கள்தொகையைக் கொண்ட பிராந்தியத்தில் மிகப்பெரிய வளர்ந்து வரும் பொருளாதாரமான போலந்து ஊடாக மத்திய/கிழக்கு ஐரோப்பாவுடனான தனது வர்த்தக ஈடுபாட்டை அதிகரிப்பதன் மூலம் பல ஏற்றுமதிப் பொருட்களுக்கான நீண்டகால வளர்ச்சி வாய்ப்புகள் குறித்து இலங்கை நம்பிக்கையுடன் இருக்க முடியும்.",
        "போலந்து தேயிலை சந்தை, ஆண்டுக்கு $630 மில்லியன் மதிப்புடையதாக மதிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது, சீராக வளர்ந்து வருகிறது. ஐரோப்பிய பிராந்தியத்தில் நான்காவது பெரிய தேயிலை சந்தையாக (அயர்லாந்து, இங்கிலாந்து மற்றும் ரஷ்யாவிற்கு அடுத்தபடியாக), போலந்தின் வருடாந்திர தேயிலை இறக்குமதிகள் சுமார் 31,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்கள் மதிப்புள்ள $120 மில்லியன் ஆகும். மதிப்பு கூட்டப்பட்ட தேயிலைகளில் நிபுணத்துவம் பெற்ற போலந்து, முக்கியமாக இந்தியா மற்றும் கென்யாவிலிருந்து தனது தயாரிப்புகளில் பெரும்பகுதியை இறக்குமதி செய்கிறது.",
        "போர்ச்சுகலின் ஜெரோனிமோ மார்ட்டின்ஸ் குழுமத்திற்குச் சொந்தமான Biedronka, போலந்தில் 1995 முதல் PLN 14 பில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான முதலீடுகளைக் கொண்டுள்ளது. நாடு முழுவதும் 3,154 கடைகளைக் கொண்ட சூப்பர் மார்க்கெட் சங்கிலி, போலந்தின் மிகப்பெரிய தனியார் முதலாளியாக உள்ளது (70,000 பணியாளர்கள்) மற்றும் அதன் தயாரிப்புகளை முக்கியமாக ஆதாரமாகக் கொண்டுள்ளது. போலந்து சப்ளையர்கள்.",
        "சர்வதேச தொண்டு பஜார் 2021 இல் சிலோன் தேயிலை காட்சிப்படுத்தல் மற்றும் விற்பனை",
        "Wrocław Tea Festival \"Czaisz?\" 7வது பதிப்பில் இலங்கை தேநீர் காட்சி 2022"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "போலந்து",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆச்சான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரெஞ்சு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "குரோயிக்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரான்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "போலந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1996 முதல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "போலிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிலோன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "போலந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெண் பறவை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆச்சான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "109,699",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிலோன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "754,641.12",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிப்ரவரி மற்றும் ஜூலை 2022 க்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிலோன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "போலிஷ்",
