{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/පළාත්-කීපයකට-අදත්-ටික-ටික-වැසි/1-615394",
  "time_ut": 1656210406,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පළාත් කීපයකට අදත් ටික ටික වැසි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Showers in several parts of the country today",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Showers or thundershowers will occur at times in the Sabaragamuwa Province and in the Kandy, Nuwara Eliya, Galle and Matara districts today (26), the Met Department said.",
        "A spokesman for the department said that there will be several spells of showers in the Western and North Western provinces as well.",
        "He added that strong winds of up to 50 kmph are expected at times in the western slopes of the central hills, in the northern, north central and northwestern provinces and in the Trincomalee and Hambantota districts.",
        "The Department warns the public to take immediate action to reduce the risk of temporary strong winds and lightning along with thunder showers."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sabaragamuwa Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwara Eliya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Met Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "North Western",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "up to 50 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පළාත් කීපයකට අදත් ටික ටික වැසි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "සබරගමුව පළාතේත් මහනුවර, නුවරඑළිය, ගාල්ල සහ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් අද (26) විටින් විට වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇතිවන බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "බස්නාහිර සහ වයඹ පළාත්වලත් වැසි වාර කිහිපයක් ඇතිවන බව එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "මධ්‍යම කඳුකරයේ බටහිර බෑවුම් ප්‍රදේශවලත්, උතුරු, උතුරුමැද සහ වයඹ පළාත්වලත්, ත්‍රිකුණාමලය සහ හම්බන්තොට දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් විටින්විට පැයට කිලෝමීටර 50 ක පමණ වේගවත් සුළං ඇතිවිය හැකි බව ද ඔහු කීය.",
        "ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි සමඟ තාවකාලික තද සුළං සහ අකුණු අනතුරු ද ඇතිවිය හැකි බැවින් අනතුරු අවම කරගැනීමට ක්‍රියාකරන්නැයි එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව ජනතාවට දැනුම්දීමක් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුවරඑළිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 kmph දක්වා",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෙදපාර්තෙම්න්තුෙව්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாட்டின் பல பகுதிகளில் இன்று மழை பெய்யும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சப்ரகமுவ மாகாணத்திலும் கண்டி, நுவரெலியா, காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறை மாவட்டங்களிலும் இன்று (26) மழை அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை பெய்யும் என வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மேல் மற்றும் வடமேல் மாகாணங்களிலும் பல தடவைகள் மழை பெய்யும் என திணைக்களத்தின் பேச்சாளர் ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மத்திய மலைநாட்டின் மேற்கு சரிவுகளிலும், வடக்கு, வடமத்திய மற்றும் வடமேற்கு மாகாணங்களிலும் திருகோணமலை மற்றும் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை மாவட்டங்களிலும் அவ்வப்போது மணித்தியாலத்துக்கு 50 கிலோ மீற்றர் வேகத்தில் பலத்த காற்று வீசக்கூடும் என அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இடியுடன் கூடிய மழையுடன் கூடிய தற்காலிக பலத்த காற்று மற்றும் மின்னல் அபாயத்தைக் குறைக்க உடனடியாக நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு திணைக்களம் பொதுமக்களை எச்சரிக்கிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுவரெலியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வானிலை துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட மேற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 50 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}