{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/නයි-අල්ලන්නා-නාග-ප්‍රහාරයකින්-මරුට/11-396631",
  "time_ut": 1661511553,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "නයි අල්ලන්නා නාග ප්‍රහාරයකින් මරුට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Knife catcher killed by cobra attack",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Ambalangoda police say that yesterday (25th), a knife catcher who carried the captured knife in the forest and put it on display died in a knife attack.",
        "The police say that a father of four named Sudath Kumara, a resident of Ambalangoda Akurala, has died.",
        "The villagers said that the dead man had caught a Naya who had come to a house in Akurala and while holding the naya on his shoulders, he was being attacked while holding the naya by both hands and pulling him to and fro.",
        "Police say that the person who was attacked by Nai was first transferred to Balapitiya Hospital and then to Karapitiya Hospital and he died while receiving treatment at Karapitiya Hospital for four days.",
        "Locals say that the person who died from snake venom had caught many snakes and released them into the wild."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "25th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sudath Kumara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambalangoda Akurala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Naya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Akurala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nai",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Balapitiya Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karapitiya Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karapitiya Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "four days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නයි අල්ලන්නා නාග ප්‍රහාරයකින් මරුට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අල්ලාගත් නයා වනයට මුදා නොහැර කරේ දමාගෙන දර්ශනය දැමූ නයි අල්ලන්නෙක් නයි ප්‍රහාරයකින් ඊයේ (25දා) මියගොස් ඇති බව අම්බලන්ගොඩ පොලීසිය කියයි.",
        "මෙසේ මිය ගොස් ඇත්තේ අම්බලන්ගොඩ අකුරල පදිංචි සුදත් කුමාර නමැති සිව් දරු පියෙක් බවද පොලීසිය කියයි.",
        "අකුරළ නිවසකට පැමිණි නයෙක් මිය ගිය තැනැත්තා විසින් අල්ලා ගෙන ඇති අතර අල්ලාගත් නයා කරේ දමාගෙන කරේ සිටියදීම අත් දෙකෙන් නයාගේ දෙකොනෙ න් අල්ලාගෙන  එහේට මෙහේට අදිමින් සිටියදී නයි පහාරයට ලක්වූ බව පදේශවාසීහු කියති.",
        "නයි පහාරයට ලක්වූ තැනැත්තා පළමුව බලපිටිය රෝහලටත් ඉන් අනතුරුව කරාපිටිය රෝහලට මාරුකර යවා ඇති බවත් කරාපිටිය රෝහලේ සිව් දිනක් පතිකාර ලබමින් සිටියදී ඔහු මිය ගිය බවත් පොලීසිය කියයි.",
        "නයි විසෙන් මිය ගියතැනැත්තා මීට පෙර නයි රැසක් අල්ලා වනයට මුදා හැර ඇති බව පදේශවාසීහු කියති."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "25 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුදත් කුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්බලන්ගොඩ අකුරල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නායා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අකුරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලපිටිය රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කරාපිටිය රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කරාපිටිය රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாகப்பாம்பு தாக்கியதில் கத்தி பிடிப்பவன் பலி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிடிபட்ட கத்தியை காட்டுக்குள் கொண்டு சென்று காட்சிக்கு வைத்த கத்தி பிடிப்பவர் நேற்று (25) கத்திக்குத்து தாக்குதலில் உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக அம்பலாங்கொடை பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "அம்பலாங்கொட அக்குரல பிரதேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்த சுதத் குமார என்ற நான்கு பிள்ளைகளின் தந்தையே இவ்வாறு உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "அக்குறலயிலுள்ள வீடொன்றுக்கு வந்த நாயா ஒருவரை இறந்தவர் பிடித்து தோளில் தாங்கிய வேளையில் நாயாரை இரு கைகளாலும் பிடித்து அங்கும் இங்கும் இழுத்து தாக்கியதாக கிராம மக்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "நயினால் தாக்கப்பட்ட நபர் முதலில் பலப்பிட்டி வைத்தியசாலைக்கு மாற்றப்பட்டு பின்னர் கராப்பிட்டிய வைத்தியசாலைக்கு மாற்றப்பட்டு நான்கு நாட்களாக கராப்பிட்டிய வைத்தியசாலையில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வந்த நிலையில் உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "பாம்பு விஷத்தால் உயிரிழந்த நபர் பல பாம்புகளை பிடித்து காட்டுக்குள் விட்டதாக அப்பகுதி மக்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "25 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதத் குமார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பலாங்கொட அக்குரல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அகுரலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பலபிட்டிய வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கராபிட்டிய வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கராபிட்டிய வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}