{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/top_story/IMF-tells-Sri-Lanka-to-work-expeditiously-to-gain-debt-relief-from-creditors/155-244165",
  "time_ut": 1662061037,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "IMF tells Sri Lanka to work “expeditiously” to gain debt relief from creditors",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "IMF tells Sri Lanka to work “expeditiously” to gain debt relief from creditors",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "IMF mission chief for Sri Lanka Masahiro Nozaki (left) and senior mission chief Peter Breuer addressing the media at the Central Bank premises yesterday. Pic by Kithsiri de Mel",
        "Says disbursement of any IMF funding contingent upon reaching a deal with creditors and setting the reform process in motion",
        "SL enters staff-level agreement with IMF fora potential 48-month US$ 2.9 billion Extended Fund Facility (EFF)",
        "“The staff-level agreement is only the beginning of a long road ahead for Sri Lanka to emerge from the crisis”- IMF senior mission chief",
        "Says if creditors failed to provide relief it will deepen SL’s crisis and undermine its repayment capacity even further",
        "The International Monetary Fund (IMF) yesterday said Sri Lanka should move forward “expeditiously” to secure debt relief from its creditors to ensure debt sustainability as disbursement of any IMF financing is contingent upon that and the reforms carried out by the authorities to restore macroeconomic stability.",
        "Sri Lanka yesterday entered a staff-level deal with the IMF for a potential 48-month US$ 2.9 billion Extended Fund Facility (EFF), subject to the approval of the IMF management and the executive board.",
        "“The staff-level agreement is only the beginning of a long road ahead for Sri Lanka to emerge from the crisis,” IMF senior mission chief for Sri Lanka, Peter Breuer told reporters in Colombo.",
        "He said Sri Lankan authorities have already begun the reform process, and stressed on the need to continue on that path with the support of all segments of the society.",
        "In tandem with the reform process, Breuer also said the debt restructuring negotiations with Sri Lanka’s creditors—both official and private—should get underway immediately with the support of the legal and financial advisors appointed by the authorities.",
        "“Once these financing assurances (from creditors) are secured, then we can move to a disbursing arrangement that can be considered by the executive board, and then ultimately disburse,” he said.",
        "If creditors failed to provide these assurances, Breuer said it will deepen Sri Lanka’s crisis and undermine its repayment capacity as the resources available at the country’s disposal to repay will further diminish.",
        "“So, it is actually in the interest of all creditors to collaborate with Sri Lanka, so that Sri Lanka could emerge from this crisis as quickly as possible and regain its repayment capacity and service its debt,” he pointed out.",
        "Sri Lanka’s debt situation is a unique one, as much of its debt is outside the Paris Club creditors. Sri Lanka owes large sums of moneys to India and China, who are not Paris Club members. While India has signaled its liking to provide Sri Lanka with debt relief, China’s position to this day remains unclear.",
        "At Sri Lanka’s request, Japan has come forward to organise a Sri Lanka creditors’ conference to help the island nation emerge from the worst economic crisis since its independence. But, it is not clear whether China would join this conference.",
        "Meanwhile, the reform programme Sri Lankan authorities have come up with and supported by the IMF includes fiscal consolidation via major tax reforms, cost-recovery based pricing for fuel and electricity, implementation of targeted safety nets for the vulnerable, data driven-monetary policy, and a flexible exchange rate. The policy package also undertakes to assure Central Bank’s autonomy and reduce corruption vulnerabilities."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peter Breuer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kithsiri de Mel",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$ 2.9 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "The International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$ 2.9 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peter Breuer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Breuer",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Breuer",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paris Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paris Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ණය හිමියන්ගෙන් ණය සහන ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා \"ඉක්මන්\" වැඩ කරන ලෙස IMF ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට කියයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා IMF දූත මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානී Masahiro Nozaki (වමේ) සහ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ දූත මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානී Peter Breuer ඊයේ මහ බැංකු පරිශ්‍රයේදී මාධ්‍ය අමතමින්. ඡායාරූපය කිත්සිරි ද මෙල්",
        "ණය හිමියන් සමඟ ගනුදෙනුවකට එළඹීමෙන් සහ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ ක්‍රියාවලිය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමෙන් පසු ඕනෑම IMF අරමුදල් කණ්ඩායමක් බෙදා හැරීම පවසයි",
        "මාස 48 ක විභව US$ 2.9 බිලියන විස්තීරණ අරමුදල් පහසුකම (EFF) සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා IMF සමඟ කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමකට එළැඹේ.",
        "\"මාණ්ඩලික මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුම ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩ ඒමට ඉදිරි දිගු මාවතක ආරම්භය පමණි\" - IMF ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ දූත මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානියා",
        "ණයහිමියන් සහන සැලසීමට අපොහොසත් වුවහොත් එය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අර්බුදය ගැඹුරු කරන අතර එහි ආපසු ගෙවීමේ හැකියාව තවත් අඩාල කරනු ඇතැයි පවසයි.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) ඊයේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ඕනෑම IMF මූල්‍යකරණයක් ලබා දීම සහ සාර්ව ආර්ථික ස්ථාවරත්වය යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් කිරීම සඳහා බලධාරීන් විසින් ගෙන යන ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ අඛණ්ඩව සිදුවන බැවින් ණය තිරසාර බව සහතික කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය ණය හිමියන්ගෙන් ණය සහන ලබා ගැනීමට “ඉක්මන්” ඉදිරියට යා යුතු බවයි. .",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ කළමනාකාරිත්වයේ සහ විධායක මණ්ඩලයේ අනුමැතියට යටත්ව, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඊයේ IMF සමඟ ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9ක විභව විස්තීරණ අරමුදල් පහසුකමක් (EFF) සඳහා කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගනුදෙනුවකට එළඹ ඇත.",
        "\"කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුම ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩ ඒම සඳහා ඉදිරි දිගු මාවතක ආරම්භය පමනි,\" ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා IMF ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ දූත මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානී පීටර් බෲවර් කොළඹදී වාර්තාකරුවන්ට පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලධාරීන් ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ ක්‍රියාවලිය දැනටමත් ආරම්භ කර ඇති බව පැවසූ ඔහු, සමාජයේ සියලුම කොටස්වල සහයෝගය ඇතිව එම මාර්ගයේ ඉදිරියට යාමේ අවශ්‍යතාව අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ ක්‍රියාවලියට සමගාමීව, නිල සහ පෞද්ගලික යන දෙඅංශයෙන්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය හිමියන් සමඟ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ සාකච්ඡා බලධාරීන් විසින් පත් කරන ලද නීතිමය සහ මූල්‍ය උපදේශකයින්ගේ සහාය ඇතිව වහාම ක්‍රියාත්මක විය යුතු බව Breuer පැවසීය.",
        "\"මෙම මූල්‍ය සහතික (ණය හිමියන්ගෙන්) සුරක්ෂිත වූ පසු, අපට විධායක මණ්ඩලය විසින් සලකා බැලිය හැකි බෙදා හැරීමේ විධිවිධානයකට යා හැකි අතර අවසානයේ දී බෙදා හරිනු ලැබේ,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ණයහිමියන් මෙම සහතික ලබා දීමට අපොහොසත් වුවහොත්, එය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අර්බුදය ගැඹුරු කරන බවත්, ආපසු ගෙවීමට රට සතුව ඇති සම්පත් තවදුරටත් අඩු වන බැවින් එහි ආපසු ගෙවීමේ හැකියාව අඩපණ කරන බවත් බෲයර් පැවසීය.",
        "“එබැවින්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හැකි ඉක්මනින් මෙම අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩ ඒමට සහ ආපසු ගෙවීමේ හැකියාව නැවත ලබා ගැනීමට සහ එහි ණය ගෙවීමට හැකි වන පරිදි, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ සහයෝගයෙන් කටයුතු කිරීම සියලුම ණය හිමියන්ගේ අවශ්‍යතාවයයි,” ඔහු පෙන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය තත්ත්වය අද්විතීය එකක් වන අතර, එහි ණය වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් පැරිස් ක්ලබ් ණය හිමියන්ගෙන් පිටත පවතී. පැරිස් සමාජයේ සාමාජිකයන් නොවන ඉන්දියාවට සහ චීනයට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව විශාල මුදලක් ණයයි. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ණය සහන ලබාදීමට ඉන්දියාව කැමැත්ත පළ කර ඇතත්, අද දක්වා චීනයේ ස්ථාවරය අපැහැදිලි ය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉල්ලීම පරිදි, ජපානය නිදහසින් පසු දිවයිනේ දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩ ඒමට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා ණය හිමියන්ගේ සමුළුවක් සංවිධානය කිරීමට ඉදිරිපත් වී ඇත. එහෙත් චීනය මෙම සමුළුවට එක්වන්නේද යන්න පැහැදිලි නැත.",
        "මේ අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලධාරීන් IMF විසින් ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති සහ සහාය දක්වන ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ වැඩසටහනට ප්‍රධාන බදු ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ හරහා මූල්‍ය ඒකාග්‍රතාවය, ඉන්ධන සහ විදුලිය සඳහා පිරිවැය-ප්‍රතිසාධනය පදනම් කරගත් මිලකරණය, අවදානමට ලක්විය හැකි, දත්ත මත පදනම් වූ මුදල් ප්‍රතිපත්තිය සඳහා ඉලක්කගත ආරක්ෂක දැල් ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම ඇතුළත් වේ. සහ නම්‍යශීලී විනිමය අනුපාතයක්. මෙම ප්‍රතිපත්ති පැකේජය මහ බැංකුවේ ස්වාධීනත්වය සහතික කිරීම සහ දූෂණ අවදානම් අවම කිරීම සඳහා ද භාර ගනී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීටර් බෲවර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිත්සිරි ද මෙල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීටර් බෲවර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බෲයර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "බෲයර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැරිස් සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැරිස් සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුවේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கடனாளிகளிடமிருந்து கடன் நிவாரணம் பெறுவதற்கு \"விரைவாக\" வேலை செய்யுமாறு IMF இலங்கையிடம் கூறுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கைக்கான சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பணித் தலைவர் மசாஹிரோ நோசாகி (இடது) மற்றும் சிரேஷ்ட தூதரகத் தலைவர் பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர் ஆகியோர் நேற்று மத்திய வங்கி வளாகத்தில் ஊடகவியலாளர்களிடம் உரையாற்றினர். படம் கித்சிறி டி மெல்",
        "கடனளிப்பவர்களுடன் ஒரு ஒப்பந்தத்தை எட்டியதும், சீர்திருத்த செயல்முறையை இயக்கத்தில் அமைத்ததும், எந்தவொரு IMF நிதியுதவி குழுவையும் வழங்குவதாகக் கூறுகிறது.",
        "48 மாத US$ 2.9 பில்லியன் விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட நிதி வசதி (EFF) க்கு IMF உடன் பணியாளர்கள் அளவிலான ஒப்பந்தத்தில் SL நுழைகிறது",
        "\"சிறிலங்கா நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து மீள்வதற்கான நீண்ட பாதையின் ஆரம்பம் மட்டுமே பணியாளர் மட்ட ஒப்பந்தம்\" - IMF மூத்த பணித் தலைவர்",
        "கடன் வழங்குபவர்கள் நிவாரணம் வழங்கத் தவறினால், அது இலங்கையின் நெருக்கடியை ஆழமாக்கி அதன் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தும் திறனை மேலும் குறைமதிப்பிற்கு உட்படுத்தும் என்கிறார்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் (IMF) நேற்று இலங்கை தனது கடனாளிகளிடமிருந்து கடன் நிவாரணத்தைப் பெறுவதற்கு \"விரைவாக\" முன்னேற வேண்டும் என்று கூறியது, எந்தவொரு சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் நிதியுதவியையும் வழங்குவது மற்றும் மேக்ரோ பொருளாதார ஸ்திரத்தன்மையை மீட்டெடுப்பதற்காக அதிகாரிகளால் மேற்கொள்ளப்படும் சீர்திருத்தங்கள் தொடர்ந்து கடனை நிலைநிறுத்துவதை உறுதி செய்ய வேண்டும். .",
        "IMF நிர்வாகம் மற்றும் நிர்வாகக் குழுவின் ஒப்புதலுக்கு உட்பட்டு, 48 மாத US$ 2.9 பில்லியன் விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட நிதி வசதிக்கான (EFF) பணியாளர்கள் அளவிலான ஒப்பந்தத்தை இலங்கை நேற்று IMF உடன் மேற்கொண்டது.",
        "\"பணியாளர்கள் மட்ட ஒப்பந்தமானது, நெருக்கடியில் இருந்து இலங்கை மீள்வதற்கான நீண்ட பாதையின் ஆரம்பம் மட்டுமே\" என்று இலங்கைக்கான சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் மூத்த பணித் தலைவர் பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர் கொழும்பில் செய்தியாளர்களிடம் கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கை அதிகாரிகள் சீர்திருத்த நடவடிக்கைகளை ஏற்கனவே ஆரம்பித்துவிட்டதாகத் தெரிவித்த அவர், சமூகத்தின் அனைத்துப் பிரிவினரின் ஆதரவுடன் அந்தப் பாதையில் தொடர வேண்டியதன் அவசியத்தையும் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "சீர்திருத்த செயல்முறையுடன் இணைந்து, அதிகாரிகளால் நியமிக்கப்பட்ட சட்ட மற்றும் நிதி ஆலோசகர்களின் ஆதரவுடன், உத்தியோகபூர்வ மற்றும் தனியார் ஆகிய இரண்டும் இலங்கையின் கடனாளிகளுடன் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு பேச்சுவார்த்தைகள் உடனடியாக மேற்கொள்ளப்பட வேண்டும் என்றும் ப்ரூயர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"இந்த நிதியுதவி உத்தரவாதங்கள் (கடன் வழங்குநர்களிடமிருந்து) பாதுகாக்கப்பட்டவுடன், நிர்வாகக் குழுவால் பரிசீலிக்கப்படும் ஒரு விநியோக ஏற்பாட்டிற்கு நாம் செல்லலாம், பின்னர் இறுதியில் வழங்கலாம்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "கடன் வழங்குபவர்கள் இந்த உறுதிமொழிகளை வழங்கத் தவறினால், அது இலங்கையின் நெருக்கடியை ஆழமாக்கும் மற்றும் திருப்பிச் செலுத்துவதற்கு நாட்டின் வசம் உள்ள வளங்கள் மேலும் குறைவடையும் என்பதால் அதன் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தும் திறனைக் குறைமதிப்பிற்கு உட்படுத்தும் என்று ப்ரூயர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"எனவே, இலங்கையுடன் ஒத்துழைப்பது உண்மையில் அனைத்து கடன் வழங்குநர்களின் நலனுக்காகவும் உள்ளது, இதன்மூலம் இலங்கை இந்த நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து விரைவாக மீள்வதற்கும் அதன் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தும் திறனை மீட்டெடுப்பதற்கும் அதன் கடனைச் செலுத்துவதற்கும்\" என்று அவர் சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் கடன் நிலைமை ஒரு தனித்துவமான ஒன்றாகும், ஏனெனில் அதன் கடனில் பெரும்பகுதி பரிஸ் கிளப் கடனாளர்களுக்கு வெளியே உள்ளது. பாரிஸ் கிளப் உறுப்பினர்களாக இல்லாத இந்தியா மற்றும் சீனாவுக்கு இலங்கை பெரும் தொகையை செலுத்த வேண்டியுள்ளது. இலங்கைக்கு கடன் நிவாரணம் வழங்குவதற்கு இந்தியா விருப்பம் தெரிவித்தாலும், சீனாவின் நிலைப்பாடு இன்றுவரை தெளிவற்றதாகவே உள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையின் வேண்டுகோளுக்கு இணங்க, தீவு நாடு சுதந்திரம் அடைந்த பின்னர் ஏற்பட்ட மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து மீள்வதற்கு உதவுவதற்காக இலங்கை கடனாளர் மாநாட்டை ஏற்பாடு செய்ய ஜப்பான் முன்வந்துள்ளது. ஆனால், இந்த மாநாட்டில் சீனா சேருமா என்பது தெரியவில்லை.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், இலங்கை அதிகாரிகள் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தால் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட மற்றும் ஆதரவளிக்கும் சீர்திருத்த திட்டத்தில் முக்கிய வரி சீர்திருத்தங்கள், எரிபொருள் மற்றும் மின்சாரத்திற்கான செலவு-மீட்பு அடிப்படையிலான விலை, பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடிய, தரவு உந்துதல்-பணவியல் கொள்கை, இலக்கு பாதுகாப்பு வலைகளை செயல்படுத்துதல் ஆகியவற்றின் மூலம் நிதி ஒருங்கிணைப்பு அடங்கும். மற்றும் ஒரு நெகிழ்வான மாற்று விகிதம். இந்தக் கொள்கைப் பொதியானது மத்திய வங்கியின் சுயாட்சியை உறுதிப்படுத்துவதற்கும் ஊழல் பாதிப்புகளைக் குறைப்பதற்கும் உறுதியளிக்கிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கித்சிறி டி மெல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க டாலர் 2.9 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க டாலர் 2.9 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ப்ரூயர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ப்ரூயர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ் கிளப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ் கிளப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கியின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}