{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/03/india-now-world-s-fifth-largest-economy-overtakes-uk/",
  "time_ut": 1662200280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "India Now World’s Fifth Largest Economy, Overtakes UK",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "India Now World’s Fifth Largest Economy, Overtakes UK",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "(NDTV); Britain has dropped behind India to become the world's sixth largest economy, delivering a further blow to the government in London as it grapples with a brutal cost-of-living shock.",
        "India leaped past the UK in the final three months of 2021 to become the fifth-biggest economy. The calculation is based in US dollars, and India extended its lead in the first quarter, according to GDP figures from the International Monetary Fund.",
        "The UK's decline down the international rankings is an unwelcome backdrop for the new prime minister. Conservative Party members choose Boris Johnson's successor on Monday, with Foreign Secretary Liz Truss expected to beat former Chancellor of the Exchequer Rishi Sunak in the run-off.",
        "The winner will take over a nation facing the fastest inflation in four decades and rising risks of a recession that the Bank of England says may last well into 2024.",
        "By contrast, the Indian economy is forecast to grow more than 7% this year. A world-beating rebound in Indian stocks this quarter has just seen their weighting rise to the second spot in the MSCI Emerging Markets Index, trailing only China's.",
        "On an adjusted basis and using the dollar exchange rate on the last day of the relevant quarter, the size of the Indian economy in \"nominal\" cash terms in the quarter through March was $854.7 billion. On the same basis, UK was $816 billion.",
        "The calculations were done using the IMF database and historic exchange rates on the Bloomberg terminal.",
        "The UK is likely to have fallen further since. UK GDP grew just 1% in cash terms in the second quarter and, after adjusting for inflation, shrank 0.1%. Sterling has also underperformed the dollar relative to the rupee, with the pound falling 8% against the Indian currency this year.",
        "The IMF's own forecasts show India overtaking the UK in dollar terms on an annual basis this year, putting the Asian powerhouse behind just the US, China, Japan and Germany. A decade ago, India ranked 11th among the largest economies, while the UK was 5th",
        "Positive response from International community over IMF mission statement on SL"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Fifth Largest Economy",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Overtakes",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "UK",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "NDTV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Britain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "sixth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "London",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the final three months of 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "fifth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first quarter",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Conservative Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boris Johnson's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liz Truss",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rishi Sunak",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bank of England",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 7%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "this quarter",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the MSCI Emerging Markets Index",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the last day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the relevant quarter",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the quarter through March",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$854.7 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$816 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bloomberg",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "just 1%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the second quarter",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.1%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "8%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "A decade ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියාව දැන් ලෝකයේ පස්වන විශාලතම ආර්ථිකය, එක්සත් රාජධානිය අභිබවා යයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "(NDTV); ම්ලේච්ඡ ජීවන වියදම් කම්පනය සමඟ පොරබදමින් සිටින ලන්ඩනයේ ආන්ඩුවට තවත් පහරක් දෙමින් බ්‍රිතාන්‍යය ලෝකයේ හයවන විශාලතම ආර්ථිකය බවට පත්වීමට ඉන්දියාවට පිටුපසින් වැටී ඇත.",
        "2021 අවසන් මාස තුනේදී ඉන්දියාව එක්සත් රාජධානිය පසුකර පස්වන විශාලතම ආර්ථිකය බවට පත් විය. මෙම ගණනය පදනම් වී ඇත්තේ එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලර් වලින් වන අතර, ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ දළ දේශීය නිෂ්පාදිතයේ සංඛ්‍යාලේඛනවලට අනුව ඉන්දියාව පළමු කාර්තුවේදී එහි ඉදිරියෙන් සිටියේය.",
        "එක්සත් රාජධානිය ජාත්‍යන්තර ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම් පහත වැටීම නව අගමැතිට අකමැති පසුබිමකි. කොන්සර්වේටිව් පක්ෂ සාමාජිකයින් සඳුදා බොරිස් ජොන්සන්ගේ අනුප්‍රාප්තිකයා තෝරා ගන්නා අතර, විදේශ ලේකම් ලිස් ට්‍රස්, හිටපු චාන්සලර් රිෂි සුනැක් පරාජය කරනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "ජයග්‍රාහකයා දශක හතරක් තුළ වේගවත්ම උද්ධමනයට මුහුණ දෙන ජාතියක් සහ 2024 දක්වා පැවතිය හැකි බව එංගලන්ත බැංකුව පවසන පරිදි අවපාතයක ඉහළ යාමේ අවදානම භාර ගනී.",
        "ඊට වෙනස්ව, ඉන්දීය ආර්ථිකය මේ වසරේ 7%කට වඩා වැඩි වර්ධනයක් අපේක්ෂා කරයි. මෙම කාර්තුවේ ඉන්දියානු කොටස්වල ලෝක ප්‍රබෝධමත් ප්‍රබෝධයක් MSCI නැගී එන වෙළඳපල දර්ශකයේ දෙවන ස්ථානය දක්වා ඔවුන්ගේ බර වැඩිවීම චීනයට පමණක් පසුපසින් ගොස් තිබේ.",
        "ගැලපුම් පදනමක් මත සහ අදාළ කාර්තුවේ අවසාන දිනයේ ඩොලර් විනිමය අනුපාතිකය භාවිතා කරමින්, මාර්තු සිට කාර්තුව තුළ ඉන්දියානු ආර්ථිකයේ \"නාමික\" මුදල් ප්‍රමාණය ඩොලර් බිලියන 854.7 කි. එම පදනම මත එක්සත් රාජධානිය ඩොලර් බිලියන 816 ක් විය.",
        "IMF දත්ත සමුදාය සහ Bloomberg පර්යන්තයේ ඓතිහාසික විනිමය අනුපාත භාවිතා කරමින් ගණනය කිරීම් සිදු කරන ලදී.",
        "එතැන් සිට එක්සත් රාජධානිය තවදුරටත් පහත වැටීමට ඉඩ ඇත. දෙවන කාර්තුවේදී එක්සත් රාජධානියේ දළ දේශීය නිෂ්පාදිතය මුදල්මය වශයෙන් 1% කින් පමණක් වර්ධනය වූ අතර උද්ධමනය සඳහා ගැලපීමෙන් පසු 0.1% හැකිලී ගියේය. මේ වසරේ ඉන්දීය මුදලට සාපේක්ෂව පවුම 8% කින් පහත වැටීමත් සමඟ ස්ටර්ලින් ද රුපියලට සාපේක්ෂව ඩොලරයේ ක්‍රියාකාරීත්වය අඩු කර ඇත.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ පුරෝකථනයන් පෙන්නුම් කරන්නේ, ඉන්දියාව මේ වසරේ වාර්ෂික පදනමින් ඩොලර් අනුව එක්සත් රාජධානිය අභිබවා යමින්, ආසියානු බලාගාරය එක්සත් ජනපදය, චීනය, ජපානය සහ ජර්මනිය පිටුපසින් තබමිනි. දශකයකට පෙර ඉන්දියාව විශාලතම ආර්ථිකයන් අතර 11 වන ස්ථානයට පත් වූ අතර එක්සත් රාජධානිය 5 වන ස්ථානයට පත්විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පිළිබඳ IMF මෙහෙවර ප්‍රකාශය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාවෙන් ධනාත්මක ප්‍රතිචාරයක්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "පස්වන විශාලතම ආර්ථිකය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අභිබවා යයි",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "NDTV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය වන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලන්ඩන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 අවසාන මාස තුන",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පස්වන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමු කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොන්සර්වේටිව් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරිස් ජොන්සන්ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිස් ට්‍රස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිෂි සුනක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දශක හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එංගලන්තයේ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "7% ට වඩා",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MSCI නැගී එන වෙළඳපල දර්ශකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවසාන දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අදාළ කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු සිට කාර්තුව දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 854.7 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 816 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්ලූම්බර්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හුදෙක් 1%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවන කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.1%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "8%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දශකයකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்தியா இப்போது உலகின் ஐந்தாவது பெரிய பொருளாதாரம், இங்கிலாந்தை முந்தியுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "(என்டிடிவி); உலகின் ஆறாவது பெரிய பொருளாதாரமாக ஆவதற்கு இந்தியாவுக்குப் பின்னால் பிரிட்டன் பின்தங்கியுள்ளது, இது லண்டனில் உள்ள அரசாங்கத்திற்கு மேலும் ஒரு அடியை வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "2021 இன் இறுதி மூன்று மாதங்களில் இந்தியா இங்கிலாந்தைக் கடந்து ஐந்தாவது பெரிய பொருளாதாரமாக மாறியது. இந்த கணக்கீடு அமெரிக்க டாலர்களை அடிப்படையாகக் கொண்டது மற்றும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் மொத்த உள்நாட்டு உற்பத்தியின் புள்ளிவிவரங்களின்படி, முதல் காலாண்டில் இந்தியா அதன் முன்னிலையை நீட்டித்தது.",
        "சர்வதேச தரவரிசையில் இங்கிலாந்து வீழ்ச்சியடைந்தது புதிய பிரதமருக்கு விரும்பத்தகாத பின்னணியாகும். கன்சர்வேடிவ் கட்சி உறுப்பினர்கள் திங்களன்று போரிஸ் ஜான்சனின் வாரிசைத் தேர்வு செய்கிறார்கள், வெளியுறவு செயலாளர் லிஸ் ட்ரஸ், ரன்-ஆஃப்-ல் முன்னாள் அதிபர் ரிஷி சுனக்கை தோற்கடிப்பார் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "நான்கு தசாப்தங்களில் வேகமான பணவீக்கத்தை எதிர்கொள்ளும் மற்றும் 2024 ஆம் ஆண்டு வரை நீடிக்கும் என்று பாங்க் ஆஃப் இங்கிலாந்து கூறும் மந்தநிலையின் அபாயங்களை எதிர்கொள்ளும் ஒரு நாட்டை வெற்றியாளர் கைப்பற்றுவார்.",
        "மாறாக, இந்த ஆண்டு இந்தியப் பொருளாதாரம் 7%க்கும் அதிகமாக வளரும் என்று கணிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. இந்த காலாண்டில் இந்தியப் பங்குகளில் உலக அளவில் பின்னடைவு ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதால், MSCI வளர்ந்து வரும் சந்தைகள் குறியீட்டில், சீனாவை மட்டும் பின்னுக்குத் தள்ளி, அதன் எடை இரண்டாவது இடத்திற்கு உயர்ந்துள்ளது.",
        "சரிசெய்யப்பட்ட அடிப்படையில் மற்றும் தொடர்புடைய காலாண்டின் கடைசி நாளில் டாலர் மாற்று விகிதத்தைப் பயன்படுத்தி, மார்ச் வரையிலான காலாண்டில் இந்தியப் பொருளாதாரத்தின் அளவு \"பெயரளவு\" பண அடிப்படையில் $854.7 பில்லியன் ஆகும். அதே அடிப்படையில், இங்கிலாந்து $816 பில்லியன் ஆகும்.",
        "புளூம்பெர்க் முனையத்தில் IMF தரவுத்தளம் மற்றும் வரலாற்று மாற்று விகிதங்களைப் பயன்படுத்தி கணக்கீடுகள் செய்யப்பட்டன.",
        "இங்கிலாந்து மேலும் வீழ்ச்சியடைய வாய்ப்புள்ளது. UK GDP இரண்டாவது காலாண்டில் பண அடிப்படையில் வெறும் 1% மட்டுமே வளர்ந்தது மற்றும் பணவீக்கத்தை சரிசெய்த பிறகு, 0.1% சுருங்கியது. இந்த ஆண்டு இந்திய நாணயத்திற்கு எதிராக பவுண்டு 8% வீழ்ச்சியடைந்ததன் மூலம், ஸ்டெர்லிங் ரூபாயுடன் ஒப்பிடுகையில் டாலரின் மதிப்பை குறைத்துள்ளது.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் சொந்த கணிப்புகள், இந்தியா இந்த ஆண்டு டாலர் மதிப்பில் இங்கிலாந்தை முந்தியதைக் காட்டுகின்றன, இது ஆசிய அதிகார மையத்தை அமெரிக்கா, சீனா, ஜப்பான் மற்றும் ஜேர்மனிக்கு பின்னால் நிறுத்துகிறது. ஒரு தசாப்தத்திற்கு முன்பு, இந்தியா மிகப்பெரிய பொருளாதாரங்களில் 11 வது இடத்தில் இருந்தது, அதே நேரத்தில் இங்கிலாந்து 5 வது இடத்தில் இருந்தது",
        "SL பற்றிய IMF பணி அறிக்கைக்கு சர்வதேச சமூகத்தின் நேர்மறையான பதில்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஐந்தாவது பெரிய பொருளாதாரம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "முந்துகிறது",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "யுகே",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "என்டிடிவி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லண்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 இன் கடைசி மூன்று மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்தாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதல் காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கன்சர்வேடிவ் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "போரிஸ் ஜான்சனின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிஸ் டிரஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிஷி சுனக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு தசாப்தங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இங்கிலாந்து வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "7%க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த காலாண்டில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MSCI வளர்ந்து வரும் சந்தைகள் குறியீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடைசி நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொடர்புடைய காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் முதல் காலாண்டு வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$854.7 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$816 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ப்ளூம்பெர்க்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெறும் 1%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.1%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "8%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மனி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தாண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}