{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Armed-forces-Police-given-powers-to-search-for-firearms-seized-from-military-by-protesters/56-737574",
  "time_ut": 1657911785,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Armed forces, Police given powers to search for firearms seized from military by protesters",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Armed forces, Police given powers to search for firearms seized from military by protesters",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Cabinet of Ministers, which met yesterday, has decided to authorise the Tri-Forces commanders and the Inspector General of Police to take any steps to recover the firearms stolen from the Army personnel as soon as possible, as firearms falling into the hands of the rioters can pose a serious threat to public safety.",
        "The Cabinet met under the Chairmanship of Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe yesterday and decided to give necessary powers to the commanders of the three armed forces and the Inspector General of Police to ensure the security of the country.",
        "The Cabinet also decided to take maximum measures to ensure the security of the country.",
        "Also, a decision has been reached in the Cabinet to take any steps to ensure the security of the Parliament when it meets and to protect the right of MPs to meet freely.",
        "It has also been decided to take action against even a Member of Parliament who behaves in a way that interferes with the freedom of the Members of Parliament.",
        "It has been discussed in the Cabinet that a certain political party caused the tense situation near the entrance of the Parliament on Wednesday night. During the attempt to take over the Parliament, a group of protesters had attacked the Army soldiers and stolen their T-56 firearms with live ammunition.",
        "The Ministers have decided to authorise the security department to take any appropriate measures to search for the two firearms that were stolen from the Army in that incident.",
        "The Acting President has also informed the Cabinet that if a Member of Parliament obstructs the entrance of the Parliament, the law will be strictly enforced against him."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Inspector General of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Inspector General of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විරෝධතාකරුවන් විසින් හමුදාවෙන් අත්පත් කරගත් ගිනි අවි සෙවීමට සන්නද්ධ හමුදාවන්ට, පොලිසියට බලතල ලබාදී ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "යුද හමුදා සාමාජිකයින් අතට පත් වූ ගිනි අවි නිසා සොරාගත් ගිනි අවි කඩිනමින් සොයා ගැනීමට අවශ්‍ය ඕනෑම පියවරක් ගැනීමට ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාපතිවරුන්ට සහ පොලිස්පතිවරයාට බලය පැවරීමට ඊයේ රැස්වූ අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය තීරණය කර තිබේ. කැරලිකරුවන් මහජන ආරක්ෂාවට බරපතල තර්ජනයක් විය හැකිය.",
        "වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් ඊයේ රැස්වූ කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය තීරණය කළේ රටේ ආරක්ෂාව තහවුරු කිරීම සඳහා ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාපතිවරුන්ට සහ පොලිස්පතිවරයාට අවශ්‍ය බලතල ලබාදීමටයි.",
        "රටේ ආරක්ෂාව තහවුරු කිරීම සඳහා උපරිම ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගැනීමට ද අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය තීරණය කළා.",
        "එමෙන්ම පාර්ලිමේන්තුව රැස්වන විට එහි ආරක්ෂාව තහවුරු කිරීමටත් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට නිදහසේ රැස්වීමට ඇති අයිතිය ආරක්ෂා කිරීමටත් ඕනෑම පියවරක් ගැනීමට කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයේ තීරණයකට එළඹ තිබෙනවා.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ නිදහසට බාධා වන අයුරින් හැසිරෙන මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකුට වුවද එරෙහිව ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගැනීමට ද තීරණය කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "බදාදා රාත්‍රියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු ප්‍රවේශය අසල ඇති වූ උණුසුම්කාරී තත්ත්වය කිසියම් දේශපාලන පක්ෂයක් විසින් ඇති කළ බව කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයේ කතාබහට ලක්ව තිබේ. පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අත්පත් කර ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කිරීමේදී විරෝධතාකරුවන් පිරිසක් යුද හමුදා සෙබළුන්ට පහර දී ඔවුන් සතුව තිබූ ටී 56 ගිනි අවි ජීව උණ්ඩ සමඟ සොරකම් කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "එම සිද්ධියේදී යුද හමුදාවෙන් සොරාගත් ගිනි අවි දෙක සෙවීමට අවශ්‍ය ඕනෑම සුදුසු ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයක් ගැනීමට ආරක්ෂක අංශ වෙත බලය පැවරීමට අමාත්‍යවරු තීරණය කර ඇත.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු පාර්ලිමේන්තු පිවිසුමට බාධා කළහොත් ඔහුට එරෙහිව නීතිය දැඩිව ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන බව ද වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට දැනුම් දී තිබෙනවා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "போராட்டக்காரர்களால் ராணுவத்திடம் இருந்து கைப்பற்றப்பட்ட துப்பாக்கிகளை தேடும் அதிகாரம் ஆயுதப்படை, காவல்துறைக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இராணுவத்தினரிடம் இருந்து திருடப்பட்ட துப்பாக்கிகள் கைகளில் சிக்கியுள்ள நிலையில், அவற்றை விரைவில் மீட்பதற்கான நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொள்ள முப்படைத் தளபதிகள் மற்றும் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபருக்கு அதிகாரம் வழங்குவதற்கு நேற்று கூடிய அமைச்சரவை தீர்மானித்துள்ளது. கலவரக்காரர்கள் பொது பாதுகாப்புக்கு கடுமையான அச்சுறுத்தலை ஏற்படுத்தலாம்.",
        "பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தலைமையில் நேற்று கூடிய அமைச்சரவைக் கூட்டத்தில் நாட்டின் பாதுகாப்பை உறுதிப்படுத்துவதற்கு தேவையான அதிகாரங்களை முப்படைகளின் தளபதிகள் மற்றும் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் ஆகியோருக்கு வழங்குவதற்கு தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "நாட்டின் பாதுகாப்பை உறுதிப்படுத்தும் வகையில் அதிகபட்ச நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுக்கவும் அமைச்சரவை தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "அத்துடன், நாடாளுமன்றம் கூடும் போது அதன் பாதுகாப்பை உறுதிப்படுத்தவும், எம்.பி.க்கள் சுதந்திரமாகச் சந்திக்கும் உரிமையைப் பாதுகாக்கவும் எந்தவொரு நடவடிக்கையும் எடுக்க அமைச்சரவையில் தீர்மானம் எட்டப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் சுதந்திரத்தில் தலையிடும் வகையில் நடந்து கொள்ளும் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மீதும் நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கவும் தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "புதன்கிழமை இரவு பாராளுமன்ற நுழைவாயில் அருகே பதற்றமான சூழ்நிலையை குறிப்பிட்ட அரசியல் கட்சியொன்று ஏற்படுத்தியதாக அமைச்சரவையில் பேசப்பட்டுள்ளது. பாராளுமன்றத்தை கைப்பற்றும் முயற்சியின் போது, ​​ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் குழுவொன்று இராணுவ சிப்பாய்கள் மீது தாக்குதல் நடத்தியதுடன், அவர்களின் T-56 துப்பாக்கிகளை உயிருள்ள தோட்டாக்களுடன் திருடியுள்ளது.",
        "அந்தச் சம்பவத்தில் இராணுவத்தினரிடம் இருந்து திருடப்பட்ட இரண்டு துப்பாக்கிகளையும் தேடுவதற்கு உரிய நடவடிக்கை எடுப்பதற்கு பாதுகாப்புத் துறைக்கு அதிகாரம் வழங்க அமைச்சர்கள் தீர்மானித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஒருவர் பாராளுமன்ற நுழைவாயிலுக்கு இடையூறு விளைவித்தால் அவருக்கு எதிராக கடுமையான சட்டம் அமுல்படுத்தப்படும் எனவும் பதில் ஜனாதிபதி அமைச்சரவைக்கு அறிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்ஸ்பெக்டர் ஜெனரல் ஆஃப் போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்ஸ்பெக்டர் ஜெனரல் ஆஃப் போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}