{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131070",
  "time_ut": 1657276665,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஜப்பானில் நீண்டகாலம் பிரதமராக பதவி வகித்தவர்-சர்ச்சைக்குரிய தேசியவாதி- ஷின்சோ அபே",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Japan's longest-serving prime minister—a controversial nationalist—is Shinzo Abe",
      "author": "Rajeeban",
      "body_lines": [
        "Japan's longest-serving prime minister, Shinzo Abe, is known for his bellicose foreign policies and his own unique style of economic strategy.",
        "Because of the specialty of his economic strategy those principles were called aponomics.",
        "A conservative nationalist by most accounts, Abe (67) has won two elections for the Liberal Democrats.",
        "His first term was controversial and short-lived - little more than a year.",
        "However, Abe made a surprise comeback in 2012 and remained in office until 2020 – when he stepped down due to ill health.",
        "Shinzo Abe announced easing of monetary policy and introduced structural reforms. He was praised as the one who brought the declining economy back to the stage of development.",
        "He saved Japan from the massive destruction caused by the Tokoku earthquake and tsunami in 2011 (20,000 people died, the Fujima nuclear reactor collapsed).",
        "In 2020, he resigned after announcing that he was suffering from ulcerative colitis, and in 2007, Abe resigned after announcing that he was suffering from the same disease.",
        "Although his friend and party member Yoshihide Suga became the new prime minister, Shinzo Abe continued to be influential in Japanese politics.",
        "Son of former Foreign Minister Shintare Abe and grandson of former Prime Minister Nobusuke Kishi, Shinzo Abe is a member of political royalty.",
        "Elected to parliament in 1993, Abe was appointed minister in 2005.",
        "His rise was seen as rapid, and in 2006 Abe became Prime Minister. Through this, he became the proud prime minister of post-war Japan at a young age.",
        "However, several scandals, including the government's loss of pension documents, have hampered progress under Abe's government.",
        "In July 2007, his party suffered a crushing defeat in the Upper House elections, and Abe resigned in September, citing ill health.",
        "Abe returned to politics in 2012 after announcing his recovery from health problems, and was elected from 2014 to 2017 - becoming Japan's longest-serving prime minister.",
        "Despite declines in popular influence, his influence within the party meant that there was no one to oppose him.",
        "Changes were made in the party's manifesto to suit him for a third term as party leader.",
        "Shinzo Abe is known for his bellicose policies on Japan's defense and foreign affairs policies.",
        "Japan's conservatives see the post-World War II government as a reminder of Japan's humiliating defeat in World War II.",
        "Shinzo Abe; It is notable that China has often had disputes with South Korea due to nationalistic policies.",
        "In 2013, Abe caused controversy when he visited Tokyo's Yasukuni shrine, associated with Japan's military before and after World War II.",
        "His repeated visits infuriated Japan's leftists. They felt that Abe was trying to whitewash the injustices committed by the Japanese military during World War II.",
        "In 2015, Abe advocated the right of collective self-defense, where Japan maintains troops overseas to protect itself and its allies under attack.",
        "Japan's parliament accepted it despite protests from foreign countries and the Japanese public.",
        "His ambitious goal of completely transforming the government by recognizing the Japanese military remains unfulfilled"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Shinzo Abe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "67",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Liberal Democrats",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than a year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tokoku",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2011",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fujima",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2007",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yoshihide Suga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shintare Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nobusuke Kishi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2006",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 2007",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Upper House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "September",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "post-World War II",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "World War II",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2013",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tokyo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yasukuni shrine",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "World War II",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "World War II",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජපානයේ දීර්ඝතම කාලයක් සේවය කළ අගමැති - මතභේදාත්මක ජාතිකවාදියෙක් - ෂින්සෝ අබේ ය",
      "author": "රජීබන්",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජපානයේ දීර්ඝතම කාලයක් අගමැති ධුරය දැරූ ෂින්සෝ අබේ, ඔහුගේ සටන්කාමී විදේශ ප්‍රතිපත්ති සහ ඔහුටම ආවේණික ආර්ථික උපාය මාර්ගයක් සඳහා ප්‍රසිද්ධය.",
        "ඔහුගේ ආර්ථික ක්‍රමෝපායේ විශේෂත්වය නිසා එම ප්‍රතිපත්ති හැඳින්වූයේ අපෝනොමික්ස් යනුවෙනි.",
        "බොහෝ ගිණුම් වලට අනුව ගතානුගතික ජාතිකවාදියෙකු වන අබේ (67) ලිබරල් ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදීන් සඳහා මැතිවරණ දෙකක් ජයග්‍රහණය කර ඇත.",
        "ඔහුගේ පළමු ධූර කාලය මතභේදාත්මක හා කෙටි කාලීන විය - වසරකට වැඩි කාලයක්.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, 2012 දී අබේ පුදුමයට පත් වූ අතර 2020 දක්වා නිලයේ රැඳී සිටියේය - අසනීප තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් ඔහු ඉල්ලා අස්විය.",
        "ෂින්සෝ අබේ මුදල් ප්‍රතිපත්ති ලිහිල් කිරීම සහ ව්‍යුහාත්මක ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ හඳුන්වා දීම නිවේදනය කළේය. කඩා වැටෙමින් තිබූ ආර්ථිකය යළිත් සංවර්ධනයේ වේදිකාවට ගෙන ආ තැනැත්තා ලෙස පැසසුමට ලක් විය.",
        "2011 දී ටොකෝකු භූමිකම්පාව සහ සුනාමිය නිසා ඇති වූ දැවැන්ත විනාශයෙන් ඔහු ජපානය බේරා ගත්තේය (මිනිසුන් 20,000 ක් මිය ගියේය, ෆුජිමා න්‍යෂ්ටික ප්‍රතික්‍රියාකාරකය කඩා වැටුණි).",
        "2020 දී ඔහු ulcerative colitis රෝගයෙන් පෙළෙන බව ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් පසු ඉල්ලා අස් වූ අතර 2007 දී අබේ එම රෝගයෙන් පෙළෙන බව ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් පසු ඉල්ලා අස්විය.",
        "ඔහුගේ මිතුරෙකු සහ පක්ෂ සාමාජිකයෙකු වන Yoshihide Suga නව අගමැතිවරයා බවට පත් වුවද, ෂින්සෝ අබේ ජපන් දේශපාලනයේ බලගතු විය.",
        "හිටපු විදේශ ඇමති ෂින්තාරේ අබේගේ පුත් සහ හිටපු අගමැති නොබුසුකේ කිෂිගේ මුනුපුරා වන ෂින්සෝ අබේ දේශපාලන රාජකීයත්වයේ සාමාජිකයෙකි.",
        "1993 දී පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට තේරී පත් වූ අබේ 2005 දී ඇමති ධුරයට පත් විය.",
        "ඔහුගේ නැගීම වේගවත් ලෙස දැකිය හැකි වූ අතර 2006 දී අබේ අගමැති විය. මේ හරහා ඔහු තරුණ වියේදීම පශ්චාත් යුධ ජපානයේ සාඩම්බර අගමැති බවට පත් විය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ආණ්ඩුවේ විශ්‍රාම වැටුප් ලේඛන අහිමි වීම ඇතුළු අපකීර්ති කිහිපයක් අබේගේ රජය යටතේ ප්‍රගතියට බාධා කර ඇත.",
        "2007 ජූලි මාසයේදී, ඔහුගේ පක්ෂය ඉහළ මන්ත්‍රණ සභා මැතිවරණයෙන් අන්ත පරාජයක් අත්විඳි අතර, අසනීප තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් සැප්තැම්බර් මාසයේදී අබේ ඉල්ලා අස්විය.",
        "සෞඛ්‍ය ගැටලුවලින් සුවය ලැබීම ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් පසු 2012 දී අබේ නැවත දේශපාලනයට පැමිණි අතර 2014 සිට 2017 දක්වා තේරී පත් විය - ජපානයේ දීර්ඝතම අගමැති ධුරයට පත් විය.",
        "ජනප්‍රිය බලපෑම අඩු වුවද, පක්ෂය තුළ ඔහුගේ බලපෑම නිසා ඔහුට විරුද්ධ වීමට කිසිවෙක් නොසිටියේය.",
        "පක්‍ෂයේ ප‍්‍රතිපත්ති ප‍්‍රකාශය තුළ ඔහුට තුන්වන වරටත් පක්‍ෂ නායකයා වීමට ගැළපෙන පරිදි වෙනස්කම් සිදු කරන ලදී.",
        "ෂින්සෝ අබේ ජපානයේ ආරක්ෂක සහ විදේශ කටයුතු ප්‍රතිපත්ති පිළිබඳ ඔහුගේ සටන්කාමී ප්‍රතිපත්ති සඳහා ප්‍රසිද්ධය.",
        "ජපානයේ ගතානුගතිකයින් පශ්චාත් දෙවන ලෝක යුද්ධයේ ආන්ඩුව දකින්නේ දෙවන ලෝක යුද්ධයේදී ජපානය ලැබූ නින්දිත පරාජය මතක් කිරීමක් ලෙසය.",
        "ෂින්සෝ අබේ; ජාතිකවාදී ප්‍රතිපත්ති හේතුවෙන් චීනය දකුණු කොරියාව සමඟ නිතර ආරවුල් ඇතිකරගෙන තිබීම විශේෂත්වයකි.",
        "2013 දී, අබේ දෙවන ලෝක යුද්ධයට පෙර සහ පසුව ජපානයේ හමුදාව හා සම්බන්ධ ටෝකියෝවේ යසුකුනි සිද්ධස්ථානයට ගිය විට මතභේදයට තුඩු දුන්නේය.",
        "ඔහුගේ නැවත නැවත සංචාරය ජපානයේ වාමාංශිකයන් කෝපයට පත් කළේය. දෙවන ලෝක යුධ සමයේදී ජපන් හමුදාව විසින් සිදු කරන ලද අසාධාරණකම් වලට අබේ සුදු හුනු ගෑමට උත්සාහ කරන බව ඔවුන්ට හැඟුනි.",
        "2015 දී, අබේ සාමූහික ආත්මාරක්ෂාව සඳහා ඇති අයිතිය වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි අතර, ජපානය ප්‍රහාරයට ලක්ව සිටින තමා සහ එහි සහචරයින් ආරක්ෂා කිරීම සඳහා විදේශයන්හි හමුදා පවත්වාගෙන යයි.",
        "විදෙස් රටවල සහ ජපන් ජනතාවගේ විරෝධය නොතකා ජපාන පාර්ලිමේන්තුව එය පිළිගත්තේය.",
        "ජපාන හමුදාව පිළිගැනීමෙන් රජය සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම පරිවර්තනය කිරීමේ ඔහුගේ අභිලාෂකාමී ඉලක්කය තවමත් ඉටු වී නොමැත"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Shinzo Abe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "67",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිබරල් ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරකට වැඩි කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tokoku",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2011",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fujima",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2007",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yoshihide Suga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shintare Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nobusuke Kishi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2006",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2007 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉහළ සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පශ්චාත් දෙවන ලෝක යුද්ධය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවන ලෝක යුද්ධය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2013",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටෝකියෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yasukuni shrine",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවන ලෝක යුද්ධය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවන ලෝක යුද්ධය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜப்பானில் நீண்டகாலம் பிரதமராக பதவி வகித்தவர்-சர்ச்சைக்குரிய தேசியவாதி- ஷின்சோ அபே",
      "author": "Rajeeban",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜப்பானில் நீண்டகாலம் பிரதமராக பதவிவகித்தவரான -ஷின்சோ அபே  தனது போர்க்குணம் மிக்க வெளிவிவகார கொள்கைகளிற்காகவும் தனக்கே உரித்தான பாணியிலான பொருளாதார மூலோபாயங்களிற்காகவும் பெயர் பெற்றவர்.",
        "அவரது பொருளாதார மூலோபாயத்தின் சிறப்பு காரணமாக அந்த கொள்கைகள் அபோனெமிக்ஸ் என அழைக்கப்பட்டன.",
        "பெரும்பாலான விளக்கங்களின்படி ஒரு பழமைவாத தேசியவாதியான அபே (67)லிபரல் ஜனநாயக கட்சிக்கு இரண்டு தேர்தல்களில் வெற்றியை பெற்றுக்கொடுத்தவர்.",
        "அவரது முதலாவது பதவிக்காலம் சர்ச்சைக்குரியதாகவும் குறுகியகாலம் மாத்திரமே நீடித்ததாகவும் காணப்பட்டது - ஒரு வருடத்திற்கும் சற்று அதிகம்.",
        "எனினும் 2012 ஆச்சரியமளிக்கும் விதத்தில் மீள்வருகை புரிந்த அபே 2020 வரை பதவியில் நீடித்தார்- உடல்நல பாதிப்புகளால் பதவி விலகினார்.",
        "ஷின்சோ அபே நாணயக்கொள்கைகளில் தளர்வுகளை அறிவித்தார்,கட்டமைப்பு மாற்றங்களை முன்னெடுத்தார். வீழ்ச்சியடைந்துகொண்டிருந்த பொருளாதாரத்தை மறுபடி வளர்ச்சி நிலைக்கு கொண்டுவந்தவர் என பாராட்டுப்பெற்றார்.",
        "2011 இல் டொகோக்குவில் பூகம்பமும் சுனாமியும் ஏற்படுத்திய பாரிய அழிவிலிருந்து ஜப்பானை மீட்டார்,(20,000 பேர் உயிரிழந்தனர்,புஷிமா அணுஉலை சிதைந்தது)",
        "2020இல் பெருங்குடல்புண்ணிணால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டதாக அறிவித்து பதவி விலகினார்,2007ம் ஆண்டிலும் இதேநோயினால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அறிவித்தே அபே பதவி விலகினார்.",
        "அவரது நண்பரும் கட்சி உறுப்பினருமான யொசிகிடே சுகா புதிய பிரதமராக பதவியேற்ற போதிலும் சி;ன்சோ அபே தொடர்ந்தும் ஜப்பான் அரசியலில் செல்வாக்கு மிக்கவராக காணப்பட்டார்.",
        "முன்னாள் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் சின்டாரே அபேயின் மகனும் முன்னாள் பிரதமர் நொபுசுக்கே கிசியின் பேரனுமான ஷின்சோ அபே அரசியல் அரசகுடும்பத்தை சேர்ந்தவர்.",
        "1993 இல் நாடாளுமன்றத்திற்கு தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்ட அபே 2005 இல் அமைச்சராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "அவரது வளர்ச்சி மிகவேகமானதாக காணப்பட்டது,2006 இல் அபே பிரதமரானார். இதன் மூலம் யுத்தத்திற்கு பிந்திய ஜப்பானில் இளம் வயதில் பிரதமரானவர் என்ற  பெருமைக்குரியவரானார்.",
        "எனினும் அரசாங்கம் ஓய்வூதிய ஆவணங்களை இழந்தமை உட்பட பல சர்சைகள் குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் அபேயின் அரசாங்கத்தின் முன்னேற்றத்தை பாதித்தன.",
        "2007ஜூலையில்  இல் மேல்சபைக்கான தேர்தலில் அவரது கட்சி மோசமான தோல்வியை  தழுவியது, இதனை தொடர்ந்து செப்டம்பரில் தனது உடல்நிலையை காரணம் காட்டி அபே பதவியை இராஜினாமா செய்தார்.",
        "2012 இல் உடல்நிலைபாதிப்புகளில் இருந்து மீண்டுவிட்டதாக தெரிவித்து மீண்டும் அரசியலில் ஈடுபட்ட அபே 2014 -2017 இல் தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டு - ஜப்பானில் நீண்ட நாள் பிரதமர் பதவியில் நீடித்தவர் என்ற பெருமைக்குரியவரானார்.",
        "மக்கள் செல்வாக்கில் வீழ்ச்சிகள் ஏற்பட்ட போதிலும் கட்சியில் அவருக்கு காணப்பட்ட செல்வாக்கு காரணமாக அவரை எதிர்க்க எவரும் இல்லாத நிலை காணப்பட்டது.",
        "அவர் மூன்றாவது தடவையும் கட்சியின் தலைவராக பதவி வகிப்பதற்கு ஏற்ற வகையில் கட்சியி;ன் யாப்பில் மாற்றங்கள் செய்யப்பட்டன.",
        "ஜப்பானின் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் வெளிவிவகார கொள்கைகள் குறித்த தனது போர்க்குணம் மிக்க கொள்கைகளிற்காக பெயர் பெற்றவர் ஷின்சோ அபே",
        "இரண்டாம் உலக யுத்தத்தின் பின்னர் அமெரிக்கா தயாரித்த அரசமைப்பை இரண்டாம் உலக யுத்தத்தில் ஜப்பானி;ற்கு ஏற்பட்ட அவமானகரமான தோல்வியை நினைவுபடுத்தும் ஒன்றாக ஜப்பானின் கென்சவேர்ட்டிவ்கள் கருதுகின்றனர்.",
        "ஷின்சோ அபே; தேசிய வாத கொள்கைகள் காரணமாக அடிக்கடி சீனா தென்கொரியாவுடன் சர்ச்சைகள் உருவானமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது.",
        "2013 இல் அபே இரண்டாம் உலக போருக்கு முன்னும் பின்னும்ஜப்பானின் இராணுவத்துடன் தொடர்புடைய டோக்கியோவின் யாசுகுனி வழிபாட்டுதலத்திற்கு  விஜயம் மேற்கொண்டமை சர்ச்சையை ஏற்படுத்தியது.",
        "அவர் மீண்டும் மீண்டும் அங்கு சென்றமை ஜப்பானின் இடதுசாரிகளிற்கு சீற்றத்தை ஏற்படுத்தியது. இரண்டாம் உலக யுத்தத்தின்போது ஜப்பான் இராணுவத்தினர் புரிந்த அநீதிகளிற்கு  அபே வெள்ளையடிக்க முயல்கின்றார் என அவர்கள் கருதினார்.",
        "2015 இ;ல் ஜப்பான் தன்னை  பாதுகாத்துக்கொள்ளவதற்கும் தாக்குதலிற்கு உள்ளான சகாக்களை பாதுகாத்துக்கொள்வதற்கும் வெளிநாடுகளில் படையினரை வைத்திருப்பதற்கான கூட்டு தற்பாதுகாப்பிற்கான உரிமையை அபே முன்வைத்தார்.",
        "ஜப்பானின் அயல்நாடுகளும் பொதுமக்களும் எதிர்ப்பை வெளியிட்ட போதிலும் ஜப்பான் நாடாளுமன்றம் அதனை ஏற்றுக்கொண்டது.",
        "ஜப்பான் இராணுவத்தை அங்கீகரிக்கும் வித்தில் அரசமைப்பை முழுமையாக மாற்றும் அவரது பாரிய இலக்கு இன்னமும் நிறைவேறாததாக காணப்படுகின்றது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Shinzo Abe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "67",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாராளவாத ஜனநாயகவாதிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வருடத்திற்கும் மேலாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tokoku",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2011",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fujima",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2007",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yoshihide Suga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shintare Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nobusuke Kishi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2006",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 2007",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேலவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாம் உலகப் போருக்குப் பிந்தைய",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாம் உலக போர்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2013",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோக்கியோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yasukuni shrine",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாம் உலக போர்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாம் உலக போர்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}