{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Vote-for-presidency-SLFP-not-to-support-any-candidate-Maithri/108-241223",
  "time_ut": 1657976881,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Vote for presidency; SLFP not to support any candidate: Maithri",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Vote for presidency; SLFP not to support any candidate: Maithri",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Freedom Party (SLFP) has decided not to vote for any candidate during the vote to be taken in Parliament to elect a new President, SLFP Chairman former president Maithripala Sirisena said today.",
        "He told a news conference that if only one candidate had contested they could have considered voting.",
        "\"Four candidates have contested by now. It might increase by Tuesday. However, only one will win and all the others will refrain from supporting the one who wins in the future. If there is no consensus in Parliament,we won't be able to resolve the crisis faced by the country,\" he said.",
        "Mr. Sirisena said the SLFP has not decided to field a candidate either. (Ajith Siriwardana)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "only one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "only one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Siriwardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති ධුරය සඳහා ඡන්දය දෙන්න; ශ්‍රීලනිපය කිසිම අපේක්ෂකයෙකුට සහය නොදෙන බව මෛත්‍රී කියයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ පැවැත්වෙන ඡන්ද විමසීමේදී කිසිදු අපේක්ෂකයෙකුට ඡන්දය නොදීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය තීරණය කළ බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ සභාපති හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා අද (25) ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ප්‍රවෘත්ති සාකච්ඡාවකදී ඔහු කියා සිටියේ එක් අපේක්ෂකයෙකු පමණක් ඉදිරිපත් වූයේ නම් ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීම ගැන සලකා බැලිය හැකි බවයි.",
        "\"මේ වන විට අපේක්ෂකයින් හතර දෙනෙක් ඉදිරිපත් වී ඇත. අඟහරුවාදා වන විට එය වැඩි විය හැක. කෙසේ වෙතත් එක් අයෙකු පමණක් ජයග්‍රහණය කරන අතර අනෙක් සියල්ලන්ම අනාගතයේදී දිනන තැනැත්තාට සහය දීමෙන් වළකිනු ඇත. පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සම්මුතියක් නැතිනම් අපට නොහැකි වනු ඇත. රට මුහුණ දී ඇති අර්බුදය විසඳීමට\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "සිරිසේන මහතා පැවසුවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය ද අපේක්ෂකයෙකු ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට තීරණය කර නොමැති බවයි. (අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීලනිප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එකක් පමණයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එකක් පමණයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීලනිප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு வாக்களியுங்கள்; ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி எந்தவொரு வேட்பாளருக்கும் ஆதரவளிக்காது: மைத்திரி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவுசெய்வதற்காக பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நடைபெறவுள்ள வாக்கெடுப்பின் போது எந்தவொரு வேட்பாளருக்கும் வாக்களிக்க வேண்டாம் என ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் தலைவர் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஒரு வேட்பாளர் மட்டும் போட்டியிட்டிருந்தால் வாக்களிப்பதை பரிசீலித்திருக்கலாம் என்று அவர் செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பில் கூறினார்.",
        "\"தற்போது நான்கு வேட்பாளர்கள் போட்டியிட்டுள்ளனர். செவ்வாய் கிழமைக்குள் இது அதிகரிக்கலாம். இருப்பினும் ஒருவர் மட்டுமே வெற்றி பெறுவார், மற்றவர்கள் அனைவரும் வெற்றி பெறுபவருக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதைத் தவிர்ப்பார்கள். நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் ஒருமித்த கருத்து ஏற்படாவிட்டால், எங்களால் முடியாது. நாடு எதிர்கொள்ளும் நெருக்கடியை தீர்க்க வேண்டும்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியும் வேட்பாளரை நிறுத்த முடிவு செய்யவில்லை என்று திரு. சிறிசேன கூறினார். (அஜித் சிறிவர்தன)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரே ஒரு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரே ஒரு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}