{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132491",
  "time_ut": 1659090117,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இலங்கையின் பொறுப்பு கூறல், மனித உரிமைகள் தொடர்பில் பிரித்தானிய உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் - ஜனாதிபதிக்கிடையில் விசேட கலந்துரையாடல்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "British High Commissioner-Presidential Special Discussion on Sri Lanka's Accountability, Human Rights",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "Discussions were held between President Ranil Wickremesinghe and the British High Commissioner to Sri Lanka regarding Sri Lanka's accountability to United Nations human rights and compliance with human rights.",
        "Attention was paid to this matter during the meeting between President Ranil Wickremesinghe and British High Commissioner to Sri Lanka Sarah Halton on Thursday 28th.",
        "During this, High Commissioner Halton conveyed his greetings to the President and engaged in a detailed discussion on various issues.",
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe briefed the High Commissioner on the measures taken by the government for economic recovery and political stability.",
        "Various issues including Sri Lanka's accountability to United Nations human rights and compliance with human rights were also discussed here.",
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe stated that it is his wish to strengthen the relations between Sri Lanka and Britain and the High Commissioner promised full support for it.",
        "At the same time, the British High Commissioner posted on his Twitter page regarding this meeting, 'We expect to strengthen the relationship between Britain and Sri Lanka in a peaceful and democratic environment.",
        "This extensive discussion with the President emphasized the importance of human rights in Sri Lanka through the process of the United Nations Human Rights Council. mentioned that."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "British",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka's",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "United Nations",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sarah Halton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday 28th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Halton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "United Nations",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Britain",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Twitter",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Britain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations Human Rights Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වගවීම, මානව හිමිකම් පිළිබඳ බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය මහ කොමසාරිස්-ජනාධිපති විශේෂ සාකච්ඡාව",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වගවීම සහ මානව හිමිකම්වලට අනුකූලව කටයුතු කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයා අතර සාකච්ඡාවක් සිදුව තිබේ.",
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය මහ කොමසාරිස් සාරා හැල්ටන් මහත්මිය අතර 28 බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා පැවති හමුවේදී මේ පිළිබඳව අවධානය යොමු විය.",
        "මෙහිදී මහ කොමසාරිස් හැල්ටන් මහතා ජනාධිපතිවරයා වෙත සිය සුබපැතුම් පළ කළ අතර විවිධ කරුණු සම්බන්ධයෙන් සවිස්තර සාකච්ඡාවක ද නිරත විය.",
        "ආර්ථික ප්‍රකෘතිය සහ දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වය වෙනුවෙන් රජය ගෙන ඇති ක්‍රියාමාර්ග පිළිබඳව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයා දැනුවත් කළේය.",
        "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වගවීම, මානව හිමිකම්වලට අනුකූල වීම ඇතුළු විවිධ කරුණු ද මෙහිදී සාකච්ඡා කෙරිණි.",
        "ශී‍්‍ර ලංකාව සහ බි‍්‍රතාන්‍යය අතර සබඳතා ශක්තිමත් කර ගැනීම තම අපේක්ෂාව බව ප‍්‍රකාශ කළ ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික‍්‍රමසිංහ ඊට පූර්ණ සහයෝගය ලබාදෙන බවට මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයා පොරොන්දු වුණා.",
        "ඒ සමගම මෙම හමුව සම්බන්ධයෙන් බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයා සිය ට්විටර් පිටුවේ සටහනක් තබමින්, 'බ්‍රිතාන්‍යය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර සබඳතාව සාමකාමී සහ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී පරිසරයක් තුළ ශක්තිමත් කිරීමට අපි බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා.",
        "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයේ ක්‍රියාවලිය තුළින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මානව හිමිකම් පිළිබඳ වැදගත්කම ජනාධිපතිවරයා සමඟ පැවැති මෙම පුළුල් සාකච්ඡාවේදී අවධාරණය කෙරිණි. බව සඳහන් කළා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාරා හැල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හැල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්විටර්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் பொறுப்பு கூறல், மனித உரிமைகள் தொடர்பில் பிரித்தானிய உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் - ஜனாதிபதிக்கிடையில் விசேட கலந்துரையாடல்",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபையின் மனித உரிமைகள் தொடர்பில் இலங்கையின் பொறுப்புக்கூறல், மனித உரிமைகளுக்கு இணங்க செயற்படுதல் உள்ளிட்ட முக்கிய விடயங்கள் தொடர்பில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றும் இலங்கைக்கான பிரித்தானிய உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் ஆகியோருக்கிடையில் கலந்துரையாடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றும் இலங்கைக்கான பிரித்தானிய உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் சாரா ஹல்டன் ஆகியோருக்கிடையில் 28 ஆம் திகதி வியாழக்கிழமை இடம்பெற்ற சந்திப்பின் போதே இவ்விடயம் தொடர்பில் அவதானம் செலுத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "இதன் போது ஜனாதிபதிக்கு தனது வாழ்த்துக்களைத் தெரிவித்த உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் ஹல்டன், பல்வேறு விடயங்கள் தொடர்பாக விரிவான கலந்துரையாடலிலும் ஈடுபட்டார்.",
        "பொருளாதார மீட்சி மற்றும் அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மைக்காக அரசாங்கம் எடுத்துள்ள நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்து ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க உயர்ஸ்தானிகருக்கு விளக்கமளித்தார்.",
        "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபையின் மனித உரிமைகள் தொடர்பில் இலங்கையின் பொறுப்புக்கூறல், மனித உரிமைகளுக்கு இணங்க செயற்படுதல் உள்ளிட்ட  பல்வேறு விடயங்கள் குறித்தும்  இங்கு கலந்துரையாடப்பட்டது.",
        "இலங்கைக்கும் பிரித்தானியாவுக்கும் இடையிலான உறவுகளை வலுப்படுத்துவதே தமது விருப்பம் என்று ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க , குறிப்பிட்டதுடன் அதற்கு பூரண ஆதரவை வழங்குவதாக உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் உறுதியளித்தார்.",
        "இதே வேளை இந்த சந்திப்பு தொடர்பில் தனது டுவிட்டர் பக்கத்தில் பதிவிட்டுள்ள பிரித்தானிய உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் , 'பிரித்தானியா - இலங்கைக்கு இடையிலான உறவை அமைதியானதும் ஜனநாயகமானதுமான சூழலுக்குள் வலுப்படுத்த எதிர்பார்க்கின்றோம்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியுடனான இந்த விரிவான கலந்துரையாடலானது , ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவையின் செயன்முறைக்கமைய இலங்கையில் மனித உரிமைகளின் முக்கியத்துவத்தை வலியுறுத்துவதாக அமைந்தது.' என்று குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாரா ஹால்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன் 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹால்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ட்விட்டர்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}