{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/බිත්තර---කුකුල්-මස්-මිල-අඩු-කරන්න-සාකච්ඡා/101-618300",
  "time_ut": 1660749306,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "බිත්තර - කුකුල් මස් මිල අඩු කරන්න සාකච්ඡා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Negotiations to reduce egg-chicken prices",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Director General of Consumer Affairs Authority S. said that the main producers of eggs and chicken expressed their willingness to reduce the prices of eggs and they requested to provide solutions to several problems of the producers in order to reduce the prices. T. Mr. Kodikara said today (17).",
        "Mr. Kodikara said that the producers of eggs and chicken meat clarified the facts about the increase in their production costs and also mentioned that the consumer authority worked to inform about the market information of the two food items.",
        "Mr. Kodikara further said that he is confident that the issues regarding the price of eggs and chicken can be resolved.",
        "After the discussions held today (17) at the consumer authority with the representatives of the two main associations of egg and chicken meat producers, the director general of that authority S. T. Mr. Kodikara said so."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Consumer Affairs Authority S.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kodikara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kodikara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kodikara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. T.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kodikara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බිත්තර - කුකුල් මස් මිල අඩු කරන්න සාකච්ඡා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "බිත්තර සහ කුකුල් මස් මිල අඩු කිරීමට ඒවායේ ප්‍රධාන නිෂ්පාදකයන් කැමැත්ත පළ කළ බවත් මිල අඩුකිරීමට නම් නිෂ්පාදකයන්ගේ ගැටලු කීපයකට විසඳුම් ලබාදෙන ලෙස ඉල්ලීම් කළ බවත් පාරිභෝගික කටයුතු පිළිබඳ අධිකාරියේ අධ්‍යක්‍ෂ ජනරාල් එස්. ටී. කොඩිකාර මහතා අද (17) පැවසීය.",
        "බිත්තර සහ කුකුල් මස් නිෂ්පාදකයන් ඔවුන්ගේ නිෂ්පාදන පිරිවැය ඉහළ යෑම පිළිබඳව කරුණු පැහැදිළි කළ බව කී කොඩිකාර මහතා එම ආහාර ද්‍රව්‍ය දෙකේ වෙළඳපොල තොරතුරු පිළිබඳව දැනුවත් කිරීමට පාරිභෝගික අධිකාරිය කටයුතු කළ බව ද සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "බිත්තර සහ කුකුල් මස් මිල පිළිබඳ ප්‍රශ්න විසඳා ගතහැකි බවට විශ්වාසයක් ඇති බව ද කොඩිකාර මහතා වැඩි දුරටත් කීය.",
        "බිත්තර සහ කුකුල් මස නිෂ්පාදකයන ප්‍රධාන සංගම් දෙකේ නියෝජිතයන් සමඟ පාරිභෝගික අධිකාරියේදී අද (17) පැවැති සාකච්ඡාවලින් පසුව එම අධිකාරියේ අධ්‍යක්‍ෂ ජනරාල් එස්. ටී. කොඩිකාර මහතා එසේ සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාරිභෝගික කටයුතු අධිකාරියේ එස්.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොඩිකාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොඩිකාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොඩිකාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ටී.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොඩිකාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முட்டை-கோழி விலையை குறைக்க பேச்சுவார்த்தை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முட்டை மற்றும் கோழிக்கறி உற்பத்தியாளர்கள் முட்டை விலையை குறைப்பதற்கு விருப்பம் தெரிவித்துள்ளதாகவும், உற்பத்தியாளர்களின் பல பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு தீர்வினை பெற்றுக்கொடுக்குமாறும் நுகர்வோர் விவகார அதிகார சபையின் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் எஸ். டி. கொடிகார இன்று (17) தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "முட்டை மற்றும் கோழி இறைச்சி உற்பத்தியாளர்கள் தமது உற்பத்திச் செலவு அதிகரிப்பு தொடர்பான உண்மைகளை தெளிவுபடுத்தியதாகத் தெரிவித்த திரு.கொடிகாரா, இரண்டு உணவுப் பொருட்களின் சந்தைத் தகவல்களை தெரிவிக்க நுகர்வோர் அதிகாரசபை செயற்பட்டதாகவும் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "முட்டை மற்றும் கோழிக்கறியின் விலை தொடர்பான பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு தீர்வு காண முடியும் என தாம் நம்புவதாகவும் திரு.கொடிகார மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "முட்டை மற்றும் கோழி இறைச்சி உற்பத்தியாளர்களின் இரண்டு பிரதான சங்கங்களின் பிரதிநிதிகளுடன் நுகர்வோர் அதிகாரசபையில் இன்று (17) இடம்பெற்ற கலந்துரையாடலின் பின்னர், அந்த அதிகாரசபையின் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் எஸ். டி. திரு.கொடிகார தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நுகர்வோர் விவகார அதிகாரசபை எஸ்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொடிகார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொடிகார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொடிகார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.டி.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொடிகார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}