{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/29/52-soes-made-a-significant-loss-of-rs-859-bn-in-2022/",
  "time_ut": 1659075900,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "52 SOEs made a significant loss of Rs. 859 Bn in 2022",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "52 SOEs made a significant loss of Rs. 859 Bn in 2022",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "During the first four months of 2022, the key 52 State Owned Enterprises reported a significant loss of Rs. 859 billion which is a significant deterioration compared to the loss of Rs. 13 billion in the corresponding period in 2021.",
        "This was revealed in the Mid-Year fiscal position report 2022.",
        "During the first four months of 2022, State Owned Enterprises (SOEs) encountered significant operational and financial challenges. The lack of foreign exchange liquidity has adversely affected the supply chain management of many key SOEs, particularly in the energy and transportation sectors. The negative impacts of this have been experienced across the entire economy.",
        "Whilst the recent adoption of cost reflective pricing in the fuel sector is a positive step towards the operational sustainability of the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC), there remain a multitude of issues that require resolution.",
        "The primary concern is the legacy debt of CPC that is predominantly in foreign currency, resulting in frequent foreign exchange losses for the entity which in turn results in additional fiscal stress for the government and financial stress for the stateowned banks. As a result, the CPC has negative equity of Rs. 986 billion as at end April 2022.",
        "The Ceylon Electricity Board (CEB) has also not revised electricity tariffs for close to 8 years, contributing to an accumulated loss of Rs. 236 billion. The rising cost of fuel and coal in the global market coupled with the depreciation of the currency has contributed to a spike in the CEB’s operating cost, which calls for an urgent adjustment of pricing for this sector. It is important to address the financial position of these two key energies related SOEs in order to ensure a stable and sustainable supply of energy to support economic activity across the board.",
        "SriLankan Airlines (SLA) is another SOE that has significant fiscal implications. SLA’s losses for 2021/22 reached Rs. 171 billion, creating a going concern issue for the entity. In addition to the",
        "fiscal losses, SLA also has external liabilities that need to be honoured under challenging operating circumstances where revenue is adversely affected by the decline in tourism, and fuel costs have escalated along with finance costs.",
        "During the first four months of 2022, the key 52 SOEs reported a significant loss of Rs. 859 billion which is a significant deterioration compared to the loss of Rs. 13 billion in the corresponding period",
        "The key driver of the loss is the foreign exchange loss of CPC due to the depreciation of the currency. The exchange loss of CPC stood at Rs. 549 billion in the first four months of 2022.",
        "The General Treasury collected levies and dividends of Rs. 11.4 billion in the first four months of 2022, which was a 67 percent increase compared to the corresponding period in 2021.",
        "No new financing for Sri Lanka until adequate macroeconomic policy framework is in place – World Bank"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "52",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "859",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the first four months of 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "859 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "13 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mid-Year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the first four months of 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "April 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "close to 8 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "236 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "171 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the first four months of 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "859 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "13 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "549 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first four months of 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The General Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "11.4 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first four months of 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "67 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "52 SOEs සැලකිය යුතු පාඩුවක් රු. 2022 දී බිලියන 859 කි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "2022 පළමු මාස ​​හතර තුළ ප්‍රධාන රාජ්‍ය ව්‍යවසායන් 52 රු. බිලියන 859 ක අලාභයට සාපේක්ෂව සැලකිය යුතු පිරිහීමකි. 2021 වසරේ අනුරූප කාලපරිච්ඡේදය තුළ බිලියන 13 කි.",
        "2022 වසරේ මැද මූල්‍ය තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳ වාර්තාවෙන් මෙය අනාවරණය විය.",
        "2022 පළමු මාස ​​හතර තුළ රාජ්‍ය සතු ව්‍යවසායන් (SOEs) සැලකිය යුතු මෙහෙයුම් සහ මූල්‍ය අභියෝගවලට මුහුණ දුන්නේය. විදේශ විනිමය ද්‍රවශීලතා හිඟය බොහෝ ප්‍රධාන SOE වල, විශේෂයෙන්ම බලශක්ති සහ ප්‍රවාහන ක්ෂේත්‍රවල සැපයුම් දාම කළමනාකරණයට අහිතකර ලෙස බලපා ඇත. මෙහි අහිතකර බලපෑම් සමස්ත ආර්ථිකයටම අත්විඳ ඇත.",
        "ඉන්ධන ක්‍ෂේත්‍රයේ පිරිවැය පරාවර්තක මිල ක්‍රමයක් මෑතකදී අනුගමනය කිරීම ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවේ (CPC) මෙහෙයුම් තිරසාරභාවය සඳහා ධනාත්මක පියවරක් වන අතර, විසඳුම් අවශ්‍ය වන ගැටලු රාශියක් පවතී.",
        "මූලික අවධානය යොමු වන්නේ CPC හි උරුම නය ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් විදේශ මුදල් වලින් වන අතර, එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස ආයතනයට නිතර විදේශ විනිමය පාඩු සිදු වන අතර එමඟින් රජයට අතිරේක මූල්‍ය ආතතිය සහ රාජ්‍ය බැංකු සඳහා මූල්‍ය ආතතිය ඇති වේ. එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් වශයෙන්, CPC හි සෘණ කොටස් රු. 2022 අප්‍රේල් අවසන් වන විට බිලියන 986 කි.",
        "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය (CEB) ද වසර 8 කට ආසන්න කාලයක් විදුලි ගාස්තු සංශෝධනය නොකිරීම නිසා සමුච්චිත පාඩුව රු. බිලියන 236 කි. ගෝලීය වෙලඳපොලේ ඉන්ධන සහ ගල් අඟුරු මිල ඉහල යාම සහ මුදල් ඒකකයේ අවප්‍රමාණය වීම ලංවිමේ මෙහෙයුම් පිරිවැය ඉහල යාමට හේතු වී ඇති අතර, මෙම අංශය සඳහා මිල ගණන් හදිසි ගැලපීමක් ඉල්ලා සිටී. මණ්ඩලය හරහා ආර්ථික ක්‍රියාකාරකම්වලට සහාය වීම සඳහා ස්ථාවර සහ තිරසාර බලශක්ති සැපයුමක් සහතික කිරීම සඳහා මෙම ප්‍රධාන ශක්තීන් දෙක හා සම්බන්ධ SOEs හි මූල්‍ය තත්ත්වය ආමන්ත්‍රණය කිරීම වැදගත් වේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය (SLA) සැලකිය යුතු මූල්‍ය ඇඟවුම් ඇති තවත් SOE වේ. 2021/22 සඳහා SLA හි පාඩුව රු. බිලියන 171ක්, ආයතනය සඳහා පවතින ගැටලුවක් නිර්මාණය කරයි. ඊට අමතරව",
        "රාජ්‍ය මූල්‍ය පාඩු, සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරයේ පහත වැටීම හේතුවෙන් ආදායමට අහිතකර ලෙස බලපා ඇති අතර, මූල්‍ය පිරිවැය සමඟ ඉන්ධන පිරිවැය ඉහළ ගොස් ඇති අභියෝගාත්මක මෙහෙයුම් තත්වයන් යටතේ ගරු කළ යුතු බාහිර වගකීම් ද SLA සතුව ඇත.",
        "2022 පළමු මාස ​​හතර තුළ ප්‍රධාන 52 SOEs සැලකිය යුතු පාඩුවක් රු. බිලියන 859 ක අලාභයට සාපේක්ෂව සැලකිය යුතු පිරිහීමකි. අනුරූප කාල සීමාව තුළ බිලියන 13 කි",
        "අලාභයේ ප්‍රධාන සාධකය වන්නේ මුදල් අවප්‍රමාණය වීම හේතුවෙන් CPC හි විදේශ විනිමය පාඩුවයි. CPC හි විනිමය පාඩුව රු. 2022 පළමු මාස ​​හතර තුළ රුපියල් බිලියන 549 කි.",
        "මහා භාණ්ඩාගාරය විසින් රු. 2022 මුල් මාස හතර තුළ රුපියල් බිලියන 11.4 ක් වූ අතර එය 2021 වසරේ අනුරූප කාලපරිච්ඡේදයට සාපේක්ෂව සියයට 67 ක වර්ධනයකි.",
        "ප්‍රමාණවත් සාර්ව ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිපත්ති රාමුවක් ක්‍රියාත්මක වන තුරු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා නව මූල්‍ය පහසුකම් නොමැත - ලෝක බැංකුව"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "52",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "859",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 පළමු මාස ​​හතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 859 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 13 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වසර මැද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 පළමු මාස ​​හතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 8කට කිට්ටුයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 236 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 171 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.එල්.ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 පළමු මාස ​​හතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 859 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 13 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 549 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 පළමු මාස ​​හතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහා භාණ්ඩාගාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 11.4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 පළමු මාස ​​හතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 67 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "52 SOEகள் கணிசமான இழப்பைச் சந்தித்தன. 2022 இல் 859 பில்லியன்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "2022 இன் முதல் நான்கு மாதங்களில், முக்கிய 52 அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான நிறுவனங்கள் ரூ. 859 பில்லியனை ஒப்பிடுகையில் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க சரிவு ரூ. 2021 ஆம் ஆண்டின் இதே காலத்தில் 13 பில்லியன்.",
        "இது 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் மத்திய ஆண்டு நிதி நிலை அறிக்கையில் தெரியவந்துள்ளது.",
        "2022 இன் முதல் நான்கு மாதங்களில், அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான நிறுவனங்கள் (SOEs) குறிப்பிடத்தக்க செயல்பாட்டு மற்றும் நிதி சவால்களை எதிர்கொண்டன. அந்நியச் செலாவணி பணப்புழக்கம் பல முக்கிய SOEகளின் விநியோகச் சங்கிலி நிர்வாகத்தை, குறிப்பாக ஆற்றல் மற்றும் போக்குவரத்துத் துறைகளில் மோசமாகப் பாதித்துள்ளது. இதன் எதிர்மறையான தாக்கங்கள் ஒட்டுமொத்தப் பொருளாதாரத்திலும் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "எரிபொருள் துறையில் செலவு பிரதிபலிப்பு விலை நிர்ணயம் என்பது இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்தின் (CPC) செயற்பாட்டு நிலைத்தன்மையை நோக்கிய ஒரு சாதகமான படியாகும் அதேவேளையில், தீர்வு தேவைப்படும் பல பிரச்சினைகள் உள்ளன.",
        "CPC இன் மரபுக் கடன் முதன்மையாக வெளிநாட்டு நாணயத்தில் உள்ளது, இதன் விளைவாக நிறுவனத்திற்கு அடிக்கடி அந்நிய செலாவணி இழப்பு ஏற்படுகிறது, இது அரசாங்கத்திற்கு கூடுதல் நிதி அழுத்தத்தையும், அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான வங்கிகளுக்கு நிதி அழுத்தத்தையும் ஏற்படுத்துகிறது. இதன் விளைவாக, CPC எதிர்மறையான ஈக்விட்டி ரூ. ஏப்ரல் 2022 இறுதியில் 986 பில்லியன்.",
        "இலங்கை மின்சார சபையும் (CEB) கடந்த 8 வருடங்களாக மின்சாரக் கட்டணத்தை திருத்தியமைக்கவில்லை, இது ரூ. 236 பில்லியன். உலக சந்தையில் எரிபொருள் மற்றும் நிலக்கரியின் விலை உயர்வு மற்றும் நாணயத்தின் தேய்மானம் ஆகியவை CEB இன் இயக்கச் செலவில் அதிகரிப்புக்கு பங்களித்துள்ளன. இந்த இரண்டு முக்கிய ஆற்றல்கள் தொடர்பான SOE களின் நிதி நிலைமையை நிவர்த்தி செய்வது முக்கியம், இதன் மூலம் போர்டு முழுவதும் பொருளாதார நடவடிக்கைகளை ஆதரிக்க நிலையான மற்றும் நிலையான ஆற்றல் விநியோகத்தை உறுதி செய்வதற்காக.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் (SLA) என்பது குறிப்பிடத்தக்க நிதி தாக்கங்களைக் கொண்ட மற்றொரு SOE ஆகும். 2021/22க்கான SLA இன் இழப்புகள் ரூ. 171 பில்லியன், நிறுவனத்திற்கு கவலையளிக்கும் சிக்கலை உருவாக்குகிறது. கூடுதலாக",
        "நிதி இழப்புகள், SLA ஆனது சவாலான இயக்க சூழ்நிலைகளின் கீழ் மதிக்கப்பட வேண்டிய வெளிப்புற பொறுப்புகளையும் கொண்டுள்ளது, அங்கு சுற்றுலாத்துறையின் வீழ்ச்சியால் வருவாய் மோசமாக பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது, மேலும் நிதி செலவுகளுடன் எரிபொருள் செலவுகள் அதிகரித்துள்ளன.",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் முதல் நான்கு மாதங்களில், முக்கிய 52 SOE கள் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க இழப்பு ரூ. 859 பில்லியனை ஒப்பிடுகையில் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க சரிவு ரூ. இதே காலத்தில் 13 பில்லியன்",
        "நாணயத்தின் தேய்மானம் காரணமாக CPC இன் அந்நிய செலாவணி இழப்பு இழப்பின் முக்கிய இயக்கி ஆகும். CPC இன் பரிமாற்ற இழப்பு ரூ. 2022 முதல் நான்கு மாதங்களில் 549 பில்லியன்.",
        "பொது கருவூலம் வரி மற்றும் ஈவுத்தொகையாக ரூ. 2022 இன் முதல் நான்கு மாதங்களில் 11.4 பில்லியன், இது 2021 இன் தொடர்புடைய காலகட்டத்துடன் ஒப்பிடும்போது 67 சதவீதம் அதிகமாகும்.",
        "போதுமான பெரிய பொருளாதாரக் கொள்கை கட்டமைப்பை நடைமுறைப்படுத்தும் வரை இலங்கைக்கு புதிய நிதியுதவி இல்லை - உலக வங்கி"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "52",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "859",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 இன் முதல் நான்கு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "859 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "13 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டின் நடுப்பகுதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 இன் முதல் நான்கு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு அருகில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "236 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "171 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 இன் முதல் நான்கு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "859 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "13 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "549 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 இன் முதல் நான்கு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொது கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "11.4 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 இன் முதல் நான்கு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "67 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}