{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/rootcode-wins-startup-of-the-year-and-peoples-choice-award-at-saarc-startup-awards-2022/",
  "time_ut": 1660926960,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Rootcode wins Startup of the Year and People’s Choice Award at SAARC Startup Awards 2022",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Rootcode wins Startup of the Year and People’s Choice Award at SAARC Startup Awards 2022",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "Rootcode, one of Sri Lanka’s leading tech companies, recently took home the “People’s Choice Award” in addition to being bestowed with the “Startup of the Year” title at the SAARC Startup Awards 2022. This regional recognition marks a significant milestone for the Sri Lankan tech space and workforce. Rootcode’s mission to build great tech is well underway, and it is gaining traction faster than ever.",
        "This is the first time a Sri Lankan tech company has made a name for itself in the regional competition, and it is a watershed moment that has focused the global spotlight on Rootcode’s distinct approach to fostering innovation in Sri Lanka. This is also the first time that a Sri Lankan company was able to take home two awards of those presented at the SAARC Startup Awards.",
        "Global Startup Awards SAARC celebrates the spirit of entrepreneurship and promotes bridging boundaries through innovation in its regions, which include Afghanistan, Bangladesh, Bhutan, India, Maldives, Nepal, Pakistan, and Sri Lanka, by recognizing them with its most prestigious awards program, attended by top-notch entrepreneurs, corporates, investors, and ecosystem builders from Nordic, Central Europe, SAARC, and ASEAN regions.",
        "Every year, the SAARC Startup Awards bring together hundreds of South Asian startups, entrepreneurs, investors, co-working spaces, and accelerators to provide a platform to highlight trailblazers in the region’s startup world. Rootcode was chosen ahead of dozens of other regional tech startups in the competition.",
        "Sri Lanka is a relative newcomer to the South Asian startup fraternity, and Rootcode’s ability to represent the country on the global stage not long after its inception is remarkable.",
        "“We are extremely humbled and honored by the support shown to us at the SAARC Startup Awards 2022, and being recognized under two categories is a huge milestone for us,” said the CEO and Founder of Rootcode Labs, Alagan Mahalingam. “We have always been driven forward by excellence, collaboration, and integrity, which I believe is the reason why we have come so far and why Rootcode continues to grow every day.”",
        "Rootcode is driven by its focus on helping businesses build great tech not just locally but globally, and its achievement at the SAARC awards stands as a testament to that. Despite the challenging times, this is a win for Sri Lanka.",
        "Unilever ranked No 1 most respected FMCG company in Lanka once again",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Startup",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "People’s Choice Award",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "SAARC Startup Awards",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the “People’s Choice Award",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Startup of the Year",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rootcode",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Global Startup Awards SAARC",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Afghanistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bhutan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nepal",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nordic, Central Europe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SAARC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ASEAN",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Every year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "hundreds",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rootcode",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "dozens",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the South Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rootcode",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rootcode Labs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alagan Mahalingam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rootcode",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Unilever",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Rootcode SAARC Startup Awards 2022 හි වසරේ ආරම්භය සහ ජනතා තේරීම සම්මානය දිනා ගනී",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ තාක්ෂණික සමාගමක් වන Rootcode, 2022 SAARC Startup Awards හි “වසරේ ආරම්භය” යන මාතෘකාවට අමතරව “People's Choice Award” පසුගියදා හිමිකර ගත්තේය. ලංකා තාක්ෂණික අවකාශය සහ ශ්රම බලකාය. විශිෂ්ට තාක්‍ෂණය ගොඩනැගීමේ Rootcode හි මෙහෙවර හොඳින් සිදුවෙමින් පවතින අතර එය වෙන කවරදාටත් වඩා වේගයෙන් කම්පනය වෙමින් පවතී.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය තාක්ෂණික සමාගමක් කලාපීය තරඟාවලියේ නමක් දිනාගත් පළමු අවස්ථාව මෙය වන අතර, එය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ නවෝත්පාදනයන් පෝෂණය කිරීම සඳහා Rootcode හි සුවිශේෂී ප්‍රවේශය කෙරෙහි ගෝලීය අවධානය යොමු කර ඇති වැදගත් අවස්ථාවකි. SAARC Startup Awards හිදී පිරිනැමුණු සම්මාන අතරින් ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය සමාගමකට සම්මාන දෙකක් ලබා ගැනීමට හැකි වූ පළමු අවස්ථාව ද මෙයයි.",
        "Global Startup Awards SAARC විසින් ව්‍යවසායකත්වයේ ආත්මය සමරන අතර ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානය, බංග්ලාදේශය, භූතානය, ඉන්දියාව, මාලදිවයින, නේපාලය, පකිස්ථානය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඇතුළු එහි කලාපවල නව්‍යකරණයන් හරහා සීමා මායිම් ප්‍රවර්ධනය කරයි. Nordic, මධ්‍යම යුරෝපය, SAARC සහ ASEAN කලාපවල ඉහළ පෙළේ ව්‍යවසායකයින්, ආයතනිකයින්, ආයෝජකයින් සහ පරිසර පද්ධති සාදන්නන් විසිනි.",
        "සෑම වසරකම, SAARC Startup Awards විසින් දකුණු ආසියානු ආරම්භකයින්, ව්‍යවසායකයින්, ආයෝජකයින්, සම-වැඩ කරන අවකාශයන් සහ ත්වරණකරුවන් සියගණනක් එකට එකතු කර කලාපයේ ආරම්භක ලෝකයේ trailblazers ඉස්මතු කිරීමට වේදිකාවක් සපයයි. Rootcode තරඟයේ අනෙකුත් කලාපීය තාක්ෂණික ආරම්භක දුසිම් ගණනකට වඩා ඉදිරියෙන් තෝරා ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දකුණු ආසියානු ආරම්භක සහෝදරත්වයට සාපේක්ෂ නවකයෙක් වන අතර, ආරම්භ වී වැඩි කල් නොගොස් ගෝලීය වේදිකාවේ රට නියෝජනය කිරීමට Rootcode සතු හැකියාව විශිෂ්ටයි.",
        "\"SAARC Startup Awards 2022 හිදී අපට දැක්වූ සහයෝගයෙන් අපි අතිශයින් නිහතමානීව සහ ගෞරවයට පත්වෙනවා. කාණ්ඩ දෙකක් යටතේ පිළිගැනීම අපට විශාල සන්ධිස්ථානයක්\" යැයි Rootcode Labs හි ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී සහ නිර්මාතෘ අලගන් මහාලිංගම් පැවසීය. \"අපි සෑම විටම විශිෂ්ටත්වය, සහයෝගීතාවය සහ අඛණ්ඩතාවයෙන් ඉදිරියට ගෙන ගොස් ඇත, එය අප මෙතරම් දුර පැමිණීමට හේතුව සහ Rootcode සෑම දිනකම වර්ධනය වීමට හේතුව ලෙස මම විශ්වාස කරමි.\"",
        "Rootcode මෙහෙයවනු ලබන්නේ ව්‍යාපාරවලට දේශීයව පමණක් නොව ගෝලීය වශයෙන් විශිෂ්ට තාක්‍ෂණය ගොඩනගා ගැනීමට උපකාර කිරීම කෙරෙහි වන අවධානයෙන් වන අතර, SAARC සම්මාන උළෙලේදී එහි ජයග්‍රහණය සාක්ෂියක් ලෙස පවතී. අභියෝගාත්මක කාලයක වුවද මෙය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ලැබූ ජයග්‍රහණයකි.",
        "යුනිලීවර් නැවත වරක් ලංකාවේ වඩාත්ම ගෞරවනීය FMCG සමාගම අංක 1 ශ්‍රේණිගත කළේය",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පණ ගන්වන්න",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජනතා තේරීම් සම්මානය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "SAARC ආරම්භක සම්මාන",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "\"ජනතා තේරීම් සම්මානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරේ ආරම්භය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල කේතය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Global Startup Awards SAARC",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "භූතානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නේපාලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෝර්ඩික්, මධ්යම යුරෝපය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෑම වසරකම",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිය ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල කේතය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුසිම්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල කේතය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල කේත රසායනාගාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලගන් මහාලිංගම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල කේතය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුනිලීවර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SAARC ஸ்டார்ட்அப் விருதுகள் 2022 இல் ரூட்கோட் ஆண்டின் தொடக்க மற்றும் மக்கள் தேர்வு விருதை வென்றது",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் முன்னணி தொழில்நுட்ப நிறுவனங்களில் ஒன்றான Rootcode, SAARC Startup Awards 2022 இல் \"ஆண்டின் தொடக்கம்\" என்ற பட்டத்தை வழங்கியதுடன், \"மக்கள் தேர்வு விருதை\" சமீபத்தில் பெற்றுள்ளது. இலங்கை தொழில்நுட்ப இடம் மற்றும் பணியாளர்கள். சிறந்த தொழில்நுட்பத்தை உருவாக்குவதற்கான ரூட்கோடின் பணி சிறப்பாக நடந்து வருகிறது, மேலும் இது முன்னெப்போதையும் விட வேகமாக இழுவைப் பெற்று வருகிறது.",
        "இலங்கையின் தொழில்நுட்ப நிறுவனம் ஒன்று பிராந்திய போட்டியில் தனக்கென ஒரு பெயரை உருவாக்குவது இதுவே முதல் தடவையாகும், மேலும் இது இலங்கையில் புதுமைகளை வளர்ப்பதற்கான Rootcode இன் தனித்துவமான அணுகுமுறையில் உலகளாவிய கவனத்தை செலுத்திய ஒரு முக்கியமான தருணமாகும். சார்க் ஸ்டார்ட்அப் விருதுகளில் வழங்கப்பட்ட இரண்டு விருதுகளை இலங்கை நிறுவனம் ஒன்றுக்கு எடுத்துச் செல்வது இதுவே முதல் முறை.",
        "Global Startup Awards SAARC தொழில்முனைவோரின் உணர்வைக் கொண்டாடுகிறது மற்றும் ஆப்கானிஸ்தான், பங்களாதேஷ், பூட்டான், இந்தியா, மாலத்தீவுகள், நேபாளம், பாகிஸ்தான் மற்றும் இலங்கையை உள்ளடக்கிய அதன் பிராந்தியங்களில் புதுமைகளின் மூலம் எல்லைகளை மேம்படுத்துவதை ஊக்குவிக்கிறது. நார்டிக், மத்திய ஐரோப்பா, சார்க் மற்றும் ஆசியான் பகுதிகளைச் சேர்ந்த உயர்மட்ட தொழில்முனைவோர், பெருநிறுவனங்கள், முதலீட்டாளர்கள் மற்றும் சுற்றுச்சூழல் அமைப்பாளர்களால்.",
        "ஒவ்வொரு ஆண்டும், SAARC ஸ்டார்ட்அப் விருதுகள் நூற்றுக்கணக்கான தெற்காசிய ஸ்டார்ட்அப்கள், தொழில்முனைவோர், முதலீட்டாளர்கள், இணை வேலை செய்யும் இடங்கள் மற்றும் முடுக்கிகளை ஒன்றிணைத்து, பிராந்தியத்தின் தொடக்க உலகில் டிரெயில்பிளேசர்களை முன்னிலைப்படுத்த ஒரு தளத்தை வழங்குகிறது. போட்டியில் டஜன் கணக்கான பிற பிராந்திய தொழில்நுட்ப தொடக்கங்களை விட ரூட்கோடு தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இலங்கை தெற்காசிய ஸ்டார்ட்அப் சகோதரத்துவத்திற்கு ஒப்பீட்டளவில் புதுவரவாகும், மேலும் ரூட்கோட் தொடங்கப்பட்ட சிறிது காலத்திலேயே உலக அரங்கில் நாட்டைப் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் திறன் குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது.",
        "\"SAARC ஸ்டார்ட்அப் விருதுகள் 2022 இல் எங்களுக்குக் காட்டப்பட்ட ஆதரவால் நாங்கள் மிகவும் தாழ்மையும் மரியாதையும் அடைகிறோம், மேலும் இரண்டு பிரிவுகளின் கீழ் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்டது எங்களுக்கு ஒரு பெரிய மைல்கல்\" என்று ரூட்கோட் லேப்ஸின் CEO மற்றும் நிறுவனர் அழகன் மகாலிங்கம் கூறினார். \"நாங்கள் எப்பொழுதும் சிறந்து, ஒத்துழைப்பு மற்றும் ஒருமைப்பாடு ஆகியவற்றால் முன்னோக்கிச் செல்லப்பட்டுள்ளோம், நாங்கள் இதுவரை வந்ததற்கும், ரூட்கோடு ஒவ்வொரு நாளும் வளர்ந்து வருவதற்கும் இதுவே காரணம் என்று நான் நம்புகிறேன்.\"",
        "ரூட்கோடு வணிகங்கள் உள்நாட்டில் மட்டுமல்லாமல் உலகளவில் சிறந்த தொழில்நுட்பத்தை உருவாக்க உதவுவதில் கவனம் செலுத்துகிறது, மேலும் SAARC விருதுகளில் அதன் சாதனை அதற்கு ஒரு சான்றாக உள்ளது. சவாலான காலங்கள் இருந்தபோதிலும், இது இலங்கைக்கு கிடைத்த வெற்றியாகும்.",
        "யுனிலீவர் மீண்டும் இலங்கையில் மிகவும் மரியாதைக்குரிய FMCG நிறுவனமாக முதலிடத்தைப் பிடித்துள்ளது",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தொடக்கம்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "மக்கள் தேர்வு விருது",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சார்க் ஸ்டார்ட்அப் விருதுகள்",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "\"மக்கள் தேர்வு விருது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டின் தொடக்கம்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூட்கோடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Global Startup Awards SAARC",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்கானிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூட்டான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேபாளம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நோர்டிக், மத்திய ஐரோப்பா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சார்க்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒவ்வொரு வருடமும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நூற்றுக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூட்கோடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டஜன் கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூட்கோடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூட்கோட் ஆய்வகங்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அழகன் மகாலிங்கம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூட்கோடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யுனிலீவர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}