{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/national-list-convenient-for-political-parties-gravy-for-those-appointed/",
  "time_ut": 1656079440,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "National List: convenient for political parties, gravy for those appointed",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "National List: convenient for political parties, gravy for those appointed",
      "author": "Dilshan Nadeera",
      "body_lines": [
        "Business tycoon Dhammika Perera’s swearing last week as a National List MP of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) evoked a great deal of interest for a number of self-evident reasons. Among these was that fact that he has publicly claimed to be the country’s biggest taxpayer. This has been seen on youtube by hundreds of thousands of viewers. Whether Perera claimed this in his personal capacity or whether it included the companies he controls – and there are a great many of them both listed and unlisted – has not been clarified. Apart from that claim, it is very well known that he is a major shareholder in a clutch of listed companies including the Hayleys conglomerate, the thriving ceramics sector (Royal Ceramics, Lanka Tiles, Lanka Walltiles etc), his own Vallibel Group together with LB Finance, one of the country’s biggest finance companies. He also owns significant stakes in the banking sector. On top of that are his interests in the gambling industry in which the foundation of his fortune lies.",
        "The SLPP’s decision to nominate Perera to fill the vacancy created by the resignation of ruling clan sibling, Basil Rajapaksa, was challenged in the Supreme Court by the Center for Policy Alternatives and some other petitioners. They included a former Chairman of the Ceylon Chamber of Commerce, Mr. Chandra Jayaratne, who has post-retirement been a vigorous public interest activist. As many as five fundamental rights actions challenging Perera’s appointment were filed after his appointment was gazetted by the Elections Commission. Last Monday he undertook before a three-judge bench of the Supreme Court that he would not take his oaths as a Member of Parliament until the court had reached a determination on the actions before it. The court ruled in Perera’s favour by a divided decision. He is now an MP and likely to take a cabinet seat in a new Ministry of Technology and Investment Promotion created for him. Many subjects, previously covered by the President, have been assigned to this ministry.",
        "Perera has not been sworn a minister at the time this commentary is being written. He has been quoted in the media saying that he expects a “suitable ministry” saying that he headed by Board of Investment during civil war – he was also Secretary Transport under the Mahinda Rajapaksa presidency – and that he was confident of providing solutions during the current crisis as well. The NewsWire website quoted him saying “at a time when people are losing jobs, I have entered Parliament to create job opportunities.” Whether an appeal is possible against the determination of the Supreme Court, generally considered as final, is still an open question. It has been speculated whether the petitioners will seek a hearing by a fuller bench in the light of their success in convincing one of three judges may be pursued. For this to be possible, the order made in Perera’s favour must be studied. The word on Friday was that this had not yet been done and requires further examination once the court order, dictated on the bench, is available.",
        "However that be, questions now arise on the value of the 30 MPs appointed to Parliament on the National Lists of the various parties running for election. During the early post-Independence years, then Ceylon had six Appointed MPs to represent “unrepresented interests” in the 101-Member Legislature. Under this arrangement, MPs were appointed from communities like the so-called ‘estate Tamils’ disenfranchised by the first Parliament, Burghers, Malays and even British interests of that time. Older readers may remember that Mrs. Bandaranaike appointed the well known paediatrician, Dr. L.O. Abeyratne to Parliament to represent the country’s children. Previously, Mr. SWRD Bandaranaike appointed Mr. Asoka Karunaratne on a caste basis. All that, of course, is now water under the bridge. Today we have as many as 30 National List MPs and it would be difficult, with the exception of Mr. Lakshman Kadirgamar, to find anybody who had adorned parliamentary benches in a National List capacity. The existence of these positions have almost exclusively served narrow interests of political parties and their leaders.",
        "The primary ground of the challenge on Dhammika Perera’ s appointment lies in article 99A of the Constitution. This says that the Commissioner of Elections shall by notice requite the secretary of a recognized political party or an independent group that secures National List places at a general election to nominate persons to be appointed (being persons whose names are included in the list submitted to the Commissioner of Elections under this Article or any other nomination paper submitted in respect of any electoral district by such party or group at that election) to fill such seats and shall declare elected as Members of Parliament the persons so nominated. (Emphasis added). Dhammika Perera does not belong to either such category. The Island editorially commented last Thursday (June 23) that there is a serious discrepancy between a section of the Parliamentary Election Act No. 1 of 1981 and some provisions of the Constitution governing National List appointments. These have been permitted to long continue.",
        "Field Marshal Sarath Fonseka entered Parliament on the UNP National List having run for election under the banner of another party. Mr. Ratnasiri Wickremanayake, who subsequently served as prime minister, entered Parliament on a UPFA National List slot without his name being on that party’s National or any other nomination paper, filling a vacancy created by a resignation. This was challenged (also by the CPA) but not taken up by the Sarath Silva Supreme Court for three years and was eventually withdrawn. There is no escaping the conclusion that the National List serves as an instrument of convenience for political parties and a source of gravy for those appointed under it. Should it continue?",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "hundreds of thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hayleys",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Royal Ceramics",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka Tiles",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vallibel Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Center for Policy Alternatives",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Chamber of Commerce",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandra Jayaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "As many as five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Elections Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Last Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Technology and Investment Promotion",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Board of Investment",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NewsWire",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Lists of the",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "post-Independence years",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "101",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Legislature",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malays",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandaranaike",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "L.O. Abeyratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SWRD Bandaranaike",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asoka Karunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "as many as 30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakshman Kadirgamar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera’",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "article 99A of the Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Emphasis",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Island",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliamentary Election Act No",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the UNP National List",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnasiri Wickremanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UPFA National List",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sarath Silva Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National List",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව: දේශපාලන පක්ෂ සඳහා පහසු, පත් කළ අයට හොදි",
      "author": "ඩිල්ෂාන් නදීර",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ලෙස ව්‍යාපාරික ධම්මික පෙරේරා පසුගිය සතියේ දිවුරුම් දීම ස්වයංසිද්ධ හේතු ගණනාවක් නිසා මහත් උනන්දුවක් ඇති කළේය. මේ අතර ඔහු රටේ විශාලතම බදු ගෙවන්නා බව ප්‍රසිද්ධියේ ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත. මෙය යූ ටියුබ් හි ලක්ෂ සංඛ්‍යාත නරඹන්නන් විසින් නරඹා ඇත. පෙරේරා මෙය ඔහුගේ පුද්ගලික හැකියාවෙන් ප්‍රකාශ කළේද නැතහොත් ඔහු පාලනය කරන සමාගම් එයට ඇතුළත් කර තිබේද යන්න සහ ඒවායින් බොහොමයක් ලැයිස්තුගත කර ඇති සහ ලැයිස්තුගත නොකළ ඒවාද යන්න පැහැදිලි කර නොමැත. එම ප්‍රකාශය හැරුණු විට, ඔහු හේලීස් සමූහ ව්‍යාපාරය, දියුණු වෙමින් පවතින සෙරමික් අංශය (රෝයල් සෙරමික්, ලංකා ටයිල්ස්, ලංකා වෝල්ටයිල්ස් යනාදී) ඇතුළු ලැයිස්තුගත සමාගම් සමූහයක ප්‍රධාන කොටස් හිමියෙකු වන බව ඉතා හොඳින් දන්නා කරුණකි. ෆිනෑන්ස්, රටේ විශාලතම මූල්‍ය සමාගමකි. බැංකු ක්‍ෂේත්‍රයේ සැලකිය යුතු කොටස් ද ඔහු සතුය. ඊට ඉහළින් ඔහුගේ වාසනාවේ පදනම ඇති සූදු කර්මාන්තයේ ඔහුගේ උනන්දුව වේ.",
        "පාලක වංශික සහෝදරයෙකු වන බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් ඇති වූ පුරප්පාඩුව සඳහා පෙරේරා නම් කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ගත් තීරණය විකල්ප ප්‍රතිපත්ති කේන්ද්‍රය සහ තවත් සමහර පෙත්සම්කරුවන් විසින් ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය හමුවේ අභියෝගයට ලක් කරන ලදී. ලංකා වාණිජ මණ්ඩලයේ හිටපු සභාපතිවරයෙකු වූ චන්ද්‍රා ජයරත්න මහතාද ඔවුන් අතර වූ අතර ඔහු විශ්‍රාම ගැනීමෙන් පසු දැඩි මහජන උනන්දුවකින් ක්‍රියාකරන්නෙකු විය. පෙරේරා මහතාගේ පත්වීම අභියෝගයට ලක් කරමින් මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් ක්‍රියාමාර්ග පහක් ගොනු කරනු ලැබුවේ මැතිවරණ කොමිෂන් සභාව විසින් ඔහුගේ පත් කිරීම ගැසට් කිරීමෙන් පසුවය. පසුගිය සඳුදා ඔහු ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයේ ත්‍රිපුද්ගල විනිසුරු මඩුල්ලක් හමුවේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේ තමන් ඉදිරි ක්‍රියාමාර්ග සම්බන්ධයෙන් අධිකරණය තීරණයක් ගන්නා තුරු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ලෙස දිවුරුම් නොදෙන බවයි. පෙරේරාට පක්ෂව උසාවිය තීන්දුවක් දුන්නේ බෙදී ගිය තීන්දුවකිනි. ඔහු දැන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු වන අතර ඔහු වෙනුවෙන්ම නිර්මාණය කරන ලද නව තාක්ෂණ හා ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන අමාත්‍යාංශයක කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයක් ගැනීමට බොහෝ දුරට ඉඩ ඇත. මීට පෙර ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් ආවරණය කරන ලද විෂයයන් රැසක් මෙම අමාත්‍යාංශයට පවරා ඇත.",
        "පෙරේරා මේ අටුවාව ලියන මොහොත වන විට ඇමැතිවරයකු ලෙස දිවුරුම් දී නැත. සිවිල් යුද සමයේදී ආයෝජන මණ්ඩලයේ ප්‍රධානියා ලෙස කටයුතු කළ බවත්, මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් ප්‍රවාහන ලේකම්වරයා ලෙසද කටයුතු කළ බවත්, පවතින කාලය තුළ විසඳුම් ලබා දීමට තමාට විශ්වාසයක් ඇති බවත්, “සුදුසු අමාත්‍යාංශයක්” තමා බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව මාධ්‍ය මගින් උපුටා දක්වා තිබේ. අර්බුදය ද. නිව්ස් වයර් වෙබ් අඩවිය ඔහු උපුටා දක්වමින් කියා සිටියේ \"මිනිසුන්ට රැකියා අහිමි වන මොහොතක, මම රැකියා අවස්ථා නිර්මාණය කිරීමට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණියෙමි.\" සාමාන්‍යයෙන් අවසාන වශයෙන් සැලකෙන ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයේ තීරණයට එරෙහිව අභියාචනයක් ඉදිරිපත් කළ හැකිද යන්න තවමත් විවෘත ප්‍රශ්නයකි. විනිසුරුවරුන් තිදෙනෙකුගෙන් එක් අයෙකුට ඒත්තු ගැන්වීමේ සාර්ථකත්වය මත පෙත්සම්කරුවන් පූර්ණ විනිසුරු මඩුල්ලක් මගින් විභාගයක් ඉල්ලා සිටීද යන්න අනුමාන කර ඇත. මෙය කළ හැකි වීමට නම් පෙරේරාට පක්ෂව කරන ලද නියෝගය අධ්‍යයනය කළ යුතුය. සිකුරාදා වචනය වූයේ මෙය තවමත් සිදු කර නොමැති අතර විනිසුරු මඩුල්ලේ නියම කරන ලද අධිකරණ නියෝගය ලැබුණු පසු වැඩිදුර විභාගයක් අවශ්‍ය බවයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, මැතිවරණයට ඉදිරිපත් වන විවිධ පක්ෂවල ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පත් කර ඇති මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 30 දෙනාගේ වටිනාකම පිළිබඳව දැන් ප්‍රශ්න මතු වේ. නිදහසින් පසු මුල් වසරවලදී, මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 101 දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් ව්‍යවස්ථාදායකයේ \"නියෝජිත නොවන අවශ්‍යතා\" නියෝජනය කිරීම සඳහා එවකට ලංකාවට පත් කරන ලද මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් හය දෙනෙක් සිටියහ. මෙම විධිවිධානය යටතේ, පළමු පාර්ලිමේන්තුව, බර්ගර්, මැලේ සහ එවකට බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය අවශ්‍යතාවලින් පවා ඡන්දය අහිමි වූ ඊනියා ‘වතු දෙමළ’ වැනි ප්‍රජාවන්ගෙන් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පත් කරන ලදී. බණ්ඩාරනායක මැතිනිය විසින් සුප්‍රසිද්ධ ළමා රෝග විශේෂඥ වෛද්‍ය එල්.ඕ. අබේරත්න රටේ දරුවන් වෙනුවෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට. මීට පෙර එස්.ඩබ්ලිව්.ආර්.ඩී.බණ්ඩාරනායක මහතා විසින් අශෝක කරුණාරත්න මහතා කුල ක්‍රමයට පත් කළේය. ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම, ඒ සියල්ල දැන් පාලම යට ජලයයි. අද අපට ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 30ක් පමණ සිටින අතර ලක්ෂ්මන් කදිරගාමර් මහතා හැර ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයකු ලෙස පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත‍්‍රී මන්ත‍්‍රී මන්ත‍්‍රී මන්ත‍්‍රී මන්ත‍්‍රීවරුන් 30ක් පමණ සිටින අතර කිසිවෙකු සොයා ගැනීම අපහසුය. මෙම තනතුරුවල පැවැත්ම තනිකරම පාහේ දේශපාලන පක්ෂවල සහ ඒවායේ නායකයින්ගේ පටු අවශ්‍යතා සඳහා සේවය කර ඇත.",
        "ධම්මික පෙරේරාගේ පත්වීම පිළිබඳ අභියෝගයේ මූලික පදනම ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 99A වගන්තියේ ඇත. මෙයින් කියැවෙන්නේ පත් කළ යුතු පුද්ගලයන් නම් කිරීම සඳහා මැතිවරණ කොමසාරිස්වරයා විසින් දැනුම් දීමක් මගින් පිළිගත් දේශපාලන පක්ෂයක හෝ ජාතික ලැයිස්තු ස්ථාන තහවුරු කරන ස්වාධීන කණ්ඩායමක ලේකම්වරයාට ඉල්ලා සිටිය යුතු බවයි. මෙම වගන්තිය යටතේ මැතිවරණ කොමසාරිස්වරයා හෝ එම මැතිවරණයේදී කිසියම් මැතිවරණ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලද වෙනත් නාමයෝජනා පත්‍රයක් එවැනි පක්ෂයක් හෝ කණ්ඩායමක් විසින්) එම ආසන පිරවීම සඳහා සහ එසේ නම් කරන ලද පුද්ගලයින් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ලෙස තේරී පත් වූ බව ප්‍රකාශ කළ යුතුය. (අවධාරණය එකතු කර ඇත). ධම්මික පෙරේරා එවැනි ගණයකට අයත් නොවේ. 1981 අංක 1 දරන පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණ පනතේ වගන්තියක් සහ ජාතික ලැයිස්තු පත්කිරීම් පාලනය කරන ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ ඇතැම් විධිවිධාන අතර බරපතළ පරස්පරතාවයක් පවතින බව පසුගිය බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (ජුනි 23) අයිලන්ඩ් පුවත්පත කතුවැකියෙන් ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. මේවා දිගු කාලයක් පවත්වාගෙන යාමට අවසර දී ඇත.",
        "ෆීල්ඩ් මාර්ෂල් සරත් ෆොන්සේකා මහතා එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පිවිසියේ වෙනත් පක්ෂයක ධජය යටතේ මැතිවරණයට ඉදිරිපත්වමිනි. පසුව අගමැති ලෙස කටයුතු කළ රත්නසිරි වික්‍රමනායක මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පුරප්පාඩු වූ පුරප්පාඩුවක් පුරවමින් එම පක්ෂයේ ජාතික හෝ වෙනත් නාමයෝජනා පත්‍රයේ නමක් නොමැතිව එක්සත් ජනතා නිදහස් සන්ධානයේ ජාතික ලැයිස්තු අපේක්ෂකයකු ලෙස පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පිවිසියේය. මෙය අභියෝගයට ලක් කරන ලදී (CPA විසින් ද) නමුත් සරත් සිල්වා ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය විසින් වසර තුනක් තිස්සේ නොගත් අතර අවසානයේ එය ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගන්නා ලදී. ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව දේශපාලන පක්ෂවල පහසුව සඳහා මෙවලමක් ලෙසත් ඒ යටතේ පත්වන අයගේ හොඳි උල්පතක් ලෙසත් ක්‍රියා කරයි යන නිගමනයෙන් ගැලවීමක් නැත. එය දිගටම පැවතිය යුතුද?",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිය දහස් ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හේලීස්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජකීය සෙරමික්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ටයිල්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිබල් සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විකල්ප ප්‍රතිපත්ති මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා වාණිජ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රා ජයරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහක් තරම්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැතිවරණ කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තාක්ෂණ හා ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආයෝජන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NewsWire",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හි ජාතික ලැයිස්තු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහසින් පසු වසර",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "101",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාදායකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැලේ ජාතිකයන්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්.ඕ. අබේරත්න ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SWRD බණ්ඩාරනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අශෝක කරුණාරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 ක් තරම්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂ්මන් කදිරගාමර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාවේ 99A වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිපිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවධාරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණ පනත අංක",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නසිරි වික්‍රමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජනිස ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සරත් සිල්වා ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தேசிய பட்டியல்: அரசியல் கட்சிகளுக்கு வசதியானது, நியமிக்கப்பட்டவர்களுக்கு குழம்பு",
      "author": "தில்ஷான் நதீரா",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் (SLPP) தேசியப் பட்டியல் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக கடந்த வாரம் வர்த்தக அதிபர் தம்மிக்க பெரேரா பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டது பல சுயமான காரணங்களுக்காக பெரும் ஆர்வத்தை ஏற்படுத்தியது. இவற்றில், அவர் நாட்டின் மிகப்பெரிய வரி செலுத்துபவர் என்று பகிரங்கமாகக் கூறியது. இதை யூடியூப்பில் லட்சக்கணக்கான பார்வையாளர்கள் பார்த்துள்ளனர். பெரேரா இதை தனது தனிப்பட்ட தகுதியில் கூறினாரா அல்லது அவர் கட்டுப்படுத்தும் நிறுவனங்களை உள்ளடக்கியதா - மற்றும் அவற்றில் பல பட்டியலிடப்பட்ட மற்றும் பட்டியலிடப்படாதவை - தெளிவுபடுத்தப்படவில்லை. அந்தக் கூற்றைத் தவிர, ஹெய்லிஸ் கூட்டுத்தாபனம், செழித்து வரும் மட்பாண்டத் துறை (ராயல் செராமிக்ஸ், லங்கா டைல்ஸ், லங்கா வால்டைல்ஸ் போன்றவை) உள்ளிட்ட பட்டியலிடப்பட்ட நிறுவனங்களின் கிளாச்சில் அவர் முக்கிய பங்குதாரராக உள்ளார் என்பது அனைவரும் அறிந்ததே. நாட்டின் மிகப்பெரிய நிதி நிறுவனங்களில் ஒன்று நிதி. வங்கித் துறையிலும் அவருக்கு கணிசமான பங்குகள் உள்ளன. அதற்கு மேல் சூதாட்டத் தொழிலில் அவனது ஆர்வங்கள், அதில் அவனது செல்வத்தின் அடித்தளம் உள்ளது.",
        "ஆளும் குல சகோதரரான பசில் ராஜபக்சவின் இராஜினாமாவால் ஏற்பட்ட வெற்றிடத்திற்கு பெரேராவை நியமிப்பதற்கான SLPP இன் தீர்மானம், மாற்றுக் கொள்கைகளுக்கான மையம் மற்றும் வேறு சில மனுதாரர்களால் உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தில் சவால் செய்யப்பட்டது. அவர்களில் இலங்கை வர்த்தக சம்மேளனத்தின் முன்னாள் தலைவர் திரு. சந்திரா ஜயரத்னவும் அடங்குவார், அவர் ஓய்வு பெற்ற பின்னர் தீவிரமான பொது நலன் செயற்பாட்டாளராக இருந்தார். பெரேராவின் நியமனம் தேர்தல்கள் ஆணைக்குழுவினால் வர்த்தமானியில் வெளியிடப்பட்டதையடுத்து, பெரேராவின் நியமனத்தை சவால் செய்யும் ஐந்து அடிப்படை உரிமைகள் நடவடிக்கைகள் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டன. கடந்த திங்கட்கிழமை அவர் உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தின் மூன்று நீதிபதிகள் கொண்ட அமர்வு முன், நீதிமன்றத்திற்கு முன் எடுக்கப்படும் நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்து நீதிமன்றம் தீர்மானம் எடுக்கும் வரை நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்யப் போவதில்லை என்று உறுதியளித்தார். பிரிக்கப்பட்ட தீர்ப்பின் மூலம் பெரேராவுக்கு ஆதரவாக நீதிமன்றம் தீர்ப்பளித்தது. அவர் இப்போது எம்.பி. மற்றும் அவருக்காக உருவாக்கப்பட்ட புதிய தொழில்நுட்பம் மற்றும் முதலீட்டு மேம்பாட்டு அமைச்சகத்தில் அமைச்சரவையில் இடம் பெறுவார். முன்னர் ஜனாதிபதியால் உள்ளடக்கப்பட்ட பல பாடங்கள் இந்த அமைச்சுக்கு ஒதுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "இந்த வர்ணனை எழுதப்படும் நேரத்தில் பெரேரா அமைச்சராக பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்து கொள்ளவில்லை. உள்நாட்டுப் போரின் போது முதலீட்டுச் சபையின் தலைமையில், மகிந்த ராஜபக்சவின் ஆட்சியின் கீழ் போக்குவரத்துச் செயலாளராகவும் இருந்ததாகவும், தற்போதைக்கு தீர்வொன்றை வழங்குவதில் நம்பிக்கையிருப்பதாகவும், “பொருத்தமான அமைச்சொன்றை” தான் எதிர்பார்ப்பதாக ஊடகங்களில் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். நெருக்கடியும். நியூஸ்வயர் இணையதளம், \"மக்கள் வேலை இழக்கும் நேரத்தில், வேலை வாய்ப்புகளை உருவாக்குவதற்காக நான் நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் நுழைந்துள்ளேன்\" என்று அவர் கூறியதாகக் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது. பொதுவாக இறுதி என்று கருதப்படும் உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தின் தீர்மானத்திற்கு எதிராக மேல்முறையீடு செய்ய முடியுமா என்பது இன்னும் திறந்த கேள்வியாகவே உள்ளது. மூன்று நீதிபதிகளில் ஒருவரை நம்ப வைப்பதில் அவர்கள் வெற்றி பெற்றதன் வெளிச்சத்தில் மனுதாரர்கள் முழு பெஞ்ச் மூலம் விசாரணையை நாடுவார்களா என்பது ஊகிக்கப்படுகிறது. இது சாத்தியப்படுவதற்கு, பெரேராவுக்கு ஆதரவாக செய்யப்பட்ட உத்தரவை ஆய்வு செய்ய வேண்டும். இது இன்னும் செய்யப்படவில்லை என்றும், பெஞ்சில் ஆணையிடப்பட்ட நீதிமன்ற உத்தரவு கிடைத்தவுடன் மேலும் ஆய்வு செய்ய வேண்டும் என்றும் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை வார்த்தை இருந்தது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், தேர்தலில் போட்டியிடும் பல்வேறு கட்சிகளின் தேசியப்பட்டியலில் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள 30 பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் பெறுமதி குறித்த கேள்விகள் தற்போது எழுந்துள்ளன. சுதந்திரத்திற்குப் பிந்தைய ஆரம்ப ஆண்டுகளில், 101 உறுப்பினர்களைக் கொண்ட சட்டமன்றத்தில் \"பிரதிநிதித்துவமற்ற நலன்களை\" பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்துவதற்காக, இலங்கைக்கு ஆறு நியமன எம்.பி.க்கள் இருந்தனர். இந்த ஏற்பாட்டின் கீழ், முதல் பாராளுமன்றம், பர்கர்கள், மலாய்க்காரர்கள் மற்றும் அன்றைய பிரிட்டிஷ் நலன்களால் கூட உரிமையற்ற 'தோட்டத் தமிழர்கள்' போன்ற சமூகங்களில் இருந்து எம்.பி.க்கள் நியமிக்கப்பட்டனர். பழைய வாசகர்கள் திருமதி பண்டாரநாயக்கா அவர்கள் நன்கு அறியப்பட்ட குழந்தை மருத்துவரான டாக்டர் எல்.ஓ. அபேரத்ன நாட்டின் குழந்தைகளை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்துவதற்காக பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு. இதற்கு முன்னர் திரு. எஸ்.டபிள்யூ.ஆர்.டி. அதெல்லாம், இப்போது பாலத்தின் அடியில் தண்ணீர். இன்று எங்களிடம் 30 தேசியப்பட்டியல் எம்.பி.க்கள் உள்ளனர், திரு.லக்ஷ்மன் கதிர்காமரைத் தவிர, தேசியப்பட்டியல் தகுதியில் பாராளுமன்ற ஆசனங்களை அலங்கரித்த எவரையும் கண்டுபிடிப்பது கடினம். இந்த நிலைப்பாடுகளின் இருப்பு கிட்டத்தட்ட அரசியல் கட்சிகள் மற்றும் அவற்றின் தலைவர்களின் குறுகிய நலன்களுக்கு மட்டுமே சேவை செய்துள்ளது.",
        "தம்மிக்க பெரேராவின் நியமனம் தொடர்பான சவாலின் முதன்மையான காரணம் அரசியலமைப்பின் 99A சரத்தில் உள்ளது. பொதுத் தேர்தலில் தேசியப் பட்டியல் இடங்களைப் பெற்றுக் கொள்ளும் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்ட அரசியல் கட்சி அல்லது சுயேச்சைக் குழுவின் செயலாளருக்கு நியமனம் செய்யப்பட வேண்டிய நபர்களை நியமனம் செய்ய தேர்தல்கள் ஆணையாளர் நோட்டீஸ் மூலம் கோர வேண்டும் என்று கூறுகிறது. இந்தக் கட்டுரையின் கீழ் தேர்தல்கள் ஆணையாளர் அல்லது எந்தவொரு தேர்தல் மாவட்டத்தைப் பொறுத்தமட்டில் அந்தத் தேர்தலில் அத்தகைய கட்சி அல்லது குழுவால் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்ட வேறு ஏதேனும் நியமனப் பத்திரம்) அத்தகைய இடங்களை நிரப்புவதற்கும், அவ்வாறு பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்ட நபர்களை நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களாகத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டதாக அறிவிக்க வேண்டும். (முக்கியத்துவம் சேர்க்கப்பட்டது). தம்மிக்க பெரேரா அவ்வாறான இரண்டு வகையிலும் சேர்ந்தவரல்ல. 1981 ஆம் ஆண்டு 1 ஆம் இலக்க பாராளுமன்ற தேர்தல் சட்டத்தின் ஒரு பிரிவுக்கும் தேசிய பட்டியல் நியமனங்களை நிர்வகிக்கும் அரசியலமைப்பின் சில விதிகளுக்கும் இடையில் பாரிய முரண்பாடு இருப்பதாக ஐலண்ட் கடந்த வியாழன் (ஜூன் 23) ஆசிரியர் தலையங்கத்தில் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது. இவை நீண்ட காலம் தொடர அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "பீல்ட் மார்ஷல் சரத் பொன்சேகா ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தேசியப்பட்டியலில் வேற்றுக் கட்சியின் சின்னத்தில் தேர்தலில் போட்டியிட்டு பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு பிரவேசித்துள்ளார். அதனைத் தொடர்ந்து பிரதமராக பதவி வகித்த திரு. ரத்னசிறி விக்கிரமநாயக்க, ராஜினாமா செய்த வெற்றிடத்தை நிரப்பி, அக்கட்சியின் தேசிய அல்லது வேறு எந்த வேட்பு மனுவில் அவரது பெயர் இல்லாமல் சுதந்திர முன்னணியின் தேசியப் பட்டியல் வரிசையில் நாடாளுமன்றம் நுழைந்தார். இது சவாலுக்கு உட்படுத்தப்பட்டது (CPA யாலும்) ஆனால் சரத் சில்வா உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தால் மூன்று வருடங்களாக எடுத்துக்கொள்ளப்படவில்லை, இறுதியில் அது திரும்பப் பெறப்பட்டது. தேசியப்பட்டியல் என்பது அரசியல் கட்சிகளுக்கு வசதியாகவும், அதன் கீழ் நியமிக்கப்படுபவர்களுக்கு ரசம் ஊட்டும் கருவியாகவும் விளங்குகிறது என்ற முடிவில் இருந்து தப்ப முடியாது. அது தொடர வேண்டுமா?",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர்*",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நூறாயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹேலிஸ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராயல் செராமிக்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கா டைல்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாலிபெல் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.பி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாற்றுக் கொள்கைகளுக்கான மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை வர்த்தக சம்மேளனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்திரா ஜயரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து என",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேர்தல்கள் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொழில்நுட்பம் மற்றும் முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலீட்டு வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நியூஸ் வயர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பட்டியல்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரத்திற்குப் பிந்தைய ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிலோன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "101",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சட்டமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலாய்க்காரர்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்கா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்.ஓ. அபேரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.டபிள்யூ.ஆர்.டி பண்டாரநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அசோக கருணாரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 வரை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்ஷ்மன் கதிர்காமர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பின் பிரிவு 99A",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுரை",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வலியுறுத்தல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தீவு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
