{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/இலங்கையை-உன்னிப்பாக-அவதானிக்கும்-பிரித்தானியா/175-300100",
  "time_ut": 1657395196,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இலங்கையை உன்னிப்பாக அவதானிக்கும் பிரித்தானியா",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Britain is watching Sri Lanka closely",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "British High Commissioner to Sri Lanka Sarah Halton and the country's Minister of Foreign Affairs Tariq Ahmed have said this.",
        "High Commissioner Sarah Halton, who has posted on Twitter regarding the demonstrations taking place in Sri Lanka, has mentioned that peaceful demonstrations and freedom of expression are essential for Sri Lanka's democracy.",
        "Meanwhile, the British Foreign Minister has mentioned that the situation in Sri Lanka is worrying and peaceful protests should be protected. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Britain",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sarah Halton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tariq Ahmed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sarah Halton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බි‍්‍රතාන්‍යය ශ‍්‍රී ලංකාව දෙස සමීපව බලා සිටී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය මහ කොමසාරිස් සාරා හැල්ටන් සහ එරට විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය තාරික් අහමඩ් මේ බව පවසා තිබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පැවැත්වෙන පෙළපාලි සම්බන්ධයෙන් ට්විටර් ගිණුමේ සටහනක් තබා ඇති මහ කොමසාරිස් සාරා හැල්ටන් සඳහන් කර ඇත්තේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය සඳහා සාමකාමී පෙළපාලි සහ අදහස් ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමේ නිදහස අත්‍යවශ්‍ය බවයි.",
        "මේ අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තත්ත්වය කණගාටුදායක බවත් සාමකාමී විරෝධතා ආරක්ෂා කළ යුතු බවත් බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරයා සඳහන් කර ඇත. (ඒ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බ්රිතාන්යය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාරා හැල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තාරික් අහමඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සාරා හැල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையை உன்னிப்பாக அவதானிக்கும் பிரித்தானியா",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கைக்கான பிரித்தானிய உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் சாரா ஹல்டன் மற்றும் அந்நாட்டு வெளிநாட்டலுவல்கள் அமைச்சர் தாரிக் அஹமட் ஆகியோர் இதனை தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இலங்கையில் இடம்பெற்றுவரும் ஆர்ப்பாட்டங்கள் தொடர்பில் டுவிட்டரில் பதிவிட்டுள்ள உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் சாரா ஹல்டன், அமைதியான ஆர்ப்பாட்டமும், கருத்து சுதந்திரமும் இலங்கையின் ஜனநாயகத்திற்கு இன்றியமையாதது என குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, இலங்கையின் நிலைமை கவலைக்கிடமாக உள்ளதாகவும், அமைதியான போராட்டங்கள் பாதுகாக்கப்பட வேண்டுமெனவும் பிரித்தானிய வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பிரிட்டன்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாரா ஹால்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாரிக் அகமது",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாரா ஹால்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}