{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/26/tus-concerned-about-fuel-availability/",
  "time_ut": 1656243000,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "TUs concerned about fuel availability",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "TUs concerned about fuel availability",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Media Spokesperson of the Samagi United Trade Union Force, Ananda Palitha states that only 10 or so filling stations might have fuel from tomorrow (26).",
        "Speaking during a press conference, Palitha pointed out that there is only around 1,500 metric tons of Petrol in the country.",
        "This 1,500 MT can only be distributed to 200 filling stations, he said.",
        "He further stated that even the Diesel stocks in the country has come down to 8,000 to 9,000 metric tons.",
        "If there is no foreseeable date for a ship carrying fuel to arrive in the country, in order to sustain the transport sector, fuel can only be provided to about ten filling stations from tomorrow (27) at most, Palitha mentioned.",
        "These filling stations may receive this limited fuel if they make deals with close friends and relatives in power, who will undoubtedly make use of this fuel. Palitha said that crude oil for refineries are missing as well.",
        "Commenting on power outages, the TU member mentioned that Kelanitissa alone needs 1,500 metric tons to function.",
        "“If we continue to give 1,500 MT fuel to power stations, the country will stop functioning in two days,” he added."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "TUs",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Samagi United Trade Union Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ananda Palitha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "only 10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Palitha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "only around 1,500 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Petrol",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1,500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MT",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,000 to 9,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about ten",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Palitha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Palitha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "TU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelanitissa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,500 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1,500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MT",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "TUs ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීමේ හැකියාව ගැන සැලකිලිමත් වේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); හෙට (26) සිට ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් 10ක හෝ ඊට වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක පමණක් ඉන්ධන තිබිය හැකි බව සමගි ඒකාබද්ධ වෘත්තීය සමිති බලකායේ මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක ආනන්ද පාලිත පවසනවා.",
        "මාධ්‍ය හමුවක් අමතමින් පාලිත පෙන්වා දුන්නේ රට තුළ ඇත්තේ පෙට්‍රල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 1500ක් පමණ බවයි.",
        "මෙම මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 1500 බෙදා හැරිය හැක්කේ ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් 200කට පමණක් බවද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මෙරට ඩීසල් තොග පවා මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 8,000 සිට 9,000 දක්වා පහළ බැස ඇති බවද ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ඉන්ධන රැගත් නෞකාවක් මෙරටට පැමිණීමට අපේක්ෂා කළ හැකි දිනයක් නොමැති නම් ප්‍රවාහන ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ තිරසාර පැවැත්ම සඳහා හෙට (27) සිට ඉන්ධන ලබාදිය හැක්කේ ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් දහයකට පමණ පමණක් බව පාලිත සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "බලයේ සිටින සමීප මිතුරන් සහ ඥාතීන් සමඟ ගනුදෙනු කළහොත් මෙම ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල්වලට මෙම සීමිත ඉන්ධන ලැබෙනු ඇත, ඔවුන් මෙම ඉන්ධන භාවිතා කරනු ඇත. පාලිත කියා සිටියේ පිරිපහදුවලට අවශ්‍ය බොරතෙල් ද අතුරුදන් වී ඇති බවයි.",
        "විදුලිය ඇනහිටීම් පිළිබඳව අදහස් දක්වමින් TU සාමාජිකයා සඳහන් කළේ කැලණිතිස්සට පමණක් ක්‍රියාත්මක වීමට මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 1500ක් අවශ්‍ය බවයි.",
        "“අපි දිගටම විදුලි බලාගාරවලට ඉන්ධන මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 1500ක් දුන්නොත් තව දවස් දෙකකින් රටේ ක්‍රියාකාරීත්වය නවතිනවා,” ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "TUs",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි එක්සත් වෘත්තීය සමිති බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආනන්ද පාලිත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 ක් පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාලිත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 1500ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙට්රල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1,500 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.ටී",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 8,000 සිට 9,000 දක්වා",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දහයක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාලිත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාලිත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "TU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැලණිතිස්ස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 1,500 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1,500 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.ටී",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் இருப்பு பற்றி TUs கவலை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); நாளை (26) முதல் 10 அல்லது அதற்கு மேற்பட்ட எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையங்களில் மட்டுமே எரிபொருள் இருக்கும் என சமகி ஐக்கிய தொழிற்சங்கப் படையின் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர் ஆனந்த பாலித தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பின் போது பேசிய பாலித, நாட்டில் 1500 மெற்றிக் தொன் பெற்றோல் மாத்திரமே இருப்பதாக சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "இந்த 1,500 மெட்ரிக் டன் 200 நிரப்பு நிலையங்களுக்கு மட்டுமே விநியோகிக்க முடியும் என்றார்.",
        "நாட்டில் டீசல் கையிருப்பு கூட 8,000 முதல் 9,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் வரை குறைந்துள்ளதாக அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எரிபொருளை ஏற்றிச் செல்லும் கப்பல் நாட்டிற்கு வருவதற்கு எதிர்பார்த்த திகதி இல்லை என்றால், போக்குவரத்துத் துறையை நிலைநிறுத்தும் வகையில், நாளை (27) முதல் அதிகபட்சமாக சுமார் பத்து நிரப்பு நிலையங்களுக்கு மட்டுமே எரிபொருள் வழங்க முடியும் என பாலித குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இந்த எரிபொருள் நிரப்பும் நிலையங்கள் அதிகாரத்தில் இருக்கும் நெருங்கிய நண்பர்கள் மற்றும் உறவினர்களுடன் ஒப்பந்தங்களைச் செய்தால், அவர்கள் இந்த எரிபொருளைப் பயன்படுத்துவார்கள் என்பதில் சந்தேகமில்லை. சுத்திகரிப்பு நிலையங்களுக்கான கச்சா எண்ணெய்யும் காணாமல் போயுள்ளதாக பாலித தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மின்வெட்டு குறித்து கருத்து தெரிவித்த TU உறுப்பினர், களனிதிஸ்ஸ மட்டும் இயங்குவதற்கு 1500 மெட்ரிக் தொன் தேவைப்படுவதாக குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "\"நாங்கள் தொடர்ந்து 1,500 மெட்ரிக் டன் எரிபொருளை மின் நிலையங்களுக்கு வழங்கினால், நாடு இரண்டு நாட்களில் செயல்படுவதை நிறுத்திவிடும்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "TUs",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஐக்கிய தொழிற்சங்கப் படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆனந்த பாலித",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாலித",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 1,500 மெட்ரிக் டன்கள் மட்டுமே",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1,500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,000 முதல் 9,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் பத்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாலித",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாலித",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "TU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "களனிதிஸ்ஸ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,500 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1,500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}