{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/opinion/The-cry-of-Sri-Lankas-people-Give-us-a-Mandela/172-240664",
  "time_ut": 1657313434,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "The cry of Sri Lanka’s people: “Give us a Mandela”",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The cry of Sri Lanka’s people: “Give us a Mandela”",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "With the Rajapaksa Government facing an unprecedented Aragalaya or public revolt and the protests going on in most parts of the country for three months, Sri Lanka desperately needs a statesperson who will work for the next generation and not for the election. Unfortunately, we have seen few if any such statespersons since independence in 1948. Leaders like former Prime Minister Dudley Senanayake came close to achieving such status but the people rejected him and his party in the 1970 general election mainly because he cut the rice ration from two kilos to one and the winning Prime Minister Sirimavo Bandaranaike boasted to the people that she would even bring rice from the moon.",
        "In the recent era, one of the greatest statespersons was South Africa’s Nelson Mandela who was imprisoned and tortured for decades because he spoke out against the white-supremacist policy of the South African Government, which marginalised and humiliated the coloured people in its apartheid policy, which was condemned virtually by the whole world. This wicked and inhuman policy affected various areas including sports when the South African Government banned a cricket tour by the England team because the team included a coloured player Basil D’Oliveira. As a result, the International Cricket Council (ICC) banned South Africa from test cricket and it was a tragic event because the South African team comprised some of the world’s best players.",
        "Next week on July 18, the United Nations marks Nelson Mandela International Day. He is among the few political leaders who have been given such an international honour by the world body. In a statement to mark the occasion, the UN cites one of Mr. Mandela’s most powerful statements where he said, “It is easy to break down and destroy. The heroes are those who make peace and build”. The UN has invited all countries and people to mark the day by making a difference in their communities.",
        "According to the UN, everyone has the ability and the responsibility to change the world for the better. Mandela Day is an occasion for all to take action and inspire change. Nelson Mandela devoted his life to the service of humanity — as a human rights lawyer, a prisoner of conscience, an international peacemaker and the first democratically elected president of a free South Africa. In November 2009, UN General Assembly declared July 18 as Nelson Mandela International Day. The resolution recognises Mr. Mandela’s values and his dedication to the service of humanity in conflict resolution; race relations; promotion and protection of human rights; reconciliation; gender equality and the rights of children and other vulnerable groups; the fight against poverty; the promotion of social justice. The resolution acknowledges his contribution to the struggle for democracy internationally and the promotion of a culture of peace throughout the world.",
        "On September 24, 2018, world leaders gathered at United Nations Headquarters in New York for the Nelson Mandela Peace Summit. At the Summit, nearly 100 Heads of State and Government, Ministers, Member States and representatives of civil society participants adopted a political declaration committed to redoubling efforts to build a just, peaceful, prosperous, inclusive and fair world, as they paid tribute to the late South African President’s celebrated qualities and service to humanity.",
        "Recognising the period from 2019 to 2028 as the Nelson Mandela Decade of Peace, the Declaration saluted Mr. Mandela for his humility, forgiveness and compassion, acknowledging as well his contribution to the struggle for democracy and the promotion of a culture of peace throughout the world. By the text, Heads of State and Government and Member States representatives reaffirmed their commitment to uphold the sovereign equality of all States and respect for their territorial integrity and political independence, and the duty of Member States to refrain from the threat or use of force. Recognising that peace and security, development and human rights are the pillars of the UN system and the foundations for collective security and wellbeing, the Declaration reaffirmed the 2030 agenda for sustainable development.",
        "“We resolve to move beyond words in the promotion of peaceful, just, inclusive and nondiscriminatory societies,” leaders pledged, as they stressed the importance of the equal participation and full involvement of women and youth. They also declared that racism, xenophobia and related intolerance represent the very opposite of the purposes of the UN and emphasised their resolve to protect the rights of children, especially in armed conflict. “Protecting children contributes to breaking the cycle of violence and sows the seeds for future peace,” the Declaration said.",
        "Millions of young people and others involved in Sri Lanka’s Aragalaya or public revolt against the Rajapaksa Government are raising many issues while people are dying in days-long fuel queues. The cry from their heart may be, “Give us a Mandela”."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mandela",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Rajapaksa Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dudley Senanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1970",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sirimavo Bandaranaike",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the recent era",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Africa’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nelson Mandela",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the South African Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the South African Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "England",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil D’Oliveira",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Cricket Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Africa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South African",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Next week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nelson Mandela International Day",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mandela",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mandela Day",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nelson Mandela",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Africa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "November 2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UN General Assembly",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nelson Mandela International Day",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mandela",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "September 24, 2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "United Nations Headquarters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "New York",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Nelson Mandela Peace Summit",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Heads of State and Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "South African",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Nelson Mandela Decade of Peace",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mandela",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Heads of State and Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Declaration",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "2030 agenda",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UN",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Millions",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Rajapaksa Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mandela",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "\"අපිට මැන්ඩෙලා කෙනෙක් දෙන්න\" ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවගේ කෑගැසීම",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රාජපක්ෂ ආණ්ඩුව පෙර නොවූ විරූ අරගලයකට හෝ මහජන කැරැල්ලකට මුහුණ දී සිටින අතර රටේ බොහෝ ප්‍රදේශවල මාස තුනක විරෝධතා ක්‍රියාත්මක වන විට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට මැතිවරණයට නොව ඊළඟ පරම්පරාවට වැඩ කරන රාජ්‍ය නායකයෙකු දැඩි ලෙස අවශ්‍ය වේ. අවාසනාවකට මෙන් 1948 නිදහසින් පසු එවැනි රාජ්‍ය නායකයන් අප දැක ඇත්තේ ස්වල්ප දෙනෙකි. හිටපු අගමැති ඩඩ්ලි සේනානායක වැනි නායකයන් එවැනි තත්ත්වයකට ළඟා වූ නමුත් 1970 මහ මැතිවරණයේදී ජනතාව ඔහු සහ ඔහුගේ පක්ෂය ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේ ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් සහල් සලාකය දෙකකින් කපා හැරීම නිසාය. එකෙකුට කිලෝ ග‍්‍රහණය කර දිනූ අගමැතිනි සිරිමාවෝ බණ්ඩාරනායක මැතිනිය හඳෙන් බත් ගේනවා කියා ජනතාවට උදම් ඇනුවාය.",
        "මෑත යුගයේ, දකුණු අප්‍රිකාවේ නෙල්සන් මැන්ඩෙලා දශක ගණනාවක් සිරගත කර වධ හිංසාවලට ලක් වූ විශිෂ්ටතම රාජ්‍ය නායකයෙකු වූයේ වර්ණභේදවාදී ප්‍රතිපත්තිය තුළ වර්ණවත් ජනතාව කොන් කළ සහ අවමානයට ලක් කළ දකුණු අප්‍රිකානු රජයේ සුදු ආධිපත්‍යවාදී ප්‍රතිපත්තියට එරෙහිව ඔහු කතා කළ බැවිනි. මුළු ලෝකයම පාහේ හෙළා දකින ලදී. මෙම දුෂ්ට සහ අමානුෂික ප්‍රතිපත්තිය ක්‍රීඩාව ඇතුළු විවිධ ක්ෂේත්‍රවලට බලපෑවේ දකුණු අප්‍රිකානු රජය එංගලන්ත කණ්ඩායමේ ක්‍රිකට් සංචාරයක් තහනම් කළ විට කණ්ඩායමේ වර්ණවත් ක්‍රීඩකයෙකු වන බැසිල් ඩි ඔලිවේරා ඇතුළත් වූ බැවිනි. එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස ජාත්‍යන්තර ක්‍රිකට් කවුන්සිලය (ICC) දකුණු අප්‍රිකාවට ටෙස්ට් ක්‍රිකට් තහනම් කළ අතර එය ඛේදනීය සිදුවීමක් වූයේ දකුණු අප්‍රිකානු කණ්ඩායම ලොව හොඳම ක්‍රීඩකයින් කිහිප දෙනෙකුගෙන් සමන්විත වීමයි.",
        "ලබන සතියේ ජූලි 18 වෙනිදා එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවිධානය නෙල්සන් මැන්ඩෙලා ජාත්‍යන්තර දිනය සමරයි. ලෝක ආයතනය විසින් එවැනි ජාත්‍යන්තර ගෞරවාදරයට පාත්‍ර වූ දේශපාලන නායකයන් අතලොස්ස අතරට ඔහු ද සිටී. මෙම අවස්ථාව සනිටුහන් කිරීම සඳහා ප්‍රකාශයක් නිකුත් කරමින් එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවිධානය මැන්ඩෙලා මහතාගේ ප්‍රබලතම ප්‍රකාශයක් උපුටා දක්වයි, එහිදී ඔහු පැවසුවේ, “එය බිඳ දැමීම සහ විනාශ කිරීම පහසුය. වීරයන් යනු සාමය ඇති කරන සහ ගොඩනඟන අයයි. ” ඔවුන්ගේ ප්‍රජාවන් තුළ වෙනසක් ඇති කරමින් දිනය සමරන ලෙස එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවිධානය සියලුම රටවලට සහ ජනතාවට ආරාධනා කර ඇත.",
        "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවිධානයට අනුව, ලෝකය යහපත් අතට හැරවීමේ හැකියාව සහ වගකීම සෑම කෙනෙකුටම ඇත. මැන්ඩෙලා දිනය යනු සියලු දෙනා ක්‍රියා කිරීමට සහ වෙනසක් ඇති කිරීමට අවස්ථාවකි. නෙල්සන් මැන්ඩෙලා මානව හිමිකම් නීතිඥයෙකු, හෘද සාක්ෂියේ සිරකරුවෙකු, ජාත්‍යන්තර සාමය ඇති කරන්නෙකු සහ නිදහස් දකුණු අප්‍රිකාවේ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදීව තේරී පත් වූ ප්‍රථම ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස - මානව වර්ගයාගේ සේවය සඳහා සිය ජීවිතය කැප කළේය. 2009 නොවැම්බර් මාසයේදී එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මහා මණ්ඩලය විසින් ජූලි 18 නෙල්සන් මැන්ඩෙලා ජාත්‍යන්තර දිනය ලෙස ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලදී. මෙම යෝජනාව මැන්ඩෙලා මහතාගේ වටිනාකම් සහ ගැටුම් නිරාකරණයේදී මනුෂ්‍යත්වයේ සේවය සඳහා වූ ඔහුගේ කැපවීම පිළිගනී. වර්ග සම්බන්ධතා; මානව හිමිකම් ප්රවර්ධනය සහ ආරක්ෂා කිරීම; සංහිඳියාව; ස්ත්‍රී පුරුෂ සමානාත්මතාවය සහ ළමුන්ගේ සහ අනෙකුත් අවදානම් කණ්ඩායම්වල අයිතිවාසිකම්; දරිද්රතාවයට එරෙහි සටන; සමාජ සාධාරණත්වය ප්රවර්ධනය කිරීම. ජාත්‍යන්තර වශයෙන් ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය සඳහා අරගලයට සහ ලොව පුරා සාමයේ සංස්කෘතියක් ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමට ඔහු කළ දායකත්වය මෙම යෝජනාව මගින් පිළිගනී.",
        "2018 සැප්තැම්බර් 24 වන දින, නෙල්සන් මැන්ඩෙලා සාම සමුළුව සඳහා ලෝක නායකයින් නිව් යෝර්ක් හි එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මූලස්ථානයට රැස් විය. සමුළුවේදී, රාජ්‍ය නායකයින්, අමාත්‍යවරුන්, සාමාජික රාජ්‍යයන් සහ සිවිල් සමාජ නියෝජිතයින් 100කට ආසන්න සංඛ්‍යාවක් සාධාරණ, සාමකාමී, සමෘද්ධිමත්, සියල්ලන් ඇතුළත් සහ සාධාරණ ලෝකයක් ගොඩනැගීමේ ප්‍රයත්නයන් දෙගුණ කිරීමට කැප වූ දේශපාලන ප්‍රකාශයක් සම්මත කළහ. දිවංගත දකුණු අප්‍රිකානු ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ කීර්තිමත් ගුණාංග සහ මනුෂ්‍යත්වයට කළ සේවය.",
        "2019 සිට 2028 දක්වා කාලය නෙල්සන් මැන්ඩෙලා සාම දශකය ලෙස පිළිගනිමින්, ප්‍රකාශනය මැන්ඩෙලා මහතාගේ නිහතමානීකම, සමාව දීම සහ දයාව වෙනුවෙන් ඔහුට ආචාර කරන අතර, ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය සඳහා වන අරගලයට සහ ලොව පුරා සාම සංස්කෘතියක් ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමට ඔහු කළ දායකත්වය ද පිළිගනී. . පෙළ මගින්, රාජ්‍ය නායකයින් සහ රජයේ සහ සාමාජික රාජ්‍ය නියෝජිතයින් සියලු රාජ්‍යවල ස්වෛරී සමානාත්මතාවය සහ ඔවුන්ගේ භෞමික අඛණ්ඩතාව සහ දේශපාලන ස්වාධීනත්වයට ගරු කිරීම සහ තර්ජනයෙන් හෝ බලය භාවිතා කිරීමෙන් වැළකී සිටීමේ සාමාජික රටවල යුතුකම තහවුරු කිරීමට ඔවුන්ගේ කැපවීම නැවත තහවුරු කළහ. සාමය සහ ආරක්ෂාව, සංවර්ධනය සහ මානව හිමිකම් එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ පද්ධතියේ කුළුණු සහ සාමූහික ආරක්ෂාව සහ යහපැවැත්ම සඳහා පදනම් වන බව පිළිගනිමින්, ප්‍රකාශනය තිරසාර සංවර්ධනය සඳහා 2030 න්‍යාය පත්‍රය නැවත තහවුරු කළේය.",
        "\"සාමකාමී, යුක්තිසහගත, සියල්ලන් ඇතුළත් සහ වෙනස් කොට සැලකීමකින් තොරව සමාජයන් ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමේදී වචනවලින් ඔබ්බට ගමන් කිරීමට අපි අධිෂ්ඨාන කරමු,\" නායකයින් ප්‍රතිඥා දුන්නේ කාන්තාවන් සහ තරුණයින්ගේ සමාන සහභාගීත්වයේ සහ පූර්ණ මැදිහත්වීමේ වැදගත්කම අවධාරණය කළ බැවිනි. ජාතිවාදය, විජාතික භීතිකාව සහ ඒ ආශ්‍රිත නොඉවසීම එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ අරමුණුවලට බෙහෙවින් ප්‍රතිවිරුද්ධ බව ඔවුන් ප්‍රකාශ කළ අතර විශේෂයෙන් සන්නද්ධ ගැටුම්වලදී දරුවන්ගේ අයිතිවාසිකම් ආරක්ෂා කිරීමට ඔවුන්ගේ අධිෂ්ඨානය අවධාරණය කළහ. “දරුවන් ආරක්ෂා කිරීම ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වයේ චක්‍රය බිඳ දැමීමට දායක වන අතර අනාගත සාමය සඳහා බීජ වපුරයි,” ප්‍රකාශනය පවසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අරගලයට හෝ රාජපක්ෂ රජයට එරෙහි මහජන කැරැල්ලට සම්බන්ධ මිලියන සංඛ්‍යාත තරුණ තරුණියන් සහ තවත් අය දින ගණන් ඉන්ධන පෝලිම්වල මිනිසුන් මිය යද්දී බොහෝ ප්‍රශ්න මතු කරති. ඔවුන්ගේ හදවතින් නැගෙන කෑගැසීම විය හැක්කේ \"අපට මැන්ඩෙලා කෙනෙක් දෙන්න\" යන්න විය හැකිය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "මැන්ඩෙලා",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ ආණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩඩ්ලි සේනානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1970",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරිමාවෝ බණ්ඩාරනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෑත යුගය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු අප්‍රිකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෙල්සන් මැන්ඩෙලා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දශක",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු අප්‍රිකානු රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු අප්‍රිකානු රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එංගලන්තය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් ඩි ඔලිවේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර ක්‍රිකට් කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු අප්රිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු අප්රිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෙල්සන් මැන්ඩෙලා ජාත්‍යන්තර දිනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එ.ජා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැන්ඩෙලා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එ.ජා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එ.ජා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැන්ඩෙලා දිනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෙල්සන් මැන්ඩෙලා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු අප්රිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009 නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මහා මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෙල්සන් මැන්ඩෙලා ජාත්‍යන්තර දිනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැන්ඩෙලා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2018 සැප්තැම්බර් 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මූලස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිව්යෝක්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෙල්සන් මැන්ඩෙලා සාම සමුළුව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය සහ රජයේ ප්රධානීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු අප්රිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නෙල්සන් මැන්ඩෙලා සාමයේ දශකය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැන්ඩෙලා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය සහ රජයේ ප්රධානීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එ.ජා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රකාශනය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "2030 න්‍යාය පත්‍රය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එ.ජා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ ආණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැන්ඩෙලා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"எங்களுக்கு ஒரு மண்டேலாவை கொடுங்கள்\" என இலங்கை மக்களின் கூக்குரல்.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ராஜபக்ச அரசாங்கம் முன்னோடியில்லாத அரகலயா அல்லது பொது கிளர்ச்சியை எதிர்கொண்டு, நாட்டின் பெரும்பாலான பகுதிகளில் மூன்று மாதங்களாக போராட்டங்கள் நடந்து வரும் நிலையில், இலங்கைக்கு தேர்தலுக்காக அல்லாமல் அடுத்த தலைமுறைக்காக உழைக்கும் ஒரு அரச தலைவர் தேவை. துரதிஷ்டவசமாக, 1948ல் சுதந்திரம் பெற்றதில் இருந்து இப்படியான அரச தலைவர்களை நாம் பார்த்திருக்கிறோம். முன்னாள் பிரதமர் டட்லி சேனநாயக்கா போன்ற தலைவர்கள் அத்தகைய நிலையை அடையும் நிலைக்கு வந்தாலும், 1970 பொதுத் தேர்தலில் அவர் அரிசி ரேஷன் இரண்டில் இருந்து குறைத்ததால் மக்கள் அவரையும் அவரது கட்சியையும் நிராகரித்தனர். ஒருவருக்கு கிலோ, வெற்றி பெற்ற பிரதமர் சிறிமாவோ பண்டாரநாயக்கா, நிலவில் இருந்து சோறு கூட கொண்டு வருவேன் என்று மக்களிடம் பெருமை பேசினார்.",
        "சமீப காலத்தில், தென்னாப்பிரிக்காவின் நெல்சன் மண்டேலா, தென்னாப்பிரிக்க அரசின் வெள்ளை மேலாதிக்கக் கொள்கைக்கு எதிராகப் பேசியதால், பல தசாப்தங்களாக சிறையில் அடைக்கப்பட்டு சித்திரவதை செய்யப்பட்டார், அவர் நிறவெறிக் கொள்கையில் நிற மக்களை ஒதுக்கி, அவமானப்படுத்தினார். இது கிட்டத்தட்ட முழு உலகத்தால் கண்டிக்கப்பட்டது. இந்த தீய மற்றும் மனிதாபிமானமற்ற கொள்கையானது, தென்னாப்பிரிக்க அரசாங்கம் இங்கிலாந்து அணியின் கிரிக்கெட் சுற்றுப்பயணத்தை தடை செய்தபோது விளையாட்டு உட்பட பல்வேறு துறைகளை பாதித்தது, ஏனெனில் அணியில் ஒரு வண்ண வீரர் பசில் டி'ஒலிவேரா இருந்தார். இதன் விளைவாக, சர்வதேச கிரிக்கெட் கவுன்சில் (ஐசிசி) தென்னாப்பிரிக்காவை டெஸ்ட் கிரிக்கெட்டில் இருந்து தடை செய்தது மற்றும் இது ஒரு சோகமான நிகழ்வாகும், ஏனெனில் தென்னாப்பிரிக்க அணி உலகின் சிறந்த வீரர்கள் சிலரை உள்ளடக்கியது.",
        "அடுத்த வாரம் ஜூலை 18 அன்று, ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபை நெல்சன் மண்டேலா சர்வதேச தினத்தைக் குறிக்கிறது. உலக அமைப்பால் இத்தகைய சர்வதேச கௌரவம் பெற்ற சில அரசியல் தலைவர்களில் அவரும் ஒருவர். இந்த நிகழ்வைக் குறிக்கும் ஒரு அறிக்கையில், ஐ.நா., திரு. மண்டேலாவின் மிக சக்திவாய்ந்த அறிக்கைகளில் ஒன்றை மேற்கோளிட்டுள்ளது, அதில் அவர் கூறினார், \"இதை உடைத்து அழிப்பது எளிது. சமாதானம் செய்து கட்டியெழுப்புபவர்களே ஹீரோக்கள்”. ஐநா அனைத்து நாடுகளையும் மக்களையும் தங்கள் சமூகங்களில் மாற்றத்தை ஏற்படுத்துவதன் மூலம் தினத்தை கொண்டாட அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபையின் கூற்றுப்படி, உலகை சிறப்பாக மாற்றும் திறனும் பொறுப்பும் அனைவருக்கும் உள்ளது. மண்டேலா தினம் என்பது அனைவரும் நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கவும் மாற்றத்தை ஊக்குவிக்கவும் ஒரு சந்தர்ப்பம். மனித உரிமை வழக்கறிஞராக, மனசாட்சியின் கைதியாக, சர்வதேச சமாதானம் செய்பவராக, சுதந்திர தென்னாப்பிரிக்காவின் ஜனநாயக ரீதியில் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட முதல் ஜனாதிபதியாக - மனிதகுலத்தின் சேவைக்காக நெல்சன் மண்டேலா தனது வாழ்க்கையை அர்ப்பணித்தார். நவம்பர் 2009 இல், ஐநா பொதுச் சபை ஜூலை 18 ஐ நெல்சன் மண்டேலா சர்வதேச தினமாக அறிவித்தது. தீர்மானம் திரு. மண்டேலாவின் மதிப்புகள் மற்றும் மோதலைத் தீர்ப்பதில் மனிதகுலத்தின் சேவைக்கான அவரது அர்ப்பணிப்பை அங்கீகரிக்கிறது; இன உறவுகள்; மனித உரிமைகளை மேம்படுத்துதல் மற்றும் பாதுகாத்தல்; நல்லிணக்கம்; பாலின சமத்துவம் மற்றும் குழந்தைகள் மற்றும் பிற பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடிய குழுக்களின் உரிமைகள்; வறுமைக்கு எதிரான போராட்டம்; சமூக நீதியை மேம்படுத்துதல். சர்வதேச அளவில் ஜனநாயகத்திற்கான போராட்டத்திற்கும், உலகம் முழுவதும் அமைதி கலாச்சாரத்தை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கும் அவர் ஆற்றிய பங்களிப்பை தீர்மானம் அங்கீகரிக்கிறது.",
        "செப்டம்பர் 24, 2018 அன்று, நெல்சன் மண்டேலா அமைதி உச்சி மாநாட்டிற்காக உலகத் தலைவர்கள் நியூயார்க்கில் உள்ள ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் தலைமையகத்தில் கூடினர். உச்சிமாநாட்டில், ஏறக்குறைய 100 மாநில மற்றும் அரசாங்கத் தலைவர்கள், அமைச்சர்கள், உறுப்பு நாடுகள் மற்றும் சிவில் சமூகத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகள், நீதியான, அமைதியான, வளமான, அனைவரையும் உள்ளடக்கிய மற்றும் நியாயமான உலகைக் கட்டியெழுப்புவதற்கான முயற்சிகளை இரட்டிப்பாக்க உறுதிபூண்ட அரசியல் பிரகடனத்தை ஏற்றுக்கொண்டனர். மறைந்த தென்னாப்பிரிக்க ஜனாதிபதியின் போற்றப்படும் குணங்கள் மற்றும் மனித குல சேவை.",
        "2019 முதல் 2028 வரையிலான காலத்தை நெல்சன் மண்டேலா அமைதியின் தசாப்தமாக அங்கீகரித்து, பிரகடனம் திரு. மண்டேலாவின் பணிவு, மன்னிப்பு மற்றும் இரக்கத்திற்காக அவருக்கு வணக்கம் செலுத்தியது. . உரையின் மூலம், மாநிலத் தலைவர்கள் மற்றும் அரசு மற்றும் உறுப்பு நாடுகளின் பிரதிநிதிகள் அனைத்து மாநிலங்களின் இறையாண்மை சமத்துவத்தையும், அவர்களின் பிராந்திய ஒருமைப்பாடு மற்றும் அரசியல் சுதந்திரத்திற்கான மரியாதையையும், அச்சுறுத்தல் அல்லது சக்தியைப் பயன்படுத்துவதைத் தவிர்ப்பதற்கான உறுப்பு நாடுகளின் கடமையையும் நிலைநிறுத்துவதற்கான தங்கள் உறுதிப்பாட்டை மீண்டும் உறுதிப்படுத்தினர். அமைதி மற்றும் பாதுகாப்பு, வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் மனித உரிமைகள் ஆகியவை ஐ.நா அமைப்பின் தூண்கள் மற்றும் கூட்டு பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் நல்வாழ்வுக்கான அடித்தளங்கள் என்பதை உணர்ந்து, பிரகடனம் நிலையான வளர்ச்சிக்கான 2030 நிகழ்ச்சி நிரலை மீண்டும் உறுதிப்படுத்தியது.",
        "பெண்கள் மற்றும் இளைஞர்களின் சம பங்கேற்பு மற்றும் முழு ஈடுபாட்டின் முக்கியத்துவத்தை வலியுறுத்திய தலைவர்கள், \"அமைதியான, நீதியான, உள்ளடக்கிய மற்றும் பாரபட்சமற்ற சமூகங்களை மேம்படுத்துவதில் வார்த்தைகளுக்கு அப்பால் செல்ல நாங்கள் தீர்மானிக்கிறோம்\" என்று உறுதியளித்தனர். இனவெறி, இனவெறி மற்றும் அதனுடன் தொடர்புடைய சகிப்புத்தன்மையின்மை ஆகியவை ஐ.நா.வின் நோக்கங்களுக்கு முற்றிலும் எதிரானவை என்றும் அவர்கள் அறிவித்தனர் மற்றும் குறிப்பாக ஆயுத மோதலில் குழந்தைகளின் உரிமைகளைப் பாதுகாப்பதற்கான தங்கள் உறுதியை வலியுறுத்தினர். \"குழந்தைகளைப் பாதுகாப்பது வன்முறையின் சுழற்சியை உடைப்பதில் பங்களிக்கிறது மற்றும் எதிர்கால அமைதிக்கான விதைகளை விதைக்கிறது\" என்று பிரகடனம் கூறுகிறது.",
        "இலங்கையின் அரகலயா அல்லது ராஜபக்ச அரசுக்கு எதிரான பொதுக் கிளர்ச்சியில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள மில்லியன் கணக்கான இளைஞர்களும் மற்றவர்களும் பல பிரச்சினைகளை எழுப்பி வருகின்றனர். \"எங்களுக்கு ஒரு மண்டேலாவைக் கொடுங்கள்\" என்று அவர்களின் இதயத்திலிருந்து கூக்குரலாக இருக்கலாம்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "மண்டேலா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்ச அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டட்லி சேனாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1970",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறிமாவோ பண்டாரநாயக்கா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமீபத்திய சகாப்தம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் ஆப்பிரிக்காவின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நெல்சன் மண்டேலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தாண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்னாப்பிரிக்க அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்னாப்பிரிக்க அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இங்கிலாந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் டி'ஒலிவேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச கிரிக்கெட் கவுன்சில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்னாப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்னாப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நெல்சன் மண்டேலா சர்வதேச தினம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மண்டேலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மண்டேலா தினம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நெல்சன் மண்டேலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்னாப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நெல்சன் மண்டேலா சர்வதேச தினம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மண்டேலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 24, 2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் தலைமையகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நியூயார்க்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நெல்சன் மண்டேலா அமைதி உச்சி மாநாடு",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநில மற்றும் அரசாங்கத் தலைவர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்னாப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நெல்சன் மண்டேலா அமைதிப் பத்தாண்டு",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மண்டேலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநில மற்றும் அரசாங்கத் தலைவர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரகடனம்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "2030 நிகழ்ச்சி நிரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மில்லியன்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்ச அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாட்களில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மண்டேலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}