{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/BIA-Customs-thwart-attempt-to-smuggle-in-Rs-16mn-worth-fags-with-five-inbound-passengers/342-243851",
  "time_ut": 1661573227,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "BIA Customs thwart attempt to smuggle in Rs.16mn worth fags with five inbound passengers",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "BIA Customs thwart attempt to smuggle in Rs.16mn worth fags with five inbound passengers",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Five passengers coming from Oman with a large stock of counterfeit cigarettes worth over Rs.16 million was seized by Sri Lanka Customs at the Bandaranaike International Airport (BIA) yesterday morning.",
        "Customs officials at the BIA Arrival Terminal on suspicion searched a group of male passengers coming on an Oman Airline flight WY612 at 7.45am yesterday and found the large stock of foreign cigarettes in their baggages.",
        "The sleuths found 162, 000 sticks of cigarettes of Marlboro and Manchester in 810 cartons, which had been valued at Rs.1,650,000, the Customs sources said. The suspects who are aged between 24 and 45 years were residents of Maligawatta, Chilaw and Moratuwa.",
        "The Customs detection was conducted by Assistant Superintendents Jude Fernando, Rasika Ariyasena, Ruwan Perera and Naveen Matharage on the instructions of Customs Superintendents Sugandi Padmanadan, K. Pallawala and Indunil Udaya.",
        "The counterfeit cigarettes were forfeited and a fine of Rs.25, 000 was imposed on each suspect. (KURULU KOOJANA KARIYAKARAWANA)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "five",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oman",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Customs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bandaranaike International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Customs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the BIA Arrival Terminal",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oman Airline",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "162",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marlboro",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manchester",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "810",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs.1,650,000",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Customs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "between 24 and 45 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maligawatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chilaw and Moratuwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Customs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jude Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rasika Ariyasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ruwan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sugandi Padmanadan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "K. Pallawala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indunil Udaya",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "KURULU KOOJANA KARIYAKARAWANA",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගුවන් මගීන් පස් දෙනෙකු සමඟ රුපියල් මිලියන 16ක් වටිනා මත්කුඩු නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස ප්‍රවාහනය කිරීමට ගත් උත්සාහය BIA රේගුව ව්‍යර්ථ කරයි.",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රුපියල් මිලියන 16කට අධික වටිනාකමකින් යුත් ව්‍යාජ දුම්වැටි තොගයක් සමඟ ඕමානයේ සිට පැමිණි මගීන් 5 දෙනෙකු බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළේදී (BIA) ඊයේ පෙරවරුවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා රේගු භාරයට ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "BIA පැමිණීමේ පර්යන්තයේ රේගු නිලධාරීන් විසින් ඊයේ පෙරවරු 7.45 ට ඕමාන් ගුවන් සේවයේ WY612 දරන ගුවන් යානයෙන් පැමිණි පිරිමි මගීන් පිරිසක් සැකපිට පරීක්‍ෂා කිරීමේදී ඔවුන්ගේ ගමන් මලුවල තිබී මෙම විශාල විදේශීය දුම්වැටි තොගය සොයා ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "පෙට්ටි 810ක තිබී Marlboro සහ Manchester වර්ගයේ දුම්වැටි කූරු 162,000ක් සොයා ගත් අතර, ඒවායේ වටිනාකම රුපියල් 1,650,000ක් බව රේගු ආරංචි මාර්ග පවසයි. සැකකරුවන් අවුරුදු 24ත් 45ත් අතර වයස්වල පසුවන මාලිගාවත්ත, හලාවත සහ මොරටුව ප්‍රදේශවල පදිංචිකරුවන්.",
        "රේගු අධිකාරීවරුන් වන සුගන්දි පද්මනාදන්, කේ.පල්ලාවල සහ ඉඳුනිල් උදය යන මහත්වරුන්ගේ උපදෙස් මත සහකාර රේගු අධීක්‍ෂණ කටයුතු ජූඩ් ප්‍රනාන්දු, රසික ආරියසේන, රුවන් පෙරේරා, නවීන් මාතරගේ යන මහත්වරුන් විසින් සිදු කරන ලදී.",
        "ව්‍යාජ දුම්වැටි රාජසන්තක කර ඇති අතර එක් සැකකරුවෙකුට රුපියල් 25,000 බැගින් දඩ මුදලක් ද නියම කෙරුණා. (කුරුළු කූජන කාරියකරවන)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පහ",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රේගුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රේගුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BIA පැමිණීමේ පර්යන්තය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමාන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "162",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාල්බෝරෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැන්චෙස්ටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "810",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල් 1,650,000",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රේගුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 24 සහ 45 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලිගාවත්ත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හලාවත සහ මොරටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රේගුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූඩ් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රසික ආරියසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුවන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුගන්දි පද්මනාදන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේ පල්ලාවල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉඳුනිල් උදය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුරුලු කූජන කාරියකරවන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஐந்து உள்வரும் பயணிகளுடன் ரூ.16 மில்லியன் மதிப்புள்ள பாக்குகளை கடத்தும் முயற்சியை BIA சுங்கத்துறை முறியடித்தது.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "16 மில்லியன் ரூபா பெறுமதியான போலி சிகரெட்டுகளுடன் ஓமானில் இருந்து வந்த ஐந்து பயணிகள் நேற்று காலை பண்டாரநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தில் (BIA) இலங்கை சுங்க அதிகாரிகளால் கைப்பற்றப்பட்டனர்.",
        "நேற்று காலை 7.45 மணியளவில் ஓமன் ஏர்லைன் விமானம் WY612 இல் வந்து கொண்டிருந்த ஆண் பயணிகளை சந்தேகத்தின் பேரில் BIA வருகை முனையத்தில் உள்ள சுங்க அதிகாரிகள் சோதனையிட்டபோது, ​​அவர்களது பைகளில் வெளிநாட்டு சிகரெட்டுகள் அதிக அளவில் இருப்பதைக் கண்டனர்.",
        "810 அட்டைப்பெட்டிகளில் மார்ல்போரோ மற்றும் மான்செஸ்டர் சிகரெட்டுகளின் 162,000 குச்சிகள் இருந்ததாகவும், அதன் மதிப்பு ரூ.1,650,000 என்றும் சுங்கத்துறை வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன. மாளிகாவத்தை, சிலாபம் மற்றும் மொரட்டுவை ஆகிய பிரதேசங்களைச் சேர்ந்த 24 மற்றும் 45 வயதுடைய சந்தேகநபர்கள்.",
        "சுங்க அத்தியட்சகர்களான சுகந்தி பத்மநாதன், கே.பல்லவல மற்றும் இந்துனில் உதய ஆகியோரின் அறிவுறுத்தலின் பேரில் உதவி அத்தியட்சகர்களான ஜூட் பெர்னாண்டோ, ரசிக ஆரியசேன, ருவன் பெரேரா மற்றும் நவீன் மாதரகே ஆகியோரினால் சுங்கக் கண்டறிதல் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டது.",
        "போலி சிகரெட்டுகள் பறிமுதல் செய்யப்பட்டதுடன், சந்தேகநபர்கள் ஒவ்வொருவருக்கும் தலா 25,000 ரூபாய் அபராதம் விதிக்கப்பட்டது. (குருலு கூஜன காரியகரவன)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஐந்து",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்கா சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BIA வருகை முனையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "162",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ல்போரோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மான்செஸ்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "810",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ.1,650,000",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 மற்றும் 45 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாளிகாவத்தை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிலாபம் மற்றும் மொரட்டுவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூட் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரசிக ஆரியசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ருவன் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகந்தி பத்மநாதன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கே. பல்லவல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்துனில் உதயா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குருலு கூஜன காரியகாரவன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}