{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/US-will-support-SL-through-IMF-if-agreement-reached-Julie-Chung/342-243963",
  "time_ut": 1661793667,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "US will support SL through IMF, if agreement reached: Julie Chung",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "US will support SL through IMF, if agreement reached: Julie Chung",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The US will support Sri Lanka through International Monetary Fund (IMF), if Sri Lanka could reach an agreement with the IMF, US Ambassador to Sri Lanka Julie Chung said.",
        "She said in a twitter post that the US will redouble its endeavours to support Sri Lanka through ongoing efforts such as financing for SMEs, fertilizer and seeds for farmers, education exchange and training to strengthen public financial management.",
        "In her tweet she also mentioned that she spoke with the US-SL Business Council on ways US and Sri Lanka businesses can collaborate to ensure Sri Lanka gets back on a path to prosperity.",
        "\"US-SL bilateral trade already supports more than 180,000 workers supplying exports to the US and contribute billions to the Sri Lanka's economy,\" she tweeted."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Julie Chung",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 180,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "එකඟතාවයකට පැමිණියහොත්, IMF හරහා එක්සත් ජනපදය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය දෙනු ඇත: ජූලි චුන්ග්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ එකඟතාවකට පැමිණිය හැකි නම්, එක්සත් ජනපදය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) හරහා සහය දෙන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඇමරිකානු තානාපතිනි Julie Chung පවසයි.",
        "ඇය ට්විටර් සටහනක් තබමින් කියා සිටියේ කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයින් සඳහා මූල්‍යකරණය, ගොවීන් සඳහා පොහොර සහ බීජ, අධ්‍යාපන හුවමාරුව සහ රාජ්‍ය මූල්‍ය කළමනාකරණය ශක්තිමත් කිරීම සඳහා පුහුණුව වැනි අඛණ්ඩ ප්‍රයත්නයන් හරහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය දැක්වීමට එක්සත් ජනපදය දරන උත්සාහය දෙගුණ කරන බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සෞභාග්‍යයේ මාවතකට නැවත පැමිණීම සහතික කිරීම සඳහා එක්සත් ජනපද සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ව්‍යාපාරවලට සහයෝගයෙන් ක්‍රියා කළ හැකි ක්‍රම පිළිබඳව ඇය එක්සත් ජනපද-ශ්‍රී ලංකා ව්‍යාපාරික කවුන්සිලය සමඟ කතා කළ බව ද ඇය සිය ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයේ සඳහන් කළාය.",
        "\"US-SL ද්විපාර්ශ්වික වෙළඳාම දැනටමත් එක්සත් ජනපදයට අපනයන සපයන කම්කරුවන් 180,000 කට වැඩි පිරිසකට සහාය වන අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථිකයට බිලියන ගණනින් දායක වේ,\" ඇය ට්වීට් කළාය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්යන්තර මූල්ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "180,000 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "உடன்பாடு எட்டப்பட்டால் IMF மூலம் SL ஐ அமெரிக்கா ஆதரிக்கும்: ஜூலி சுங்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் (IMF) உடன்பாட்டை எட்டினால், அமெரிக்கா இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவளிக்கும் என இலங்கைக்கான அமெரிக்க தூதுவர் ஜூலி சுங் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "SME களுக்கு நிதியுதவி, விவசாயிகளுக்கு உரம் மற்றும் விதைகள், கல்வி பரிமாற்றம் மற்றும் பொது நிதி நிர்வாகத்தை வலுப்படுத்துவதற்கான பயிற்சி போன்ற தொடர்ச்சியான முயற்சிகள் மூலம் இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதற்கான தனது முயற்சிகளை அமெரிக்கா இரட்டிப்பாக்கும் என்று அவர் தனது ட்விட்டர் பதிவில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அவர் தனது ட்வீட்டில், இலங்கை மீண்டும் செழிப்புக்கான பாதையில் செல்வதை உறுதி செய்வதற்காக அமெரிக்கா மற்றும் இலங்கை வணிகங்கள் ஒத்துழைக்கக்கூடிய வழிகள் குறித்து அமெரிக்க-ஸ்ரீல வர்த்தக சபையுடன் பேசியதாகவும் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "\"US-SL இருதரப்பு வர்த்தகம் ஏற்கனவே 180,000 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட தொழிலாளர்களை அமெரிக்காவிற்கு ஏற்றுமதி செய்வதை ஆதரிக்கிறது மற்றும் இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரத்திற்கு பில்லியன்களை பங்களிக்கிறது\" என்று அவர் ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "180,000க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}