{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-cpc-may-need-treasurys-help-to-repay-indias-700-mln-minister-96533/",
  "time_ut": 1656334440,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’ CPC may need Treasury’s help to repay India’s $700 mln – minister",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’ CPC may need Treasury’s help to repay India’s $700 mln – minister",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s state-run fuel retailer Ceylon Petroleum Corporation will need the help of the island nation’s Treasury when the repayment of $700 million Indian credit line starts, Power and Energy Minister Kanchan Wijesekera said.",
        "Sri Lanka has already borrowed $700 million from India to finance its fuel requirement from March and the last shipment arrived in on June 16 under the two credit line – $500 million fuel credit time and $200 million essential commodity credit line.",
        "The credit lines for one year and Minister Wijesekera said the CPC has already started collecting rupees for the repayment, which starts in March 2023.",
        "“Our responsibility is to collect the rupee value pay the $700 million. The payment starts in March next year,” Wijesekera told reporters at a media briefing in Colombo on Sunday (26) at the Ministry of Power and Energy.",
        "“Of course we will have to get some sort of support from treasury as well because, even though during the $700 million credit line the prices were adjusted, initially in March and April, the CPC and IOC were selling fuel at a much lower price than what we had import at. So there will be a bridging gap. That gap will be bridged by treasury.”",
        "Wijesekera last month said a fresh $500 million fuel credit which is under discussion will have a grace period of more than one year.",
        "Sri Lanka has been looking for the fresh credit line as the CPC has failed to ensure any shipment since the last fuel cargo came from the Indian credit line on June 16. (Colombo/June 27/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "CPC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Treasury",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "700",
          "label": "MONEY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$700 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Power and Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchan Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$700 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "March",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "$500 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$200 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "March 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$700 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "March next year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Power and Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$700 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "March",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IOC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$500 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than one year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/June 27/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියාවේ ඩොලර් මිලියන 700 ආපසු ගෙවීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවට භාණ්ඩාගාරයේ සහාය අවශ්‍ය විය හැකිය - ඇමති",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රාජ්‍ය ඉන්ධන සිල්ලර වෙළෙන්දෙකු වන ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවට ඩොලර් මිලියන 700 ක ඉන්දීය ණය ආපසු ගෙවීම ආරම්භ වන විට දිවයිනේ භාණ්ඩාගාරයේ සහාය අවශ්‍ය වනු ඇතැයි විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචන් විජේසේකර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දැනටමත් මාර්තු මාසයේ සිට සිය ඉන්ධන අවශ්‍යතාවයට මුදල් සැපයීම සඳහා ඉන්දියාවෙන් ඩොලර් මිලියන 700ක් ණයට ගෙන ඇති අතර, ඩොලර් මිලියන 500ක ඉන්ධන ණය කාලය සහ ඩොලර් මිලියන 200ක අත්‍යවශ්‍ය භාණ්ඩ ණය රේඛාව යන ණය රේඛාව යටතේ අවසන් නැව්ගත කිරීම ජුනි 16 වැනි දින පැමිණ ඇත.",
        "වසරක් සඳහා ණය ලබාදී ඇති අතර, 2023 මාර්තු මාසයේදී ආරම්භ වන ආපසු ගෙවීම සඳහා තෙල් සංස්ථාව රුපියල් එකතු කිරීම දැනටමත් ආරම්භ කර ඇති බව විජේසේකර අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "“අපේ වගකීම වන්නේ රුපියල් මිලියන 700 ගෙවීමට රුපියල එකතු කිරීමයි. ලබන වසරේ මාර්තු මාසයේදී ගෙවීම ආරම්භ කරනවා,” විජේසේකර ඉරිදා (26) කොළඹදී විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍යාංශයේ පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී මාධ්‍යවේදීන් අමතමින් පැවසීය.",
        "“ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම අපට භාණ්ඩාගාරයෙන් ද යම් ආකාරයක සහයෝගයක් ලබා ගැනීමට සිදුවනු ඇත, මන්ද, ඩොලර් මිලියන 700 ක ණය සීමාව තුළ මිල ගණන් සකස් කළද, මුලින් මාර්තු සහ අප්‍රේල් මාසවලදී, CPC සහ IOC ඉන්ධන අලෙවි කළේ වඩා බෙහෙවින් අඩු මිලකට ය. අපි ආනයනය කළ දේ. එබැවින් පාලම් පරතරයක් ඇති වනු ඇත. එම පරතරය භාණ්ඩාගාරය මගින් පියවනු ඇත.",
        "විජේසේකර පසුගිය මාසයේ පැවසුවේ සාකච්ඡාවට ලක්ව ඇති ඩොලර් මිලියන 500 ක ඉන්ධන ණය සඳහා වසරකට වැඩි සහන කාලයක් පවතින බවයි.",
        "ජූනි 16 වැනි දින ඉන්දීය ණය මාර්ගයෙන් අවසන් ඉන්ධන භාණ්ඩ තොගය පැමිණි දා සිට කිසිදු නැව්ගත කිරීමක් සහතික කිරීමට CPC අපොහොසත් වූ බැවින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව නැවුම් ණය මාර්ගයක් සොයමින් සිටී. (කොළඹ/ජූනි 27/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "CPC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "700",
          "label": "MONEY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 700 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදුලි බල හා බලශක්ති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන් විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 700 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 500 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 200 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වසරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023 මාර්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 700 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන වසරේ මාර්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 700 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයි.ඕ.සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 500 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරකට වැඩි කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජුනි 27/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் CPC இந்தியாவின் 700 மில்லியன் டாலர்களை திருப்பிச் செலுத்த கருவூலத்தின் உதவி தேவைப்படலாம் - அமைச்சர்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - இலங்கையின் அரசால் நடத்தப்படும் எரிபொருள் சில்லறை விற்பனையாளரான சிலோன் பெட்ரோலியம் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்திற்கு 700 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்கள் இந்தியக் கடனைத் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தத் தொடங்கும் போது தீவு நாட்டின் திறைசேரியின் உதவி தேவைப்படும் என மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் கஞ்சன் விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கை தனது எரிபொருள் தேவையை மார்ச் மாதத்தில் இருந்து பெறுவதற்காக இந்தியாவிடமிருந்து 700 மில்லியன் டாலர்களை ஏற்கனவே கடனாகப் பெற்றுள்ளது மற்றும் கடைசி ஏற்றுமதி ஜூன் 16 அன்று இரண்டு கடன் வரியின் கீழ் வந்தது - $500 மில்லியன் எரிபொருள் கடன் நேரம் மற்றும் $200 மில்லியன் அத்தியாவசிய பொருட்கள் கடன் வரி.",
        "ஒரு வருடத்திற்கான கடன் வரிகள் மற்றும் அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகர, CPC ஏற்கனவே 2023 ஆம் ஆண்டு மார்ச் மாதம் தொடங்கும் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தலுக்கான ரூபாய்களை வசூலிக்கத் தொடங்கியுள்ளது என்றார்.",
        "700 மில்லியன் டாலர் தொகையை செலுத்துவதே எங்கள் பொறுப்பு. அடுத்த வருடம் மார்ச் மாதம் இந்த கொடுப்பனவு ஆரம்பமாகும்” என மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சில் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை (26) கொழும்பில் நடைபெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"நிச்சயமாக கருவூலத்திலிருந்தும் ஒருவித ஆதரவைப் பெற வேண்டும், ஏனெனில் $700 மில்லியன் கடன் வரியின் போது விலைகள் சரிசெய்யப்பட்டாலும், ஆரம்பத்தில் மார்ச் மற்றும் ஏப்ரல் மாதங்களில், CPC மற்றும் IOC ஆகியவை எரிபொருளை விட மிகக் குறைந்த விலையில் விற்பனை செய்தன. நாம் எதை இறக்குமதி செய்தோம். அதனால் ஒரு பாலம் இடைவெளி இருக்கும். அந்த இடைவெளி கருவூலத்தால் குறைக்கப்படும்.",
        "விஜேசேகர கடந்த மாதம் புதிய $500 மில்லியன் எரிபொருள் கடனுக்கான விவாதத்தில் இருக்கும் ஒரு வருடத்திற்கும் மேலாக சலுகைக் காலம் இருக்கும் என்றார்.",
        "ஜூன் 16 அன்று இந்தியக் கடன் வரியிலிருந்து கடைசியாக எரிபொருள் சரக்கு வந்ததிலிருந்து CPC எந்த கப்பலையும் உறுதி செய்யத் தவறியதால், புதிய கடன் வரியை இலங்கை தேடுகிறது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூன் 27/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "CPC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "கருவூலம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "700",
          "label": "MONEY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$700 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சக்தி மற்றும் ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சன் விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$700 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "$500 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$200 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$700 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த ஆண்டு மார்ச்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$700 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐஓசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$500 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வருடத்திற்கும் மேலாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூன் 27/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}