{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/world_news/තායිලන්ත-අගමැතිගේ-ධුරය-අත්හිටුවයි/14-618683",
  "time_ut": 1661335894,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "තායිලන්ත අගමැතිගේ ධුරය අත්හිටුවයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Thailand's Prime Minister suspended",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The country's Constitutional Court decided today (24) to suspend the tenure of the Prime Minister of Thailand, Prayuth Chan-o-cha.",
        "The Constitutional Court suspended the tenure of the Prime Minister while hearing a petition submitted by the opposition political groups on tenure.",
        "Taiwanese media have reported that Prawit Wong Suwan, who served as Deputy Prime Minister after the temporary suspension of the position of Prayuth Chan-o-cha, who is also a former army general, will begin his duties as caretaker Prime Minister.",
        "In 2014, General Prayuth Chan-o-cha was the Chief of Army Staff of Thailand. Considering the instability in Thai politics at that time, General Prayuth Chan-o-cha led the army and seized power in the country through a coup. And without any bloodshed.",
        "General Prayuth Chan-o-cha served as the head of the military junta that was established for 5 years. However, in 2019, he took steps to hold a general election confirming democracy.",
        "Prayuth Chan-o-cha, who had resigned as army commander, ran as a civilian and won by rallying pro-military political groups. Sworn in as a civilian Prime Minister, Prayuth Chan-o-cha took office in July 2019.",
        "According to the Thai constitution, the term of office of the Prime Minister of Thailand is 8 years. Thai opposition groups had continuously pointed out that Prayuth Chan-o-cha's tenure as Prime Minister would end today (24), as he served as both a military commander and a civilian.",
        "The opposition political groups pointed that out in a petition to the Constitutional Court. Accordingly, the court decided to suspend Prayuth Chan-o-cha's tenure.",
        "The Constitutional Court, which is set to hear the petition, will extend its tenure as head of the military junta to its tenure as civilian prime minister.",
        "It also says that Prayuth Chan-o-cha will be able to continue as Prime Minister if it is ruled impossible to add."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Thailand",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Constitutional Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prayuth Chan-o",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Constitutional Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Taiwanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prawit Wong Suwan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prayuth Chan-o-cha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prayuth Chan-o",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army Staff",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thai",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prayuth Chan-o",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prayuth Chan-o",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prayuth Chan-o-cha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prayuth Chan-o",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thai",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thai",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prayuth Chan-o-cha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Constitutional Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prayuth Chan-o-cha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Constitutional Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prayuth Chan-o-cha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තායිලන්ත අගමැතිගේ ධුරය අත්හිටුවයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "තායිලන්ත අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ප්‍රයුත් චාන්-ඕ-චාගේ ධුර කාලය අත් හිටුවීමට එරට ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා අධිකරණය අද (24) තීරණය කළේය.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා අධිකරණය අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ ධුර කාලය මෙසේ අත්හිටු වූයේ ධුර කාලය පිළිබඳ විපක්ෂ දේශපාලන කණ්ඩායම් ඉදිරිපත් කළ පෙත්සමක් විභාග කරමිණි.",
        "හිටපු හමුදා ජනරාල්වරයකු ද වන ප්‍රයුත් චාන්-ඕ-චාගේ ධුරය තාවකාලික අත්හිටුවීමෙන් පසු නියෝජ්‍ය අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ලෙස කටයුතු කළ ප්‍රවිත් වොන්ග් සුවන් භාරකාර අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස රාජකාරි අරඹනු ඇතැයි තායිවාන මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කර තිබේ.",
        "2014 වසරේ තායිලන්ත හමුදා ප්‍රධානියා ලෙස කටයුතු කළේ ජනරාල් ප්‍රයුත් චාන්-ඕ-චා ය. එම කාලයේ තායිලන්ත දේශපාලනයේ පැවැති අස්ථාවරත්වය සැලකිල්ලට ගනිමින් ජනරාල් ප්‍රයුත් චාන්-ඕ-චා හමුදාව මෙහෙයවා කුමන්ත්‍රණයකින් රටේ බලය අල්ලා ගත්තේය. ඒ, කිසිදු ලේ වැගිරීමකින් තොරවය.",
        "ඉන්පසු පිහිටුවූ හමුදා ජුන්ටාවේ ප්‍රධානියා ලෙස ජනරාල් ප්‍රයුත් චාන්-ඕ-චා වසර 5 ක් කටයුතු කළේය. කෙසේ නමුත් 2019 දී ඔහු ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය තහවුරු කරමින් මහ මැතිවරණයක් පැවැත්වීමට පියවර ගත්තේය.",
        "හමුදාපති ධුරයෙන් ඉවත් වූ ප්‍රයුත් චාන්-ඕ-චා, සිවිල් වැසියකු ලෙස හමුදාවට හිතවත් දේශපාලන කණ්ඩායම් එක් කර ගනිමින් ඊට ඉදිරිපත් වී ජය ගත්තේය. සිවිල් අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයකු ලෙස දිවුරුම් දී ප්‍රයුත් චාන්-ඕ-චා රාජකාරි ආරම්භ ​කළේ 2019 ජූලි මාසයේය.",
        "තායිලන්ත ව්‍යවස්ථාවට අනුව, තායිලන්ත අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ ධුර කාලය වසර 8 කි. ප්‍රයුත් චාන්-ඕ-චා හමුදාපති ලෙසත්, සිවිල් වැසියකු ලෙසත් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරයේ කටයුතු කළ බැවින් ඔහුගේ ධුර කාලය අද (24) අවසන් වන බව තායිලන්ත විපක්ෂ කණ්ඩායම් දිගින් දිගටම පෙන්වා දී තිබුණි.",
        "විපක්ෂ දේශපාලන කණ්ඩායම් ඒ බව ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා අධිකරණයට පෙත්සමක් ඉදිරිපත් කරමින් පෙන්වා දුන්නේය. ඒ අනුව, ප්‍රයුත් චාන්-ඕ-චාගේ ධුර කාලය අත් හිටුවීමට අධිකරණය තීරණය කළේය.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා අධිකරණය, පෙත්සම විභාග කිරීමට නියමිතව ඇති අතර, මිලිටරි ජුන්ටාවේ ප්‍රධානියා ලෙස කටයුතු කළ කාලය, සිවිල් අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කළ ධුර කාලයට",
        "එකතු කළ නොහැකි බවට තීන්දු කළහොත් ප්‍රයුත් චාන්-ඕ-චා ට දිගටම අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරය හෙබවීමට හැකි වනු ඇතැයි ද පැවැසෙයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තායිලන්තය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථා අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රයුත් චාන්-ඕ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථා අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තායිවාන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prawit Wong Suwan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prayuth Chan-o-cha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රයුත් චාන්-ඕ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රයුත් චාන්-ඕ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රයුත් චාන්-ඕ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර 5 ක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prayuth Chan-o-cha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රයුත් චාන්-ඕ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තායි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 8 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prayuth Chan-o-cha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථා අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prayuth Chan-o-cha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථා අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prayuth Chan-o-cha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தாய்லாந்து பிரதமர் சஸ்பெண்ட் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தாய்லாந்து பிரதமர் பிரயுத் சான்-ஓ-சாவின் பதவிக்காலத்தை இடைநிறுத்த அந்நாட்டு அரசியலமைப்பு நீதிமன்றம் இன்று (24) தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "பிரதமரின் பதவிக்காலம் தொடர்பாக எதிர்க்கட்சி அரசியல் குழுக்கள் தாக்கல் செய்த மனுவை விசாரித்த அரசியலமைப்பு நீதிமன்றம், பிரதமரின் பதவிக் காலத்தை நிறுத்தி வைத்துள்ளது.",
        "முன்னாள் ராணுவ ஜெனரலாக இருந்த பிரயுத் சான்-ஓ-சா தற்காலிகமாக இடைநீக்கம் செய்யப்பட்டதையடுத்து, துணைப் பிரதமராகப் பணியாற்றிய பிரவிட் வோங் சுவான், தற்காலிகப் பிரதமராக தனது பணிகளைத் தொடங்குவார் என்று தைவான் ஊடகங்கள் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளன.",
        "2014 இல், ஜெனரல் பிரயுத் சான்-ஓ-சா தாய்லாந்தின் இராணுவத் தளபதியாக இருந்தார். அந்த நேரத்தில் தாய்லாந்து அரசியலில் நிலவும் உறுதியற்ற தன்மையைக் கருத்தில் கொண்டு, ஜெனரல் பிரயுத் சான்-ஓ-சா இராணுவத்தை வழிநடத்தி, ஆட்சிக் கவிழ்ப்பு மூலம் நாட்டில் ஆட்சியைக் கைப்பற்றினார். மற்றும் இரத்தம் சிந்தாமல்.",
        "ஜெனரல் பிரயுத் சான்-ஓ-சா 5 ஆண்டுகள் நிறுவப்பட்ட இராணுவ ஆட்சிக்குழுவின் தலைவராக பணியாற்றினார். எனினும், 2019ல் ஜனநாயகத்தை உறுதிப்படுத்தும் பொதுத் தேர்தலை நடத்த நடவடிக்கை எடுத்தார்.",
        "இராணுவத் தளபதி பதவியை ராஜினாமா செய்த பிரயுத் சான்-ஓ-சா, ஒரு சிவிலியனாகப் போட்டியிட்டு இராணுவ ஆதரவு அரசியல் குழுக்களை அணிதிரட்டி வெற்றி பெற்றார். சிவிலியன் பிரதமராக பதவியேற்ற பிரயுத் சான்-ஓ-சா ஜூலை 2019 இல் பதவியேற்றார்.",
        "தாய்லாந்து அரசியலமைப்பின் படி, தாய்லாந்து பிரதமரின் பதவிக்காலம் 8 ஆண்டுகள். பிரயுத் சான்-ஓ-சா இராணுவத் தளபதியாகவும், சிவிலியனாகவும் பதவி வகித்து வந்த பிரயுத் சான்-ஓ-சாவின் பதவிக்காலம் இன்றுடன் (24) முடிவடைவதாக தாய்லாந்து எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் தொடர்ச்சியாக சுட்டிக்காட்டி வந்தன.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சி அரசியல் குழுக்கள் அரசியலமைப்பு நீதிமன்றத்தில் தாக்கல் செய்த மனுவில் சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளன. அதன்படி, பிரயுத் சான்-ஓ-சாவின் பதவிக்காலத்தை நிறுத்தி வைக்க நீதிமன்றம் முடிவு செய்தது.",
        "இந்த மனுவை விசாரிக்க உள்ள அரசியலமைப்பு நீதிமன்றம், ராணுவ ஆட்சிக்குழுவின் தலைவராக தனது பதவிக் காலத்தை சிவில் பிரதம மந்திரி பதவிக்கு நீட்டிக்கும்.",
        "சேர்க்க முடியாது என்று தீர்ப்பளித்தால் பிரயுத் சான்-ஓ-சா பிரதமராக நீடிக்க முடியும் என்றும் கூறுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரயுத் சான்-ஓ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தைவானியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரவிட் வோங் சுவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரயுத் சான்-ஓ-சா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரயுத் சான்-ஓ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவ ஊழியர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரயுத் சான்-ஓ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரயுத் சான்-ஓ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரயுத் சான்-ஓ-சா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரயுத் சான்-ஓ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தாய்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரயுத் சான்-ஓ-சா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரயுத் சான்-ஓ-சா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரயுத் சான்-ஓ-சா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}