{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/St-James-achieves-highest-price-for-Uva-Pekoe1/34-738506",
  "time_ut": 1660088539,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "St. James achieves highest price for Uva Pekoe1",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "St. James achieves highest price for Uva Pekoe1",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The team of St. James (Dickwella) broke their own record when they achieved a price of Rs. 4,000 per kg for a Pekoe1 grade at this week’s auction. This is the highest price for any seasonal Uva tea sold at the auction of 9 August. St. James teas comes from Dickwella Factory which is part of Malwatte Valley Plantations PLC.  Dickwella Estate is managed by Regional Manager Chaminda Perera and the factory is under the supervision of Master Tea Maker A.M. Shajahan. The record-breaking price was paid by S. St. Clair Teas Ltd. and was marketed by Asia Siyaka Commodities PLC."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "St. James",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Uva",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "St. James",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,000 per kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dickwella Factory",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malwatte Valley Plantations PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dickwella Estate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaminda Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Master Tea Maker A.M. Shajahan",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. St. Clair Teas Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia Siyaka Commodities PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශාන්ත ජේම්ස් Uva Pekoe1 සඳහා ඉහළම මිල ලබා ගනී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සාන්ත ජේම්ස් (දික්වැල්ල) කණ්ඩායම ඔවුන්ගේම වාර්තාවක් බිඳ දැමූ අතර ඔවුන් රු. මෙම සතියේ වෙන්දේසියේදී Pekoe1 ශ්‍රේණියක් සඳහා කිලෝවකට රුපියල් 4,000ක්. අගෝස්තු 9 වැනිදා වෙන්දේසියේදී අලෙවි වූ ඕනෑම සෘතුමය ඌව තේ සඳහා ඉහළම මිල මෙය වේ. ශාන්ත ජේම්ස් තේ පැමිණෙන්නේ මල්වත්ත වැලි ප්ලාන්ටේෂන් පීඑල්සී හි කොටසක් වන දික්වැල්ල කර්මාන්ත ශාලාවෙනි. දික්වැල්ල වතුයාය ප්‍රාදේශීය කළමනාකරු චමින්ද පෙරේරා මහතා විසින් කළමනාකරණය කරනු ලබන අතර කර්මාන්තශාලාව මාස්ටර් ටී මේකර් ඒ.එම්. ෂාජහාන්. S. St. Clair Teas Ltd විසින් වාර්තාගත මිලක් ගෙවන ලද අතර Asia Siyaka Commodities PLC විසින් අලෙවි කරන ලදී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශාන්ත ජේම්ස්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඌව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශාන්ත ජේම්ස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දික්වැල්ල කර්මාන්ත ශාලාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මල්වත්ත වැලි වැවිලි පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දික්වැල්ල වත්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චමින්ද පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස්ටර් ටී මේකර් ඒ.එම්. ෂාජහාන්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. St. Clair Teas Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia Siyaka Commodities PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "செயின்ட் ஜேம்ஸ் Uva Pekoe1 க்கான அதிக விலையை அடைகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "செயின்ட் ஜேம்ஸ் (டிக்வெல்லா) அணி தனது சாதனையை தானே முறியடித்து ரூ. இந்த வார ஏலத்தில் Pekoe1 கிரேடுக்கு கிலோ ஒன்றுக்கு 4,000 ரூபாய். ஆகஸ்ட் 9 ஏலத்தில் விற்கப்பட்ட பருவகால ஊவா தேயிலைக்கு இதுவே அதிகபட்ச விலையாகும். செயின்ட் ஜேம்ஸ் டீஸ் மல்வத்தை வேலி பிளான்டேஷன்ஸ் பிஎல்சியின் ஒரு அங்கமான டிக்வெல்ல தொழிற்சாலையிலிருந்து வருகிறது. டிக்வெல்ல தோட்டம் பிராந்திய முகாமையாளர் சமிந்த பெரேராவினால் நிர்வகிக்கப்படுகிறது மற்றும் தொழிற்சாலை மாஸ்டர் டீ மேக்கர் ஏ.எம். ஷாஜஹான். சாதனை படைத்த விலையை S. St. Clair Teas Ltd செலுத்தியது மற்றும் Asia Siyaka Commodities PLC ஆல் சந்தைப்படுத்தப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "புனித ஜேம்ஸ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஊவா",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "புனித ஜேம்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு கிலோ 4,000",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிக்வெல்ல தொழிற்சாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malwatte Valley Plantations PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிக்வெல்ல தோட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமிந்த பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்டர் டீ மேக்கர் ஏ.எம். ஷாஜஹான்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ். செயின்ட் கிளேர் டீஸ் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா சியாக்கா கமாடிடீஸ் பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}