{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Union-Bank-wins-Most-Campaign-Partnerships-award-from-Daraz/34-738537",
  "time_ut": 1660176674,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Union Bank wins Most Campaign Partnerships award from Daraz",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Union Bank wins Most Campaign Partnerships award from Daraz",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Union Bank team (from left): Manager Business Development and Marketing – Cards Winu de Silva, Chief Manager Retails Assets and Cards Chamara Gomis and Assistant Manager Business Development – Cards Manuri Rodrigo receiving the award from Daraz CEO/Managing Director Rakhil Fernando and Head of Payments and Partnerships Dulika Jayamanne",
        "Union Bank for the second consecutive year was recognised at the Daraz Payment Partner Performance Awards and received the ‘Most Campaign Partnerships’ award this year in an event held on 28 July at Uga Residencies, Colombo.",
        "This award once again reaffirms Union Bank’s continuous efforts to enhance credit card usage on e-commerce platforms and its efforts in developing new campaigns which contributed to developing the most number of campaigns on the Daraz platform by a bank for the year 2021-2022.",
        "The Daraz Payment Partner Performance Awards is an annual event for payment partners and rewards and recognises the contribution of bank partners towards the success of the platform’s business growth. Since the inception of its partnership with Daraz, the bank has continuously introduced innovative campaigns to enhance the online shopping experience.",
        "An array of offers have been launched along with Daraz including, weekly discounts, offers on utility payments and partnering for special campaigns and extended payment plans such as the 11.11, Black Friday, Avurudu and Christmas Sales, etc. to reward the bank’s cardholder base with an exciting online shopping experience. Daraz is South Asia’s premier online shopping marketplace, backed by the global ecommerce giant, Alibaba Group, and has successfully brought together consumers and sellers to create Sri Lanka’s largest e-commerce venue over the years.",
        "Union Bank Credit Cards are available in Gold, Platinum and Signature variants based on pre-set eligibility criteria."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Union Bank",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Daraz",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Union Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manuri Rodrigo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daraz",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rakhil Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Union Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the second consecutive year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Union Bank’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daraz",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021-2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "annual",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daraz",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Daraz",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11.11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Avurudu",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daraz",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asia’s",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alibaba Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Union Bank Credit Cards",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gold, Platinum",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යුනියන් බැංකුව Daraz වෙතින් Most Campaign Partnerships සම්මානය දිනා ගනී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "යුනියන් බැංකු කණ්ඩායම (වමේ සිට): ව්‍යාපාර සංවර්ධන සහ අලෙවි කළමනාකරු – කාඩ්පත් විනු ද සිල්වා, ප්‍රධාන කළමනාකරු සිල්ලර වත්කම් සහ කාඩ්පත් චාමර ගෝමිස් සහ සහකාර කළමනාකාර ව්‍යාපාර සංවර්ධන – කාඩ්පත් Manuri Rodrigo Daraz හි ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී/කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ රඛිල් ප්‍රනාන්දු සහ ප්‍රධානියා අතින් සම්මානය ලබා ගත්හ. ගෙවීම් සහ හවුල්කාරිත්වය දුලීකා ජයමාන්න",
        "යුනියන් බැංකුව අඛණ්ඩව දෙවන වසරටත් Daraz Payment Partner Performance Awards සම්මාන උළෙලේදී ඇගයීමට ලක් වූ අතර මෙම වසරේ ජුලි 28 වන දින කොළඹ Uga Residences හි පැවති උත්සවයකදී ‘Most Campaign Partnerships’ සම්මානය හිමිකර ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "2021-2022 වසර සඳහා බැංකුවක් විසින් Daraz වේදිකාවේ වැඩිම ප්‍රචාරණ ප්‍රචාරණ සංඛ්‍යාවක් සංවර්ධනය කිරීමට දායක වූ නව ප්‍රචාරණ ව්‍යාපාර සංවර්ධනය කිරීමට සහ ඊ-වාණිජ්‍ය වේදිකාවල ක්‍රෙඩිට් කාඩ් භාවිතය ඉහළ නැංවීමට යුනියන් බැංකුව දරන අඛණ්ඩ උත්සාහය මෙම සම්මානය නැවත වරක් තහවුරු කරයි.",
        "Daraz Payment Partner Performance Awards යනු ගෙවීම් හවුල්කරුවන් සහ ත්‍යාග සඳහා වාර්ෂික උත්සවයක් වන අතර වේදිකාවේ ව්‍යාපාරික වර්ධනයේ සාර්ථකත්වය සඳහා බැංකු හවුල්කරුවන්ගේ දායකත්වය හඳුනා ගනී. Daraz සමඟ හවුල්කාරිත්වය ආරම්භයේ සිටම, බැංකුව අන්තර්ජාල සාප්පු සවාරි අත්දැකීම වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම සඳහා නව්‍ය ව්‍යාපාර අඛණ්ඩව හඳුන්වා දී ඇත.",
        "Daraz සමඟින් සතිපතා වට්ටම්, උපයෝගිතා ගෙවීම් පිළිබඳ දීමනා සහ විශේෂ ව්‍යාපාර සඳහා හවුල් වීම සහ බැංකුවේ කාඩ්පත් හිමියන්ට ප්‍රතිලාභ ලබා දීම සඳහා 11.11, කළු සිකුරාදා, අවුරුදු සහ නත්තල් විකුණුම් වැනි දිගු ගෙවීම් සැලසුම් ඇතුළු දීමනා රැසක් දියත් කර ඇත. ආකර්ෂණීය අන්තර්ජාල සාප්පු සවාරි අත්දැකීමක්. Daraz යනු ගෝලීය ඊ-වාණිජ්‍යය දැවැන්තයා වන Alibaba සමූහයේ පිටුබලය ලබන දකුණු ආසියාවේ ප්‍රමුඛතම අන්තර්ජාල සාප්පු සවාරි වෙළඳපොළ වන අතර වසර ගණනාවක් පුරා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විශාලතම ඊ-වාණිජ්‍ය ස්ථානය නිර්මාණය කිරීම සඳහා පාරිභෝගිකයින් සහ විකුණුම්කරුවන් සාර්ථකව එක් කර ඇත.",
        "යුනියන් බැංකුවේ ක්‍රෙඩිට් කාඩ්පත් රන්, ප්ලැටිනම් සහ සිග්නේචර් යන ප්‍රභේදවලින් පෙර සැකසූ සුදුසුකම් නිර්ණායක මත පදනම් වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "යුනියන් බැංකුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Daraz",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "යුනියන් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනුරි රුද්‍රිගු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daraz",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රඛිල් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුනියන් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඛණ්ඩව දෙවන වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුනියන් බැංකුවේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daraz",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021-2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daraz",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Daraz",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11.11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daraz",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියාවේ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලිබබා සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුනියන් බැංකු ක්‍රෙඩිට් කාඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්, ප්ලැටිනම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "யூனியன் வங்கி Daraz இலிருந்து அதிக பிரச்சார கூட்டாண்மை விருதை வென்றது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "யூனியன் வங்கி குழு (இடமிருந்து): வணிக அபிவிருத்தி மற்றும் சந்தைப்படுத்தல் முகாமையாளர் – அட்டைகள் வினு டி சில்வா, சில்லறை விற்பனை சொத்துக்கள் மற்றும் அட்டைகள் பிரதான முகாமையாளர் சாமர கோமிஸ் மற்றும் உதவி முகாமையாளர் வர்த்தக அபிவிருத்தி – அட்டைகள் Manuri Rodrigo Daraz CEO/ முகாமைத்துவப் பணிப்பாளர் ரகில் பெர்னாண்டோ மற்றும் தலைவர் ஆகியோரிடமிருந்து விருதைப் பெறுகின்றனர். கொடுப்பனவுகள் மற்றும் கூட்டாண்மைகள் துலிகா ஜெயமான்னே",
        "யூனியன் வங்கி தொடர்ந்து இரண்டாவது ஆண்டாக Daraz Payment Partner Performance Awardsல் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்டது மற்றும் இந்த ஆண்டு ஜூலை 28 அன்று கொழும்பு Uga Residencies இல் நடைபெற்ற நிகழ்வில் 'Most Campaign Partnerships' விருதைப் பெற்றது.",
        "இ-காமர்ஸ் தளங்களில் கிரெடிட் கார்டு பயன்பாட்டை மேம்படுத்த யூனியன் வங்கியின் தொடர்ச்சியான முயற்சிகள் மற்றும் 2021-2022 ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கான வங்கியினால் Daraz தளத்தில் அதிக எண்ணிக்கையிலான பிரச்சாரங்களை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கு பங்களித்த புதிய பிரச்சாரங்களை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கான முயற்சிகளை இந்த விருது மீண்டும் உறுதிப்படுத்துகிறது.",
        "Daraz Payment Partner Performance Awards என்பது பேமெண்ட் பார்ட்னர்கள் மற்றும் வெகுமதிகளுக்கான வருடாந்திர நிகழ்வாகும், மேலும் தளத்தின் வணிக வளர்ச்சியின் வெற்றிக்கு வங்கி கூட்டாளர்களின் பங்களிப்பை அங்கீகரிக்கிறது. Daraz உடனான தனது கூட்டாண்மையின் தொடக்கத்திலிருந்து, ஆன்லைன் ஷாப்பிங் அனுபவத்தை மேம்படுத்துவதற்காக வங்கி தொடர்ந்து புதுமையான பிரச்சாரங்களை அறிமுகப்படுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "Daraz உடன் வாராந்திர தள்ளுபடிகள், பயன்பாட்டுக் கொடுப்பனவுகளுக்கான சலுகைகள் மற்றும் சிறப்புப் பிரச்சாரங்களுக்கான கூட்டாண்மை மற்றும் வங்கியின் அட்டைதாரருக்கு வெகுமதி அளிக்கும் வகையில் 11.11, கருப்பு வெள்ளி, அவுருடு மற்றும் கிறிஸ்துமஸ் விற்பனை போன்ற நீட்டிக்கப்பட்ட கட்டணத் திட்டங்கள் உட்பட பல சலுகைகள் தொடங்கப்பட்டுள்ளன. ஒரு அற்புதமான ஆன்லைன் ஷாப்பிங் அனுபவம். Daraz என்பது தெற்காசியாவின் முதன்மையான ஆன்லைன் ஷாப்பிங் சந்தையாகும், இது உலகளாவிய மின்வணிக நிறுவனமான அலிபாபா குழுமத்தின் ஆதரவுடன் உள்ளது, மேலும் பல ஆண்டுகளாக இலங்கையின் மிகப்பெரிய ஈ-காமர்ஸ் இடத்தை உருவாக்குவதற்கு நுகர்வோர் மற்றும் விற்பனையாளர்களை வெற்றிகரமாக ஒன்றிணைத்துள்ளது.",
        "யூனியன் பேங்க் கிரெடிட் கார்டுகள் தங்கம், பிளாட்டினம் மற்றும் சிக்னேச்சர் வகைகளில் முன் அமைக்கப்பட்ட தகுதியின் அடிப்படையில் கிடைக்கின்றன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "யூனியன் வங்கி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "தராஸ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "யூனியன் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனுரி ரோட்ரிகோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தராஸ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரகில் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யூனியன் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொடர்ந்து இரண்டாவது ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யூனியன் வங்கியின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தராஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021-2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தராஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தராஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11.11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அவுருடு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தராஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசியாவின்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலிபாபா குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யூனியன் வங்கி கடன் அட்டைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தங்கம், பிளாட்டினம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}