{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Parliament-approves-emergency-regulations/108-241902",
  "time_ut": 1658923925,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Parliament approves emergency regulations",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Parliament approves emergency regulations",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The emergency regulations declared by the then Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe were approved in Parliament today with 120 MPs voting for it and 63 against.",
        "The state of emergency was declared in a proclamation by Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe in terms of Article 40(1) (C) of the Constitution in the interests of public security, the protection of public order and the maintenance of supplies and services essential to the life of the community."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "120",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "63",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 40(1",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හදිසි නීති රෙගුලාසි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අනුමත කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "එවක වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද හදිසි නීති රෙගුලාසි අද පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී සම්මත වූ අතර ඊට පක්ෂව මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 120 දෙනෙකු සහ විපක්ෂව 63 දෙනෙකු ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 40(1) (C) වගන්තිය ප්‍රකාරව මහජන ආරක්ෂාව, මහජන සාමය ආරක්ෂා කිරීම සහ රජයට අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සැපයුම් සහ සේවා පවත්වාගෙන යාමේ අවශ්‍යතා මත වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ විසින් ප්‍රකාශයක් කරමින් හදිසි නීතිය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලදී. ප්රජාවගේ ජීවිතය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "120",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "63",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 වැනි වගන්තිය(1",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அவசரகாலச் சட்டங்களுக்கு நாடாளுமன்றம் ஒப்புதல் அளித்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அப்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் பிரகடனப்படுத்தப்பட்ட அவசரகாலச் சட்டத்திற்கு 120 பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் ஆதரவாகவும் 63 பேர் எதிராகவும் வாக்களித்த நிலையில் இன்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் அங்கீகாரம் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பொது பாதுகாப்பு, பொது ஒழுங்கைப் பாதுகாத்தல் மற்றும் அத்தியாவசிய பொருட்கள் மற்றும் சேவைகளைப் பேணுதல் ஆகியவற்றின் நலன்களுக்காக அரசியலமைப்பின் 40(1) (C) பிரிவின்படி பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் அவசரகாலச் சட்டம் பிரகடனப்படுத்தப்பட்டது. சமூகத்தின் வாழ்க்கை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "120",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "63",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிவு 40(1",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}