{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/10/sjb-party-leaders-to-meet-today-10/",
  "time_ut": 1657434300,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SJB Party Leaders to meet today (10)",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SJB Party Leaders to meet today (10)",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) is scheduled to hold a special party meeting on Sunday (10) morning.",
        "The Secretary-General of the Samagi Jana Balawegaya Ranjith Maddumabandara said that the meeting will be held this morning to establish an all-party government and the emerging political situation.",
        "Chairman of Samagi Jana Balavegaya & Leader of the Opposition Sajith Premadasa",
        "Leader of All Ceylon Makkal Congress Rishad Bathiudeen including party leaders.",
        "Meanwhile, a meeting is planned to be held among the leaders of the 9 parties, including the National Freedom Front on Sunday (10).",
        "Vice President of the Communist Party of Sri Lanka Weerasumana Weerasinghe said that there will be a lengthy discussion about the all-party government."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SJB Party Leaders",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Samagi Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10) morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Maddumabandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi Jana Balavegaya & Leader",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Opposition Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Freedom Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Communist Party of Sri Lanka Weerasumana Weerasinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SJB පක්ෂ නායකයින් අද (10) රැස්වීමට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); සමගි ජන බලවේගය ඉරිදා (10) පෙරවරුවේ විශේෂ පක්ෂ රැස්වීමක් පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතය.",
        "සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ මහලේකම් රංජිත් මද්දුමබණ්ඩාර මහතා පැවසුවේ සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම සහ නැගී එන දේශපාලන තත්ත්වය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අද පෙරවරුවේ මෙම හමුව පැවැත්වෙන බවයි.",
        "සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ සභාපති සහ විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
        "සමස්ත ලංකා මක්කල් කොංග්‍රසයේ නායක රිෂාඩ් බදියුදීන් ඇතුළු පක්ෂ නායකයින්.",
        "මේ අතර ජාතික නිදහස් පෙරමුණ ඇතුළු පක්ෂ 9ක නායකයින් අතර හමුවක් ඉරිදා (10) පැවැත්වීමට සැලසුම් කර තිබේ.",
        "එහිදී සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුව සම්බන්ධයෙන් දීර්ඝ ලෙස සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට නියමිත බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා කොමියුනිස්ට් පක්ෂයේ උප සභාපති වීරසුමන වීරසිංහ මහතා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SJB පක්ෂ නායකයින්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10) උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් මද්දුමබණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය සහ නායකයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂය සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික නිදහස් පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා කොමියුනිස්ට් පක්ෂය වීරසුමන වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SJB கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் இன்று (10) சந்திக்கவுள்ளனர்.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை (10) காலை விசேட கட்சிக் கூட்டமொன்றை நடத்தவுள்ளது.",
        "அனைத்துக் கட்சி ஆட்சியை ஸ்தாபிப்பதற்கும், உருவாகி வரும் அரசியல் நிலைமைகள் தொடர்பாகவும் இன்று காலை கூட்டம் நடைபெறவுள்ளதாக சமகி ஜன பலவேகய கட்சியின் செயலாளர் நாயகம் ரஞ்சித் மத்துமபண்டார தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயவின் தலைவர் மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
        "அகில இலங்கை மக்கள் காங்கிரஸின் தலைவர் ரிஷாட் பதியுதீன் உட்பட கட்சித் தலைவர்கள்.",
        "இதேவேளை, தேசிய சுதந்திர முன்னணி உள்ளிட்ட 9 கட்சிகளின் தலைவர்களுக்கு இடையில் எதிர்வரும் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை (10) சந்திப்பொன்று நடத்த திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் தொடர்பில் நீண்ட நேரம் கலந்துரையாடப்படும் என இலங்கை கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கட்சியின் உப தலைவர் வீரசுமண வீரசிங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SJB கட்சி தலைவர்கள்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10) காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சித் மத்துமபண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா & தலைவர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்க்கட்சியான சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய சுதந்திர முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கட்சி வீரசுமண வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}