{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Carcasses-of-Sambar-deer-floating-in-Ambewela-reservoir/108-243362",
  "time_ut": 1660899695,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Carcasses of Sambar deer floating in Ambewela reservoir",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Carcasses of Sambar deer floating in Ambewela reservoir",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The carcasses of a large number of Sambar deer that inhabit in Hortain Planes were found floating in the Ambewela reservoir in Nanu- oya, people fisihing in the reservoir said.",
        "They said about ten such carcases of Sambar deer were found within a week.",
        "According to the fishermen, these animals that come to the reservoir for water might have been bitten and chased away by some hounds, abandoned by hunters and they might have drowned.",
        "They said people who use water from this reservoir for drinking and irrigation purposes are faced with serious issues due the contamination of water.",
        "They complained that wildlife officials were yet to take any action against this, despite several complaints. (Ranjith Rajapaksa)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ambewela",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sambar",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hortain Planes",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambewela",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanu-",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ten",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sambar",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "a week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අඹේවෙල ජලාශයේ පාවෙන සාම්බාර් මුවන්ගේ සිරුරු",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හෝටේන් ප්ලේන්වල වෙසෙන සාම්බාර් මුවන් විශාල සංඛ්‍යාවකගේ මළ සිරුරු නානුඔය, අඹේවෙල ජලාශයේ පාවෙමින් තිබියදී සොයාගත් බව ජලාශයේ මසුන් අල්ලමින් සිටි ජනතාව පවසති.",
        "සතියක් ඇතුළත එවැනි සාම්බාර් මුවන්ගේ මළ සිරුරු දහයක් පමණ සොයාගත් බව ඔවුහු පැවසූහ.",
        "ජලාශයට ජලය ලබා ගැනීමට පැමිණෙන මෙම සතුන් දඩයම්කරුවන් විසින් අතහැර දමා ගොස් දියේ ගිලී මිය යන්නට ඇති බව ධීවරයින් ප්‍රකාශ කරයි.",
        "මෙම ජලාශයේ ජලය පානීය හා වාරිමාර්ග කටයුතු සඳහා භාවිත කරන ජනතාව ජලය අපවිත්‍ර වීම හේතුවෙන් බරපතළ ගැටලුවලට මුහුණ පා සිටින බව ඔවුහු පැවසූහ.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් පැමිණිලි ගණනාවක් කළද වනජීවී නිලධාරීන් මෙතෙක් කිසිදු ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයක් ගෙන නොමැති බවටයි ඔවුන් චෝදනා කළේ. (රංජිත් රාජපක්ෂ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අඹේවෙල",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සාම්බාර්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෝටන් ගුවන් යානා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඹේවෙල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නානු-",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දස",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාම්බාර්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතියක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அம்பேவெல நீர்த்தேக்கத்தில் மிதக்கும் சாம்பார் மான்களின் சடலங்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நானுஓயாவில் உள்ள அம்பேவெல நீர்த்தேக்கத்தில் ஹொர்டெய்ன் பிளானில் வசிக்கும் பெருமளவிலான சம்பார் மான்களின் சடலங்கள் மிதப்பதாக நீர்த்தேக்கத்தில் மீன்பிடிக்கும் மக்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "ஒரு வாரத்திற்குள் இதுபோன்ற பத்து சாம்பார் மான்களின் சடலங்கள் கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டதாக அவர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இந்த நீர்த்தேக்கத்திற்கு தண்ணீருக்காக வரும் இந்த விலங்குகளை சில வேட்டைநாய்கள் கடித்து விரட்டியடித்து, வேட்டையாடுபவர்களால் கைவிடப்பட்டு நீரில் மூழ்கி இறந்திருக்கலாம் என மீனவர்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "இந்த நீர்த்தேக்கத்தின் நீரை குடிப்பதற்கும் பாசனத்துக்கும் பயன்படுத்தும் மக்கள் நீர் மாசடைவதால் பாரிய பிரச்சினைகளை எதிர்கொள்வதாக அவர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இதுகுறித்து பலமுறை புகார் அளித்தும் வனவிலங்கு அதிகாரிகள் எந்த நடவடிக்கையும் எடுக்கவில்லை என புகார் தெரிவித்தனர். (ரஞ்சித் ராஜபக்ஷ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அம்பேவெல",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சாம்பார்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹார்டைன் விமானங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பேவெல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நானு-",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பத்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாம்பார்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சித் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}