{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/02/dullas-faction-forms-the-freedom-people-s-congress/",
  "time_ut": 1662132060,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Dullas faction forms the Freedom People’s Congress",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dullas faction forms the Freedom People’s Congress",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The 13 SLPP MPs who became independent of their party, including MPs Prof. G. L. Peiris and Dullas Alahapperuma, launched a New Political Movement on Friday (2), it is identified as the Freedom People's Congress.",
        "The new office premises of the Freedom People's Congress was opened in Koswatte, Nawala where the inaugural media briefing also took place.",
        "MP Charitha Herath, speaking at the press conference following the event, said that it is important to free the country of corruption and nepotism.",
        "MP Prof. G. L. Peiris too, speaking at the event said that we live during times when State repression is high, and the PTA is being misused.",
        "MP Dullas Alahapperuma said that the event signifies a new beginning, as the Governmen has become fearful of them.",
        "\"All our representatives were removed from Parliament Committees, Secondly, some of us were taken off the Speaker's List. Thirdly, yesterday, during the interim budget debate which is of paramount importance, we were banned from the parliamentary debate area\" MP Alahapperuma said.",
        "He further stated that although the power of the executive is visible, the power of the legislature remains invisible. Pointing out that this was a situation which was previously faced during the last Presidential Election, MP Alahapperuma said that the latest crisis facing Sri Lankan democracy has become taking control of the legislation.",
        "\"It should not happen in a democratic society anywhere in the world. In fact, the President, Prime Minister, Speaker, Leader of the House should all be ashamed. Shame on you for remaining blind and mute when the legislature is being controlled by invisible forces,\" Alahapperuma said.",
        "When inquired on the invisible force that is controlling the legislative, MP Dilan Perera acknowledged a nearby crow.",
        "It’s a good budget – Mahinda Rajapaksa on Budget Amendment 2022"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dullas",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "G. L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Political Movement",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Freedom People's Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Koswatte",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nawala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Charitha Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "G. L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament Committees",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Secondly",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thirdly",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Presidential Election",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "democratic",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dilan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඩලස් කණ්ඩායම නිදහස් මහජන කොංග්‍රසය පිහිටුවයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්. පීරිස් සහ ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම ඇතුළු ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 13 දෙනා සිකුරාදා (2) නව දේශපාලන ව්‍යාපාරයක් ආරම්භ කළ අතර එය නිදහස් ජනතා කොංග්‍රසය ලෙස හඳුනාගෙන ඇත.",
        "නිදහස් ජනතා කොංග්‍රසයේ නව කාර්යාල පරිශ්‍රය නාවල කොස්වත්ත ප්‍රදේශයේ විවෘත කෙරුණු අතර එහිදී මංගල මාධ්‍ය හමුව ද පැවැත්වුණා.",
        "ඉන් අනතුරුව පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවට එක්වෙමින් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී චරිත හේරත් කියා සිටියේ දූෂණයෙන් සහ ඥාති සංග්‍රහයෙන් රට නිදහස් කර ගැනීම වැදගත් බවයි.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්. පීරිස් ද මෙහිදී අදහස් දක්වමින් කියා සිටියේ අප ජීවත් වන්නේ රාජ්‍ය මර්දනය ඉහළ මට්ටමක පවතින අතර ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත අවභාවිතා කරන යුගයක බවයි.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම කියා සිටියේ ආණ්ඩුකාරවරුන් ඔවුන්ට බිය වී ඇති බැවින් මෙම උත්සවය නව ආරම්භයක් සනිටුහන් කරන බවයි.",
        "\"අපේ සියලුම නියෝජිතයන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු කාරක සභාවලින් ඉවත් කළා. දෙවනුව අපි කිහිප දෙනෙකු කථානායක ලැයිස්තුවෙන් ඉවත් කළා. තුන්වනුව ඊයේ අතිවැදගත් අයවැය අතුරු අයවැය විවාදයේදී අපට පාර්ලිමේන්තු විවාද භූමිය තහනම් කළා\" අලහප්පෙරුම මන්ත්‍රීවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "විධායකයේ බලය දෘශ්‍යමාන වුවද ව්‍යවස්ථාදායකයේ බලය අදෘශ්‍යමානව පවතින බවයි ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් කියා සිටියේ. මෙය මීට පෙර පසුගිය ජනාධිපතිවරණ සමයේදී මුහුණ දුන් තත්ත්වයක් බව පෙන්වා දුන් අලහප්පෙරුම මන්ත්‍රීවරයා කියා සිටියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය මුහුණ දී ඇති නවතම අර්බුදය නීති සම්පාදනය කර ගැනීම බවට පත්ව ඇති බවයි.",
        "“ලෝකයේ කොතැනකවත් ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී සමාජයක එය සිදු නොවිය යුතුයි.ඇත්තටම ජනාධිපති, අගමැති, කථානායක, සභානායක සියලුදෙනාම ලැජ්ජ විය යුතුයි.ව්‍යවස්ථාදායකය අදෘශ්‍යමානව පාලනය කරන විට අන්ධව ගොළුවී සිටීම ගැන ලැජ්ජා විය යුතුයි. බලවේග,” අලහප්පෙරුම පැවසීය.",
        "ව්‍යවස්ථාදායකය පාලනය කරන අදෘශ්‍යමාන බලවේගය පිළිබඳව කළ විමසීමකදී ඩිලාන් පෙරේරා මන්ත්‍රීවරයා අසල සිටි කපුටෙකු පිළිගත්තේය.",
        "ඒක හොඳ අයවැයක් - මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ 2022 අයවැය සංශෝධනය ගැන"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩලස්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල්. පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දේශපාලන ව්‍යාපාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොංග්රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් මහජන කොංග්‍රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොස්වත්ත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චරිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල්. පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු කාරක සභා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවනුව",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවනුව",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපතිවරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්රජාතන්ත්රවාදී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩිලාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டல்லாஸ் அணி சுதந்திர மக்கள் காங்கிரசை உருவாக்குகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ் மற்றும் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும உட்பட 13 ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன கட்சியின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் இணைந்து புதிய அரசியல் இயக்கமொன்றை வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (2) ஆரம்பித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "சுதந்திர மக்கள் காங்கிரஸின் புதிய அலுவலக வளாகம் நாவல, கொஸ்வத்தையில் திறந்து வைக்கப்பட்டது, அங்கு அங்குரார்ப்பண ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பும் இடம்பெற்றது.",
        "இந்நிகழ்வைத் தொடர்ந்து நடைபெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் கலந்துகொண்டு கருத்துத் தெரிவித்த பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சரித ஹேரத், நாட்டை ஊழல் மற்றும் உறவுமுறையில் இருந்து விடுவிப்பது முக்கியம்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பேராசிரியர் ஜீ.எல்.பீரிஸ் அவர்களும் இந்த நிகழ்வில் உரையாற்றுகையில், அரச அடக்குமுறைகள் அதிகமாக உள்ள காலப்பகுதியில் நாம் வாழ்கின்றோம், பயங்கரவாத தடைச்சட்டம் தவறாகப் பயன்படுத்தப்படுகின்றது.",
        "இந்த நிகழ்வு புதிய ஆரம்பத்தை குறிப்பதாக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "நாடாளுமன்றக் குழுக்களில் இருந்து எங்களுடைய பிரதிநிதிகள் அனைவரும் நீக்கப்பட்டனர், இரண்டாவதாக, சபாநாயகர் பட்டியலிலிருந்து எங்களில் சிலர் நீக்கப்பட்டோம். மூன்றாவதாக, நேற்று, மிக முக்கியத்துவம் வாய்ந்த இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட விவாதத்தின் போது, ​​நாடாளுமன்ற விவாதப் பகுதியிலிருந்து எங்களுக்குத் தடை விதிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரம் கண்ணுக்குத் தெரிந்தாலும், சட்டமன்றத்தின் அதிகாரம் கண்ணுக்குத் தெரியாத நிலையிலேயே இருப்பதாக அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார். இது முன்னர் கடந்த ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலின் போது எதிர்கொள்ளப்பட்ட ஒரு நிலை என்று சுட்டிக்காட்டிய எம்.பி அழகப்பெரும, இலங்கை ஜனநாயகம் எதிர்கொண்டுள்ள சமீபத்திய நெருக்கடியானது சட்டத்தை கட்டுப்படுத்தும் நிலைக்கு மாறியுள்ளது என்றும் கூறினார்.",
        "“உலகில் எங்கும் ஜனநாயக சமூகத்தில் இப்படி நடக்கக் கூடாது.உண்மையில் குடியரசுத் தலைவர், பிரதமர், சபாநாயகர், அவைத்தலைவர் அனைவரும் வெட்கப்பட வேண்டும்.சட்டமன்றம் கண்ணுக்குத் தெரியாதவர்களால் கட்டுப்படுத்தப்படும்போது கண்மூடித்தனமாகவும், ஊமையாகவும் இருப்பது வெட்கப்பட வேண்டியது. படைகள்\" என அழஹப்பெரும கூறினார்.",
        "சட்டமன்றத்தை கட்டுப்படுத்தும் கண்ணுக்கு தெரியாத சக்தி குறித்து விசாரித்த போது, ​​பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டிலான் பெரேரா அருகில் இருந்த காக்கையை ஒப்புக்கொண்டார்.",
        "இது ஒரு நல்ல வரவு செலவுத் திட்டம் - வரவு செலவுத் திருத்தம் 2022 இல் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதிய அரசியல் இயக்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திர மக்கள் காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொஸ்வத்தை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாவல",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சரித ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற குழுக்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவதாக",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவதாக",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயக",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திலான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}