{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/79013",
  "time_ut": 1660481280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Hundreds of Tamil mothers Conduct  rally in Kilinochchi  to mark 2,000 days of protests  to seek justice for their sons who they claim were forcibly disappeared during and after the civil war.",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Hundreds of Tamil mothers Conduct  rally in Kilinochchi  to mark 2,000 days of protests  to seek justice for their sons who they claim were forcibly disappeared during and after the civil war.",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Hundreds of Tamil mothers engaged in a rally last Friday (12) in Kilinochchi District to mark 2,000 days of protests and activism to seek justice for their sons who they claim were forcibly disappeared during and after the civil war.",
        "The protests commenced in February 2017 during the Yahapalana Government, which promised justice to the families of the disappeared, to demand answers about the fate of their loved ones.",
        "Speaking to The Morning, Mariya Suresh Ishwaree said: “We urge that Gotabaya Rajapaksa be arrested. We would receive justice after his arrest. we haven’t received any justice from anyone. The Sinhala community also has joined our struggle. We are looking for our husbands. I have been in Geneva twice, asking for justice. Many of the mothers of these disappeared children, especially those depending on a daily wage job, are facing enormous hardships while continuing to agitate for justice. Some of them are eating only one or two meals instead of three because of the current situation.”",
        "Sandya Eknaligoda, human rights activist and wife of missing journalist Prageeth Eknaligoda, who also participated in the rally, told The Morning: “For 2,000 days these mothers waited for justice. They continued this struggle for all these years. The new President in Sri Lanka used these mothers during the election in 2015, so he has the opportunity to give justice and truth to these mothers. I’m taking part in this event on behalf of the mothers in the South.",
        "“I have participated in this struggle in different places, and the result we want is truth and justice. I experienced this struggle for 12 years. The ‘aragalaya’ (struggle) is the only solution to winning truth and justice.”",
        "Fr. Selvan from Jaffna, who was also an active member of the campaign, speaking to The Morning said: “We lost thousands and we need justice. This is our duty to ensure solidarity. All these people have a lot of stories. Former President Maithreepala Sirisena, at a discussion with Tamil families of the disappeared, said ‘there is no one here; if you want you can visit all the prisons’, but no one knows what happened. This is the post-conflict situation and we need justice.”",
        "Ceylon Teachers’ Union General Secretary Joseph Stalin, who also participated in the rally, told The Morning: “This is one of the longest-running ‘aragalayas’ in Sri Lanka. More than 1,000 parents surrendered their children to the Army, and 136 parents died during this ‘aragalaya’, fighting for justice. we have a responsibility to urge an international investigation.”",
        "Meanwhile, Anand Raja, whose son went missing during the last stage of the war in 2009, told The Morning: “We have started this continuous struggle from that year (2009). He was 34 years old at that stage. He was farming. We hope to receive a response regarding our son. Former President Maithreepala Sirisena said that our demand was reasonable, and that he would look into this matter to achieve the best result. But he has not fulfilled his promise. Our people don’t believe in the Office of Missing Persons. It’s powerless. They have done nothing.”",
        "The years that have passed since the armed conflict in Sri Lanka, which ended in 2009, have not brought solace to the families of the over 16,000 persons who, according to the International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC) records, remain missing."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Hundreds",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tamil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Conduct",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kilinochchi",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2,000 days",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "the civil war",
          "label": "EVENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Hundreds",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kilinochchi District",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,000 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the civil war",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "February 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Yahapalana Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Geneva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sandya Eknaligoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prageeth Eknaligoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Morning: “For",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,000 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "these years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Morning",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithreepala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Teachers’ Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joseph Stalin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Morning: “This is one of the longest-running ‘aragalayas’ in Sri Lanka",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "More than 1,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "136",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anand Raja",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Morning: “",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "that year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "34 years old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithreepala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Office of Missing Persons",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Committee of the Red Cross",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සිවිල් යුද්ධයේදී සහ ඉන් පසුව බලහත්කාරයෙන් අතුරුදහන් වූ බව පවසන තම පුතුන්ට යුක්තිය ඉල්ලා දින 2,000 ක විරෝධතා ව්‍යාපාර සිය ගණනක් කිලිනොච්චියේ පවත්වයි.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "සිවිල් යුද්ධයේදී සහ ඉන් පසුව බලහත්කාරයෙන් අතුරුදහන් වූ බව කියන තම පුතුන්ට යුක්තිය ඉල්ලා දින 2,000 ක් සපිරෙන දින 2,000 ක් සපිරෙන විරෝධතා සහ ක්‍රියාකාරීත්වය වෙනුවෙන් පසුගිය සිකුරාදා (12) දින කිලිනොච්චි දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ දෙමළ මව්වරුන් සිය ගණනක් රැළියක නිරත වූහ.",
        "අතුරුදහන් වූවන්ගේ පවුල්වලට සාධාරණය ඉටු කරන බවට පොරොන්දු වූ යහපාලන රජය සමයේ 2017 පෙබරවාරි මාසයේදී විරෝධතා ආරම්භ වූයේ ඔවුන්ගේ ආදරණීයයන්ගේ ඉරණම පිළිබඳව පිළිතුරු ඉල්ලා සිටීමයි.",
        "The Morning වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් Mariya Suresh Ishwaree මෙසේ පැවසුවාය: “ගෝඨාබය රාජපක්ෂ අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා ලෙස අපි ඉල්ලා සිටිමු. ඔහු අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමෙන් පසුව අපට යුක්තිය ඉටුවනු ඇත. අපිට කාගෙන්වත් සාධාරණයක් ලැබිලා නැහැ. අපේ අරගලයට සිංහල සමාජයත් එකතු වෙලා. අපි අපේ ස්වාමිපුරුෂයන් සොයනවා. මම යුක්තිය ඉල්ලා දෙවරක් ජිනීවා ගොස් ඇත. මෙම අතුරුදහන් වූ දරුවන්ගේ මව්වරුන්ගෙන් බොහෝ දෙනෙක්, විශේෂයෙන් දෛනික වැටුපෙන් රැකියාවෙන් යැපෙන බොහෝ දෙනෙක් යුක්තිය ඉල්ලා අඛණ්ඩ උද්ඝෝෂණවල යෙදී සිටින අතරතුර දැවැන්ත දුෂ්කරතාවන්ට මුහුණ දෙති. ඔවුන්ගෙන් සමහරෙක් දැනට පවතින තත්ත්වය නිසා වේල් තුනක් වෙනුවට එක වේලක් හෝ දෙකක් පමණක් අනුභව කරති.",
        "මෙම රැලියට සහභාගී වූ මානව හිමිකම් ක්‍රියාකාරිනියක සහ අතුරුදහන් වූ මාධ්‍යවේදී ප්‍රගීත් එක්නැලිගොඩගේ බිරිඳ වන සන්ධ්‍යා එක්නැලිගොඩ The Morning වෙත මෙසේ පැවසුවාය: “දින 2000ක් මේ අම්මලා සාධාරණය එනකම් බලාගෙන හිටියා. ඔවුන් මේ වසර පුරාවටම මේ අරගලය කරගෙන ගියා. 2015 මැතිවරණයේදී ලංකාවේ නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා මේ අම්මලාව පාවිච්චි කළ නිසා මේ අම්මලාට සාධාරණය සහ සත්‍යය ලබාදෙන්න එතුමාට අවස්ථාව තියෙනවා. මම මේ උත්සවයට සහභාගි වෙන්නේ දකුණේ අම්මලා වෙනුවෙන්.",
        "“මම විවිධ ස්ථානවල මෙම අරගලයට සහභාගී වී ඇති අතර, අපට අවශ්‍ය ප්‍රතිඵලය සත්‍යය සහ යුක්තියයි. මම අවුරුදු 12ක් මේ අරගලය අත්වින්දා. සත්‍යය සහ යුක්තිය දිනා ගැනීමට ඇති එකම විසඳුම ‘අරගලය’ (අරගලය) ය.",
        "ශා. උද්ඝෝෂනයේ ක්‍රියාකාරී සාමාජිකයෙකු වූ යාපනයේ සෙල්වන් ද මෝනිං වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් මෙසේ පැවසීය: “අපට දහස් ගණනක් අහිමි වූ අතර අපට යුක්තිය අවශ්‍යයි. සහයෝගීතාවය සහතික කිරීම අපගේ යුතුකමයි. මේ හැමෝගෙම කතා ගොඩයි. හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා අතුරුදන්වූවන්ගේ දෙමළ පවුල් සමඟ පැවැති සාකච්ඡාවකදී ‘මෙහි කවුරුත් නැහැ; ඔබට අවශ්‍ය නම් ඔබට සියලුම සිරගෙවල් බලන්න පුළුවන්, නමුත් සිදුවූයේ කුමක්දැයි කිසිවෙකු දන්නේ නැත. මෙය පශ්චාත් ගැටුම් තත්ත්වයයි, අපට යුක්තිය අවශ්‍යයි.”",
        "රැලියට සහභාගී වූ ලංකා ගුරු සංගමයේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් ජෝසප් ස්ටාලින් ද මෝනිං වෙත පැවසුවේ, “මෙය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දීර්ඝතම ‘අරගලය’ වලින් එකකි. දෙමාපියන් 1000කට අධික පිරිසක් තම දරුවන් හමුදාවට භාර දුන් අතර, යුක්තිය වෙනුවෙන් සටන් කරමින් මෙම ‘අරගලය’ තුළදී දෙමාපියන් 136ක් මිය ගියහ. ජාත්‍යන්තර පරීක්ෂණයක් ඉල්ලා සිටීමේ වගකීම අපට තිබෙනවා.”",
        "මේ අතර, 2009 යුද්ධයේ අවසන් අදියරේදී තම පුත්‍රයා අතුරුදහන් වූ ආනන්ද් රාජා The Morning පුවත්පතට මෙසේ පැවසීය: “අපි මෙම අඛණ්ඩ අරගලය එම වසරේ (2009) සිට ආරම්භ කළෙමු. ඒ වන විට ඔහුගේ වයස අවුරුදු 34 කි. ඔහු ගොවිතැන් කරමින් සිටියේය. අපේ පුතා ගැන ප්‍රතිචාරයක් ලැබෙයි කියලා බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා. අපේ ඉල්ලීම සාධාරණ බවත්, හොඳම ප්‍රතිඵලය ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා තමන් මේ පිළිබඳව සොයා බලන බවත් හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා පැවසීය. එහෙත් ඔහු දුන් පොරොන්දුව ඉටු කර නැත. අතුරුදන් වූවන් පිළිබඳ කාර්යාලය ගැන අපේ ජනතාව විශ්වාස කරන්නේ නැහැ. එය බල රහිත ය. ඔවුන් කිසිවක් කර නැත. ”",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර රතු කුරුස කමිටුවේ (ICRC) වාර්තාවලට අනුව අතුරුදහන්ව සිටින 16,000 කට අධික පුද්ගලයින්ගේ පවුල්වලට 2009 දී අවසන් වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සන්නද්ධ ගැටුමෙන් පසු ගත වූ වසර ගණනාව සැනසීමක් ගෙන නැත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සිය ගණනක්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "දෙමළ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "හැසිරීම",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "කිලිනොච්චි",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "දින 2,000 යි",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "සිවිල් යුද්ධය",
          "label": "EVENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සිය ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලිනොච්චි දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 2,000 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිවිල් යුද්ධය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2017 පෙබරවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යහපාලන රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිනීවා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සන්ධ්‍යා එක්නැලිගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රගීත් එක්නැලිගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන: \"සඳහා",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 2,000 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 12 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ගුරු සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝසප් ස්ටාලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන: “මෙය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දීර්ඝතම ‘අරගලය’ වලින් එකකි",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "1000කට වඩා වැඩියි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "136",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආනන්ද රාජා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන: \"",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 34 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අතුරුදහන් වූවන් පිළිබඳ කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර රතු කුරුස කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நூற்றுக்கணக்கான தமிழ் தாய்மார்கள் கிளிநொச்சியில் 2,000 நாட்களைக் கொண்டாடும் வகையில், உள்நாட்டுப் போரின் போதும் அதற்குப் பின்னரும் பலவந்தமாக காணாமல் ஆக்கப்பட்ட தங்கள் மகன்களுக்கு நீதி கோரி போராட்டங்களை நடத்தினர்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "உள்நாட்டுப் போரின் போதும் அதற்குப் பின்னரும் பலவந்தமாக காணாமல் ஆக்கப்பட்ட தமது மகன்களுக்கு நீதி கோரி கிளிநொச்சி மாவட்டத்தில் கடந்த வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (12) நூற்றுக்கணக்கான தமிழ்த் தாய்மார்கள் 2000 நாட்களைக் கொண்டாடும் பேரணியில் ஈடுபட்டனர்.",
        "2017 பெப்ரவரி மாதம் யஹபாலன அரசாங்கத்தின் போது, ​​காணாமல் ஆக்கப்பட்டவர்களின் குடும்பங்களுக்கு நீதி வழங்குவதாக உறுதியளித்து, அவர்களது அன்புக்குரியவர்களின் கதி என்னவெனப் பதிலளிக்கக் கோரி போராட்டங்கள் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டன.",
        "தி மோர்னிங்கிடம் பேசிய மரிய சுரேஷ் ஈஸ்வரே, “கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவை கைது செய்ய வேண்டும் என்று நாங்கள் வலியுறுத்துகிறோம். அவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட பிறகு எங்களுக்கு நீதி கிடைக்கும். யாரிடமிருந்தும் எங்களுக்கு நீதி கிடைக்கவில்லை. சிங்கள சமூகமும் எமது போராட்டத்தில் இணைந்துள்ளது. எங்கள் கணவர்களை தேடி வருகிறோம். நான் இரண்டு முறை ஜெனிவா சென்று நீதி கேட்டு இருக்கிறேன். காணாமல் போன இந்த குழந்தைகளின் தாய்மார்களில் பலர், குறிப்பாக தினசரி கூலித் தொழிலில் தங்கியிருப்பவர்கள், நீதிக்காக தொடர்ந்து போராடும் போது பாரிய இன்னல்களை எதிர்கொள்கின்றனர். அவர்களில் சிலர் தற்போதைய சூழ்நிலையால் மூன்று வேளைக்கு பதிலாக ஒன்று அல்லது இரண்டு வேளை மட்டுமே சாப்பிடுகிறார்கள்.",
        "மனித உரிமை செயற்பாட்டாளரும், காணாமல் போன ஊடகவியலாளர் பிரகீத் எக்னலிகொடவின் மனைவியுமான சந்தியா எக்னலிகொட, The Morning இடம் கூறினார்: “இந்த தாய்மார்கள் 2,000 நாட்கள் நீதிக்காக காத்திருந்தனர். இத்தனை ஆண்டுகளாக இந்தப் போராட்டத்தைத் தொடர்ந்தனர். இலங்கையில் புதிய ஜனாதிபதி 2015 ஆம் ஆண்டு தேர்தலின் போது இந்த அம்மக்களை பயன்படுத்தியதால் இந்த அம்மக்களுக்கு நீதியையும் உண்மையையும் வழங்க அவருக்கு வாய்ப்பு கிடைத்துள்ளது. தென்னிலங்கையில் உள்ள தாய்மார்கள் சார்பாக நான் இந்த நிகழ்வில் பங்கேற்கிறேன்.",
        "“நான் வெவ்வேறு இடங்களில் இந்தப் போராட்டத்தில் கலந்து கொண்டேன், இதன் விளைவாக நாங்கள் விரும்புவது உண்மையும் நீதியும்தான். இந்தப் போராட்டத்தை 12 வருடங்களாக அனுபவித்தேன். உண்மையையும் நீதியையும் வென்றெடுப்பதற்கான ஒரே தீர்வு ‘அறகலயா’ (போராட்டம்)தான்.",
        "Fr. பிரச்சாரத்தின் தீவிர உறுப்பினரான யாழ்ப்பாணத்தைச் சேர்ந்த செல்வன், தி மார்னிங்கிடம் பேசுகையில், “நாங்கள் ஆயிரக்கணக்கானவர்களை இழந்தோம், எங்களுக்கு நீதி வேண்டும். ஒற்றுமையை உறுதிப்படுத்துவது நமது கடமையாகும். இவர்கள் அனைவரிடமும் நிறைய கதைகள் உள்ளன. முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன, காணாமல் ஆக்கப்பட்டவர்களின் தமிழ் குடும்பங்களுடனான கலந்துரையாடலில் ‘இங்கு யாரும் இல்லை; நீங்கள் விரும்பினால், நீங்கள் அனைத்து சிறைகளையும் பார்வையிடலாம், ஆனால் என்ன நடந்தது என்பது யாருக்கும் தெரியாது. இதுவே மோதலுக்குப் பிந்தைய நிலையாகும், எங்களுக்கு நீதி வேண்டும்” என்றார்.",
        "பேரணியில் கலந்துகொண்ட இலங்கை ஆசிரியர் சங்கத்தின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் ஜோசப் ஸ்டாலினும் தி மார்னிங்கிற்குத் தெரிவித்தார்: “இலங்கையில் மிக நீண்ட காலமாக இயங்கும் ‘அரகலயா’ இதுவாகும். 1,000 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட பெற்றோர்கள் தங்கள் குழந்தைகளை இராணுவத்திடம் ஒப்படைத்தனர், மேலும் 136 பெற்றோர்கள் இந்த ‘அறகலயா’வின் போது நீதிக்காக போராடி இறந்தனர். சர்வதேச விசாரணையை வலியுறுத்தும் பொறுப்பு எங்களுக்கு உள்ளது.",
        "இதேவேளை, 2009ஆம் ஆண்டு இறுதிக்கட்டப் போரின் போது காணாமல் போன தனது மகன் ஆனந்தராஜா தி மோர்னிங்கிடம் கூறியது: “இந்த தொடர்ச்சியான போராட்டத்தை அந்த ஆண்டிலிருந்து (2009) ஆரம்பித்துள்ளோம். அப்போது அவருக்கு வயது 34. விவசாயம் செய்து வந்தார். எங்கள் மகன் தொடர்பாக பதில் கிடைக்கும் என நம்புகிறோம். எங்களின் கோரிக்கை நியாயமானது என்றும், சிறந்த பலனைப் பெறுவதற்கு இந்த விடயம் தொடர்பில் கவனம் செலுத்துவதாகவும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன தெரிவித்தார். ஆனால் அவர் கொடுத்த வாக்குறுதியை நிறைவேற்றவில்லை. காணாமல் போனோர் அலுவலகத்தை எமது மக்கள் நம்பவில்லை. அது சக்தியற்றது. அவர்கள் எதுவும் செய்யவில்லை.",
        "சர்வதேச செஞ்சிலுவைச் சங்கத்தின் (ICRC) பதிவுகளின்படி, காணாமல் போன 16,000 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட நபர்களின் குடும்பங்களுக்கு 2009 இல் முடிவடைந்த ஆயுதப் போருக்குப் பின்னர் ஆண்டுகள் கடந்துவிட்டன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நூற்றுக்கணக்கானவர்கள்",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "தமிழ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "நடத்து",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "கிளிநொச்சி",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2,000 நாட்கள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "உள்நாட்டுப் போர்",
          "label": "EVENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நூற்றுக்கணக்கானவர்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வெள்ளிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிளிநொச்சி மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,000 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உள்நாட்டுப் போர்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிப்ரவரி 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யஹபாலன அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்களம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெனீவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சந்தியா எக்னலிகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரகீத் எக்னலிகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை: \"அதற்காக",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,000 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி மார்னிங்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ஆசிரியர் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜோசப் ஸ்டாலின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி மார்னிங்: “இது இலங்கையில் மிக நீண்ட காலமாக இயங்கும் ‘அறகலயா’க்களில் ஒன்றாகும்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,000க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "136",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆனந்த் ராஜா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை: \"",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "34 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காணாமல் போனோர் அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச செஞ்சிலுவைச் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}