{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Verbal-battle-erupts-between-RW-and-SP/108-240392",
  "time_ut": 1657018015,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Verbal battle erupts between RW and SP",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Verbal battle erupts between RW and SP",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A verbal battle between Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe and Leader of Opposition Sajith Premadasa rocked Parliament today with Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardene warning  that he would have to suspend the sessions if  the agenda is not followed.",
        "Mr. Premadasa who insisted that he has the right to reply to the Prime Minister irrespective of the agreed agenda said the latter had done the usual by talking about the bankrupt status of the country.",
        "Sajith -  “Prime Minister has failed as he has ended up talking of the economic downturn of the country. He had failed to come up with any solution to the long queues to purchase fuel and gas. It was the government which was led by Mr. Wickremesinghe that banned the Qatar charity fund. Now the government is going with the begging bowl to purchase fuel.\"",
        "Ranil -  \"One cannot purchase fuel from Qatar. It was I who was sent by Mr. Premadasa’s father to purchase fuel from the nations which had fuel.\"",
        "Sajith -  \"My father made Mr. Wickremeisnghe the ceremonies head of his 200 garment factory program. It was my father who gave opportunities to Mr. Wickremesinghe.\"",
        "Ranil - \"I was never the Minister in charge of appeal industry under President Premadasa’s cabinet. It was U. B. Wijekoon who was in charge of apparel industry.  Sajih and others don’t know how to capture power. One has to grip the power and then hold on to it. You cannot come to power by holding placards. I request Mr. Premadasa and others to come join me an I will teach them political lessons.\"",
        "Sajith - \"We  have thought a good lesion to Mr. Wickremeisnghe. His party was reduced to nothing and he was able to come to Parliament from the national list. He later got a kana chance and become the Prime Minister.\"",
        "Ranil - \"I am the one who saved Mr. Premadasa's father from the impeachment.\" (Yohan Perera and Ajith Siriwardana)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Verbal",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "RW",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Leader of Opposition Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith -  ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil -  ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith -  ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremeisnghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremeisnghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "kana",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yohan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Siriwardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "RW සහ SP අතර වාචික සටනක් ඇවිලෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "න්‍යාය පත්‍රය ක්‍රියාත්මක නොකළහොත් සැසිවාරය අත්හිටුවීමට සිදුවන බවට කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන අනතුරු ඇඟවීමත් සමඟ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ සහ විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස අතර වාචික සටනක් අද පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කැළඹුණා.",
        "එකඟ වූ න්‍යාය පත්‍රය කුමක් වුවත් අගමැතිවරයාට පිළිතුරු දීමට තමාට අයිතියක් ඇති බව තරයේ කියා සිටි ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා රටේ බංකොලොත් තත්ත්වය ගැන කතා කරමින් අගමැතිවරයා සුපුරුදු පරිදි කටයුතු කළ බව පැවසීය.",
        "සජිත් -  “රටේ ආර්ථික පසුබෑම ගැන කතා කර අවසන් නිසා අගමැති අසාර්ථකයි. ඉන්ධන සහ ගෑස් මිලදී ගැනීමට දිගු පෝලිම්වලට කිසිදු විසඳුමක් ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට ඔහු අපොහොසත් වී ඇත. කටාර් පුණ්‍යාධාර අරමුදල තහනම් කළේ වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ප්‍රමුඛ රජයයි. දැන් ආණ්ඩුව හිඟාකෑමට තෙල් ගන්න යනවා.",
        "රනිල් -  \"කෙනෙකුට කටාර් එකෙන් තෙල් ගන්න බෑ. ප්‍රේමදාස මහත්තයාගේ තාත්තා මාව තමයි ඉන්ධන තියෙන ජාතීන්ගෙන් තෙල් ගන්න එව්වේ.\"",
        "සජිත් -  \"මගේ තාත්තා එයාගේ ඇඟලුම් කම්හල් 200 වැඩසටහනේ උත්සව ප්‍රධානියා කළේ වික්‍රමසිංහ මහත්තයා. මගේ තාත්තා තමයි වික්‍රමසිංහ මහත්තයට අවස්ථා දුන්නේ.\"",
        "රනිල් - \"මම කවදාවත් ප්‍රේමදාස ජනාධිපතිතුමාගේ කැබිනට්ටුව යටතේ අභියාචනා කර්මාන්තය භාර ඇමති වුණේ නැහැ. ඇඟලුම් කර්මාන්තය භාරව හිටියේ යූ. බී. විජේකෝන්.  සජිහ් ඇතුළු පිරිස බලය අල්ලගන්න දන්නේ නැහැ. බලය අල්ලන්න ඕනේ ඊට පස්සේ ඒක අල්ලගෙන ඉන්න. පුවරු අල්ලාගෙන බලයට එන්න බැහැ. ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ඇතුළු පිරිසට මා සමඟ එකතු වන ලෙස මම ඉල්ලා සිටිනවා, ඔවුන්ට දේශපාලන පාඩම් කියා දෙන්නම්.\"",
        "සජිත් - \"අපි  හිතුවා වික්‍රමසිංහ මහත්තයට හොඳ වදයක් කියලා. එතුමාගේ පක්‍ෂය තුට්ටු දෙකට දාලා ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට එන්න පුළුවන් වුණා. පසුව එතුමාට කන අවස්ථාවක් ලැබිලා අගමැති වුණා.\"",
        "රනිල් - \"ප්‍රේමදාස මහත්තයාගේ තාත්තා දෝෂාභියෝගයෙන් බේරුවේ මමයි.\" (යොහාන් පෙරේරා සහ අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "වාචික",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "RW",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් -",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් -",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් -",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කනා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යොහාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "RW மற்றும் SP இடையே வாய்மொழி சண்டை வெடிக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாசவுக்கும் இடையிலான வாய்ச் சண்டை இன்று பாராளுமன்றத்தை உலுக்கிய சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன  நிகழ்ச்சி நிரலை பின்பற்றாவிடின் அமர்வுகளை இடைநிறுத்த நேரிடும் என எச்சரித்தார்.",
        "ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்பட்ட நிகழ்ச்சி நிரலைப் பொருட்படுத்தாமல் பிரதமருக்குப் பதிலளிக்க தமக்கு உரிமை உண்டு என்று வலியுறுத்திய திரு.",
        "சஜித் -  “நாட்டின் பொருளாதார வீழ்ச்சி பற்றி பேசி முடித்த பிரதமர் தோல்வியடைந்துள்ளார். எரிபொருள் மற்றும் எரிவாயுவை கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்கான நீண்ட வரிசையில் அவர் தீர்வைக் கொண்டு வரவில்லை. திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்க தலைமையிலான அரசாங்கமே கட்டார் தொண்டு நிதியை தடை செய்தது. இப்போது அரசாங்கம் எரிபொருள் வாங்க பிச்சைக் கிண்ணத்துடன் செல்கிறது.",
        "ரணில் -  \"கத்தாரில் இருந்து எரிபொருளை வாங்க முடியாது. எரிபொருள் உள்ள நாடுகளிடம் இருந்து எரிபொருளை வாங்குவதற்காக திரு. பிரேமதாசவின் தந்தையினால் நான் அனுப்பப்பட்டேன்.\"",
        "சஜித் -  \"எனது தந்தை திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்கவை தனது 200 ஆடைத் தொழிற்சாலைத் திட்டத்தின் விழாக்களுக்குத் தலைவராக்கினார். எனது தந்தைதான் திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு வாய்ப்புகளை வழங்கினார்.\"",
        "ரணில் - \"ஜனாதிபதி பிரேமதாசவின் அமைச்சரவையில் நான் ஒருபோதும் மேல்முறையீட்டுத் துறை அமைச்சராக இருந்ததில்லை. ஆடைத் தொழிலுக்குப் பொறுப்பாக இருந்தவர் யு.பி. விஜேகோன்.  சஜிக்கும் மற்றவர்களுக்கும் அதிகாரத்தைக் கைப்பற்றத் தெரியாது. ஒருவர் அதிகாரத்தைக் கைப்பற்ற வேண்டும். அதைப் பிடித்துக் கொள்ளுங்கள். பதாகைகளை ஏந்திக்கொண்டு ஆட்சிக்கு வர முடியாது. திரு. பிரேமதாசவையும் மற்றவர்களையும் என்னுடன் சேருமாறு கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறேன், அவர்களுக்கு அரசியல் பாடம் கற்பிப்பேன்.",
        "சஜித் - \"திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு நாங்கள் ஒரு நல்ல காயம் என்று நினைத்தோம். அவருடைய கட்சி ஒன்றுமில்லாமல் போய்விட்டது, அவர் தேசியப் பட்டியலில் இருந்து நாடாளுமன்றத்திற்கு வர முடிந்தது. பின்னர் அவருக்கு கனா வாய்ப்பு கிடைத்து பிரதமரானார்.\"",
        "ரணில் - \"திரு. பிரேமதாசவின் தந்தையை பதவி நீக்கத்தில் இருந்து காப்பாற்றியது நான்தான்.\" (யோஹான் பெரேரா மற்றும் அஜித் சிறிவர்தன)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வாய்மொழி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "RW",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் -",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் -",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் -",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்கே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்கே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோஹான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}