{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ජනාධිපති-තේරීමේදී-ජනතා-මතයට-පිටුපෑවා/101-616758",
  "time_ut": 1658317272,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ජනාධිපති තේරීමේදී ජනතා මතයට පිටුපෑවා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "He turned his back on public opinion in the presidential election",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Dr. Omalpe Sobitha Thero, Chief Sanghanayake of Sri Lanka Ramanya Maha Nikaya, said that the people's opinion was not represented in the election of the President in the Parliament, and the MPs were not sensitive to the people's struggle.",
        "However, Sobitha Thero also stated that according to the demands made by religious leaders and civil organizations led by Maha Na Thero, the current administration should work to establish an all-party government very soon, to end the suffering of the people, to amend the constitution and to hold a general election as soon as possible.",
        "Sobitha Thero who said that the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna accused Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe of misleading the country in 2019, and said that Mr. Wickramasinghe was also deprived of his parliamentary seat by saying that he was a thief, a traitor and a person who sold out the country who committed the bond fraud.",
        "Omalpe Sobitha Thero said that if Mr. Ranil Wickremesinghe rejects the allegations, action should be taken against those who made false accusations against him. He also said that he questions whether Mr. Dinesh Gunawardena has the legal and moral right to propose Mr. Ranil Wickremesinghe as a thief for the post of President. .",
        "He also said that the people are waiting to send home those who stole, cheated and told lies in the next election."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Omalpe Sobitha Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maha Nikaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sobitha Thero",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maha Na Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sobitha Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Omalpe Sobitha Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති තේරීමේදී ජනතා මතයට පිටුපෑවා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව තුළ ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනීමේදී ජනතා මතය නියෝජනය වී නොමැති බවත්, මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ජන අරගලය සම්බන්ධයෙන් සංවේදී නොවූ බවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා රාමඤ්ඤ මහා නිකායේ දක්ෂිණ ලංකාවේ ප්‍රධාන සංඝනායක, ආචාර්ය ඕමල්පේ සෝභිත හිමියෝ පැවසූහ.",
        "කෙසේ වුවත් දැන්වත් මහ නා හිමිවරුන් ප්‍රමුඛ ආගමික නායකයන් සහ සිවිල් සංවිධාන කළ ඉල්ලීම් අනුව ඉතා ඉක්මනින් සර්ව පාක්‍ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමට, මහජනතාවගේ දුක නැතිකිරීමට, ව්‍යවස්ථාව සංශෝධනය කිරීමට හා හැකි ඉක්මනින් මහ මැතිවරණයක් පැවැත්වීමට වත්මන් පාලනය කටයුතු කළ යුතු බව ද සෝභිත හිමියෝ සඳහන් කළහ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ 2019 දී රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට චෝදනා කරමින් රටක් මුලාවට පත්කළ බව කී සෝභිත හිමියෝ, ඔවුන් බැඳුම්කර වංචාව සිදුකළ හොරකු, දේශද්‍රෝහියකු, රට විකිණූ අයකු බව කියමින් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට පාර්ලිමේන්තු ආසනයද අහිමි කළ බව කීහ.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා එම චෝදනා ප්‍රතික්‍ෂේප කරන්නේ නම් තමන්ට අසත්‍ය චෝදනා එල්ල කළ අයට එරෙහිව පියවර ගත යුතු බව කී ඕමල්පේ සෝභිත හිමියෝ තමන් විසින්ම හොරකු ලෙස හංවඩු ගැසූ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපතිපති ධූරයට යෝජනා කිරීමට දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතාට නීතිමට හා සදාචාරාත්මක අයිතියක් තිබේදැයි තමන් ප්‍රශ්න කරන බව ද පැවසූහ.",
        "හොරකම්, වංචා කරමින්, මුසාවාද කී අය ඉදිරි මැතිවරණයකදී ගෙදර යැවීමට ජනතාව බලා සිටින බව ද උන්වහන්සේ ප්‍රකාශ කළහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕමල්පේ සෝභිත හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රමන්‍යා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහා නිකාය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෝභිත හාමුදුරුවෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහා නා හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෝභිත හාමුදුරුවෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕමල්පේ සෝභිත හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் பொதுக் கருத்துக்கு அவர் முதுகு காட்டிவிட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் மக்களின் கருத்துக்கள் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தப்படவில்லை எனவும், மக்கள் போராட்டத்தை எம்.பி.க்கள் உணரவில்லை எனவும் இலங்கை ராமன்ய மகா நிகாயத்தின் பிரதம சங்கநாயக கலாநிதி ஓமல்பே சோபித தேரர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், மகா நா தேரர் தலைமையிலான சமயத் தலைவர்கள் மற்றும் சிவில் அமைப்புக்களின் கோரிக்கைகளுக்கு அமைவாக, தற்போதைய நிர்வாகம் அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை விரைவில் நிறுவுவதற்கும், மக்களின் துன்பங்களுக்கு முடிவு கட்டுவதற்கும், திருத்தங்களைச் செய்வதற்கும் உழைக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் சோபித தேரர் குறிப்பிட்டார். அரசியலமைப்பு மற்றும் கூடிய விரைவில் பொதுத் தேர்தலை நடத்த வேண்டும்.",
        "2019ஆம் ஆண்டு ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நாட்டை தவறாக வழிநடத்தியதாக ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன குற்றம் சுமத்திய சோபித தேரர், திருடன், துரோகி, விற்பவர் என்று கூறி திரு. பத்திர மோசடி செய்த நாட்டை வெளியே.",
        "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க குற்றச்சாட்டுகளை நிராகரித்தால், தமக்கு எதிராக பொய்யான குற்றச்சாட்டை முன்வைத்தவர்களுக்கு எதிராக நடவடிக்கை எடுக்க வேண்டும் என தெரிவித்த ஓமல்பே சோபித தேரர், திரு.ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை முன்மொழிவதற்கு திரு.தினேஷ் குணவர்தனவுக்கு சட்ட மற்றும் தார்மீக உரிமை உள்ளதா எனவும் தாம் கேள்வி எழுப்புவதாகவும் தெரிவித்தார். ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு திருடனாக..",
        "அடுத்த தேர்தலில் திருடிய, ஏமாற்றிய, பொய் சொன்னவர்களை வீட்டுக்கு அனுப்ப மக்கள் காத்திருக்கின்றனர் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஓமல்பே சோபித தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரமன்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகா நிகாயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சோபித தேரோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகா நா தேரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சோபித தேரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமாதித்தன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஓமல்பே சோபித தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}