{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/If-no-diesel-supply-by-tomorrow-no-school-vans-on-Monday-Assn/342-243861",
  "time_ut": 1661599729,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "If no diesel supply by tomorrow, no school vans on Monday - Assn",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "If no diesel supply by tomorrow, no school vans on Monday - Assn",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "School vans would not be on the roads on Monday, if we do not get fuel by tomorrow, the All Island School Van Operators Association (AISVOA) said.",
        "Due to fuel shortages again hit the country, association chairman Malsiri de Silva said, \"We are unable to get adequate diesel from the Sri Lanka Transport Board (SLTB) depots.",
        "We informed the Power and Energy Minister and the Education Minister about this, as an association,\" they said.",
        "The Education Minister Susil Premajayantha requested Minister Kanchana Wijesekera to intervene and provide adequate fuel to SLTB depots. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "tomorrow",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Monday",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the All Island School Van Operators Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AISVOA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Malsiri de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Transport Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Power and Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Education",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Susil Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හෙට වන විට ඩීසල් ලබා නොදුනහොත් සඳුදා පාසල් වෑන් රථ නොමැත - සහකාර",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හෙට වන විට ඉන්ධන නොලැබුණහොත් සඳුදා පාසල් වෑන් රථ පාරේ නොයන බව සමස්ත ලංකා පාසල් වෑන් රථ ක්‍රියාකරුවන්ගේ සංගමය (AISVOA) පවසයි.",
        "යළිත් රට තුළ ඉන්ධන හිඟයක් ඇතිවී තිබෙන බැවින් එම සංගමයේ සභාපති මල්සිරි ද සිල්වා මහතා පැවසුවේ, “ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයේ (ශ්‍රී ලංගම) ඩිපෝවලින් අපට ප්‍රමාණවත් ඩීසල් ලබා ගැනීමට නොහැකි වී ඇති බවයි.",
        "අපි මේ පිළිබඳව සංගමයක් ලෙස විදුලිබල අමාත්‍යවරයා සහ අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍යවරයා දැනුවත් කළා.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් මැදිහත් වී ලංගම ඩිපෝවලට ප්‍රමාණවත් ඉන්ධන ලබා දෙන ලෙස අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍ය සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර මහතාගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කළා. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හෙට",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "සඳුදා",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමස්ත ලංකා පාසල් වෑන් රථ ක්‍රියාකරුවන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AISVOA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මල්සිරි ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බලය සහ ශක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අධ්යාපන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாளைக்குள் டீசல் சப்ளை இல்லை என்றால், திங்கள்கிழமை பள்ளி வேன்கள் இல்லை - அஸ்ஸன்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாளைய தினம் எரிபொருள் கிடைக்காவிட்டால் திங்கட்கிழமை பாடசாலை வேன்கள் வீதிகளில் இயங்காது என அகில இலங்கை பாடசாலை வேன் நடத்துநர்கள் சங்கம் (AISVOA) தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "நாட்டில் மீண்டும் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள எரிபொருள் தட்டுப்பாடு காரணமாக, இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் (SLTB) டிப்போக்களில் இருந்து போதியளவு டீசலை பெற்றுக்கொள்ள முடியாத நிலையில் உள்ளதாக சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் மல்சிறி டி சில்வா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இதுகுறித்து மின்வாரிய அமைச்சர் மற்றும் கல்வித்துறை அமைச்சரிடம் சங்கமாக தெரிவித்தோம்,'' என்றனர்.",
        "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் களஞ்சியசாலைகளுக்கு போதிய எரிபொருளை வழங்குவதற்கு தலையிட்டு நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு கல்வி அமைச்சர் சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகரவிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார். (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நாளை",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அகில இலங்கை பள்ளி வேன் நடத்துநர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AISVOA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மல்சிறி டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சக்தி மற்றும் ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கல்வி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}