{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-central-bank-governor-weerasinghe-re-appointed-96751/",
  "time_ut": 1656637080,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka central bank Governor Weerasinghe re-appointed",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka central bank Governor Weerasinghe re-appointed",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s Central Bank Governor Nandalal Weerasinghe has been re-appointed for a six year term by President Gotabaya Rajapaksa.",
        "The new term will take effect from July 04, the central bank said.",
        "He was invited to take over central bank by President Rajapaksa earlier in 2022 as the agency faced the worst currency crisis in its 72 year history and served the balance period of a six year term of Governor Indrajit Coomaraswamy.",
        "Sri Lanka is currently negotiating an International Monetary Fund bailout – the 16 of the intermediate regime central bank – along with debt restructuring. (Colombo/July01/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Weerasinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "a six year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 04",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "72 year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "six year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indrajit Coomaraswamy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකු අධිපති වීරසිංහ මහතා යළි පත් කෙරේ",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකු අධිපති නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා විසින් වසර හයක කාලයක් සඳහා නැවත පත් කර ඇත.",
        "නව කාලසීමාව ජූලි 04 වැනිදා සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන බව මහ බැංකුව පවසයි.",
        "ඒජන්සිය වසර 72ක ඉතිහාසයේ දරුණුතම මුදල් අර්බුදයට මුහුණ දුන් අතර ඉන්ද්‍රජිත් කුමාරස්වාමි ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයාගේ වසර 6ක ශේෂ කාලය සේවය කළ නිසා ඔහුට 2022 දී ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ විසින් මහ බැංකුව පවරා ගැනීමට ආරාධනා කරන ලදී.",
        "ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමත් සමඟ අතරමැදි පාලන තන්ත්‍රයේ මහ බැංකුවේ 16 වන ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල ඇපදීමක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දැනට සාකච්ඡා කරමින් සිටී. (කොළඹ/ජූලි01/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "වීරසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර හයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 04",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "72 වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්ද්‍රජිත් කුමාරස්වාමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්යන්තර මූල්ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி ஆளுநராக வீரசிங்க மீண்டும் நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையின் மத்திய வங்கி ஆளுநர் நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க, ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவினால் ஆறு வருட காலத்திற்கு மீண்டும் நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "புதிய காலக்கெடு ஜூலை 04 முதல் அமுலுக்கு வரும் என மத்திய வங்கி தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "72 ஆண்டுகால வரலாற்றில் மிக மோசமான நாணய நெருக்கடியை முகவர் நிறுவனம் எதிர்கொண்டது மற்றும் ஆளுநர் இந்திரஜித் குமாரசுவாமியின் ஆறு வருட கால மீதிக் காலத்தை அவர் 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு முன்னதாக ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்சவால் மத்திய வங்கியை எடுத்துக்கொள்ள அழைக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "இலங்கை தற்போது சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் பிணை எடுப்பு - இடைநிலை ஆட்சி மத்திய வங்கியின் 16 - கடன் மறுசீரமைப்புடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தி வருகிறது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை01/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "வீரசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு ஆறு வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 04",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "72 ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திரஜித் குமாரசுவாமி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}