{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Modi-congratulates-Dinesh/56-738187",
  "time_ut": 1659391825,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Modi congratulates Dinesh",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Modi congratulates Dinesh",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi in a congratulatory letter has wished newly appointed Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena and assured India’s support to the people of Sri Lanka.",
        "Gunawardena, 73, a veteran Politician was appointed as Sri Lanka’s Prime Minister by President Ranil Wickremesinghe on 22 July.",
        "“I would like to assure you as a dependable friend and close neighbour, India shall continue to support the people of Sri Lanka guided by our friend first policy,”",
        "Modi in his letter said. He went on to express his hope that Sri Lanka will witness quick economic recovery under Gunawardena’s leadership ensuring the prosperity and well-being of the country’s people.",
        "Last week, Modi also congratulated President Wickremesinghe and said that India will continue to be supportive of the quest of the people of the island nation for stability and economic recovery, through established democratic means."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Narendra Modi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gunawardena",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "73",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Politician",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunawardena",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Modi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "democratic",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මෝදි දිනේෂ්ට සුබ පතයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දීය අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි අභිනවයෙන් පත් වූ අගමැති දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතාට සුබපැතුම් ලිපියක් නිකුත් කරමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවට ඉන්දියාවේ සහයෝගය සහතික කර තිබේ.",
        "ප්‍රවීණ දේශපාලනඥයකු වන 73 හැවිරිදි ගුණවර්ධන මහතා ජූලි 22 වැනි දින ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස පත් කරන ලදී.",
        "\"විශ්වාසවන්ත මිතුරෙකු සහ සමීප අසල්වැසියෙකු ලෙස මම ඔබට සහතික වීමට කැමැත්තෙමි, අපගේ මිත්‍රයාගේ පළමු ප්‍රතිපත්තිය මගින් මෙහෙයවනු ලබන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවට ඉන්දියාව අඛණ්ඩව සහාය දෙන බව\"",
        "මෝදි සිය ලිපියේ සඳහන් කර ඇත. ගුණවර්ධන මහතාගේ නායකත්වය යටතේ රටේ ජනතාවගේ සමෘද්ධිය සහ යහපැවැත්ම සහතික කරමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඉක්මන් ආර්ථික ප්‍රකෘතියක් අත්කර ගනු ඇතැයි ඔහු සිය ප්‍රාර්ථනාව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "පසුගිය සතියේ මෝදි ද ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහට සුබ පැතූ අතර, ස්ථාපිත ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී මාධ්‍යයන් හරහා, ස්ථාවරත්වය සහ ආර්ථික ප්‍රකෘතිය සඳහා දිවයිනේ ජනතාවගේ ගවේෂණයට ඉන්දියාව අඛණ්ඩව සහාය දෙන බව පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "73",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දේශපාලනඥයා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෝඩි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රජාතන්ත්රවාදී",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தினேஷுக்கு மோடி வாழ்த்து தெரிவித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதிய பிரதமராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள தினேஷ் குணவர்தனவுக்கு வாழ்த்துக் கடிதம் அனுப்பியுள்ள இந்தியப் பிரதமர் நரேந்திர மோடி, இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு இந்தியாவின் ஆதரவை வழங்குவதாக உறுதியளித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மூத்த அரசியல்வாதியான 73 வயதான குணவர்தன, ஜூலை 22 அன்று ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் இலங்கையின் பிரதமராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "\"நம்பகமான நண்பராகவும் நெருங்கிய அண்டை நாடாகவும் நான் உங்களுக்கு உறுதியளிக்க விரும்புகிறேன், நமது நண்பன் முதல் கொள்கையால் வழிநடத்தப்படும் இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு இந்தியா தொடர்ந்து ஆதரவளிக்கும்\"",
        "இவ்வாறு மோடி தனது கடிதத்தில் கூறியுள்ளார். குணவர்தனவின் தலைமையின் கீழ், நாட்டின் மக்களின் செழிப்பு மற்றும் நல்வாழ்வை உறுதி செய்யும் வகையில் இலங்கை விரைவான பொருளாதார மீட்சியைக் காணும் என்று அவர் நம்பிக்கை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கடந்த வாரம், மோடியும் ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு வாழ்த்து தெரிவித்ததோடு, ஸ்திரத்தன்மை மற்றும் பொருளாதார மீட்சிக்கான தீவு தேச மக்களின் தேடலுக்கு, நிறுவப்பட்ட ஜனநாயக வழிமுறைகள் மூலம் இந்தியா தொடர்ந்து ஆதரவளிக்கும் என்று கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நரேந்திர மோடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "73",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியல்வாதி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மோடி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயக",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}