{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/joining-all-party-cabinet-wont-be-a-system-change-sri-lanka-opp-leader-98694/",
  "time_ut": 1660724040,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Joining all-party cabinet won’t be a ‘system change’: Sri Lanka opp. leader",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Joining all-party cabinet won’t be a ‘system change’: Sri Lanka opp. leader",
      "author": "Neshella Perera",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s main opposition the Samagi Jana Balavegaya (SJB) will not be taking up cabinet positions in the proposed all-party government as doing so will not be the ‘system change’ being sought, opposition and SJB leader Sajith Premadasa said.",
        "“We will not be accepting ministerial portfolios because that would not be a system change. It would be changing seats and promoting corruption,” said Premadasa speaking at an event in Colombo on Tuesday August 16.",
        "Premadasa said the SJB’s approach was to fulfill the needs of the nation through parliamentary committees that the party wishes to be part of.",
        "“If I was invited to be the President of the US or even the Prime Minister of the UK, I would not accept those positions but would choose to stand with my nation, my country,” he said.",
        "The event was an SJB-organised national assembly for women activists with representation from a number of groups involved in Sri Lanka’s youth-led Aragalaya (struggle) protest movement. Discussions focused on the economic crisis and its effect on Sri Lanka’s women.",
        "Tilted Maha Jana Sabhawa or People’s Council, the round of discussions was chaired by Premadasa. SJB national organiser Tissa Attanayake and former parliamentarian Hirunika Premachandra were also present.",
        "Speaking at the event, Attanayake said the SJB wishes to work with the government amicably but SJB members have been advised not to take the government up on any offers of positions.",
        "The event was attended by several groups that were involved in the Aragalaya, with representation from the deaf community, lawyers, mothers and state workers.",
        "SJB spokespersons said the progamme was launched to give due consideration to decisions that impact women in leadership as well as to discuss women’s issues in general. Seeking justice for protestors injured in a military raid on July 22 was also taken up.",
        "Among the issues raised was prices of sanitary napkins and menstrual products.",
        "In a recent tweet, Premadasa had praised Scotland for becoming the first country to provide sanitary napkins and menstrual products free of charge.",
        "“We raised this matter in parliament 2019 and we were laughed at and hooted at. It was not taken any notice of and I was not surprised.",
        "“They famously said they would implement it, but it was limited to words, not action,” he said. (Colombo/Aug17/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balavegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday August 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aragalaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tilted Maha Jana Sabhawa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "People’s Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tissa Attanayake",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hirunika Premachandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Attanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Aragalaya",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Scotland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Aug17/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සර්ව පාක්ෂික කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට එක්වීම ‘පද්ධති වෙනසක්’ නොවේ: ශ්‍රී ලංකාව විරුද්ධයි. නායක",
      "author": "නෙෂෙල්ලා පෙරේරා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂය වන සමගි ජන බලවේගය (SJB) යෝජිත සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවේ කැබිනට් අමාත්‍ය ධුර භාර නොගන්නා බව, එසේ කිරීමෙන් බලාපොරොත්තු වන ‘පද්ධති වෙනසක්’ නොවන බව විපක්ෂයේ සහ SJB නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "“අපි අමාත්‍ය ධුර භාරගන්නේ නැහැ මොකද ඒක ක්‍රමයේ වෙනසක් නොවන නිසා. එය ආසන මාරු කිරීම සහ දූෂණය ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමකි,” ප්‍රේමදාස අගෝස්තු 16 අඟහරුවාදා කොළඹ පැවති උත්සවයකදී පැවසීය.",
        "ප්‍රේමදාස පැවසුවේ SJB හි ප්‍රවේශය වන්නේ පක්ෂය කොටස්කරුවෙකු වීමට කැමති පාර්ලිමේන්තු කමිටු හරහා ජාතියේ අවශ්‍යතා ඉටු කිරීමයි.",
        "\"මට එක්සත් ජනපදයේ ජනාධිපති වීමට හෝ එක්සත් රාජධානියේ අගමැති වීමට ආරාධනා කළහොත්, මම එම තනතුරු භාර නොගන්නා නමුත් මගේ ජාතිය, මගේ රට සමඟ නැගී සිටීමට තීරණය කරමි,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මෙම උත්සවය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තරුණ නායකත්වයෙන් යුත් අරගලය (අරගල) විරෝධතා ව්‍යාපාරයට සම්බන්ධ කණ්ඩායම් ගණනාවක නියෝජනය සහිත කාන්තා ක්‍රියාකාරීන් සඳහා SJB විසින් සංවිධානය කරන ලද ජාතික සභාවකි. ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කාන්තාවන් කෙරෙහි එහි බලපෑම පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා අවධානය යොමු විය.",
        "ඇලවූ මහා ජන සභාව හෙවත් මහජන සභාව, සාකච්ඡා වටය ප්‍රේමදාසගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් පැවැත්විණි. මෙම අවස්ථාවට SJB ජාතික සංවිධායක තිස්ස අත්තනායක, හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීනී හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර යන මහත්ම මහත්මීහුද එක්ව සිටියහ.",
        "එහිදී අදහස් දැක්වූ අත්තනායක කියා සිටියේ SJB රජය සමඟ සුහදව කටයුතු කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන නමුත් SJB සාමාජිකයින්ට කිසිදු තනතුරු පිරිනැමීමකට රජය ගෙන නොයන ලෙසට උපදෙස් දී ඇති බවයි.",
        "මෙම අවස්ථාවට බිහිරි ප්‍රජාව, නීතීඥයින්, මව්වරුන් සහ රාජ්‍ය සේවකයින් නියෝජනය කරමින් අරගලයට සම්බන්ධ කණ්ඩායම් කිහිපයක් සහභාගී විය.",
        "SJB ප්‍රකාශකයින් පැවසුවේ නායකත්වයේ කාන්තාවන්ට බලපාන තීරණ පිළිබඳව නිසි සැලකිල්ලක් දැක්වීමට මෙන්ම පොදුවේ කාන්තා ගැටලු සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට මෙම වැඩසටහන දියත් කළ බවයි. ජුලි 22 දා හමුදා ප්‍රහාරයකින් තුවාල ලැබූ විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට යුක්තිය ඉල්ලා සිටීම ද සිදු විය.",
        "එහිදී මතු වූ ගැටලු අතර සනීපාරක්ෂක තුවා සහ ආර්තව නිෂ්පාදනවල මිල ගණන් විය.",
        "ප්‍රේමදාස මෑතකදී ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින්, සනීපාරක්ෂක තුවා සහ ඔසප් නිෂ්පාදන නොමිලේ සපයන පළමු රට බවට ස්කොට්ලන්තය පත්වීම ගැන ප්‍රශංසා කර තිබුණි.",
        "“අපි මේ කාරණය 2019 පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී මතු කළ අතර අපට හිනා වුණා, හූ කිව්වා. එය කිසිදු අවධානයක් යොමු නොකළ අතර මම පුදුමයට පත් නොවීය.",
        "\"ඔවුන් එය ක්‍රියාවට නංවන බව ප්‍රසිද්ධියේ කී නමුත් එය ක්‍රියාවට නොව වචනවලට සීමා විය,\" ඔහු පැවසීය. (කොළඹ/අගෝ.17/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 16 අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරගලය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇලවූ මහා ජන සභාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිස්ස අත්තනායක",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අත්තනායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අරගලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්කොට්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/අගෝ.17/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அனைத்துக் கட்சி அமைச்சரவையில் இணைவது அமைப்பு மாற்றமாக இருக்காது: இலங்கை எதிர்கட்சி. தலைவர்",
      "author": "நெஷெல்லா பெரேரா",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையின் பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியான சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) உத்தேச சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தில் அமைச்சரவை பதவிகளை ஏற்காது, அவ்வாறு செய்வது ‘அமைப்பு மாற்றம்’ கோரப்படாது என்று எதிர்க்கட்சி மற்றும் SJB தலைவரான சஜித் பிரேமதாச தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "“அமைச்சர் இலாகாக்களை நாங்கள் ஏற்க மாட்டோம், ஏனெனில் அது ஒரு முறை மாற்றமாக இருக்காது. இது ஆசனங்களை மாற்றி ஊழலை ஊக்குவிப்பதாக இருக்கும்” என ஆகஸ்ட் 16 செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை கொழும்பில் நடைபெற்ற நிகழ்வொன்றில் பிரேமதாச கூறினார்.",
        "கட்சியின் அங்கமாக இருக்க விரும்பும் பாராளுமன்றக் குழுக்களின் மூலம் தேசத்தின் தேவைகளை நிறைவேற்றுவதே SJB யின் அணுகுமுறை என பிரேமதாச கூறினார்.",
        "\"அமெரிக்காவின் அதிபராகவோ அல்லது இங்கிலாந்தின் பிரதமராகவோ இருக்க என்னை அழைத்தால், நான் அந்த பதவிகளை ஏற்க மாட்டேன், ஆனால் என் தேசத்துடன், என் நாட்டோடு நிற்கத் தேர்வு செய்வேன்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "இந்த நிகழ்வானது, இலங்கையின் இளைஞர்கள் தலைமையிலான அரகலயா (போராட்டம்) எதிர்ப்பு இயக்கத்தில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள பல குழுக்களின் பிரதிநிதித்துவத்துடன் கூடிய பெண் செயற்பாட்டாளர்களுக்கான SJB-யால் ஒழுங்கமைக்கப்பட்ட தேசிய சபையாகும். பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி மற்றும் இலங்கையின் பெண்கள் மீதான அதன் தாக்கம் குறித்து கலந்துரையாடல்களில் கவனம் செலுத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "சாய்ந்த மஹா ஜன சபை அல்லது மக்கள் பேரவை, கலந்துரையாடல் சுற்று பிரேமதாச தலைமையில் நடைபெற்றது. SJB தேசிய அமைப்பாளர் திஸ்ஸ அத்தநாயக்க மற்றும் முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர ஆகியோரும் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "நிகழ்வில் உரையாற்றிய அத்தநாயக்க, SJB அரசாங்கத்துடன் இணக்கமாக செயற்பட விரும்புவதாகவும் ஆனால் SJB உறுப்பினர்கள் எந்தவொரு பதவிகளையும் அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எடுத்துச் செல்ல வேண்டாம் என்று அறிவுறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்த நிகழ்வில் காதுகேளாத சமூகம், சட்டத்தரணிகள், தாய்மார்கள் மற்றும் அரச ஊழியர்களின் பிரதிநிதித்துவத்துடன் அரகலயாவில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள பல குழுக்களும் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "SJB செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர்கள் கூறுகையில், தலைமைப் பொறுப்பில் உள்ள பெண்களை பாதிக்கும் முடிவுகளுக்கு உரிய பரிசீலனை அளிப்பதற்காகவும், பொதுவாக பெண்களின் பிரச்சினைகளைப் பற்றி விவாதிக்கவும் இந்த திட்டம் தொடங்கப்பட்டது. ஜூலை 22 அன்று இராணுவ தாக்குதலில் காயமடைந்த போராட்டக்காரர்களுக்கு நீதி கோரியும் நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "எழுப்பப்பட்ட பிரச்சினைகளில் சானிட்டரி நாப்கின்கள் மற்றும் மாதவிடாய் பொருட்களின் விலையும் அடங்கும்.",
        "சமீபத்திய ட்வீட்டில், பிரேமதாசா சானிட்டரி நாப்கின்கள் மற்றும் மாதவிடாய் பொருட்களை இலவசமாக வழங்கும் முதல் நாடு ஸ்காட்லாந்து என்று பாராட்டினார்.",
        "“நாங்கள் 2019 நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் இந்த விஷயத்தை எழுப்பினோம், நாங்கள் சிரித்தோம், கூச்சலிட்டோம். இது எந்த கவனமும் எடுக்கப்படவில்லை மற்றும் நான் ஆச்சரியப்படவில்லை.",
        "\"அவர்கள் அதை செயல்படுத்துவோம் என்று பிரபலமாக சொன்னார்கள், ஆனால் அது வார்த்தைகளுக்கு மட்டுப்படுத்தப்பட்டது, செயல் அல்ல,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார். (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்17/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 16 செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரகலயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாய்ந்த மகா ஜன சபை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் கவுன்சில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திஸ்ஸ அத்தநாயக்க",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அத்தநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரகலயா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்காட்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்17/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}