{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/main_picture/තුවාලකරුවන්-බලන්න-වැඩබලන-ජනපති-හමුදා-රෝහලට-යයි/11-616480",
  "time_ut": 1657894752,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "තුවාලකරුවන් බලන්න වැඩබලන ජනපති හමුදා රෝහලට යයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The Acting President goes to the military hospital to see the injured",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Acting President Ranil Wickramasinghe visited the Army Hospital today to inquire about the well-being of the military personnel who were injured during the unrest that occurred on the 13th at Polduwa intersection near the Battaramulla Parliament entrance.",
        "There, the President also engaged in a cordial meeting with the military personnel.",
        "Army Commander and former Member of Parliament Mr. Ashu Marasinghe and others participated in this event."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 13th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Battaramulla Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ashu Marasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තුවාලකරුවන් බලන්න වැඩබලන ජනපති හමුදා රෝහලට යයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "බත්තරමුල්ල පාර්ලිමේන්තු පිවිසුම අසල පොල්දූව මංසන්ධියේ දී ඉකුත් 13 වැනිදා ඇතිවූ නොසන්සුන්තාව යේදී තුවාල ලැබූ හමුදා සාමාජිකයන්ගේ සුවදුක් විමසීමට වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අද යුද හමුදා රෝහලට ගියේ ය.",
        "එහිදී ජනාධිපතිවරයා හමුදා සාමාජිකයන් සමග සුහඳ පිළිසදරක ද නිරත විය.",
        "මෙම අවස්ථාවට යුද හමුදාපතිවරයා ද හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ආශු මාරසිංහ මහතා ඇතුළු පිරිසක් ද සහභාගී වූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බත්තරමුල්ල පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආශු මාරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "காயமடைந்தவர்களை பார்ப்பதற்காக தற்காலிக ஜனாதிபதி இராணுவ மருத்துவமனைக்கு செல்கிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பத்தரமுல்ல பாராளுமன்ற நுழைவாயிலுக்கு அருகில் உள்ள பொல்துவ சந்தியில் கடந்த 13 ஆம் திகதி இடம்பெற்ற அமைதியின்மையின் போது காயமடைந்த இராணுவ வீரர்களின் நலம் விசாரிப்பதற்காக பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இன்று இராணுவ வைத்தியசாலைக்கு விஜயம் செய்தார்.",
        "அங்கு ஜனாதிபதி இராணுவத்தினருடன் சுமூகமான சந்திப்பிலும் ஈடுபட்டார்.",
        "இந்நிகழ்வில் இராணுவத் தளபதியும் முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருமான திரு.ஆசு மாரசிங்க உள்ளிட்டோர் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தரமுல்ல பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஷு மாரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}