{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ඕමාන-තානාපති-ජනපති-හමුවෙයි/11-395013",
  "time_ut": 1656668918,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඕමාන තානාපති ජනපති හමුවෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ambassador of Oman meets President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Oman's Ambassador Ahmed Ali Saeed Al Rashidi has told the President that the two countries will help strengthen bilateral ties on fuel, gas, energy, employment and investment opportunities.",
        "The Omani ambassador, who is to leave the island after finishing his service, mentioned this while meeting President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa at the Fort President's House in Colombo today (01).",
        "About 25,000 Sri Lankans are currently working in Oman. The President also asked the Ambassador to assist in increasing job opportunities in the training sector.",
        "The president appreciated the support provided to Sri Lanka during the 08 years of service of Mr. Syed Al Rashd and discussed the wide scope for trade and investment opportunities in the country.",
        "Mr. Rashd mentioned with the President that he is proposed to report to the service of the Omani Foreign Ministry and work to strengthen the relations between the two countries from there."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Oman",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Oman",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ahmed Ali Saeed Al Rashidi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Omani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "About 25,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oman",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 08 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Syed Al Rashd",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rashd",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Omani Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඕමාන තානාපති ජනපති හමුවෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්ධන, ගෑස්, බලශක්ති, රැකියා සහ ආයෝජන අවස්ථා සම්බන්ධයෙන් දෙරට අතර ද්විපාර්ශ්වීය සබඳතා ශක්තිමත් කර ගැනීමට සහාය වන බව ඕමාන තානාපති අහමඩ් අලි සයීඩ් අල් රෂ්ඩි මහතා ජනාධිපති සමග පවසයි.",
        "සේවය අවසන් කර දිවයිනෙන් පිටත්ව යාමට නියමිත ඕමාන තානාපතිවරයා අද (01දා) පෙරවරුවේ කොළඹ, කොටුව ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ දී ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා හමුවෙමින් මේ බව සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් 25,000ක පමණ පිරිසක් මේ වන විට ඕමානයේ රැකියාවන්හි නිරතව සිටිති. පුහුණු ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ රැකියා අවස්ථා වැඩිකර ගැනීමට ද සහාය වන ලෙස ජනාධිපතිවරයා තානාපතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "සයීඩ් අල් රෂ්ඩ් මහතාගේ වසර 08ක සේවා කාලය තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබාදුන් සහාය ඇගයීමට ලක් කළ ජනාධිපතිවරයා මෙරට වෙළෙඳ සහ ආයෝජන අවස්ථා සඳහා ඇති පුළුල් අවකාශය පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡා කරනු ලැබීය.",
        "තමා ඕමාන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ සේවයට වාර්තා කිරීමට යෝජිත අතර දෙරට අතර සබඳතා ශක්තිමත් කරගැනීමට එහි සිට ද කටයුතු කරන බව රෂ්ඩ් මහතා ජනාධිපතිවරයා සමග සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඕමානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕමානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අහමඩ් අලි සයීඩ් අල් රෂිඩි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕමාන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25,000 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 08",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Syed Al Rashd",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රෂ්ඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමාන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஓமன் நாட்டு தூதர் ஜனாதிபதியை சந்தித்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எரிபொருள், எரிவாயு, எரிசக்தி, வேலைவாய்ப்பு மற்றும் முதலீட்டு வாய்ப்புகள் ஆகியவற்றில் இருதரப்பு உறவுகளை வலுப்படுத்துவதற்கு இரு நாடுகளும் உதவும் என்று ஓமன் தூதர் அஹமட் அலி சயீத் அல் ரஷிதி ஜனாதிபதியிடம் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "தனது சேவையை முடித்துக் கொண்டு நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறவுள்ள ஓமானிய தூதுவர் இன்று (01) கொழும்பு கோட்டை ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை சந்தித்த போதே இதனைக் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "சுமார் 25,000 இலங்கையர்கள் தற்போது ஓமானில் பணியாற்றி வருகின்றனர். பயிற்சித் துறையில் தொழில் வாய்ப்புகளை அதிகரிப்பதற்கு உதவுமாறும் ஜனாதிபதி தூதுவரிடம் கேட்டுக்கொண்டார்.",
        "திரு. சையத் அல் ரஷ்தின் 08 வருட சேவையின் போது இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கப்பட்ட ஆதரவைப் பாராட்டிய ஜனாதிபதி, நாட்டில் வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் முதலீட்டு வாய்ப்புகளுக்கான பரந்த வாய்ப்புகள் குறித்து கலந்துரையாடினார்.",
        "ஓமன் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சுக்கு அறிக்கை செய்து, இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையிலான உறவுகளை வலுப்படுத்த அங்கிருந்து பணியாற்ற விரும்புவதாக திரு ருஷ்ட் ஜனாதிபதியிடம் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஓமன்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஓமன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அகமது அலி சயீத் அல் ரஷிதி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஓமானி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 25,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "08 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சையத் அல் ரஷ்த்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஷ்ட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமன் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}