{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84390/australia-kicks-in-extra-25-million-emergency-aid-to-sri-lanka",
  "time_ut": 1660847640,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Australia kicks in extra $25 million emergency aid to Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Australia kicks in extra $25 million emergency aid to Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Australian government will lift emergency aid to Sri Lanka to AU$75 million as the south Asian island grapples with an economic crisis that has triggered a new surge of people fleeing on boats for Australia.",
        "Sri Lanka’s worst financial meltdown has led to skyrocketing prices and crippling shortages of food, fuel and other necessities over the past three months and year-on-year inflation has climbed beyond 60 per cent.",
        "The deterioration of living conditions has resulted in a renewal of attempted boat arrivals in Australia from Sri Lanka, with five vessels being intercepted by Australian Border Force with a total of 137 people on board and 15 more, carrying 701 passengers all up, being stopped in Sri Lankan waters.",
        "Boat arrivals also became a key focus on the day of May’s federal election after the Liberal Party texted voters in marginal seats about the interception of an asylum seeker boat that morning.",
        "In the past week, China, a key creditor of the bankrupt island nation, has also flexed its muscles by insisting on docking a giant scientific research ship at southern Sri Lanka’s Hambantota port despite concerns raised by India.",
        "In the midst of Sri Lanka’s freefall, Australia committed AU$50 million in June in urgent humanitarian backing. On Friday, it will announce a further AU$25 million to fast-track food and health supplies to those in most need in the former British colony.",
        "“Australia stands with the people of Sri Lanka, especially those experiencing severe hardship,” Foreign Minister Penny Wong said.",
        "“It is in Australia’s national interest to strengthen Sri Lanka’s economic resilience and accelerate its recovery.”",
        "The beefed-up support package comes a fortnight after an unprecedented move when Australian Border Force used its own patrol vessel to return 46 men to Colombo that it had intercepted at sea rather than taking them back by air.",
        "In a deliberate message aimed at discouraging people from paying people smugglers and boarding boats towards Australia, the 110-metre Ocean Shield was given a publicised welcoming ceremony by the Sri Lanka Navy after pulling into the port in the capital city.",
        "Lately, it has been another ship that has been the centre of attention as Beijing has demonstrated its influence there.",
        "The Sri Lankan government asked China to delay the arrival of the Yuan Wang 5 tracking vessel for a reported refuelling and replenishment at Hambantota, a port built with Chinese loans and since leased to Chinese state-owned companies for 99 years as a debt swap.",
        "There were fears that the “spy ship”, as it was labelled in the Indian media, could conduct surveillance in the region. Sri Lanka ultimately give it the go-ahead to dock on Tuesday, saying it would not carry out research activities while it was in Sri Lankan waters.",
        "The saga illustrated the fine balancing act an ailing Sri Lanka is having to perform with the two Asian powers. India, another creditor, has been the major source of foreign assistance for the island, kicking in more than $US4 billion during the crisis. But China’s agreement to restructure infrastructure loans to Sri Lanka is vital for the country to reach a bailout program with the International Monetary Fund.",
        "Former president Gotabaya Rajapaksa will reportedly return to Sri Lanka next week after leaving the country and resigning when his residence was overrun by thousands of protesters in July. He has been residing in Singapore and Thailand.",
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe, who was voted in by MPs as Rajapaksa’s successor a month ago and moved to dismantle the months-old protest camps in Colombo, said this week Sri Lanka’s state of emergency would not be imposed beyond this week.",
        "Sri Lanka in April defaulted on its foreign debt of $51 billion as its foreign currency reserves dried up."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Australia",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "$25 million",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Australian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past three months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "year-on-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "60 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "137",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "701",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the day of May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Liberal Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the past week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AU$50 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AU$25 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Penny Wong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "46",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "110-metre",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ocean Shield",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "99 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than $US4 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "a month ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "months-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$51 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඩොලර් මිලියන 25 ක හදිසි ආධාර ලබා දෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවට බෝට්ටුවලින් පලා යන මිනිසුන්ගේ නව වැඩිවීමක් ඇති කර ඇති ආර්ථික අර්බුදයක් සමඟ දකුණු ආසියානු දූපත පොරබදමින් සිටින විට ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු රජය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හදිසි ආධාර ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 75 දක්වා ඉවත් කරනු ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නරකම මූල්‍ය බිඳවැටීම පසුගිය මාස තුන තුළ මිල ගණන් ඉහළ යාමට සහ ආහාර, ඉන්ධන සහ අනෙකුත් අවශ්‍යතා හිඟවීමට හේතු වී ඇති අතර වසරින් වසර උද්ධමනය සියයට 60 ඉක්මවා ගොස් ඇත.",
        "ජීවන තත්ත්වය පිරිහීම හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාවට බෝට්ටු පැමිණීමේ උත්සාහයන් අලුත් කිරීමට හේතු වී ඇති අතර, ඔස්ට්‍රේලියානු දේශසීමා බළකාය විසින් මගීන් 701ක් සමඟින් පුද්ගලයන් 137 දෙනෙකු සහ තවත් 15 දෙනෙකු සමඟින් යාත්‍රා පහක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන නවතා ඇත. ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජලය.",
        "එදින උදෑසන සරණාගත බෝට්ටුවකට බාධා කිරීම ගැන ලිබරල් පක්ෂය ආන්තික ආසනවල ඡන්දදායකයින්ට කෙටි පණිවුඩ යැවීමෙන් පසු මැයි ෆෙඩරල් මැතිවරණය පැවැත්වෙන දිනයේ බෝට්ටු පැමිණීම ප්‍රධාන අවධානයට ලක් විය.",
        "පසුගිය සතියේ, බංකොලොත් දූපත් ජාතියේ ප්‍රධාන ණයහිමියෙකු වන චීනය, ඉන්දියාව විසින් මතු කරන ලද කනස්සල්ල නොතකා දකුණු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ හම්බන්තොට වරායේ යෝධ විද්‍යාත්මක පර්යේෂණ නෞකාවක් නැව්ගත කරන ලෙස අවධාරනය කරමින් සිය මාංශ පේශි නම්‍ය කර ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නිදහස් වැටීම මධ්‍යයේ, ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව ජූනි මාසයේදී හදිසි මානුෂීය ආධාර සඳහා ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 50 ක් ලබා දුන්නේය. සිකුරාදා, පැරණි බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය යටත් විජිතයේ වඩාත්ම අවශ්‍යතා ඇති අයට ආහාර සහ සෞඛ්‍ය සැපයුම් වේගවත් කිරීම සඳහා තවත් AU$ මිලියන 25ක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරනු ඇත.",
        "\"ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාව සමඟ, විශේෂයෙන්ම දැඩි දුෂ්කරතා අත්විඳින ජනතාව සමඟ සිට සිටිනවා,\" විදේශ අමාත්‍ය Penny Wong පැවසීය.",
        "\"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික ඔරොත්තු දීමේ හැකියාව ශක්තිමත් කිරීම සහ එහි ප්‍රකෘතිය වේගවත් කිරීම ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාවේ ජාතික අවශ්‍යතාවයයි.\"",
        "ඔස්ට්‍රේලියානු දේශසීමා හමුදාව තමන්ගේම මුර යාත්‍රාවක් යොදාගෙන ඔවුන් ගුවනින් ආපසු රැගෙන නොගොස් මුහුදේදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් මිනිසුන් 46 දෙනෙකු ආපසු කොළඹට ගෙන ඒමේදී පෙර නොවූ විරූ පියවරකින් දෙසතියකට පසු හරක් සකසන ලද ආධාරක පැකේජය පැමිණේ.",
        "මිනිසුන් ජාවාරම්කරුවන්ට මුදල් ගෙවා ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාව දෙසට බෝට්ටුවලට නැගීමෙන් ජනතාව අධෛර්යමත් කිරීමේ අරමුණින් සිතාමතා පණිවිඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින්, මීටර් 110 සාගර පලිහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් අගනුවර වරායට ඇදීමෙන් පසු ප්‍රසිද්ධියේ පිළිගැනීමේ උත්සවයක් පවත්වන ලදී.",
        "මෑතකදී, බීජිං එහි බලපෑම පෙන්නුම් කර ඇති බැවින් එය අවධානයට ලක් වූ තවත් නෞකාවකි.",
        "චීන ණය වලින් ඉදිකරන ලද සහ ණය හුවමාරුවක් ලෙස චීන රජය සතු සමාගම්වලට වසර 99කට බදු දී ඇති වරායක් වන හම්බන්තොට වරායට ඉන්ධන සැපයීම සහ නැවත පිරවීම සඳහා යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 ට්‍රැකින් යාත්‍රාව පැමිණීම ප්‍රමාද කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය චීනයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "ඉන්දියානු මාධ්‍යවල ලේබල් කර ඇති පරිදි “ඔත්තු නැව” කලාපය තුළ නිරීක්ෂණ සිදු කළ හැකි බවට බියක් පැවතුනි. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අවසානයේ දී ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුහුදු සීමාවේ සිටියදී පර්යේෂණ කටයුතු සිදු නොකරන බව පවසමින් අඟහරුවාදා නැව් තටාකයට යාමට අවසර ලබා දුන්නේය.",
        "රෝගාතුරව සිටින ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ආසියානු බලවතුන් දෙදෙනා සමඟ ඉටු කිරීමට සිදු වන සියුම් සමතුලිත ක්‍රියාව මෙම කතාවෙන් නිරූපණය විය. තවත් ණයහිමියෙකු වන ඉන්දියාව, දිවයින සඳහා විදේශ ආධාරවල ප්‍රධාන මූලාශ්‍රය වී ඇති අතර, අර්බුදය අතරතුර ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 4 කට වඩා වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් පයින් ගසා ඇත. එහෙත් ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ ඇපදීමේ වැඩසටහනකට එළැඹීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට යටිතල පහසුකම් ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමට චීනයේ එකඟතාව අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වේ.",
        "ජුලි මාසයේදී දහස් සංඛ්‍යාත විරෝධතාකරුවන් විසින් ඔහුගේ නිවසට යටවීමත් සමඟ හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ රටින් පිටව ගොස් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු ලබන සතියේ නැවත ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙන බව වාර්තා වේ. ඔහු සිංගප්පූරුවේ සහ තායිලන්තයේ පදිංචිව සිට ඇත.",
        "මාසයකට පෙර රාජපක්ෂගේ අනුප්‍රාප්තිකයා ලෙස මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් විසින් ඡන්දය ලබා දී මාස ගණනක් පැරණි කොළඹ විරෝධතා කඳවුරු කඩා බිඳ දැමීමට පියවර ගත් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, මේ සතියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ හදිසි නීතිය මේ සතියෙන් ඔබ්බට පනවන්නේ නැතැයි පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී එහි විදේශ මුදල් සංචිත සිඳී යාම නිසා ඩොලර් බිලියන 51 ක විදේශ ණය පැහැර හැරියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 25 කි",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාස තුන",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරින් වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 60 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "137",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "701",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැයි දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිබරල් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සතියේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AU ඩොලර් මිලියන 50ක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AU ඩොලර් මිලියන 25ක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙනි වොන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "46",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීටර් 110",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර පලිහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 99 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 4 කට වඩා",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසයකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස ගණනක් පැරණි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 51 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அவுஸ்திரேலியா இலங்கைக்கு 25 மில்லியன் டொலர் அவசர உதவியை வழங்கியுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தெற்காசிய தீவு பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் சிக்கித் தவிக்கும் நிலையில், ஆஸ்திரேலியாவிற்கு படகுகளில் தப்பிச் செல்லும் மக்கள் புதிய எழுச்சியைத் தூண்டியுள்ள நிலையில், ஆஸ்திரேலிய அரசாங்கம் இலங்கைக்கான அவசர உதவியை AU$75 மில்லியனாக உயர்த்தும்.",
        "இலங்கையின் மிக மோசமான நிதியச் சரிவு கடந்த மூன்று மாதங்களில் விலைவாசி உயர்வு மற்றும் உணவு, எரிபொருள் மற்றும் இதர தேவைகளின் பற்றாக்குறைக்கு வழிவகுத்தது மற்றும் ஆண்டுக்கு ஆண்டு பணவீக்கம் 60 சதவீதத்தை தாண்டி உயர்ந்துள்ளது.",
        "வாழ்க்கை நிலைமை மோசமடைந்ததன் விளைவாக, இலங்கையில் இருந்து ஆஸ்திரேலியாவுக்குப் படகு வருவதற்கான முயற்சிகள் புதுப்பிக்கப்பட்டன, ஐந்து கப்பல்களை ஆஸ்திரேலிய எல்லைப் படை தடுத்து நிறுத்தியது, மொத்தம் 137 பேர் மற்றும் 15 பேர், 701 பயணிகளை ஏற்றிச் சென்றனர். இலங்கை கடல்.",
        "மே மாத கூட்டாட்சித் தேர்தலின் நாளில், புகலிடக் கோரிக்கையாளர் படகு ஒன்று குறுக்கிடுவதைப் பற்றி லிபரல் கட்சி வாக்காளர்களுக்கு குறுஞ்செய்தி அனுப்பிய பின்னர் படகு வருகையும் முக்கிய மையமாக மாறியது.",
        "கடந்த வாரத்தில், திவாலாகிவிட்ட தீவு தேசத்தின் முக்கிய கடனாளியான சீனாவும், இந்தியாவின் கவலைகளை மீறி, தென்னிலங்கையின் அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் ஒரு மாபெரும் அறிவியல் ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பலை நிறுத்த வலியுறுத்தி அதன் தசைகளை நெகிழ வைத்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையின் வீழ்ச்சிக்கு மத்தியில், அவசர மனிதாபிமான ஆதரவில் ஜூன் மாதம் ஆஸ்திரேலியா 50 மில்லியன் ஆஸ்திரேலிய டாலர்களை வழங்கியது. வெள்ளியன்று, முன்னாள் பிரிட்டிஷ் காலனியில் மிகவும் தேவைப்படுபவர்களுக்கு உணவு மற்றும் சுகாதார பொருட்களை விரைவாகக் கண்காணிக்க மேலும் AU$25 மில்லியனை அறிவிக்கும்.",
        "அவுஸ்திரேலியா இலங்கை மக்களுடன் குறிப்பாக கடுமையான கஷ்டங்களை அனுபவிக்கும் மக்களுடன் நிற்கின்றது என வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் பென்னி வோங் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார பின்னடைவை வலுப்படுத்துவதும் அதன் மீட்சியை விரைவுபடுத்துவதும் அவுஸ்திரேலியாவின் தேசிய நலனுக்காக உள்ளது.\"",
        "ஆஸ்திரேலிய எல்லைப் படை தனது சொந்த ரோந்துக் கப்பலைப் பயன்படுத்தி, கடலில் தடுத்து நிறுத்திய 46 பேரை விமானம் மூலம் திருப்பி அழைத்துச் செல்வதற்குப் பதிலாக, அவர்களைக் கொழும்பிற்குத் திருப்பி அனுப்பியபோது, ​​முன்னோடியில்லாத நடவடிக்கைக்கு பதினைந்து நாட்களுக்குப் பிறகு மாட்டிறைச்சி செய்யப்பட்ட ஆதரவுப் பொதி வந்துள்ளது.",
        "ஆட்கடத்தல்காரர்களுக்கு பணம் கொடுத்து அவுஸ்திரேலியா நோக்கிப் படகுகளில் ஏறுவதைத் தடுக்கும் நோக்கில் வேண்டுமென்றே செய்யப்பட்ட செய்தியில், 110 மீற்றர் கடல் கேடயம் தலைநகரில் உள்ள துறைமுகத்திற்குள் இழுத்துச் செல்லப்பட்ட பின்னர் இலங்கை கடற்படையினரால் பகிரங்கமான வரவேற்பு நிகழ்ச்சி வழங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "சமீபத்தில், பெய்ஜிங் தனது செல்வாக்கை அங்கு நிரூபித்ததால், கவனத்தின் மையமாக இது மற்றொரு கப்பலாக இருந்து வருகிறது.",
        "சீனாவின் கடனுதவியில் கட்டப்பட்ட துறைமுகமான அம்பாந்தோட்டையில் யுவான் வாங் 5 கண்காணிப்பு கப்பல் வருவதை தாமதப்படுத்துமாறு இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் சீனாவிடம் கோரியது.",
        "\"உளவு கப்பல்\", இந்திய ஊடகங்களில் முத்திரை குத்தப்பட்டதால், இப்பகுதியில் கண்காணிப்பு நடத்தலாம் என்ற அச்சம் இருந்தது. இலங்கை கடற்பரப்பில் இருக்கும் போது ஆராய்ச்சி நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொள்ள மாட்டோம் என்று கூறி, இலங்கை செவ்வாய்கிழமை கப்பல்துறைக்கு அனுமதி அளித்தது.",
        "இரண்டு ஆசிய வல்லரசுகளுடன் ஒரு நோய்வாய்ப்பட்ட இலங்கை செய்ய வேண்டிய சிறந்த சமநிலையை சரித்திரம் விளக்குகிறது. மற்றொரு கடனாளியான இந்தியா, தீவிற்கு வெளிநாட்டு உதவியின் முக்கிய ஆதாரமாக உள்ளது, நெருக்கடியின் போது $4 பில்லியன் டாலர்களுக்கு மேல் உதைத்தது. ஆனால், இலங்கைக்கான உள்கட்டமைப்பு கடன்களை மறுசீரமைப்பதற்கான சீனாவின் உடன்பாடு, சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் பிணை எடுப்பு திட்டத்தை எட்டுவதற்கு இலங்கைக்கு இன்றியமையாததாகும்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச, ஜூலை மாதம் ஆயிரக்கணக்கான எதிர்ப்பாளர்களால் அவரது இல்லத்தை முற்றுகையிட்டபோது, ​​நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறி ராஜினாமா செய்த பின்னர் அடுத்த வாரம் இலங்கை திரும்புவார் என்று கூறப்படுகிறது. இவர் சிங்கப்பூர் மற்றும் தாய்லாந்தில் வசித்து வருகிறார்.",
        "ஒரு மாதத்திற்கு முன்பு ராஜபக்சேவின் வாரிசாக எம்.பி.க்களால் வாக்களிக்கப்பட்டு, கொழும்பில் பல மாதங்கள் பழமையான போராட்ட முகாம்களை அகற்ற முயன்ற ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, இந்த வாரம் இலங்கையின் அவசரகாலச் சட்டம் இந்த வாரத்திற்கு மேல் விதிக்கப்படாது என்று கூறினார்.",
        "ஏப்ரல் மாதத்தில் இலங்கையின் வெளிநாட்டு நாணய கையிருப்பு வறண்டு போனதால் 51 பில்லியன் டாலர் வெளிநாட்டுக் கடனைத் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தவில்லை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "$25 மில்லியன்",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மூன்று மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுக்கு ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "60 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "137",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "701",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மே நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிபரல் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AU$50 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AU$25 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பென்னி வோங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "46",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "110-மீட்டர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடல் கவசம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "99 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$4 பில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமாக",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாதத்திற்கு முன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள் பழமையான",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$51 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}