{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83857/droupadi-murmu-takes-oath-as-15th-president-of-india",
  "time_ut": 1658727420,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Droupadi Murmu takes oath as 15th President of India",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Droupadi Murmu takes oath as 15th President of India",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Droupadi Murmu on Monday took oath as the 15th president of India at the Parliament’s Central Hall, Indian media reported.",
        "Murmu was administered the oath by Chief Justice of India NV Ramana. Addressing the nation soon after taking the oath, President Murmu said that the trust and support of the people were her greatest strengths.",
        "She is the second woman President of the country, first-ever tribal woman to hold the highest Constitutional post and the first President to be born in independent India",
        "In her first first address as President at the Central Hall of Parliament, Droupadi Murmu said, “While Standing in the Parliament - the symbol of expectations, aspirations and rights of all Indians - I humbly express my gratitude to all of you. Your trust and support will be a major strength for me to carry out this new responsibility.”",
        "She also said that, “I am fortunate to have got this opportunity to serve during the 75th year of independence.”",
        "She also added that reaching the Presidential post is not personal achievement but an achievement of every poor in India.",
        "“My nomination is evidence that the poor in India can not only dream but also fulfill those dreams,” she said.",
        "“I am the first President of the country who was born in independent India. We will have to speed up our efforts to meet the expectations that our freedom fighters had with the citizens of independent India,” President Droupadi Murmu said.",
        "The swearing-in ceremony took place in the Central Hall of the Parliament. Chief Justice of India NV Ramana administered the oath of the office.",
        "Earlier in the day, Murmu paid tributes to Mahatma Gandhi, father of the nation, at Raj Ghat and also visited Rashtrapati Bhavan where she was welcomed by former President Ram Nath Kovind and his wife Savita Kovind.",
        "The former Jharkhand Governor marked a historic victory over Opposition’s presidential candidate Yashwant Sinha in the president polls on July 22.",
        "The results for presidential election were declared on Thursday in which it was revealed that Murmu bagged 2,824 votes against her opponent Yashwant Sinha who only secured 1,877 votes. A total of 4,809 MPs and MLAs cast their votes in the polling on July 18.",
        "After the declaration of results, Secretary General of Rajya Sabha and the Returning Officer for Presidential Election 2022, PC Mody handed over the certificate to President-elect Droupadi Murmu at her residence in the national capital."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Droupadi Murmu",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "15th",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Droupadi Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Murmu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Justice of India NV Ramana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitutional post",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "her first first",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Hall of Parliament",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Droupadi Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "While Standing in the Parliament",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indians",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 75th year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Droupadi Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Central Hall",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Justice of India NV Ramana",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Earlier in the day",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Murmu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rashtrapati Bhavan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ram Nath Kovind",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Savita Kovind",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jharkhand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yashwant Sinha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Murmu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,824",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yashwant Sinha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,877",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,809",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajya Sabha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Droupadi Murmu ඉන්දියාවේ 15 වැනි ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දියාවේ 15 වැනි ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස ද්‍රෞපදි මුර්මු සඳුදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මධ්‍යම ශාලාවේදී දිවුරුම් දුන් බව ඉන්දීය මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "මුර්මු දිවුරුම් දුන්නේ ඉන්දීය අගවිනිසුරු එන්.වී රාමනා විසිනි. දිවුරුම් දීමෙන් පසු ජාතිය අමතමින් ජනාධිපති මුර්මු කියා සිටියේ ජනතාවගේ විශ්වාසය සහ සහයෝගය තමාගේ ලොකුම ශක්තිය බවයි.",
        "ඇය රටේ දෙවන කාන්තා ජනාධිපතිවරිය, ඉහළම ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත තනතුර දැරූ පළමු ගෝත්‍රික කාන්තාව සහ නිදහස් ඉන්දියාවේ උපත ලැබූ පළමු ජනාධිපතිවරියයි.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මධ්‍යම ශාලාවේදී ජනාධිපතිනිය ලෙස ඇයගේ පළමු දේශනයේදී ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු පැවසුවේ, “සියලු ඉන්දියානුවන්ගේ අපේක්ෂාවන්, අභිලාෂයන් සහ අයිතිවාසිකම්වල සංකේතය වන පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සිටගෙන සිටින අතරතුර මම ඔබ සැමට නිහතමානීව කෘතඥතාව පළ කරමි. ඔබේ විශ්වාසය සහ සහයෝගය මට මේ අලුත් වගකීම ඉටු කරන්න ලොකු ශක්තියක් වේවි.”",
        "නිදහසේ 75 වැනි වසර තුළ සේවය කිරීමට මට මෙම අවස්ථාව ලැබීම භාග්‍යයක් බව ද ඇය පැවසුවාය.",
        "ජනාධිපති ධූරයට පත්වීම පුද්ගලික ජයග්‍රහණයක් නොව ඉන්දියාවේ සෑම දුප්පතෙකුගේම ජයග්‍රහණයක් බවද ඇය පැවසුවාය.",
        "\"මගේ නම් කිරීම ඉන්දියාවේ දුප්පතුන්ට සිහින දැකීමට පමණක් නොව එම සිහින සැබෑ කර ගැනීමටත් හැකි බවට සාක්ෂියකි,\" ඇය පැවසුවාය.",
        "“ස්වාධීන ඉන්දියාවෙන් බිහි වූ රටේ පළමු ජනාධිපතිවරයා මමයි. අපගේ නිදහස් සටන්කාමීන් නිදහස් ඉන්දියාවේ පුරවැසියන් සමඟ ඇති කර ගත් අපේක්ෂාවන් සපුරාලීමට අපගේ උත්සාහයන් වේගවත් කිරීමට අපට සිදුවනු ඇත, ”ජනාධිපති ද්‍රෞපදි මුර්මු පැවසීය.",
        "දිවුරුම් දීමේ උත්සවය පාර්ලිමේන්තු මධ්‍යම ශාලාවේදී පැවැත්විණි. ඉන්දීය අගවිනිසුරු එන්.වී රාමනා මහතා දිවුරුම් දුන්නේ ය.",
        "ඊට පෙර, මුර්මු, ජාතියේ පියා වන මහත්මා ගාන්ධිට රාජ් ගාට්හිදී උපහාර පුද කළ අතර, හිටපු ජනාධිපති රාම් නාත් කෝවින්ද් සහ ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ සවිතා කෝවින්ද් විසින් ඇයව පිළිගත් රාෂ්ට්‍රපති භවන් වෙතද ගියේය.",
        "හිටපු ජාර්කන්ඩ් ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයා ජූලි 22 වන දින පැවති ජනාධිපතිවරණයේදී විපක්ෂයේ ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂක යෂ්වන්ත් සිංහා පරදවා ඓතිහාසික ජයග්‍රහණයක් සනිටුහන් කළේය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරණ ප්‍රතිඵල බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද අතර එහිදී හෙළි වූයේ මුර්මු ඡන්ද 2,824 ක් ලබා ගත් අතර ඇයගේ ප්‍රතිවාදියා වූ යෂ්වන්ත් සිංහට එරෙහිව ඡන්ද 1,877 ක් පමණක් ලබා ගත් බවයි. ජූලි 18 වැනිදා පැවති ඡන්ද විමසීමේදී මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සහ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 4,809 දෙනෙකු ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළහ.",
        "ප්‍රතිඵල ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කිරීමෙන් පසු, රාජ්‍ය සභාවේ මහලේකම් සහ 2022 ජනාධිපතිවරණය සඳහා තේරීම් භාර නිලධාරී, පළාත් සභා මෝඩි විසින් ජාතික අගනුවර පිහිටි ඇගේ නිවසේදී ජනාධිපති ලෙස තේරී පත් වූ ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු වෙත සහතිකය භාර දෙන ලදී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "15 වැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුර්මු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය විනිසුරු එන්.වී රාමනා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුර්මු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාපිත තනතුර",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇගේ පළමු පළමු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මධ්‍යම ශාලාව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සිටගෙන සිටියදී",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "75 වන වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම ශාලාව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය විනිසුරු එන්.වී රාමනා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කලින් දවසේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුර්මු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහත්මා ගාන්ධි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාෂ්ට්‍රපති භවන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාම් නාත් කෝවින්ද්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවිතා කෝවින්ද්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාර්කන්ඩ්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යෂ්වන්ත් සිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුර්මු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,824 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යෂ්වන්ත් සිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,877 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,809",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය සභාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුර්මු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்தியாவின் 15வது ஜனாதிபதியாக திரௌபதி முர்மு பதவியேற்றார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்தியாவின் 15வது ஜனாதிபதியாக திரௌபதி முர்மு திங்கட்கிழமை நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் மத்திய மண்டபத்தில் பதவியேற்றதாக இந்திய ஊடகங்கள் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளன.",
        "முர்முவுக்கு இந்திய தலைமை நீதிபதி என்வி ரமணா பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்து வைத்தார். பதவியேற்ற உடனேயே நாட்டு மக்களுக்கு உரையாற்றிய அதிபர் முர்மு, மக்களின் நம்பிக்கையும் ஆதரவும் தான் தனது மிகப்பெரிய பலம் என்று கூறினார்.",
        "அவர் நாட்டின் இரண்டாவது பெண் குடியரசுத் தலைவர், முதல் பழங்குடிப் பெண், மிக உயர்ந்த அரசியலமைப்பு பதவியை வகித்தவர் மற்றும் சுதந்திர இந்தியாவில் பிறந்த முதல் குடியரசுத் தலைவர் ஆவார்.",
        "நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் மத்திய மண்டபத்தில் குடியரசுத் தலைவர் என்ற முறையில் திரௌபதி முர்மு தனது முதல் உரையில், “பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நிற்கும் போது - அனைத்து இந்தியர்களின் எதிர்பார்ப்புகள், அபிலாஷைகள் மற்றும் உரிமைகளின் சின்னம் - உங்கள் அனைவருக்கும் எனது நன்றியைத் தாழ்மையுடன் தெரிவித்துக் கொள்கிறேன். இந்தப் புதிய பொறுப்பை நிறைவேற்ற உங்கள் நம்பிக்கையும் ஆதரவும் எனக்குப் பெரும் பலமாக இருக்கும்.",
        "மேலும், “சுதந்திரத்தின் 75வது ஆண்டில் பணியாற்றும் இந்த வாய்ப்பை நான் பெற்ற அதிர்ஷ்டசாலி” என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "குடியரசுத் தலைவர் பதவியை அடைவது தனிப்பட்ட சாதனை அல்ல என்றும், இந்தியாவில் உள்ள ஒவ்வொரு ஏழையின் சாதனை என்றும் அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "\"இந்தியாவில் உள்ள ஏழைகள் கனவு காண்பது மட்டுமல்லாமல் அந்த கனவுகளை நிறைவேற்றவும் முடியும் என்பதற்கு எனது நியமனம் சான்றாகும்\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "“சுதந்திர இந்தியாவில் பிறந்த நாட்டின் முதல் குடியரசுத் தலைவர் நான்தான். சுதந்திர இந்தியாவின் குடிமக்களிடம் நமது சுதந்திரப் போராளிகள் கொண்டிருந்த எதிர்பார்ப்புகளைப் பூர்த்தி செய்ய நமது முயற்சிகளை விரைவுபடுத்த வேண்டும்” என்று ஜனாதிபதி திரௌபதி முர்மு கூறினார்.",
        "பதவியேற்பு விழா நாடாளுமன்ற மைய மண்டபத்தில் நடைபெற்றது. இந்திய தலைமை நீதிபதி என்வி ரமணா பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்து வைத்தார்.",
        "முன்னதாக, முர்மு, தேசத்தின் தந்தை மகாத்மா காந்திக்கு ராஜ்காட்டில் அஞ்சலி செலுத்தினார், மேலும் ராஷ்டிரபதி பவனுக்குச் சென்றார், அங்கு அவரை முன்னாள் குடியரசுத் தலைவர் ராம்நாத் கோவிந்த் மற்றும் அவரது மனைவி சவிதா கோவிந்த் வரவேற்றனர்.",
        "ஜூலை 22 அன்று நடந்த ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் எதிர்க்கட்சிகளின் ஜனாதிபதி வேட்பாளர் யஷ்வந்த் சின்ஹாவை எதிர்த்து ஜார்க்கண்ட் முன்னாள் கவர்னர் வரலாற்று வெற்றியை பதிவு செய்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலுக்கான முடிவுகள் வியாழக்கிழமை அறிவிக்கப்பட்டன, அதில் முர்மு 2,824 வாக்குகளைப் பெற்றார், அவரை எதிர்த்துப் போட்டியிட்ட யஷ்வந்த் சின்ஹா ​​1,877 வாக்குகளை மட்டுமே பெற்றார். ஜூலை 18ஆம் தேதி நடைபெற்ற வாக்குப்பதிவில் மொத்தம் 4,809 எம்.பி.க்கள் மற்றும் எம்.எல்.ஏக்கள் வாக்களித்தனர்.",
        "முடிவுகள் அறிவிக்கப்பட்ட பிறகு, ராஜ்யசபாவின் பொதுச் செயலாளரும், ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தல் 2022க்கான தேர்தல் அதிகாரியுமான பி.சி. மோடி, தேசிய தலைநகரில் உள்ள அவரது இல்லத்தில் ஜனாதிபதியாக தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட திரௌபதி முர்முவிடம் சான்றிதழை வழங்கினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "திரௌபதி முர்மு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "15வது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "திரௌபதி முர்மு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முர்மு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய நீதிபதி என்.வி.ரமணா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முர்மு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு பதவி",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அவளுடைய முதல் முதல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றத்தின் மத்திய மண்டபம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "திரௌபதி முர்மு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நிற்கும் போது",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "75 வது ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திரௌபதி முர்மு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய மண்டபம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய நீதிபதி என்.வி.ரமணா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய நாள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "முர்மு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகாத்மா காந்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஷ்டிரபதி பவன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராம் நாத் கோவிந்த்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவிதா கோவிந்த்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜார்கண்ட்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யஷ்வந்த் சின்ஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முர்மு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,824",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யஷ்வந்த் சின்ஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,877",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,809",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜ்யசபா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முர்மு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}