{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/කාලගුණයෙන්-රතු-නිවේදනයක්/101-615753",
  "time_ut": 1656777887,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කාලගුණයෙන් රතු නිවේදනයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A red notice from the weather",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Meteorological Department warns that due to the activation of southwest monsoon, the wind speed may increase to 60-70 kilometers per hour from time to time in offshore areas from Puttalam to Colombo, Galle and Hambantota and Pottuvil.",
        "The sea areas can be very rough and there is a possibility that the sea waves can rise up to 2.5 - 3.5 meters in those areas.",
        "There is also a possibility of sea waves reaching the land from Puttalam to Colombo, Galle to Matara.",
        "Therefore, the Department of Meteorology advises not to engage in fishing and navigational activities in the sea areas off the coast from Colombo to Hambantota via Galle for the next 24 hours."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Meteorological Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "southwest monsoon",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "60-70 kilometers per hour",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam to Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pottuvil",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2.5 - 3.5 meters",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Puttalam to Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next 24 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කාලගුණයෙන් රතු නිවේදනයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "නිරිත දිග යමෝසම් තත්ත්වෙ සක්‍රීයවීම නිසා, පුත්තලම සිට කොළඹ, ගාල්ල සහ හම්බන්තොට දක්වා ද පොතුවිල් දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල සුළගේ වේගය විටින් විට පැයට කිලෝ මීටර් 60 -70  දක්වා වැඩි විය හැකි බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව අනතුරු අඟවයි.",
        "එම මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ ඉතා රළුවිය හැකි බවත්  එම ප්‍රදේශවල මුහුදු රළ මීටර් 2.5 - 3.5 ක් පමණ  ඉහළ යා හැකියාවක් පවතී.",
        "පුත්තලම සිට කොළඹ, ගාල්ල හරහා මාතර දක්වා ප්‍රදේශවල මුහුදු රළ තවදුරටත් ගොඩබිමට පැමිණීමේ හැකියාවක් ද පවතී.",
        "එ බැවින් කොළඹ සිට ගාල්ල හරහා හම්බන්තොට දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල ඉදිරි පැය 24 ක කාලය තුල ධීවර සහ නාවික කටයුතුවල නොයෙදෙන ලෙස කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව දැනුම් දෙයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිරිතදිග මෝසම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැයට කිලෝමීටර් 60-70",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලමේ සිට කොළඹට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොතුවිල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මීටර් 2.5 - 3.5",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලමේ සිට කොළඹට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ පැය 24",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வானிலையிலிருந்து சிவப்பு அறிவிப்பு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தென்மேற்கு பருவமழை தீவிரமடைந்துள்ளதால் புத்தளத்திலிருந்து கொழும்பு, காலி மற்றும் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை மற்றும் பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளில் காற்றின் வேகம் அவ்வப்போது மணித்தியாலத்துக்கு 60-70 கிலோமீற்றர் வரை அதிகரிக்க கூடும் என வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் எதிர்வு கூறியுள்ளது.",
        "கடற்பரப்புகள் மிகவும் கொந்தளிப்பாகவும், கடல் அலைகள் 2.5 - 3.5 மீற்றர் வரை எழும்பவும் கூடும்.",
        "புத்தளத்தில் இருந்து கொழும்பு, காலி முதல் மாத்தறை வரை கடல் அலைகள் நிலத்தை வந்தடையும் வாய்ப்பும் உள்ளது.",
        "எனவே, எதிர்வரும் 24 மணித்தியாலங்களுக்கு கொழும்பிலிருந்து காலி ஊடாக ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளில் மீன்பிடி மற்றும் கடற்தொழில் நடவடிக்கைகளில் ஈடுபட வேண்டாம் என வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் அறிவுறுத்தியுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வானிலை ஆய்வு மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்மேற்கு பருவமழை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 60-70 கிலோமீட்டர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம் முதல் கொழும்பு வரை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொத்துவில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2.5 - 3.5 மீட்டர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம் முதல் கொழும்பு வரை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த 24 மணிநேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}