{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/පක්ෂ-නායක-රැස්විමට-සමගි-බල-වේගය-නෑ/101-616125",
  "time_ut": 1657361384,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පක්ෂ නායක රැස්විමට සමගි බල වේගය නෑ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "There is no momentum for unity at the party leaders' meeting",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Opposition leader Sajith Premadasa said in a statement that Samagi Jana Balawegaya will not participate in the party leaders' meeting called by Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "A special party leader meeting is scheduled to be held today at 4 pm at the Parliament complex under the chairmanship of Prime Minister Ranil Wickramasinghe.",
        "A group of parliament workers have been called to the parliament complex to prepare the proceedings of this meeting.",
        "Mr. Sajith Premadasa is currently in a private hospital in Colombo due to a sudden illness."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පක්ෂ නායක රැස්විමට සමගි බල වේගය නෑ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් කැඳවා ඇති එම පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමට සමගි ජන බලවේගය සහභාගි නොවන බව, විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් පැවසීය.",
        "විශේෂ පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමක් අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණයේදී අද පස්වරු 4 ට පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතය.",
        "මේ රැස්වීමේ කටයුතු සූදානම් කිරීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තු සේවකයන් පිරිසක් පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණයට කැඳවනු ලැබ සිටිති.",
        "හදිසියේ ඇති වූ අසනීප තත්වයක් නිසා සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා මේ වන විට සිටින්නේ කොළඹ පෞද්ගලික රෝහලකය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස 4",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டத்தில் ஒற்றுமைக்கான வேகம் இல்லை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் அழைப்பு விடுக்கப்பட்ட கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டத்தில் சமகி ஜன பலவேகய பங்கேற்காது என எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தலைமையில் இன்று பிற்பகல் 4 மணிக்கு பாராளுமன்ற கட்டிடத் தொகுதியில் விசேட கட்சித் தலைவர் கூட்டம் நடைபெறவுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த கூட்டத்திற்கான நடவடிக்கைகளை தயாரிப்பதற்காக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் குழுவொன்று பாராளுமன்ற வளாகத்திற்கு அழைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "திரு.சஜித் பிரேமதாச திடீர் சுகவீனம் காரணமாக தற்போது கொழும்பில் உள்ள தனியார் வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை 4 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}