{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/24/dhammika-perera-sworn-in-as-minister-of-investment-promotion/",
  "time_ut": 1656076080,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Dhammika Perera sworn in as Minister of Investment Promotion",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dhammika Perera sworn in as Minister of Investment Promotion",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); MP Dhammika Perera was sworn in as the new Minister of Investment Promotion, said the President’s Media Division.",
        "He took oaths in the presence of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
        "Committee probing recent riots obtains statement from fmr Army Commander"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Perera",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දෙයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); නව ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධම්මික පෙරේරා මහතා දිවුරුම් දුන් බව ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය පවසයි.",
        "ඔහු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය",
        "පසුගියදා ඇති වූ කලහකාරී සිදුවීම් සොයා බලන කමිටුව Fmr යුධ හමුදාපතිගෙන් ප්‍රකාශයක් ලබා ගනී"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පෙරේරා",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு அமைச்சராக தம்மிக்க பெரேரா பதவிப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); புதிய முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு அமைச்சராக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் தம்மிக்க பெரேரா பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்து கொண்டதாக ஜனாதிபதி ஊடகப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ முன்னிலையில் அவர் பதவிப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்",
        "சமீபத்திய கலவரங்களை விசாரிக்கும் குழு எஃப்எம்ஆர் இராணுவத் தளபதியிடம் இருந்து அறிக்கையைப் பெறுகிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பெரேரா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Dhammika Perera sworn in as Minister of Investment Promotion",
  "body_lines": [
    "COLOMBO (News 1st); MP Dhammika Perera was sworn in as the new Minister of Investment Promotion, said the President’s Media Division.",
    "He took oaths in the presence of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
    "Committee probing recent riots obtains statement from fmr Army Commander"
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dhammika Perera sworn in as Minister of Investment Promotion",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); MP Dhammika Perera was sworn in as the new Minister of Investment Promotion, said the President’s Media Division.",
        "He took oaths in the presence of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
        "Committee probing recent riots obtains statement from fmr Army Commander"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Perera",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දෙයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); නව ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධම්මික පෙරේරා මහතා දිවුරුම් දුන් බව ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය පවසයි.",
        "ඔහු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය",
        "පසුගියදා ඇති වූ කලහකාරී සිදුවීම් සොයා බලන කමිටුව Fmr යුධ හමුදාපතිගෙන් ප්‍රකාශයක් ලබා ගනී"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පෙරේරා",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு அமைச்சராக தம்மிக்க பெரேரா பதவிப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); புதிய முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு அமைச்சராக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் தம்மிக்க பெரேரா பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்து கொண்டதாக ஜனாதிபதி ஊடகப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ முன்னிலையில் அவர் பதவிப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்",
        "சமீபத்திய கலவரங்களை விசாரிக்கும் குழு எஃப்எம்ஆர் இராணுவத் தளபதியிடம் இருந்து அறிக்கையைப் பெறுகிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பெரேரா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}