{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/market-heavyweights-lanka-ioc-and-expolanka-holdings-boost-cse/",
  "time_ut": 1656073440,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Market heavyweights, Lanka IOC and Expolanka Holdings, boost CSE",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Market heavyweights, Lanka IOC and Expolanka Holdings, boost CSE",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "Luminex Limited, one of Sri Lanka’s small scale, multifaceted engineering firms, started trading at the Colombo Stock Exchange (CSE) this week following an initial public offer (IPO) to raise Rs 250 million, the CSE said in a statement.The shares were listed on the Diri Savi Board of the CSE under the “2010 – Capital Goods” sector. The trading launch was marked with a special bell-ringing ceremony on the CSE trading floor.",
        "Luminex is the fifth equity listing so far this year.The CSE index moved up over 1.6 per cent yesterday, pushed up by market heavyweights, Expolanka and Lanka IOC, stock market analysts said. It is said that Expolanka’s attractive dividend payment and Lanka IOC’s probable fuel hike, showed heavy buying pressure for those stocks.",
        "An analyst said the market was kept up mainly by Expolanka shares, following its Rs 8.19 dividend for the year ending March 2023. Amid those developments both indices moved upwards. The All- Share Price Index went up by 95.1 points and S and P SL20 rose by 47.5 points.Turnover stood at Rs 1.2 billion with two crossings. Those crossings were reported in Commercial Bank, which crossed 1.7 million shares to the tune of Rs 85 million, its shares traded at Rs 50 and HNB, which crossed 260,000 shares to the tune of Rs 20.8 million, its shares traded at Rs 80.",
        "In the retail market, top seven companies that mainly contributed to the turnover were; Lanka IOC Rs 241 million (3.4 million shares traded), Expolanka Holdings Rs 214 million (1.1 million shares traded), JKH Rs 87.3 million (715,000 shares traded), Commercial Bank Rs 68.5 million (1.3 million shares traded), HNB Rs 66.9 million (835,000 shares traded), Browns Investments Rs 45.6 million (5.3 million shares traded) and LOLC Finance Rs 42.4 million (597,000 shares traded). During the day 44.7 million share volumes changed hands in 12000 transactions.",
        "It is said high net worth and institutional investor participation was noted in Commercial Bank, Hatton National Bank and John Keells Holdings. Mixed interest was observed in Expolanka Holdings, Royal Ceramics and Lanka IOC while retail interest was noted in Browns Investments, LOLC Finance and SMB Leasing.Yesterday, the Central Bank announced the US dollar buying rate as Rs. 356.12 and the selling rate as Rs.367.16.",
        "Luminex officially enters the stock market with a listing on CSE",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Expolanka Holdings",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Luminex Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Stock Exchange",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "250 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Diri Savi Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Capital Goods",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Luminex",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "fifth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Expolanka",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka IOC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Expolanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka IOC’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Expolanka",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year ending March 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "95.1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "47.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.2 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commercial Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.7 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "85 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "HNB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "260,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20.8 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "241 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Expolanka Holdings Rs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "214 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.1 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "JKH Rs 87.3 million",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "715,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commercial Bank Rs 68.5 million",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.3 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "HNB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "66.9 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "835,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Browns Investments Rs 45.6 million",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.3 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC Finance",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "42.4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "597,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "44.7 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12000",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Commercial Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hatton National Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "John Keells Holdings",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Expolanka Holdings",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Royal Ceramics",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Browns Investments",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC Finance",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SMB Leasing",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "356.12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Luminex",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මාර්කට් හෙවිවේට්, ලංකා අයිඕසී සහ එක්ස්පෝලංකා හෝල්ඩිංග්ස්, කොළඹ කොටස් හුවමාරුව ඉහළ නංවයි",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කුඩා පරිමාණ බහුවිධ ඉංජිනේරු සමාගමක් වන ලුමිනෙක්ස් ලිමිටඩ්, රුපියල් මිලියන 250ක් රැස් කිරීමට මූලික මහජන දීමනාවකින් (IPO) මෙම සතියේ කොළඹ කොටස් වෙළඳපොලේ (CSE) වෙළඳාම ආරම්භ කළ බව CSE නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය. \"2010 - ප්‍රාග්ධන භාණ්ඩ\" අංශය යටතේ CSE හි Diri Savi මණ්ඩලයේ ලැයිස්තුගත කර ඇත. CSE වෙළඳ මහලේ විශේෂ සීනු නාද කිරීමේ උත්සවයකින් වෙළඳ දියත් කිරීම සනිටුහන් විය.",
        "Luminex යනු මේ වසරේ මේ දක්වා කොටස් ලයිස්තුගත පස්වන කොටසයි. CSE දර්ශකය ඊයේ සියයට 1.6 ට වඩා ඉහළ ගිය අතර, වෙළෙඳපොළ හෙවිවේට්, Expolanka සහ Lanka IOC විසින් ඉහළ ගිය බව කොටස් වෙළෙඳපොළ විශ්ලේෂකයෝ පවසති. Expolanka හි ආකර්ශනීය ලාභාංශ ගෙවීම සහ Lanka IOC හි විය හැකි ඉන්ධන ඉහළ නැංවීම එම කොටස් සඳහා දැඩි ගැනුම් පීඩනයක් පෙන්නුම් කළ බව පැවසේ.",
        "විශ්ලේෂකයෙකු පැවසුවේ, 2023 මාර්තු අවසන් වන වසර සඳහා එහි රුපියල් 8.19 ලාභාංශයෙන් පසුව, එක්ස්පෝලංකා කොටස් ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් වෙළෙඳපොළ ඉහළ නංවා ගත් බවයි. එම වර්ධනයන් මධ්‍යයේ දර්ශක දෙකම ඉහළට ගමන් කළේය. සියලුම කොටස් මිල දර්ශකය ඒකක 95.1 කින් ඉහළ ගිය අතර S සහ P SL20 ඒකක 47.5 කින් ඉහළ ගියේය. පිරිවැටුම මාරුවීම් දෙකක් සමඟ රුපියල් බිලියන 1.2 ක් විය. කොමර්ෂල් බැංකුවේ කොටස් මිලියන 1.7 ඉක්මවා රුපියල් මිලියන 85 දක්වාත්, එහි කොටස් රුපියල් 50 දක්වාත්, HNB කොටස් 260,000 ඉක්මවා රුපියල් මිලියන 20.8 දක්වාත්, එහි කොටස් රුපියල් 80 දක්වාත් එම හරස්වීම් වාර්තා විය.",
        "සිල්ලර වෙළඳපොලේ, පිරිවැටුම සඳහා ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් දායක වූ ඉහළම සමාගම් හත වූයේ; ලංකා IOC රුපියල් මිලියන 241 (කොටස් මිලියන 3.4 ක් ගනුදෙනු), එක්ස්පෝලංකා හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් රුපියල් මිලියන 214 (කොටස් මිලියන 1.1 ක් ගනුදෙනු), JKH රුපියල් මිලියන 87.3 (කොටස් 715,000 ක් ගනුදෙනු), කොමර්ෂල් බැංකුව රුපියල් මිලියන 68.5 (කොටස් මිලියන 1.3 ක් ගනුදෙනු), HNB රුපියල් මිලියන 66.9 (කොටස් 835,000ක් ගනුදෙනු කර ඇත), Browns Investments රුපියල් මිලියන 45.6ක් (කොටස් මිලියන 5.3ක් ගනුදෙනු කර ඇත) සහ LOLC Finance රුපියල් මිලියන 42.4ක් (කොටස් 597,000ක් ගනුදෙනු කර ඇත). දවස තුළ ගනුදෙනු 12000 කදී කොටස් වෙළුම් මිලියන 44.7 ක් වෙනස් විය.",
        "කොමර්ෂල් බැංකුව, හැටන් නැෂනල් බැංකුව සහ ජෝන් කීල්ස් හෝල්ඩින්ග්ස් හි ඉහළ ශුද්ධ වටිනාකමක් සහ ආයතනික ආයෝජකයින්ගේ සහභාගීත්වය සටහන් වූ බව පැවසේ. Expolanka Holdings, Royal Ceramics සහ Lanka IOC හි මිශ්‍ර පොලියක් දක්නට ලැබුණු අතර Browns Investments, LOLC Finance සහ SMB Leasing සඳහා සිල්ලර පොලී සටහන් විය. ඊයේ මහ බැංකුව විසින් එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලරයේ ගැනුම් අනුපාතිකය රු. 356.12 ක් සහ විකුණුම් මිල රු.367.16 කි.",
        "ලුමිනෙක්ස් නිල වශයෙන් කොටස් වෙලඳපොලට ඇතුල් වන්නේ CSE හි ලැයිස්තුගත කරමිනි",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්ස්පෝලංකා හෝල්ඩින්ග්ස්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලුමිනෙක්ස් ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටස් වෙළෙඳපොළ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 250 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිරි සවි මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රාග්ධන භාණ්ඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලුමිනෙක්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පස්වන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්පෝලංකා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා IOC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්පෝලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා IOC ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්පෝලංකා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023 මාර්තු අවසන් වන වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "95.1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "47.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 1.2 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමර්ෂල් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.7 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 85 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එච්.එන්.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "260,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 20.8 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 241 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 3.4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්පෝලංකා හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් රු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 214 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.1 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "JKH රුපියල් මිලියන 87.3 කි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "715,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමර්ෂල් බැංකුව රුපියල් මිලියන 68.5 කි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.3 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එච්.එන්.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 66.9 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "835,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Browns Investments රුපියල් මිලියන 45.6 කි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 5.3 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC ෆිනෑන්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 42.4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "597,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 44.7 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12000",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොමර්ෂල් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හැටන් නැෂනල් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝන් කීල්ස් හෝල්ඩිංග්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්පෝලංකා හෝල්ඩින්ග්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජකීය සෙරමික්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රවුන්ස් ආයෝජන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC ෆිනෑන්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SMB ලීසිං",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "356.12 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලුමිනෙක්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சந்தை ஹெவிவெயிட்கள், லங்கா ஐஓசி மற்றும் எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ், CSE ஐ உயர்த்துகின்றன",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் சிறிய அளவிலான, பன்முக பொறியியல் நிறுவனங்களில் ஒன்றான Luminex Limited, 250 மில்லியன் ரூபாவை திரட்டுவதற்கான ஆரம்ப பொதுச் சலுகையை (IPO) தொடர்ந்து இந்த வாரம் கொழும்பு பங்குச் சந்தையில் (CSE) வர்த்தகத்தைத் தொடங்கியது, CSE ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. \"2010 - மூலதன பொருட்கள்\" பிரிவின் கீழ் CSE இன் திரி சவி வாரியத்தில் பட்டியலிடப்பட்டுள்ளது. CSE வர்த்தக தளத்தில் சிறப்பு மணி அடிக்கும் விழாவுடன் வர்த்தக துவக்கம் குறிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "லுமினெக்ஸ் இந்த ஆண்டு இதுவரை ஐந்தாவது பங்குப் பட்டியலில் உள்ளது. CSE சுட்டெண் நேற்றைய தினம் 1.6 சதவீதத்திற்கும் மேலாக உயர்ந்தது, சந்தை ஹெவிவெயிட்களான எக்ஸ்போலங்கா மற்றும் லங்கா ஐஓசி ஆகியவற்றால் உயர்ந்தது என்று பங்குச் சந்தை ஆய்வாளர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர். எக்ஸ்போலங்காவின் கவர்ச்சிகரமான ஈவுத்தொகை செலுத்துதல் மற்றும் லங்கா ஐஓசியின் சாத்தியமான எரிபொருள் அதிகரிப்பு ஆகியவை அந்தப் பங்குகளுக்கு அதிக கொள்முதல் அழுத்தத்தைக் காட்டியதாக கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "மார்ச் 2023 இல் முடிவடைந்த ஆண்டிற்கான அதன் ரூ 8.19 ஈவுத்தொகையைத் தொடர்ந்து, எக்ஸ்போலங்கா பங்குகளால் சந்தை முக்கியமாக பராமரிக்கப்பட்டது என்று ஒரு ஆய்வாளர் கூறினார். அனைத்து-பங்கு விலைச் சுட்டெண் 95.1 புள்ளிகளாலும், S மற்றும் P SL20 47.5 புள்ளிகளாலும் உயர்ந்தன. விற்றுமுதல் இரண்டு கிராசிங்குகளுடன் ரூ.1.2 பில்லியனாக இருந்தது. கொமர்ஷல் வங்கியில் 1.7 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் ரூ. 85 மில்லியனுக்கும், அதன் பங்குகள் ரூ. 50க்கும், HNB 260,000 பங்குகளைத் தாண்டி ரூ. 20.8 மில்லியனுக்கும், அதன் பங்குகள் ரூ.",
        "சில்லறை சந்தையில், விற்றுமுதலுக்கு முக்கியமாகப் பங்களித்த முதல் ஏழு நிறுவனங்கள்; லங்கா IOC ரூ 241 மில்லியன் (3.4 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் ரூ 214 மில்லியன் (1.1 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), JKH ரூ 87.3 மில்லியன் (715,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), கொமர்ஷல் வங்கி ரூ 68.5 மில்லியன் (1.3 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), HNB ரூ 66.9 மில்லியன் (835,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), Browns Investments ரூ 45.6 மில்லியன் (5.3 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்) மற்றும் LOLC Finance ரூ 42.4 மில்லியன் (597,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்) நாளின் போது 12000 பரிவர்த்தனைகளில் 44.7 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் கைமாறின.",
        "கொமர்ஷல் வங்கி, ஹட்டன் நேஷனல் வங்கி மற்றும் ஜோன் கீல்ஸ் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் ஆகியவற்றில் அதிக நிகர பெறுமதி மற்றும் நிறுவன முதலீட்டாளர்களின் பங்களிப்பு குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது. எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ், ரோயல் செராமிக்ஸ் மற்றும் லங்கா ஐஓசி ஆகியவற்றில் கலப்பு வட்டி காணப்பட்டது. பிரவுன்ஸ் இன்வெஸ்ட்மென்ட்ஸ், எல்ஓஎல்சி ஃபினான்ஸ் மற்றும் எஸ்எம்பி லீசிங் ஆகியவற்றில் சில்லறை வட்டி குறிப்பிடப்பட்டது. நேற்று, மத்திய வங்கி அமெரிக்க டாலர் வாங்கும் விகிதத்தை ரூ. 356.12 மற்றும் விற்பனை விலை ரூ.367.16.",
        "லுமினெக்ஸ் CSE இல் பட்டியலிடப்பட்டு பங்குச் சந்தையில் அதிகாரப்பூர்வமாக நுழைகிறது",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர்*",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "லுமினெக்ஸ் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு பங்குச் சந்தை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "250 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திரி சவி வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூலதன பொருட்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லுமினெக்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்தாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எக்ஸ்போலங்கா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கா ஐ.ஓ.சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எக்ஸ்போலங்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கா ஐ.ஓ.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எக்ஸ்போலங்கா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 2023 இல் முடிவடையும் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "95.1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "47.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.2 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வணிக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.7 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "85 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "HNB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "260,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20.8 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "241 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.4 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் ரூ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "214 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.1 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "JKH ரூ 87.3 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "715,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொமர்ஷல் வங்கி ரூ 68.5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.3 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "HNB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "66.9 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "835,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரவுன்ஸ் முதலீடுகள் ரூ 45.6 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.3 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC நிதி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "42.4 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "597,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "44.7 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12000",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வணிக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹட்டன் நேஷனல் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான் கீல்ஸ் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராயல் செராமிக்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரவுன்ஸ் முதலீடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC நிதி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SMB குத்தகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "356.12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லுமினெக்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Market heavyweights, Lanka IOC and Expolanka Holdings, boost CSE",
  "body_lines": [
    "Luminex Limited, one of Sri Lanka’s small scale, multifaceted engineering firms, started trading at the Colombo Stock Exchange (CSE) this week following an initial public offer (IPO) to raise Rs 250 million, the CSE said in a statement.The shares were listed on the Diri Savi Board of the CSE under the “2010 – Capital Goods” sector. The trading launch was marked with a special bell-ringing ceremony on the CSE trading floor.",
    "Luminex is the fifth equity listing so far this year.The CSE index moved up over 1.6 per cent yesterday, pushed up by market heavyweights, Expolanka and Lanka IOC, stock market analysts said. It is said that Expolanka’s attractive dividend payment and Lanka IOC’s probable fuel hike, showed heavy buying pressure for those stocks.",
    "An analyst said the market was kept up mainly by Expolanka shares, following its Rs 8.19 dividend for the year ending March 2023. Amid those developments both indices moved upwards. The All- Share Price Index went up by 95.1 points and S and P SL20 rose by 47.5 points.Turnover stood at Rs 1.2 billion with two crossings. Those crossings were reported in Commercial Bank, which crossed 1.7 million shares to the tune of Rs 85 million, its shares traded at Rs 50 and HNB, which crossed 260,000 shares to the tune of Rs 20.8 million, its shares traded at Rs 80.",
    "In the retail market, top seven companies that mainly contributed to the turnover were; Lanka IOC Rs 241 million (3.4 million shares traded), Expolanka Holdings Rs 214 million (1.1 million shares traded), JKH Rs 87.3 million (715,000 shares traded), Commercial Bank Rs 68.5 million (1.3 million shares traded), HNB Rs 66.9 million (835,000 shares traded), Browns Investments Rs 45.6 million (5.3 million shares traded) and LOLC Finance Rs 42.4 million (597,000 shares traded). During the day 44.7 million share volumes changed hands in 12000 transactions.",
    "It is said high net worth and institutional investor participation was noted in Commercial Bank, Hatton National Bank and John Keells Holdings. Mixed interest was observed in Expolanka Holdings, Royal Ceramics and Lanka IOC while retail interest was noted in Browns Investments, LOLC Finance and SMB Leasing.Yesterday, the Central Bank announced the US dollar buying rate as Rs. 356.12 and the selling rate as Rs.367.16.",
    "Luminex officially enters the stock market with a listing on CSE",
    "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
    "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Market heavyweights, Lanka IOC and Expolanka Holdings, boost CSE",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "Luminex Limited, one of Sri Lanka’s small scale, multifaceted engineering firms, started trading at the Colombo Stock Exchange (CSE) this week following an initial public offer (IPO) to raise Rs 250 million, the CSE said in a statement.The shares were listed on the Diri Savi Board of the CSE under the “2010 – Capital Goods” sector. The trading launch was marked with a special bell-ringing ceremony on the CSE trading floor.",
        "Luminex is the fifth equity listing so far this year.The CSE index moved up over 1.6 per cent yesterday, pushed up by market heavyweights, Expolanka and Lanka IOC, stock market analysts said. It is said that Expolanka’s attractive dividend payment and Lanka IOC’s probable fuel hike, showed heavy buying pressure for those stocks.",
        "An analyst said the market was kept up mainly by Expolanka shares, following its Rs 8.19 dividend for the year ending March 2023. Amid those developments both indices moved upwards. The All- Share Price Index went up by 95.1 points and S and P SL20 rose by 47.5 points.Turnover stood at Rs 1.2 billion with two crossings. Those crossings were reported in Commercial Bank, which crossed 1.7 million shares to the tune of Rs 85 million, its shares traded at Rs 50 and HNB, which crossed 260,000 shares to the tune of Rs 20.8 million, its shares traded at Rs 80.",
        "In the retail market, top seven companies that mainly contributed to the turnover were; Lanka IOC Rs 241 million (3.4 million shares traded), Expolanka Holdings Rs 214 million (1.1 million shares traded), JKH Rs 87.3 million (715,000 shares traded), Commercial Bank Rs 68.5 million (1.3 million shares traded), HNB Rs 66.9 million (835,000 shares traded), Browns Investments Rs 45.6 million (5.3 million shares traded) and LOLC Finance Rs 42.4 million (597,000 shares traded). During the day 44.7 million share volumes changed hands in 12000 transactions.",
        "It is said high net worth and institutional investor participation was noted in Commercial Bank, Hatton National Bank and John Keells Holdings. Mixed interest was observed in Expolanka Holdings, Royal Ceramics and Lanka IOC while retail interest was noted in Browns Investments, LOLC Finance and SMB Leasing.Yesterday, the Central Bank announced the US dollar buying rate as Rs. 356.12 and the selling rate as Rs.367.16.",
        "Luminex officially enters the stock market with a listing on CSE",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Expolanka Holdings",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Luminex Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Stock Exchange",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "250 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Diri Savi Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Capital Goods",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Luminex",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "fifth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Expolanka",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka IOC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Expolanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka IOC’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Expolanka",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year ending March 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "95.1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "47.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.2 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commercial Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.7 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "85 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "HNB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "260,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20.8 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "241 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Expolanka Holdings Rs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "214 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.1 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "JKH Rs 87.3 million",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "715,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commercial Bank Rs 68.5 million",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.3 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "HNB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "66.9 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "835,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Browns Investments Rs 45.6 million",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.3 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC Finance",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "42.4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "597,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "44.7 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12000",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Commercial Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hatton National Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "John Keells Holdings",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Expolanka Holdings",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Royal Ceramics",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Browns Investments",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC Finance",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SMB Leasing",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "356.12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Luminex",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මාර්කට් හෙවිවේට්, ලංකා අයිඕසී සහ එක්ස්පෝලංකා හෝල්ඩිංග්ස්, කොළඹ කොටස් හුවමාරුව ඉහළ නංවයි",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කුඩා පරිමාණ බහුවිධ ඉංජිනේරු සමාගමක් වන ලුමිනෙක්ස් ලිමිටඩ්, රුපියල් මිලියන 250ක් රැස් කිරීමට මූලික මහජන දීමනාවකින් (IPO) මෙම සතියේ කොළඹ කොටස් වෙළඳපොලේ (CSE) වෙළඳාම ආරම්භ කළ බව CSE නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය. \"2010 - ප්‍රාග්ධන භාණ්ඩ\" අංශය යටතේ CSE හි Diri Savi මණ්ඩලයේ ලැයිස්තුගත කර ඇත. CSE වෙළඳ මහලේ විශේෂ සීනු නාද කිරීමේ උත්සවයකින් වෙළඳ දියත් කිරීම සනිටුහන් විය.",
        "Luminex යනු මේ වසරේ මේ දක්වා කොටස් ලයිස්තුගත පස්වන කොටසයි. CSE දර්ශකය ඊයේ සියයට 1.6 ට වඩා ඉහළ ගිය අතර, වෙළෙඳපොළ හෙවිවේට්, Expolanka සහ Lanka IOC විසින් ඉහළ ගිය බව කොටස් වෙළෙඳපොළ විශ්ලේෂකයෝ පවසති. Expolanka හි ආකර්ශනීය ලාභාංශ ගෙවීම සහ Lanka IOC හි විය හැකි ඉන්ධන ඉහළ නැංවීම එම කොටස් සඳහා දැඩි ගැනුම් පීඩනයක් පෙන්නුම් කළ බව පැවසේ.",
        "විශ්ලේෂකයෙකු පැවසුවේ, 2023 මාර්තු අවසන් වන වසර සඳහා එහි රුපියල් 8.19 ලාභාංශයෙන් පසුව, එක්ස්පෝලංකා කොටස් ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් වෙළෙඳපොළ ඉහළ නංවා ගත් බවයි. එම වර්ධනයන් මධ්‍යයේ දර්ශක දෙකම ඉහළට ගමන් කළේය. සියලුම කොටස් මිල දර්ශකය ඒකක 95.1 කින් ඉහළ ගිය අතර S සහ P SL20 ඒකක 47.5 කින් ඉහළ ගියේය. පිරිවැටුම මාරුවීම් දෙකක් සමඟ රුපියල් බිලියන 1.2 ක් විය. කොමර්ෂල් බැංකුවේ කොටස් මිලියන 1.7 ඉක්මවා රුපියල් මිලියන 85 දක්වාත්, එහි කොටස් රුපියල් 50 දක්වාත්, HNB කොටස් 260,000 ඉක්මවා රුපියල් මිලියන 20.8 දක්වාත්, එහි කොටස් රුපියල් 80 දක්වාත් එම හරස්වීම් වාර්තා විය.",
        "සිල්ලර වෙළඳපොලේ, පිරිවැටුම සඳහා ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් දායක වූ ඉහළම සමාගම් හත වූයේ; ලංකා IOC රුපියල් මිලියන 241 (කොටස් මිලියන 3.4 ක් ගනුදෙනු), එක්ස්පෝලංකා හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් රුපියල් මිලියන 214 (කොටස් මිලියන 1.1 ක් ගනුදෙනු), JKH රුපියල් මිලියන 87.3 (කොටස් 715,000 ක් ගනුදෙනු), කොමර්ෂල් බැංකුව රුපියල් මිලියන 68.5 (කොටස් මිලියන 1.3 ක් ගනුදෙනු), HNB රුපියල් මිලියන 66.9 (කොටස් 835,000ක් ගනුදෙනු කර ඇත), Browns Investments රුපියල් මිලියන 45.6ක් (කොටස් මිලියන 5.3ක් ගනුදෙනු කර ඇත) සහ LOLC Finance රුපියල් මිලියන 42.4ක් (කොටස් 597,000ක් ගනුදෙනු කර ඇත). දවස තුළ ගනුදෙනු 12000 කදී කොටස් වෙළුම් මිලියන 44.7 ක් වෙනස් විය.",
        "කොමර්ෂල් බැංකුව, හැටන් නැෂනල් බැංකුව සහ ජෝන් කීල්ස් හෝල්ඩින්ග්ස් හි ඉහළ ශුද්ධ වටිනාකමක් සහ ආයතනික ආයෝජකයින්ගේ සහභාගීත්වය සටහන් වූ බව පැවසේ. Expolanka Holdings, Royal Ceramics සහ Lanka IOC හි මිශ්‍ර පොලියක් දක්නට ලැබුණු අතර Browns Investments, LOLC Finance සහ SMB Leasing සඳහා සිල්ලර පොලී සටහන් විය. ඊයේ මහ බැංකුව විසින් එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලරයේ ගැනුම් අනුපාතිකය රු. 356.12 ක් සහ විකුණුම් මිල රු.367.16 කි.",
        "ලුමිනෙක්ස් නිල වශයෙන් කොටස් වෙලඳපොලට ඇතුල් වන්නේ CSE හි ලැයිස්තුගත කරමිනි",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්ස්පෝලංකා හෝල්ඩින්ග්ස්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලුමිනෙක්ස් ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටස් වෙළෙඳපොළ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 250 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිරි සවි මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රාග්ධන භාණ්ඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලුමිනෙක්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පස්වන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්පෝලංකා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා IOC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්පෝලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා IOC ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්පෝලංකා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023 මාර්තු අවසන් වන වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "95.1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "47.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 1.2 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමර්ෂල් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.7 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 85 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එච්.එන්.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "260,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 20.8 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 241 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 3.4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්පෝලංකා හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් රු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 214 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.1 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "JKH රුපියල් මිලියන 87.3 කි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "715,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමර්ෂල් බැංකුව රුපියල් මිලියන 68.5 කි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.3 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එච්.එන්.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 66.9 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "835,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Browns Investments රුපියල් මිලියන 45.6 කි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 5.3 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC ෆිනෑන්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 42.4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "597,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 44.7 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12000",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොමර්ෂල් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හැටන් නැෂනල් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝන් කීල්ස් හෝල්ඩිංග්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්පෝලංකා හෝල්ඩින්ග්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජකීය සෙරමික්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රවුන්ස් ආයෝජන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC ෆිනෑන්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SMB ලීසිං",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "356.12 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලුමිනෙක්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சந்தை ஹெவிவெயிட்கள், லங்கா ஐஓசி மற்றும் எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ், CSE ஐ உயர்த்துகின்றன",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் சிறிய அளவிலான, பன்முக பொறியியல் நிறுவனங்களில் ஒன்றான Luminex Limited, 250 மில்லியன் ரூபாவை திரட்டுவதற்கான ஆரம்ப பொதுச் சலுகையை (IPO) தொடர்ந்து இந்த வாரம் கொழும்பு பங்குச் சந்தையில் (CSE) வர்த்தகத்தைத் தொடங்கியது, CSE ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. \"2010 - மூலதன பொருட்கள்\" பிரிவின் கீழ் CSE இன் திரி சவி வாரியத்தில் பட்டியலிடப்பட்டுள்ளது. CSE வர்த்தக தளத்தில் சிறப்பு மணி அடிக்கும் விழாவுடன் வர்த்தக துவக்கம் குறிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "லுமினெக்ஸ் இந்த ஆண்டு இதுவரை ஐந்தாவது பங்குப் பட்டியலில் உள்ளது. CSE சுட்டெண் நேற்றைய தினம் 1.6 சதவீதத்திற்கும் மேலாக உயர்ந்தது, சந்தை ஹெவிவெயிட்களான எக்ஸ்போலங்கா மற்றும் லங்கா ஐஓசி ஆகியவற்றால் உயர்ந்தது என்று பங்குச் சந்தை ஆய்வாளர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர். எக்ஸ்போலங்காவின் கவர்ச்சிகரமான ஈவுத்தொகை செலுத்துதல் மற்றும் லங்கா ஐஓசியின் சாத்தியமான எரிபொருள் அதிகரிப்பு ஆகியவை அந்தப் பங்குகளுக்கு அதிக கொள்முதல் அழுத்தத்தைக் காட்டியதாக கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "மார்ச் 2023 இல் முடிவடைந்த ஆண்டிற்கான அதன் ரூ 8.19 ஈவுத்தொகையைத் தொடர்ந்து, எக்ஸ்போலங்கா பங்குகளால் சந்தை முக்கியமாக பராமரிக்கப்பட்டது என்று ஒரு ஆய்வாளர் கூறினார். அனைத்து-பங்கு விலைச் சுட்டெண் 95.1 புள்ளிகளாலும், S மற்றும் P SL20 47.5 புள்ளிகளாலும் உயர்ந்தன. விற்றுமுதல் இரண்டு கிராசிங்குகளுடன் ரூ.1.2 பில்லியனாக இருந்தது. கொமர்ஷல் வங்கியில் 1.7 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் ரூ. 85 மில்லியனுக்கும், அதன் பங்குகள் ரூ. 50க்கும், HNB 260,000 பங்குகளைத் தாண்டி ரூ. 20.8 மில்லியனுக்கும், அதன் பங்குகள் ரூ.",
        "சில்லறை சந்தையில், விற்றுமுதலுக்கு முக்கியமாகப் பங்களித்த முதல் ஏழு நிறுவனங்கள்; லங்கா IOC ரூ 241 மில்லியன் (3.4 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் ரூ 214 மில்லியன் (1.1 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), JKH ரூ 87.3 மில்லியன் (715,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), கொமர்ஷல் வங்கி ரூ 68.5 மில்லியன் (1.3 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), HNB ரூ 66.9 மில்லியன் (835,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), Browns Investments ரூ 45.6 மில்லியன் (5.3 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்) மற்றும் LOLC Finance ரூ 42.4 மில்லியன் (597,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்) நாளின் போது 12000 பரிவர்த்தனைகளில் 44.7 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் கைமாறின.",
