{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lankas-state-run-litro-gas-to-drop-cooking-gas-prices-from-sep-05-99357/",
  "time_ut": 1662105300,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s state-run Litro Gas to drop cooking gas prices from Sep 05",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s state-run Litro Gas to drop cooking gas prices from Sep 05",
      "author": "Dulya de Silva",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s state-run Litro Gas will reduce cooking gas prices for the second consecutive month on Monday 05 September after the implementation of the new price formula, Chairman Muditha Pieris said.",
        "Gas prices increased in June and dropped in August, according to a newly introduced price formula where gas prices are reviewed and amended each month. A similar system was put in place for fuel.",
        "The new prices will be announced and go into effect from Monday midnight.",
        "Pieris said that Litro had been providing cooking gas for the lowest prices, and could not take responsibility for pricing at other competing institutions.",
        "“We hope to maintain prices at a lower level than other institutions, in line with global prices,” Pieris said.",
        "Litro maintains a roughly 90-percent market share over LP gas in Sri Lanka.",
        "“[With the new pricing formula] the small profit that is made will be turned over to the Treasury at the end of the year…and giving it back to the people,” he said.",
        "Current base rates of domestic cooking gas cylinders in Sri Lanka are as follows:",
        "Prices vary according to district due to transportation costs, with 12.5kg cylinders retailing for slightly over 5,000 rupees in some districts. (Colombo/Sep02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Litro Gas",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the second consecutive month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday 05 September",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muditha Pieris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "each month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "midnight",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pieris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pieris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "90-percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of the year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12.5kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රජය විසින් පවත්වාගෙන යනු ලබන ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් සමාගම විසින් පිසූ ගෑස් මිල සැප්තැම්බර් 05 වැනිදා සිට පහත හෙළීමට නියමිතය",
      "author": "දුල්යා ද සිල්වා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - නව මිල සූත්‍රය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රජය විසින් පවත්වාගෙන යනු ලබන ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් සමාගම සැප්තැම්බර් 05 සඳුදා සිට අඛණ්ඩව දෙවන මාසයටත් පිසින ගෑස් මිල අඩු කරන බව සභාපති මුදිත පීරිස් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "සෑම මසකම ගෑස් මිල සමාලෝචනය කර සංශෝධනය කෙරෙන අලුතින් හඳුන්වා දුන් මිල සූත්‍රයට අනුව ජුනි මාසයේදී ගෑස් මිල ඉහළ ගොස් අගෝස්තු මාසයේදී පහත වැටුණි. ඉන්ධන සඳහා ද එවැනිම පද්ධතියක් සකස් කරන ලදී.",
        "නව මිල ගණන් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන අතර සඳුදා මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වේ.",
        "පීරිස් පැවසුවේ ලිට්‍රෝ සමාගම අඩුම මිලට ඉවුම් පිහුම් ගෑස් ලබාදුන් බවත් අනෙකුත් තරගකාරී ආයතනවල මිල නියම කිරීමේ වගකීම භාරගත නොහැකි බවත්ය.",
        "\"ගෝලීය මිල ගණන්වලට අනුකූලව අනෙකුත් ආයතනවලට වඩා අඩු මට්ටමක මිල පවත්වා ගැනීමට අපි බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා,\" පීරිස් පැවසීය.",
        "Litro සමාගම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ LP ගෑස් සම්බන්ධයෙන් දළ වශයෙන් සියයට 90ක වෙළඳපල කොටසක් පවත්වාගෙන යයි.",
        "“[නව මිල සූත්‍රය සමඟ] ලබන සුළු ලාභය වසර අවසානයේදී භාණ්ඩාගාරයට හරවා එය නැවත ජනතාවට ලබා දෙනු ඇත,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ගෘහස්ත ඉවුම් පිහුම් ගෑස් සිලින්ඩරවල වර්තමාන පාදක මිල පහත පරිදි වේ:",
        "ප්‍රවාහන වියදම් හේතුවෙන් දිස්ත්‍රික්ක අනුව මිල ගණන් වෙනස් වන අතර සමහර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවල කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 12.5ක සිලින්ඩර රුපියල් 5,000කට මදක් වැඩි මිලකට අලෙවි වේ. (කොළඹ/සැප්.02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ලිට්රෝ ගෑස්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ ගෑස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඛණ්ඩව දෙවන මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 05 සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදිත පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෑම මාසයකම",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "90-සියයට",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර අවසානයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12.5kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் அரச நிறுவனமான Litro Gas சமையல் எரிவாயுவின் விலையை செப்.05 முதல் குறைக்கவுள்ளது",
      "author": "துல்யா டி சில்வா",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - இலங்கையின் அரச நிறுவனமான Litro Gas புதிய விலை சூத்திரத்தை நடைமுறைப்படுத்தியதன் பின்னர் தொடர்ந்து இரண்டாவது மாதமாக சமையல் எரிவாயுவின் விலையை செப்டம்பர் 05 திங்கட்கிழமை குறைக்கும் என தலைவர் முதித பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எரிவாயு விலைகள் ஒவ்வொரு மாதமும் மதிப்பாய்வு செய்யப்பட்டு திருத்தப்படும் புதிதாக அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்ட விலை சூத்திரத்தின் படி, ஜூன் மாதத்தில் எரிவாயு விலைகள் அதிகரித்து ஆகஸ்ட் மாதத்தில் குறைக்கப்பட்டன. எரிபொருளுக்கும் இதே போன்ற அமைப்பு ஏற்படுத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "புதிய விலை அறிவிக்கப்பட்டு திங்கள்கிழமை நள்ளிரவு முதல் அமலுக்கு வரும்.",
        "லிட்ரோ குறைந்த விலையில் சமையல் எரிவாயுவை வழங்கி வருவதாகவும், போட்டியிட்ட மற்ற நிறுவனங்களில் விலை நிர்ணயம் செய்வதற்கு பொறுப்பேற்க முடியாது என்றும் பீரிஸ் கூறினார்.",
        "\"உலகளாவிய விலைகளுக்கு ஏற்ப, மற்ற நிறுவனங்களை விட குறைந்த அளவில் விலைகளை பராமரிக்க நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம்,\" என்று பீரிஸ் கூறினார்.",
        "Litro இலங்கையில் LP எரிவாயுவில் சுமார் 90 சதவீத சந்தைப் பங்கைப் பேணுகிறது.",
        "\"[புதிய விலைச் சூத்திரத்துடன்] கிடைக்கும் சிறிய லாபம் ஆண்டின் இறுதியில் கருவூலத்திற்கு மாற்றப்பட்டு மக்களுக்குத் திரும்பக் கொடுக்கப்படும்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் உள்நாட்டு சமையல் எரிவாயு சிலிண்டர்களின் தற்போதைய அடிப்படை விலைகள் பின்வருமாறு:",
        "போக்குவரத்து செலவுகள் காரணமாக விலைகள் மாவட்டத்திற்கு ஏற்ப மாறுபடும், சில மாவட்டங்களில் 12.5 கிலோ சிலிண்டர்கள் 5,000 ரூபாய்க்கு சற்று அதிகமாக விற்கப்படுகின்றன. (கொழும்பு/செப்02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொடர்ந்து இரண்டாவது மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 05 திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதிதா பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒவ்வொரு மாதமும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நள்ளிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "90-சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டின் இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12.5 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}