{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ධම්මිකට-එරෙහි-පෙත්සමේ-කරුණු-විමසන්න-දින-දෙයි/101-619136",
  "time_ut": 1662030788,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ධම්මිකට එරෙහි පෙත්සමේ කරුණු විමසන්න දින දෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dates to inquire into the facts of the petition against Dhammika",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Supreme Court today (01) ordered that the case be called on the 13th to verify the facts regarding the fundamental rights petitions filed by the executive committee member of the People's Struggle Movement, Mr. Duminda Nagamuwa and others, against the appointment of prominent businessman Dhammika Perera as a National List Member of Parliament.",
        "Such orders were issued today (01) when this petition was called before a Supreme Court bench consisting of Mr. Priyantha Jayawardena, Mr. Yasanta Kodagoda and Mr. Arjuna Obeysekera.",
        "Duminda Nagamuwa, member of the People's Struggle Executive Committee, Professor Ratnajeevan Hoole, and Nagananda Kodithuvakku, General Secretary of the Praideh Peramuna, have been named as respondents in this petition.",
        "These petitions have been presented before the Supreme Court stating that the appointment of businessman Mr. Dhammika Perera as a National List Member of Parliament contrary to the provisions of the constitution has violated the fundamental rights of the people themselves."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 13th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the People's Struggle Movement",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Duminda Nagamuwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National List",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Priyantha Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yasanta Kodagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arjuna Obeysekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Duminda Nagamuwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the People's Struggle Executive Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnajeevan Hoole",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nagananda Kodithuvakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Praideh Peramuna",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National List",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ධම්මිකට එරෙහි පෙත්සමේ කරුණු විමසන්න දින දෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ප්‍රකට ව්‍යාපාරික ධම්මික පෙරේරා මහතා ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ලෙස පත්කිරීමට එරෙහිව ජන අරගල ව්‍යාපාරයේ විධායක කමිටු සාමාජික දුමින්ද නාගමුව මහතා ඇතුළු පිරිසක් ගොනු කර ඇති මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් පෙත්සම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් කරුණු තහවුරු කිරීම සඳහා ලබන 13 වන දා එම නඩුව කැඳවන ලෙස ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය අද (01) නියෝග කළේය.",
        "ප්‍රියන්ත ජයවර්ධන, යසන්ත කෝදාගොඩ සහ අර්ජුන ඔබේසේකර යන මහත්වරුන්ගෙන් සමන්විත ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ විනිසුරු මඩුල්ලක් හමුවේ අද (01) මෙම පෙත්සම කැඳවූ අවස්ථාවේදී එලෙස නියෝග නිකුත් විණි.",
        "ජන අරගල ව්‍යාපාරයේ විධායක කමිටු සාමාජික දුමින්ද නාගමුව, මහාචාර්ය රත්නජීවන් හූල් සහ විනිවිද පෙරමුණේ මහ ලේකම් නීතිඥ නාගානන්ද කොඩිතුවක්කු යන මහත්වරුන් ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති මෙම පෙත්සමේ වගඋත්තරකරුවන් ලෙස නම් කර ඇත්තේ මැතිවරණ කොමසාරිස්, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම් ඇතුළු පිරිසකි.",
        "වියවස්තාවේ විධිවිධානයන්ට පටහැනිව ව්‍යාපාරික ධම්මික පෙරේරා මහතා ජාතික ලයිස්තු ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයකු ලෙස පත් කිරීම පත් කිරීම මගින් තමන්ගේ තමන්ගේත් ජනතාවගේ මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් කඩවන ලදැයි සඳහන් කරමින් මෙම පෙත්සම් ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය හමුවේ ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "13 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන අරගල ව්‍යාපාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුමින්ද නාගමුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රියන්ත ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යසන්ත කෝදාගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අර්ජුන ඔබේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දුමින්ද නාගමුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන අරගල විධායක කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නජීවන් හූල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාගානන්ද කොඩිතුවක්කු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රයිඩ් පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தம்மிகவுக்கு எதிரான மனுவின் உண்மைகளை விசாரிக்கும் தேதிகள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிரபல வர்த்தகர் நியமனத்திற்கு எதிராக மக்கள் போராட்ட இயக்கத்தின் செயற்குழு உறுப்பினர் திரு.துமிந்த நாகமுவ உள்ளிட்டோர் தாக்கல் செய்த அடிப்படை உரிமை மனுக்கள் தொடர்பான உண்மைகளை சரிபார்க்கும் வழக்கை எதிர்வரும் 13 ஆம் திகதி விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக் கொள்ளுமாறு உயர் நீதிமன்றம் இன்று (01) உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளது. தம்மிக்க பெரேரா தேசியப்பட்டியல் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்.",
        "பிரியந்த ஜயவர்தன, யசந்த கோதாகொட மற்றும் அர்ஜுன ஒபேசேகர ஆகியோர் அடங்கிய உச்ச நீதிமன்ற அமர்வு முன்னிலையில் இந்த மனு இன்று (01) விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக்கொள்ளப்பட்ட போதே இந்த உத்தரவு பிறப்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த மனுவில் பிரதிவாதிகளாக மக்கள் போராட்ட செயற்குழு உறுப்பினர் துமிந்த நாகமுவ, பேராசிரியர் ரட்ணஜீவன் ஹூல் மற்றும் பிரைதே பெரமுனவின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் நாகாநந்த கொடித்துவக்கு ஆகியோர் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பிற்கு முரணான வகையில் வர்த்தகர் தம்மிக்க பெரேராவை தேசியப்பட்டியல் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக நியமித்தமை மக்களின் அடிப்படை உரிமைகளை மீறும் செயலாகும் என தெரிவித்து இந்த மனுக்கள் உச்ச நீதிமன்றில் முன்வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "13வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் போராட்ட இயக்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துமிந்த நாகமுவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பட்டியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரியந்த ஜயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யசந்த கோதாகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அர்ஜுன ஒபேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துமிந்த நாகமுவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் போராட்ட செயற்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரத்னஜீவன் ஹூல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாகானந்த கொடித்துவக்கு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரைதே பெரமுனா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பட்டியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}