{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ජලය-පිරුණු-බෝක්කුවක-සිරවී-13-හැවැරිදි-සිසුවෙක්-මරුට/11-396906",
  "time_ut": 1662384543,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ජලය පිරුණු බෝක්කුවක සිරවී 13 හැවැරිදි සිසුවෙක් මරුට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A 13-year-old student died after getting stuck in a water-filled culvert",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Kurunegala Police say that a 13-year-old school student has died after falling into a water-filled culvert due to the torrential rain that fell in the Kurunegala area today (05).",
        "Sachitra Senaratne, a resident of Kurunegala Jayantipura area, who was studying in the ninth year of Kurunegala Maliadeva Adarsh ​​Maha Vidyalaya, was involved in the accident. He had met with this accident near his residence.",
        "The police say that he met with this accident yesterday afternoon while he was traveling on a side road leading to Jayanthipura area to go home after finishing school.",
        "It is said that he slipped on the side of the road to give way to a van transporting students from Kurunegala Bandaranaike Vidyalaya and fell into the canal. He was swept away in the waterway and stuck in the culvert.",
        "Heavy rain fell continuously in the Kurunegala area and due to this, the canal flowing on that road has overflowed and water has flowed. Due to this, it is said that the surrounding area including the road was completely covered with water.",
        "Later, Kurunegala Police and the soldiers of the nearby Vahera Army Camp used a backhoe to dismantle the culvert and after an hour of great effort, the student who was stuck in the culvert was freed and admitted to the Kurunegala Teaching Hospital Emergency Treatment Center for treatment.",
        "The staff of the intensive care unit of the Kurunegala Teaching Hospital have worked hard to save the life of the student who is in danger."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "13-year-old",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "13-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sachitra Senaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala Jayantipura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the ninth year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala Maliadeva Adarsh ​​Maha Vidyalaya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayanthipura",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vahera Army Camp",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "an hour",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kurunegala Teaching Hospital Emergency Treatment Center",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Kurunegala Teaching Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජලය පිරුණු බෝක්කුවක සිරවී 13 හැවැරිදි සිසුවෙක් මරුට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කුරුණෑගල ප්‍රදේශයට අද (05) දිනය පුරා ඇද හැළුණු ධාරානිපාත වර්ෂාව හේතුවෙන් ජලයෙන් පිරී ගිය බෝක්කුවකට ඇද වැටීමෙන් එහි සිරවීමෙන් 13 හැවිරිදි පාසල් ශිෂ්‍යයෙකු මරණයට පත්ව ඇති බව කුරුණෑගල පොලීසිය පවසයි.",
        "මෙසේ අනතුරට ලක්ව ඇත්තේ කුරුණෑගල මලියදේව ආදර්ශ මහා විද්‍යාලයේ නවය වසරෙහි අධ්‍යාපනය ලබමින් සිටි කුරුණෑගල ජයන්තිපුර ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි සචිත්‍ර සේනාරත්න නමැති ශිෂ්‍යයෙකි. ඔහු තමන් පදිංචි නිවස ආසන්නයේදීම මෙම අනතුරට ලක්ව තිබුණි.",
        "ඊයේ දහවල් පාසල නිම වීමෙන් අනතුරුව නිවසට යාම සඳහා පාසලේ සිට ජයන්තිපුර ප්‍රදේශයට පිවිසෙන  අතුරු මාර්ගයක ගමන් කරමින් සිටියදී  ඔහු මෙම අනතුරට මුහුණපා ඇති බව පොලීසිය කියයි.",
        "කුරුණෑගල බණ්ඩාරනායක විදුහලේ සිට සිසුන් ප්‍රවාහනය කරන වෑන් රථයකට ඉඩ දීම සඳහා මාර්ගය අයිනට වීමේදී ලිස්සා ගොස් ඔහු ඇල මාර්ගයට ඇද වැටී ඇති බව කියයි. ජල මාර්ගයේ ගසාගෙන ගොස් ඔහු බෝක්කුව තුළ සිරවී ඇත.",
        "අඛණ්ඩව කුරුණෑගල  ප්‍රදේශයට අධික වර්ෂාවක් ඇද හැළුණු අතර මේ හේතුවෙන් එම මාර්ගයේ  ගලා බසින ඇල මාර්ගය පිටාර යමින් ජලය ගලාගෙන ගොස් ඇත. මේ හේතුවෙන් මාර්ගය ඇතුළු අවට ප්‍රදේශයම සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම ජලයෙන් වැසී ගොස් තිබූ බව කියයි.",
        "පසුව කුරුණෑගල පොලීසියේ සහ ඒ ආසන්නයේම පිහිටි වැහැර යුද හමුදා කඳවුරේ සෙබළුන් එක්ව බැකෝ යන්ත්‍රයක් යොදා බෝක්කුව කඩා ඉවත් කර ඉමහත් වෙහෙසක් දරා පැයකට පමණ පසුව බෝක්කුව තුළ සිරවී සිටි ශිෂ්‍යයා මුදාගෙන ප්‍රතිකාර සඳහා කුරුණෑගල ශික්ෂණ රෝහලේ හදිසි අනතුරු ප්‍රතිකාර මධ්‍යස්ථානයට ඇතුළත් කර ඇත.",
        "අනතුරට ලක්ව සිටින ශිෂ්‍යයාගේ ජීවිතය බේරා ගැනීම සඳහා කුරුණෑගල ශික්ෂණ රෝහලේ දැඩි සත්කාර ඒකකයේ කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය දැඩි වෙහෙසක් දරා ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "13 හැවිරිදි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "13 හැවිරිදි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සචිත්‍ර සේනාරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල ජයන්තිපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවවන වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල මලියදේව ආදර්ශ මහා විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයන්තිපුර",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වහෙර යුද හමුදා කඳවුර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැයක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල ශික්ෂණ රෝහලේ හදිසි ප්‍රතිකාර මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල ශික්ෂණ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தண்ணீர் நிரம்பிய கால்வாயில் சிக்கி 13 வயது மாணவன் உயிரிழந்தான்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "குருநாகல் பகுதியில் இன்று (05) பெய்த அடைமழை காரணமாக நீர் நிரம்பிய கால்வாய்க்குள் தவறி விழுந்து 13 வயதுடைய பாடசாலை மாணவர் ஒருவர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக குருநாகல் பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "குருநாகல் மலியதேவ ஆதர்ஷ் மகா வித்தியாலயத்தில் ஒன்பதாம் ஆண்டில் கல்வி கற்கும் குருநாகல் ஜயந்திபுர பிரதேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்த சசித்ர சேனாரத்ன என்பவரே விபத்தில் சிக்கியுள்ளார். அவர் தனது வீட்டிற்கு அருகில் இந்த விபத்தை சந்தித்துள்ளார்.",
        "நேற்று மதியம் பாடசாலை முடிந்து வீட்டிற்கு செல்வதற்காக ஜயந்திபுர பிரதேசத்திற்கு செல்லும் பக்க வீதியில் சென்று கொண்டிருந்த போதே இந்த விபத்து ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "குருநாகல் பண்டாரநாயக்க வித்தியாலயத்தில் இருந்து மாணவர்களை ஏற்றிச் சென்ற வேன் ஒன்றுக்கு வழிவிடுவதற்காக வீதியோரத்தில் வழுக்கி கால்வாயில் வீழ்ந்ததாகக் கூறப்படுகிறது. அவர் நீர்வழிப்பாதையில் அடித்து செல்லப்பட்டு கால்வாயில் சிக்கினார்.",
        "குருநாகல் பகுதியில் தொடர்ச்சியாக பலத்த மழை பெய்து வருவதால், அந்த வீதியில் பாயும் கால்வாய் நிரம்பி நீர் பாய்ந்துள்ளது. இதன்காரணமாக வீதி உள்ளிட்ட சுற்றுவட்டாரப் பகுதிகள் முற்றாக நீரில் மூழ்கியதாகக் கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "பின்னர் குருநாகல் பொலிஸாரும் அருகில் உள்ள வஹெர இராணுவ முகாமின் படையினரும் இணைந்து பேக்ஹோ இயந்திரத்தை பயன்படுத்தி கால்வாயை அகற்றி ஒரு மணித்தியால கடும் முயற்சியின் பின்னர் குழியில் சிக்கிய மாணவனை மீட்டு குருநாகல் போதனா வைத்தியசாலை அவசர சிகிச்சை நிலையத்தில் சிகிச்சைக்காக அனுமதித்தனர். .",
        "குருநாகல் போதனா வைத்தியசாலையின் அதிதீவிர சிகிச்சைப் பிரிவின் ஊழியர்கள் ஆபத்தில் சிக்கிய மாணவனின் உயிரைக் காப்பாற்ற கடுமையாகப் பாடுபட்டுள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "13 வயது",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "13 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சச்சித்ர சேனாரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல் ஜெயந்திபுர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பதாம் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல் மாலியதேவ ஆதர்ஷ் மகா வித்தியாலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயந்திபுர",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல் பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வஹேரா இராணுவ முகாம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல் போதனா வைத்தியசாலை அவசர சிகிச்சை நிலையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல் போதனா வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}