{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/21/hasta-la-vista-baby-says-uks-boris-johnson/",
  "time_ut": 1658399400,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "‘Hasta la vista, baby,’ says UK’s Boris Johnson",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "‘Hasta la vista, baby,’ says UK’s Boris Johnson",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "(Reuters); British Prime Minister Boris Johnson bowed out of his final showpiece parliamentary appearance with a round of applause from his party, jeers from opponents, and an enigmatic exit line: “Mission largely accomplished … hasta la vista, baby.”",
        "Johnson was forced to announce his resignation earlier this month after a mass rebellion against the latest in a string of scandals that his party decided had undermined his ability to lead the country any longer after three turbulent years in charge.",
        "Speaking in his final “Prime Minister’s Questions”, the weekly fixture of the political calendar which pits the prime minister against his opponents in rowdy debate, Johnson sought to shape his legacy around the COVID-19 response and his support of Ukraine in its defence against Russia.",
        "“We’ve helped, I’ve helped, get this country through a pandemic and help save another country from barbarism. And frankly, that’s enough to be going on with. Mission largely accomplished,” Johnson said.",
        "The line, borrowed from Arnold Schwarzenegger in the 1991 movie “Terminator 2: Judgment Day” and translated as “see you later”, prompted a round of applause from most on his own side.",
        "Only two weeks ago, some of those clapping had resigned from his government, criticized his leadership and demanded he quit. Reporters in the debating chamber said his predecessor, Theresa May, did not stand to clap."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "la vista",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "UK",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Boris Johnson",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boris Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "la vista",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "earlier this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three turbulent years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Arnold Schwarzenegger",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1991",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Terminator 2: Judgment Day",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Only two weeks ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Theresa May",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘හස්ටා ලා විස්ටා, බබා,’ එක්සත් රාජධානියේ බොරිස් ජොන්සන් පවසයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "(රොයිටර්); බි‍්‍රතාන්‍ය අගමැති බොරිස් ජොන්සන් සිය අවසන් ප‍්‍රදර්ශන භාණ්ඩාගාරයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු පැමිණීමෙන් හිස නැමුවේ ඔහුගේ පක්‍ෂයේ අත්පොලසන් නාදයක්, විරුද්ධවාදීන්ගේ විහිළු තහළු සහ ප‍්‍රහේලිකාවක් වූ පිටවීමේ රේඛාවක් සමඟිනි: “මෙහෙවර බොහෝ දුරට ඉටු වී ඇත ... හස්ටා ලා විස්ටා, බබා.”",
        "ජොන්සන්ට මේ මස මුලදී සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීම ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට බල කෙරුනේ අවුල් සහගත වසර තුනකට පසුව රට පාලනය කිරීමට ඔහුට ඇති හැකියාව හෑල්ලුවට ලක් කර ඇති බවට ඔහුගේ පක්ෂය විසින් තීරණය කරන ලද නවතම අපකීර්තියට එරෙහිව මහජන කැරැල්ලකින් පසුවය.",
        "ඔහුගේ අවසාන “අගමැති ප්‍රශ්න”, දේශපාලන දින දර්ශනයේ සතිපතා සවිකිරීම වන අතර එය අගමැති ඔහුගේ විරුද්ධවාදීන්ට එරෙහිව රණ්ඩු දබර විවාදයකට ලක් කරයි, ජොන්සන් COVID-19 ප්‍රතිචාරය වටා ඔහුගේ උරුමය හැඩගස්වා ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කළේය. රුසියාව.",
        "“අපි උදව් කළා, මම උදව් කළා, මේ රට වසංගතයකින් මිදීමට සහ තවත් රටක් ම්ලේච්ඡත්වයෙන් බේරා ගැනීමට උදව් කළා. සහ අවංකවම, එය දිගටම කරගෙන යාමට ප්රමාණවත්ය. මෙහෙයුම බොහෝ දුරට ඉටු විය,\" ජොන්සන් පැවසීය.",
        "1991 චිත්‍රපටයේ \"ටර්මිනේටර් 2: ජජ්මන්ට් ඩේ\" හි ආර්නෝල්ඩ් ෂ්වාස්නෙගර්ගෙන් ණයට ගත් මෙම රේඛාව, \"පසුව හමුවෙමු\" ලෙස පරිවර්තනය කරන ලද අතර, ඔහුගේම පැත්තේ බොහෝ දෙනාගේ අත්පොළසන් හඬක් ඇති විය.",
        "සති දෙකකට පෙර, අත්පුඩි ගසමින් සිටි ඇතැමුන් ඔහුගේ ආන්ඩුවෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වී, ඔහුගේ නායකත්වය විවේචනය කර, ඔහු ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට බලකර ඇත. විවාද කුටියේ වාර්තාකරුවන් පැවසුවේ ඔහුගේ පූර්වගාමියා වූ තෙරේසා මේ අත්පුඩි ගැසීමට නැගී නොසිටි බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලා විස්ටා",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "බොරිස් ජොන්සන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරිස් ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලා විස්ටා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ මස මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැළඹිලි සහිත වසර තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Arnold Schwarzenegger",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1991",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටර්මිනේටර් 2: විනිශ්චය දිනය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සති දෙකකට පෙර පමණි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙරේසා මේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "‘ஹஸ்டா லா விஸ்டா, பேபி’ என்கிறார் இங்கிலாந்தின் போரிஸ் ஜான்சன்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "(ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்); பிரிட்டிஷ் பிரதம மந்திரி போரிஸ் ஜான்சன் தனது இறுதிக் காட்சிப் பொருளான நாடாளுமன்றத் தோற்றத்திற்குத் தலைவணங்கினார், அவரது கட்சியினரின் கைதட்டல், எதிரிகளின் கேலி, மற்றும் ஒரு புதிரான வெளியேறும் வரி: \"மிஷன் பெரும்பாலும் நிறைவேற்றப்பட்டது ... ஹஸ்டா லா விஸ்டா, குழந்தை.\"",
        "மூன்று கொந்தளிப்பான ஆண்டுகளுக்குப் பிறகு நாட்டை வழிநடத்தும் அவரது திறனைக் குறைமதிப்பிற்கு உட்படுத்தியதாக அவரது கட்சி முடிவு செய்த சமீபத்திய ஊழல்களுக்கு எதிரான வெகுஜன கிளர்ச்சிக்குப் பிறகு, ஜான்சன் இந்த மாத தொடக்கத்தில் தனது ராஜினாமாவை அறிவிக்க வேண்டிய கட்டாயம் ஏற்பட்டது.",
        "அவரது இறுதியான “பிரதமரின் கேள்விகள்”, அரசியல் நாட்காட்டியின் வாராந்திர அங்கமாகப் பேசிய ஜான்சன், ரவுடி விவாதத்தில் பிரதமரை எதிராளிகளுக்கு எதிராக நிறுத்துகிறார், ஜான்சன் கோவிட்-19 பதிலைச் சுற்றி தனது பாரம்பரியத்தை வடிவமைக்க முயன்றார். ரஷ்யா.",
        "“நாங்கள் உதவி செய்தோம், நான் உதவி செய்தேன், இந்த நாட்டை ஒரு தொற்றுநோய் மூலம் மீட்டு, மற்றொரு நாட்டை காட்டுமிராண்டித்தனத்திலிருந்து காப்பாற்ற உதவுகிறோம். மேலும் வெளிப்படையாக, அது நடந்துகொண்டே இருந்தால் போதும். பணி பெரும்பாலும் நிறைவேற்றப்பட்டது,\" என்று ஜான்சன் கூறினார்.",
        "1991 ஆம் ஆண்டு திரைப்படமான \"டெர்மினேட்டர் 2: ஜட்ஜ்மென்ட் டே\" இல் அர்னால்ட் ஸ்வார்ஸ்னேக்கரிடமிருந்து கடன் வாங்கப்பட்ட இந்த வரி, \"பிறகு சந்திப்போம்\" என்று மொழிபெயர்க்கப்பட்டது, இது அவரது சொந்தப் பக்கத்திலிருந்து பலரிடமிருந்து கைதட்டலைத் தூண்டியது.",
        "இரண்டு வாரங்களுக்கு முன்புதான், கைதட்டியவர்களில் சிலர் அவரது அரசாங்கத்திலிருந்து ராஜினாமா செய்தனர், அவரது தலைமையை விமர்சித்தனர் மற்றும் அவர் விலகக் கோரினர். அவரது முன்னோடி தெரசா மே கைதட்டுவதற்கு நிற்கவில்லை என்று விவாத அறையில் செய்தியாளர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "லா விஸ்டா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "யுகே",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "போரிஸ் ஜான்சன்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "போரிஸ் ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லா விஸ்டா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாத தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று கொந்தளிப்பான ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அர்னால்டு ஸ்வார்ஸ்னேக்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1991",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெர்மினேட்டர் 2: தீர்ப்பு நாள்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு வாரங்களுக்கு முன்புதான்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெரசா மே",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}