{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/caption_story/Elephantiasis-clinic-at-Gampaha/110-244006",
  "time_ut": 1661853607,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Elephantiasis clinic at Gampaha...",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Elephantiasis clinic at Gampaha...",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A medical clinic was conducted at Kiribathgoda Hospital to diagnose possible infections of the elephantiasis treponema among people, as there is a steady increase in both elephantiasis and dengue disease. The clinic was conducted by the elephantiasis control unit at Gampaha by the Public Health Field Officer (PHFO) Nirish Madushan and with the support of the Ragama Gramaniladhari (181) Saumya Somasiri. Pix by Nimalsiri Edirisinghe"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gampaha",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kiribathgoda Hospital",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Public Health Field Officer",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PHFO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nirish Madushan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ragama Gramaniladhari",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "181",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saumya Somasiri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nimalsiri Edirisinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගම්පහ අලි රෝග සායනය...",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අලි ඇතුන් සහ ඩෙංගු යන රෝග දෙකෙහිම ක්‍රමයෙන් වැඩිවීමක් දක්නට ලැබෙන බැවින්, අලි ඇතුන් ට්‍රෙපොනීමා රෝගය ජනතාව අතර ඇති විය හැකි ආසාදන හඳුනා ගැනීම සඳහා කිරිබත්ගොඩ රෝහලේ වෛද්‍ය සායනයක් පවත්වන ලදී. මහජන සෞඛ්‍ය ක්‍ෂේත්‍ර නිලධාරී (PHFO) නිරිෂ් මධුෂාන් මහතාගේ සහ රාගම ග්‍රාමනිලධාරි (181) සෞම්‍ය සෝමසිරි මහත්මියගේ සහයෝගය ඇතිව ගම්පහ අලි රෝග මර්දන ඒකකය මගින් මෙම සායනය පවත්වන ලදී. පික්ස් - නිමල්සිරි එදිරිසිංහ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගම්පහ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කිරිබත්ගොඩ රෝහල",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන සෞඛ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර නිලධාරී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PHFO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිරිෂ් මධුෂාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාගම ග්‍රාමනිලධාරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "181",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞම්‍ය සෝමසිරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිමල්සිරි එදිරිසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கம்பஹாவில் உள்ள யானைக்கால் சிகிச்சை...",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "யானைக்கால் நோய் மற்றும் டெங்கு நோய் ஆகிய இரண்டும் தொடர்ந்து அதிகரித்து வருவதால், மக்கள் மத்தியில் எலிஃபென்டியாஸிஸ் ட்ரெபோனிமாவின் சாத்தியமான தொற்றுநோய்களைக் கண்டறிவதற்காக கிரிபத்கொட வைத்தியசாலையில் மருத்துவ சிகிச்சை நிலையம் ஒன்று நடத்தப்பட்டது. பொது சுகாதார கள அதிகாரி (PHFO) நிரிஷ் மதுஷன் மற்றும் ராகம கிராமநிலாதாரி (181) சௌமிய சோமசிறி ஆகியோரின் ஆதரவுடன் கம்பஹாவில் உள்ள யானைக்கால் நோய் கட்டுப்பாட்டு பிரிவினால் இந்த கிளினிக் நடத்தப்பட்டது. நிமல்சிறி எதிரிசிங்கவின் படங்கள்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கம்பஹா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கிரிபத்கொட வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது சுகாதார கள அலுவலர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PHFO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிரிஷ் மதுஷன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராகம கிராமநிலாதாரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "181",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சௌமிய சோமசிறி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிமல்சிறி எதிரிசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}