{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83635/party-leaders-call-for-pms-immediate-resignation",
  "time_ut": 1657773900,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Party leaders call for PM’s immediate resignation",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Party leaders call for PM’s immediate resignation",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "It was decided at the special meeting held with the participation of the members of Committee on Parliamentary Business and the political party leaders yesterday (July 13) that Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe should vacate his position at the earliest possible to defuse the prevailing crisis situation.",
        "In a press release on the decisions taken at the said meeting, the Office of the Speaker of Parliament said the political party leaders had discussed the present situation of the country at length.",
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, who is currently and plans to fly out to Singapore, had previously informed Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena that he would send his resignation before midnight yesterday.",
        "Earlier today, foreign media reported that President Rajapaksa failed to board a Singapore-bound flight from the Maldives due to security reasons. Reportedly, he is now in talks to secure a private jet to Singapore.",
        "He is expected to submit his resignation after arriving in Singapore."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "PM",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Committee on Parliamentary Business",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Office of the Speaker of Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "midnight yesterday",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Earlier today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අගමැති වහාම ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බව පක්ෂ නායකයෝ ඉල්ලා සිටිති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පවතින අර්බුදකාරී තත්ත්වය සමනය කිරීම සඳහා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා හැකි ඉක්මනින් සිය ධුරයෙන් ඉවත් විය යුතු බවට ඊයේ (ජුලි 13) පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභිකයන්ගේ සහ දේශපාලන පක්ෂ නායකයින්ගේ සහභාගීත්වයෙන් පැවති විශේෂ රැස්වීමේදී තීරණය විය.",
        "එම රැස්වීමේදී ගනු ලැබූ තීරණ පිළිබඳ මාධ්‍ය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කථානායක කාර්යාලය සඳහන් කළේ දේශපාලන පක්ෂ නායකයින් රටේ වත්මන් තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව දීර්ඝ වශයෙන් සාකච්ඡා කළ බවයි.",
        "මේ වන විට සිංගප්පූරුව බලා පිටත්ව යාමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඊයේ මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියට පෙර සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීම යවන බව කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතාට මීට පෙර දන්වා තිබුණි.",
        "ආරක්ෂක හේතූන් මත මාලදිවයිනේ සිට සිංගප්පූරුව බලා පිටත්ව යන ගුවන් යානයකට ගොඩවීමට ජනාධිපතිතුමා අපොහොසත් වූ බව අද උදෑසන විදෙස් මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කළේය. වාර්තා වන පරිදි ඔහු දැන් සිංගප්පූරුවට පුද්ගලික ජෙට් යානයක් ලබා ගැනීමට සාකච්ඡා කරමින් සිටී.",
        "සිංගප්පූරුවට පැමිණීමෙන් පසු ඔහු සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීම භාරදීමට නියමිතයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "PM",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කථානායක කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද කලින්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரதமர் உடனடியாக ராஜினாமா செய்ய வேண்டும் என கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தற்போது நிலவும் நெருக்கடியான சூழ்நிலையை தணிக்க பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க விரைவில் தனது பதவியை இராஜினாமா செய்ய வேண்டும் என நேற்று (ஜூலை 13) பாராளுமன்ற அலுவல்கள் குழு உறுப்பினர்கள் மற்றும் அரசியல் கட்சி தலைவர்கள் கலந்துகொண்ட விசேட கூட்டத்தில் தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இந்தக் கூட்டத்தில் எடுக்கப்பட்ட முடிவுகள் குறித்த செய்திக் குறிப்பில், நாட்டின் தற்போதைய நிலைமை குறித்து அரசியல் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் விரிவாக விவாதித்ததாக நாடாளுமன்ற சபாநாயகர் அலுவலகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "தற்போது சிங்கப்பூர் செல்லத் திட்டமிட்டுள்ள ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ, நேற்று நள்ளிரவுக்கு முன்னர் தனது இராஜினாமாவை அனுப்புவதாக சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தனவிடம் தெரிவித்திருந்தார்.",
        "பாதுகாப்பு காரணங்களுக்காக மாலத்தீவில் இருந்து சிங்கப்பூர் செல்லும் விமானத்தில் அதிபர் ராஜபக்சே ஏறவில்லை என இன்று அதிகாலை வெளிநாட்டு ஊடகங்கள் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளன. சிங்கப்பூருக்கு ஒரு தனியார் ஜெட் விமானத்தைப் பாதுகாப்பது குறித்து அவர் இப்போது பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தி வருவதாகக் கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "சிங்கப்பூர் வந்தவுடன் அவர் தனது ராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை சமர்பிப்பார் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மாலை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற அலுவல் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற சபாநாயகர் அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று நள்ளிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முன்னதாக இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}