{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78818",
  "time_ut": 1659292740,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "India  raises the scheduled visit of Chinese research vessel ‘Yuan Wang 5’ to  Hambantota with President Ranil Wickremesinghe,the matter “was raised at the highest level by the Indian side,” an official source in Colombo tells  “The Hindu”",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "India  raises the scheduled visit of Chinese research vessel ‘Yuan Wang 5’ to  Hambantota with President Ranil Wickremesinghe,the matter “was raised at the highest level by the Indian side,” an official source in Colombo tells  “The Hindu”",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "India has raised the scheduled visit of a Chinese research vessel to a Sri Lankan port with President Ranil Wickremesinghe, after the Ministry of Defence in Colombo confirmed the ship’s arrival, despite New Delhi giving a “clear message” on its concerns.",
        "While there is no official statement so far from either the Indian mission in Colombo, or the President’s office in this regard, the matter “was raised at the highest level by the Indian side,” an official source in Colombo, familiar with the development, told  The Hindu on Monday.",
        "Following media reports last week of ‘Yuan Wang 5’ — a Chinese vessel involved in space and satellite tracking — calling at Sri Lanka’s southern Hambantota Port, the Ministry of Defence denied such a vessel was arriving. However, taking back its denial within days, the ministry said last weekend that it had cleared the vessel’s entry into the Chinese-built Hambantota Port, where it would dock from August 11 to 17.",
        "The confirmation not only sparked serious concern in New Delhi, but also raised eyebrows in Colombo too, coming two days after Ministry of External Affairs spokesperson Arindam Bagchi’s media remarks that India “carefully monitors any development having a bearing on its security and economic interests”. China has defended the ship’s visit and asked “relevant parties” to “refrain from interfering” with its “legitimate maritime activities.”",
        "Members of Sri Lanka’s political opposition on Monday commented on the vessel’s scheduled arrival, and urged the government not to “accentuate” India’s strategic concerns, especially at a time when Colombo is counting on urgent economic assistance from both New Delhi and Beijing to tide over the island’s economic crisis.",
        "Referring to a report in the local Daily Mirror, opposition parliamentarian Harsha de Silva said in a tweet on Monday: “I fervently hope the ‘highest level’ (as mentioned) will resolve this before getting out of hand. India and China are dependable friends and we certainly don’t need to change that. Specially now when we desperately need both to help us.”",
        "The opposition Tamil National Alliance, too, weighed in on the development in a series of tweets. “Chinese space-craft tracking ship Yuanwang-5 entering the Hambantota harbour on 11 August has again given rise to tensions in the region. We do not take sides with regard to power struggles between other countries. But we have also consistently stated that China’s military presence in the Indian ocean would give India a legitimate Defence concern and that SL should not accentuate that by providing space for Chinese military presence in SL,” the Alliance said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang 5’",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Colombo",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Hindu",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Defence in Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last weekend",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 11 to 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of External Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arindam Bagchi’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harsha de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil National Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuanwang-5",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීන පර්යේෂණ යාත්‍රාවක් වන ‘යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5’ හම්බන්තොටට පැමිණීමට නියමිතව ඇති බව ඉන්දියාව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සමඟ මතු කරයි, මෙම කාරණය “ඉන්දියා පාර්ශ්වයෙන් ඉහළම මට්ටමින් මතු කරන ලදී,” කොළඹ නිල මූලාශ්‍රයක් “ද හින්දු” වෙත පවසයි.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "නව දිල්ලිය එහි උත්සුකයන් පිළිබඳව “පැහැදිලි පණිවිඩයක්” ලබා දී තිබියදීත්, කොළඹ ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය විසින් නෞකාව පැමිණීම තහවුරු කිරීමෙන් පසුව, ඉන්දියාව, ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වරායකට චීන පර්යේෂණ නෞකාවක් පැමිණීමට නියමිතව තිබේ.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් කොළඹ පිහිටි ඉන්දීය දූත මණ්ඩලයෙන් හෝ ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයෙන් මේ දක්වා නිල ප්‍රකාශයක් නොමැති අතර, මෙම කාරණය “ඉන්දියා පැත්තෙන් ඉහළම මට්ටමින් මතු කරන ලදී”, සංවර්ධනය පිළිබඳව හුරුපුරුදු කොළඹ නිල මූලාශ්‍රයක්. සඳුදා හින්දු වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "පසුගිය සතියේ ‘යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5’ - අභ්‍යවකාශ සහ චන්ද්‍රිකා ලුහුබැඳීමේ යෙදී සිටින චීන යාත්‍රාවක් - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දකුණු හම්බන්තොට වරායට පැමිණෙන බවට මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කිරීමෙන් පසුව, ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය එවැනි යාත්‍රාවක් පැමිණීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය. කෙසේ වෙතත්, දින කිහිපයක් ඇතුළත එය ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කිරීම ආපසු ගනිමින්, අමාත්‍යාංශය පසුගිය සති අන්තයේ කියා සිටියේ, චීනය විසින් ඉදිකරන ලද හම්බන්තොට වරායට යාත්‍රාව ඇතුළු කිරීම තමන් විසින් ඉවත් කර ඇති බවත්, එය අගෝස්තු 11 සිට 17 දක්වා නැව්ගත කරන බවත්ය.",
        "මෙම තහවුරු කිරීම නවදිල්ලියේ බරපතල කනස්සල්ලට හේතු වූවා පමණක් නොව, කොළඹ ද ඇහිබැම ඉහළ නැංවීය, විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශක Arindam Bagchi ගේ මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශයෙන් දින දෙකකට පසුව ඉන්දියාව “ආරක්ෂාව සහ ආර්ථික අවශ්‍යතා කෙරෙහි බලපාන ඕනෑම වර්ධනයක් ප්‍රවේශමෙන් නිරීක්ෂණය කරයි”. චීනය නෞකාවේ සංචාරය ආරක්ෂා කර ඇති අතර එහි \"නීත්‍යානුකූල සමුද්‍රීය ක්‍රියාකාරකම්\" වලට \"මැදිහත් වීමෙන් වළකින\" ලෙස \"අදාළ පාර්ශ්වයන්ගෙන්\" ඉල්ලා ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දේශපාලන විපක්ෂයේ සාමාජිකයින් සඳුදා යාත්‍රාවේ නියමිත පැමිණීම ගැන අදහස් දැක්වූ අතර, විශේෂයෙන් ම කොළඹ නව දිල්ලියෙන් සහ බීජිංවලින් හදිසි ආර්ථික ආධාර බලාපොරොත්තු වන මොහොතක, ඉන්දියාවේ මූලෝපායික උත්සුකයන් \"අවධානය\" නොකරන ලෙස ආන්ඩුවෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියහ. දිවයිනේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය.",
        "ප්‍රාදේශීය ඩේලි මිරර් පුවත්පතේ වාර්තාවක් ගැන සඳහන් කරමින් විපක්ෂ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා සඳුදා ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් මෙසේ පැවසීය: “ඉහළම මට්ටම (සඳහන් කළ පරිදි) අත හැර යාමට පෙර මෙය විසඳනු ඇතැයි මම දැඩි ලෙස බලාපොරොත්තු වෙමි. ඉන්දියාව සහ චීනය විශ්වාසවන්ත මිතුරන් වන අතර අපට එය වෙනස් කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය නැත. විශේෂයෙන් දැන් අපට උපකාර කිරීමට දෙදෙනාම දැඩි ලෙස අවශ්‍ය වූ විට. ”",
        "විපක්ෂයේ දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානය ද ට්වීට් මාලාවකින් සංවර්ධනය ගැන කිරා මැන බලයි. “චීන අභ්‍යවකාශ යාත්‍රා ලුහුබැඳීමේ නෞකාවක් වන Yuanwang-5 අගෝස්තු 11 වන දින හම්බන්තොට වරායට ඇතුළු වීම කලාපය තුළ නැවතත් ආතතීන් ඇති කර තිබේ. වෙනත් රටවල් අතර බල අරගල සම්බන්ධයෙන් අපි පැත්තක් ගන්නේ නැහැ. නමුත් අපි නිරන්තරයෙන් ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත්තේ චීනය ඉන්දියානු සාගරයේ හමුදා රැඳී සිටීම ඉන්දියාවට නීත්‍යානුකූල ආරක්ෂක සැලකිල්ලක් ලබා දෙන බවත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ චීන හමුදා රැඳී සිටීමට ඉඩ ලබා දීමෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව එය අවධාරණය නොකළ යුතු බවත්ය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang 5’",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "කොළඹ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "හින්දු",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සතිඅන්තය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 11 සිට 17 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරින්දම් බග්චිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuanwang-5",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சீன ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பலான ‘யுவான் வாங் 5’ ஹம்பாந்தோட்டைக்கு ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுடன் திட்டமிடப்பட்ட பயணத்தை இந்தியா எழுப்புகிறது, இந்த விஷயம் “இந்திய தரப்பால் மிக உயர்ந்த மட்டத்தில் எழுப்பப்பட்டது” என்று கொழும்பில் உள்ள உத்தியோகபூர்வ வட்டாரம் “தி இந்து” விடம் கூறுகிறது.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "கப்பலின் வருகையை கொழும்பில் உள்ள பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம் உறுதிப்படுத்திய பின்னர், அதன் கவலைகள் குறித்து புது டெல்லி \"தெளிவான செய்தியை\" வழங்கிய போதிலும், ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுடன் இலங்கை துறைமுகத்திற்கு சீன ஆய்வுக் கப்பலின் திட்டமிடப்பட்ட பயணத்தை இந்தியா எழுப்பியுள்ளது.",
        "இது தொடர்பாக கொழும்பில் உள்ள இந்திய தூதரிடமிருந்தோ அல்லது ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகத்திடமிருந்தோ இதுவரை அதிகாரபூர்வ அறிக்கை எதுவும் இல்லை என்றாலும், இந்த விவகாரம் \"இந்திய தரப்பினால் மிக உயர்ந்த மட்டத்தில் எழுப்பப்பட்டது\" என்று கொழும்பில் உள்ள உத்தியோகபூர்வ ஆதாரம், வளர்ச்சியை நன்கு அறிந்திருக்கிறது. தி ஹிந்துவிடம் திங்கட்கிழமை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கடந்த வாரம் 'யுவான் வாங் 5' - விண்வெளி மற்றும் செயற்கைக்கோள் கண்காணிப்பில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள சீனக் கப்பல் - இலங்கையின் தெற்கு ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்திற்கு வந்ததாக ஊடக அறிக்கைகளைத் தொடர்ந்து, பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம் அத்தகைய கப்பல் வரவில்லை என்று மறுத்தது. எவ்வாறாயினும், சில நாட்களுக்குள் தனது மறுப்பைத் திரும்பப் பெற்றுக் கொண்டு, கடந்த வார இறுதியில், சீனாவால் கட்டப்பட்ட ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்துக்குள் கப்பல் நுழைவதை அனுமதித்துள்ளதாகவும், அங்கு ஆகஸ்ட் 11 முதல் 17 வரை கப்பல் நிறுத்தப்படும் என்றும் அமைச்சகம் கூறியது.",
        "இந்த உறுதிப்படுத்தல் புதுதில்லியில் தீவிர கவலையைத் தூண்டியது மட்டுமல்லாமல், கொழும்பிலும் புருவங்களை உயர்த்தியது, இரண்டு நாட்களுக்குப் பிறகு வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் அரிந்தம் பாக்ச்சியின் ஊடகக் கருத்துக்கள் இந்தியா \"தன் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் பொருளாதார நலன்களில் தாக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்தும் எந்தவொரு வளர்ச்சியையும் கவனமாகக் கண்காணிக்கிறது\". சீனா கப்பலின் வருகையை ஆதரித்து, அதன் \"சட்டபூர்வமான கடல்சார் நடவடிக்கைகளில்\" \"தலையிடுவதைத் தவிர்க்க\" \"சம்பந்தப்பட்ட தரப்பினரை\" கேட்டுக் கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையின் அரசியல் எதிர்க்கட்சி உறுப்பினர்கள் திங்களன்று கப்பலின் திட்டமிடப்பட்ட வருகை குறித்து கருத்துத் தெரிவித்ததோடு, இந்தியாவின் மூலோபாய கவலைகளை \"அதிகரிக்க\" வேண்டாம் என்று அரசாங்கத்தை வலியுறுத்தினர், குறிப்பாக புதுடெல்லி மற்றும் பெய்ஜிங் ஆகிய இரு நாடுகளின் அவசர பொருளாதார உதவியை கொழும்பு எதிர்பார்க்கும் நேரத்தில். தீவின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி.",
        "லோக்கல் டெய்லி மிரர் பத்திரிகையின் செய்தியை குறிப்பிட்டு, எதிர்க்கட்சி பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா திங்களன்று ஒரு ட்வீட்டில் கூறினார்: “உயர் மட்டம் (குறிப்பிடப்பட்டபடி) கையை விட்டு வெளியேறுவதற்கு முன்பு இதைத் தீர்க்கும் என்று நான் ஆவலுடன் நம்புகிறேன். இந்தியாவும் சீனாவும் நம்பகமான நண்பர்கள், அதை நாம் நிச்சயமாக மாற்ற வேண்டியதில்லை. விசேஷமாக இப்போது இருவரும் எங்களுக்கு உதவி செய்ய வேண்டியிருக்கும் போது.\"",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சியான தமிழ்த் தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பும் தொடர்ச்சியான ட்வீட்களில் வளர்ச்சியை எடைபோட்டுள்ளது. “சீன விண்வெளி-கப்பல் கண்காணிப்பு கப்பல் யுவான்வாங்-5 ஆகஸ்ட் 11 அன்று ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்திற்குள் நுழைந்தது மீண்டும் பிராந்தியத்தில் பதற்றத்தை ஏற்படுத்தியுள்ளது. மற்ற நாடுகளுக்கு இடையிலான அதிகாரப் போட்டிகள் தொடர்பாக நாங்கள் பக்கம் சாய்வதில்லை. ஆனால், இந்தியப் பெருங்கடலில் சீனாவின் இராணுவப் பிரசன்னம் இந்தியாவுக்கு நியாயமான பாதுகாப்புக் கவலையை அளிக்கும் என்றும், இலங்கையில் சீன இராணுவப் பிரசன்னத்திற்கு இடம் அளிப்பதன் மூலம், இலங்கை அதை வலியுறுத்தக் கூடாது என்றும் நாங்கள் தொடர்ந்து கூறியுள்ளோம்,” என்று கூட்டணி கூறியது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang 5’",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "கொழும்பு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்து",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாட்களில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வார இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 11 முதல் 17 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரிந்தம் பாக்சியின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் தேசிய கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuanwang-5",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}