{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/සමන්ප්‍රිය-හේරත්-ලෙඩ-ඇඳේ-සිට-එයි/1-616729",
  "time_ut": 1658296657,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "සමන්ප්‍රිය හේරත් ලෙඩ ඇඳේ සිට එයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Samanpriya Herat comes from sick bed",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Podujana Peramuna's Kurunegala District Member Mr. Saman Priya Herath, who is seriously ill, came to Parliament and cast his vote.",
        "The saline bottle was also attached to his body and he was seen voting with great difficulty.",
        "With the permission of the House, the Secretary General of the Parliament gave him the opportunity to vote without standing until his name was called."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala District",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Priya Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සමන්ප්‍රිය හේරත් ලෙඩ ඇඳේ සිට එයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ කුරුණෑගල දිස්ත්‍රික් මන්ත්‍රී සමන් ප්‍රිය හේරත් මහතා දැඩි ලෙස ගිලන්ව හිඳින අතර පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණ තම ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ඔහුගේ සිරුරට සේලයින් බෝතලය ද සම්බන්ධ කර තිබූ අතර ඉතා අසීරුවෙන් පැමිණ ඔහු ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කරන අයුරු දැකගත හැකි විය.",
        "නම අඬගසන තුරු නොසිට ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීම සඳහා සභාවේ අවසරය පරිදි පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම්වරයා ඔහුට අවස්ථාව ලබා දුන්නේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් ප්‍රියා හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சமன்பிரியா ஹெராத் நோய்வாய்ப்பட்ட படுக்கையில் இருந்து வருகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் குருநாகல் மாவட்ட உறுப்பினர் திரு.சமன் பிரியா ஹேரத், கடுமையான சுகவீனமுற்ற நிலையில், பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு வந்து வாக்களித்தார்.",
        "சலைன் போத்தலும் உடலில் பொருத்தப்பட்டு மிகவும் சிரமப்பட்டு வாக்களிப்பது காணப்பட்டது.",
        "சபையின் அனுமதியுடன் நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் செயலாளர் நாயகம் அவர் பெயர் அழைக்கப்படும் வரை நிற்காமல் வாக்களிக்க வாய்ப்பளித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல் மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் பிரியா ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}