{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Inter-Provincial-bus-owners-support-struggle/342-240709",
  "time_ut": 1657355876,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Inter Provincial bus owners support struggle",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Inter Provincial bus owners support struggle",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Inter Provincial Private Bus Association (IPPBA) has appealed to all bus owners to run their buses as much as they can to provide transportation for the people to participate in the struggle at the Galle Face.",
        "Association's Secretary Anjana Priyanjith told the Daily Mirror that several long distance buses were operated. The bus owners were told to offer their support to the struggle campaigns organised at the provincial level.",
        "We have a major issue with getting diesel, but with the available fuel remaining in buses, we have decided to offer our support to the people's struggle with our maximum effort. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Inter Provincial",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Inter Provincial Private Bus Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IPPBA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Galle Face",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anjana Priyanjith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අන්තර් පළාත් බස් හිමියන් අරගලයට සහය දක්වයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ගාලු මුවදොර අරගලයට සහභාගී වීම සඳහා ජනතාවට ප්‍රවාහන පහසුකම් සැලසීම සඳහා හැකිතාක් බස් රථ ධාවනය කරන ලෙස අන්තර් පළාත් පෞද්ගලික බස් රථ සංගමය (IPPBA) සියලුම බස් හිමියන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කරයි.",
        "එම සංගමයේ ලේකම් අංජන ප්‍රියන්ජිත් ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත කියා සිටියේ දුර ගමන් සේවා බස් රථ කිහිපයක් ධාවනය කළ බවයි. පළාත් මට්ටමින් සංවිධානය කෙරෙන අරගල ව්‍යාපාරවලට සහය ලබාදෙන ලෙස බස් හිමියන්ට දැනුම් දුන්නා.",
        "අපට ඩීසල් ලබා ගැනීම ප්‍රධාන ගැටලුවක් වී ඇති නමුත් පවතින ඉන්ධන බස් රථවල ඉතිරිව තිබීම හේතුවෙන් ජනතා අරගලයට අපගේ උපරිම උත්සාහයෙන් සහය ලබාදීමට අපි තීරණය කර තිබෙනවා. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අන්තර් පළාත්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අන්තර් පළාත් පෞද්ගලික බස් සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IPPBA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අංජන ප්‍රියන්ජිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மாகாணங்களுக்கு இடையிலான பேருந்து உரிமையாளர்கள் போராட்டத்திற்கு ஆதரவு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "காலி முகத்திடலில் இடம்பெறும் போராட்டத்தில் மக்கள் கலந்து கொள்வதற்காக போக்குவரத்து வசதிகளை ஏற்படுத்திக் கொடுப்பதற்காக தங்களால் இயன்ற பேரூந்துகளை இயக்குமாறு அனைத்துப் பேருந்து உரிமையாளர்களிடமும் மாகாணங்களுக்கு இடையிலான தனியார் பேருந்து சங்கம் வேண்டுகோள் விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "பல தொலைதூர பேருந்துகள் இயக்கப்பட்டதாக சங்கத்தின் செயலாளர் அஞ்சனா பிரியஞ்சித் டெய்லி மிரருக்கு தெரிவித்தார். மாகாண மட்டத்தில் முன்னெடுக்கப்படும் போராட்டங்களுக்கு தமது ஆதரவை வழங்குமாறு பஸ் உரிமையாளர்களிடம் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "எங்களுக்கு டீசல் கிடைப்பதில் பெரும் சிக்கல் உள்ளது, ஆனால் பேருந்துகளில் இருக்கும் எரிபொருள் மீதம் இருப்பதால், எங்களின் அதிகபட்ச முயற்சியுடன் மக்களின் போராட்டத்திற்கு ஆதரவை வழங்க முடிவு செய்துள்ளோம். (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மாகாணங்களுக்கு இடையே",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மாகாணங்களுக்கு இடையிலான தனியார் பேருந்து சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IPPBA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி முகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஞ்சனா பிரியஞ்சித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}