{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/President-flees-the-country-on-military-jet/108-240937",
  "time_ut": 1657672176,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President flees the country on military jet",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President flees the country on military jet",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has fled the country on a military jet, amid mass protests over its economic crisis.",
        "He arrived in the capital of the Maldives, Male, at around 03:00 local time (22:00 GMT).",
        "Mr Rajapaksa's departure ends a family dynasty that has ruled Sri Lanka for decades.",
        "He had been in hiding after crowds stormed his residence on Saturday.",
        "The president had earlier pledged to resign on Wednesday 13 July.",
        "His brother, former Finance Minister Basil Rajapaksa, has also left the country, sources have told the BBC. He is said to be heading to the US. As news of the president's departure filtered through, noisy celebrations broke out among demonstrators at Galle Face Green, the main protest site in the capital city, Colombo.",
        "On Tuesday evening there were already thousands of people massing at the park, awaiting the president's resignation.",
        "Sri Lankans blame President Rajapaksa's administration for their worst economic crisis in decades.",
        "For months they have been struggling with daily power cuts and shortages of basics like fuel, food and medicines.",
        "The leader, who enjoys immunity from prosecution while he is president, is believed to have wanted to flee abroad before stepping down to avoid the possibility of arrest by the new administration.",
        "The president's departure threatens a potential power vacuum in the country, which needs a functioning government to help start digging it out of financial ruin.",
        "Politicians from other parties have been talking about forming a new unity government but there is no sign they are near agreement yet. It's also not clear if the public would accept what they come up with.",
        "Under the constitution, it's the prime minister, Ranil Wickremesinghe, who should act in the president's stead if the latter resigns. The prime minister is considered the president's deputy in parliament.",
        "However, Mr Wickremesinghe is also deeply unpopular. Protesters set fire to his private residence on Saturday - he and his family were not inside - and he said he would resign to make way for a unity government, but gave no date.",
        "That leaves the parliament's speaker as the next most likely to step in as caretaker president, constitutional experts say. However Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena is an ally of the Rajapaksas. It is unclear whether the public would accept his authority.",
        "Whoever does become acting president has 30 days to hold an election for a new president from among members of parliament. The winner of that vote could then see out the remainder of Mr Rajapaksa's term until late 2024.",
        "On Monday, the main opposition leader Sajith Premadasa told the BBC he would be tilting for the presidency. But he also lacks public support and there is deep public suspicion of politicians in general.",
        "The protest movement which has brought Sri Lanka to the brink of change also does not have an obvious contender for the country's leadership. (BBC)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Male",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22:00 GMT",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wednesday 13 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "BBC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face Green",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "late 2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "BBC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "BBC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපති හමුදා ජෙට් යානයකින් රටින් පලා යයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "එහි ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් මහජන විරෝධතා මධ්‍යයේ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ හමුදා ජෙට් යානයකින් රටින් පලා ගොස් තිබේ.",
        "ඔහු මාලදිවයිනේ අගනුවර වන Male වෙත දේශීය වේලාවෙන් 03:00 ට පමණ (22:00 GMT) ළඟා විය.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ නික්ම යාමෙන් දශක ගණනාවක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පාලනය කළ පවුල් පෙළපතක් අවසන් වේ.",
        "සෙනසුරාදා සෙනසුරාදා ඔහුගේ නිවසට කඩා වැදීමෙන් පසු ඔහු සැඟවී සිටියේය.",
        "ජූලි 13 බදාදා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට ජනාධිපතිවරයා මීට පෙර ප්‍රතිඥා දී තිබුණි.",
        "ඔහුගේ සොහොයුරා වන හිටපු මුදල් අමාත්‍ය බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ ද රට හැර ගොස් ඇති බව ආරංචි මාර්ග බීබීසීයට පවසා ඇත. ඔහු අමෙරිකාව බලා යන බව පැවසේ. ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ නික්ම යාම පිළිබඳ පුවත පෙරීමත් සමඟම, අගනුවර වන කොළඹ නගරයේ ප්‍රධාන විරෝධතා ස්ථානය වන ගාලු මුවදොර පිටියේ විරෝධතාකරුවන් අතර ඝෝෂාකාරී සැමරුම් ඇවිලී ගියේය.",
        "අඟහරුවාදා සවස දැනටමත් දහස් ගණන් ජනයා උද්‍යානයේ රැස්ව සිටි අතර, ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම බලාපොරොත්තුවෙන් සිටියහ.",
        "දශක කිහිපයකින් තමන් මුහුණ දුන් දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයෝ ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂගේ පාලනයට දොස් කියති.",
        "ඔවුන් මාස ගණනාවක් තිස්සේ දිනපතා විදුලිය විසන්ධි කිරීම සහ ඉන්ධන, ආහාර සහ ඖෂධ වැනි මූලික ද්‍රව්‍ය හිඟය සමඟ පොරබදමින් සිටිති.",
        "ඔහු ජනාධිපතිව සිටියදී නඩු පැවරීමෙන් මුක්තිය භුක්ති විඳින නායකයාට නව පරිපාලනය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමේ හැකියාව වළක්වා ගැනීම සඳහා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට පෙර විදේශගත වීමට අවශ්‍ය වූ බව විශ්වාස කෙරේ.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ නික්මයාම රට තුළ විභව බල රික්තකයකට තර්ජනය කරයි, මූල්‍ය විනාශයෙන් එය හෑරීමට පටන් ගැනීමට උදව් කිරීමට ක්‍රියාකාරී රජයක් අවශ්‍ය වේ.",
        "වෙනත් පක්ෂවල දේශපාලනඥයන් නව ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම ගැන කතා කළත් ඔවුන් තවමත් එකඟතාවකට පැමිණෙන බවක් පෙනෙන්නට නැත. ඔවුන් ඉදිරිපත් කරන දේ මහජනතාව පිළිගන්නවාද යන්න ද පැහැදිලි නැත.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවට අනුව ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉල්ලා අස් වුවහොත් ඒ වෙනුවට ක්‍රියා කළ යුත්තේ අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාය. අගමැතිවරයා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ නියෝජ්‍ය නායකයා ලෙස සැලකේ.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ද දැඩි ලෙස ජනප්‍රිය නොවේ. විරෝධතාකරුවන් සෙනසුරාදා ඔහුගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ගිනි තැබුවේය - ඔහු සහ ඔහුගේ පවුලේ අය එහි සිටියේ නැත - ඔහු සමඟි ආන්ඩුවක් ඇති කිරීම සඳහා ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව පැවසූ නමුත් දිනයක් ලබා දුන්නේ නැත.",
        "එය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කථානායකවරයා භාරකාර ජනාධිපති ලෙස මීළඟට පැමිණීමට බොහෝ දුරට ඉඩ ඇති බව ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා විශේෂඥයෝ පවසති. කෙසේ වෙතත් මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන රාජපක්ෂලාගේ හිතවතෙකි. ඔහුගේ අධිකාරිය මහජනතාව පිළිගනීද යන්න පැහැදිලි නැත.",
        "වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති ධූරයට පත්වන ඕනෑම කෙනෙකුට පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් අතරින් නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු සඳහා මැතිවරණයක් පැවැත්වීමට දින 30ක කාලයක් තිබේ. එම ඡන්දයේ ජයග්‍රාහකයාට 2024 අග භාගය දක්වා රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ධූර කාලයෙහි ඉතිරි කාලය දැක ගත හැකිය.",
        "සඳුදා ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස බීබීසීයට පැවසුවේ තමන් ජනාධිපති ධුරයට නැඹුරු වන බවයි. එහෙත් ඔහුට මහජන සහයෝගය ද නොමැති අතර පොදුවේ දේශපාලනඥයන් පිළිබඳ ගැඹුරු මහජන සැකයක් පවතී.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වෙනසක අද්දරට ගෙන ආ විරෝධතා ව්‍යාපාරයට ද රටේ නායකත්වය සඳහා පැහැදිලි තරගකරුවෙකු නොමැත. (බීබීසී)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිරිමි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22:00 GMT",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දශක",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13 බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීබීසී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර පිටිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දශක",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024 අග",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීබීසී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීබීසී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி இராணுவ ஜெட் விமானத்தில் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறினார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ தனது பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி காரணமாக பாரிய எதிர்ப்புகளுக்கு மத்தியில் இராணுவ ஜெட் விமானத்தில் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறியுள்ளார்.",
        "அவர் மாலத்தீவின் தலைநகரான மாலேவுக்கு உள்ளூர் நேரப்படி 03:00 மணியளவில் (22:00 GMT) வந்தடைந்தார்.",
        "ராஜபக்சவின் விலகல் பல தசாப்தங்களாக இலங்கையை ஆண்ட ஒரு குடும்ப வம்சத்தை முடிவுக்குக் கொண்டுவருகிறது.",
        "சனிக்கிழமையன்று அவரது இல்லத்தை மக்கள் முற்றுகையிட்டதை அடுத்து அவர் தலைமறைவாக இருந்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி முன்னதாக ஜூலை 13 புதன்கிழமை பதவி விலகுவதாக உறுதியளித்தார்.",
        "அவரது சகோதரரும், முன்னாள் நிதியமைச்சருமான பசில் ராஜபக்சவும் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறியுள்ளதாக பிபிசி வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளன. அவர் அமெரிக்கா செல்ல உள்ளதாக கூறப்படுகிறது. ஜனாதிபதி வெளியேறிய செய்தி வடிகட்டிய போது, ​​தலைநகர் கொழும்பில் உள்ள முக்கிய போராட்டத் தளமான காலி முகத்திடலில் ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் மத்தியில் சத்தம் நிறைந்த கொண்டாட்டங்கள் வெடித்தன.",
        "செவ்வாய் மாலை, பூங்காவில் ஏற்கனவே ஆயிரக்கணக்கான மக்கள் ஜனாதிபதியின் ராஜினாமாவுக்காகக் காத்திருந்தனர்.",
        "பல தசாப்தங்களில் தங்களுக்கு ஏற்பட்ட மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு அதிபர் ராஜபக்சேவின் நிர்வாகமே காரணம் என்று இலங்கையர்கள் குற்றம் சாட்டுகின்றனர்.",
        "தினசரி மின்வெட்டு மற்றும் எரிபொருள், உணவு மற்றும் மருந்துகள் போன்ற அடிப்படைத் தட்டுப்பாடுகளால் பல மாதங்களாக அவர்கள் போராடி வருகின்றனர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியாக இருக்கும் போது வழக்கு விசாரணையில் இருந்து விலக்கு பெறும் தலைவர், புதிய நிர்வாகத்தால் கைது செய்யப்படுவதைத் தவிர்ப்பதற்காக பதவி விலகுவதற்கு முன் வெளிநாட்டுக்குத் தப்பிச் செல்ல விரும்பியதாக நம்பப்படுகிறது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் புறப்பாடு நாட்டில் ஒரு சாத்தியமான அதிகார வெற்றிடத்தை அச்சுறுத்துகிறது, நிதி அழிவிலிருந்து அதை தோண்டி எடுக்க ஒரு செயல்படும் அரசாங்கம் தேவை.",
        "மற்ற கட்சிகளைச் சேர்ந்த அரசியல்வாதிகள் புதிய ஐக்கிய அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பது பற்றி பேசிக்கொண்டிருக்கிறார்கள், ஆனால் அவர்கள் இன்னும் உடன்படுவதற்கான அறிகுறி இல்லை. அவர்கள் கொண்டு வருவதை பொதுமக்கள் ஏற்பார்களா என்பதும் தெரியவில்லை.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் பிரகாரம், ஜனாதிபதி பதவி விலகினால் அவருக்கு பதிலாக பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க செயற்பட வேண்டும். பிரதமர் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் ஜனாதிபதியின் துணைவராக கருதப்படுகிறார்.",
        "இருப்பினும், திரு விக்கிரமசிங்கவும் ஆழ்ந்த செல்வாக்கற்றவர். சனிக்கிழமையன்று அவரது தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்திற்கு எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் தீ வைத்தனர் - அவரும் அவரது குடும்பத்தினரும் உள்ளே இல்லை - மேலும் அவர் ஒரு ஐக்கிய அரசாங்கத்திற்கு வழிவகுக்க ராஜினாமா செய்வதாகக் கூறினார், ஆனால் தேதி எதுவும் தெரிவிக்கவில்லை.",
        "இதனால் நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் சபாநாயகரே தற்காலிக ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியேற்கும் வாய்ப்பு அதிகம் என அரசியலமைப்பு நிபுணர்கள் கூறுகின்றனர். எனினும் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன ராஜபக்சக்களின் கூட்டாளி. அவரது அதிகாரத்தை பொதுமக்கள் ஏற்றுக்கொள்வார்களா என்பது தெரியவில்லை.",
        "தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதியாக வருபவர் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களில் இருந்து புதிய ஜனாதிபதிக்கான தேர்தலை நடத்துவதற்கு 30 நாட்கள் அவகாசம் உள்ளது. அந்த வாக்களிப்பில் வெற்றி பெறுபவர், 2024 ஆம் ஆண்டின் பிற்பகுதி வரை ராஜபக்சேவின் எஞ்சிய காலத்தை பார்க்க முடியும்.",
        "திங்கட்கிழமை, பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச பிபிசியிடம், தான் ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் போட்டியிடப் போவதாகத் தெரிவித்தார். ஆனால் அவருக்கு பொதுமக்களின் ஆதரவும் இல்லை, மேலும் பொதுவாக அரசியல்வாதிகள் மீது மக்களுக்கு ஆழ்ந்த சந்தேகம் உள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையை மாற்றத்தின் விளிம்பிற்குக் கொண்டு வந்த எதிர்ப்பு இயக்கமும் நாட்டின் தலைமைப் பதவிக்கான வெளிப்படையான போட்டியாளர்களைக் கொண்டிருக்கவில்லை. (பிபிசி)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22:00 GMT",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தாண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13 புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிபிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face Green",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாயங்காலம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தாண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024 இன் பிற்பகுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிபிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிபிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}