{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/27/how-will-transport-services-operate-from-tuesday-28/",
  "time_ut": 1656347940,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "How will transport services operate from Tuesday (28)?",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "How will transport services operate from Tuesday (28)?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka’s Cabinet of Minister decided that ONLY essential services will operate from midnight today (27) to the 10th of July.",
        "Lanka Private Bus Owners Association said that it is unsure about operating its fleet from Tuesday (27).",
        "The National Transport Commission said that it would operate buses based on the fuel availability.",
        "Sri Lanka Railways said that it would operate its trains as per the existing time table.",
        "All schools in the Colombo region, schools in the suburbs of the Western Province and in major cities in other provinces will be closed until July 10th.",
        "The Ceylon Petroleum Corporation will ONLY issue Diesel and Petrol for essential services with effect from midnight on Monday (27).",
        "These services include Ports, Airports, Health, Food Distribution, Agriculture, said Minister Bandula Gunawardena.",
        "BREAKING: Only essential services to operate from midnight (27); CPC will only issue fuel for essential services"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Tuesday",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "28",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "midnight today",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The National Transport Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Railways",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 10th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Petrol",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "midnight",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ports, Airports, Health, Food Distribution, Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අඟහරුවාදා (28) සිට ප්‍රවාහන සේවා ක්‍රියාත්මක වන්නේ කෙසේද?",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); අද (27) මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ සිට ජූලි 10 දක්වා අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය සේවා පමණක් ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය තීරණය කළේය.",
        "ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් රථ හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය පැවසුවේ අඟහරුවාදා (27) සිට සිය ඇණිය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම පිළිබඳව අවිනිශ්චිත බවයි.",
        "ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීමේ හැකියාව මත බස් රථ ධාවනය කරන බව ජාතික ගමනාගමන කොමිෂන් සභාව පවසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දුම්රිය සේවය පැවසුවේ දැනට පවතින කාලසටහනට අනුව සිය දුම්රිය ධාවනය කරන බවයි.",
        "කොළඹ කලාපයේ සියලුම පාසල්, බස්නාහිර පළාතේ තදාසන්න ප්‍රදේශවල පාසල් සහ අනෙකුත් පළාත්වල ප්‍රධාන නගරවල පාසල් ජූලි 10 වැනිදා දක්වා වසා තැබේ.",
        "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව සඳුදා (27) මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය සේවා සඳහා ඩීසල් සහ පෙට්‍රල් පමණක් නිකුත් කරයි.",
        "වරාය, ගුවන්තොටුපළ, සෞඛ්‍ය, ආහාර බෙදා හැරීම, කෘෂිකර්මාන්තය මෙම සේවාවන්ට ඇතුළත් බව අමාත්‍ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "BREAKING: මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ (27) සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වීමට අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සේවා පමණක්; තෙල් සංස්ථාව ඉන්ධන නිකුත් කරන්නේ අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය සේවා සඳහා පමණි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "28",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 10 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ගමනාගමන කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දුම්රිය සේවය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 10 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙට්රල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වරාය, ගුවන් තොටුපළ, සෞඛ්‍ය, ආහාර බෙදා හැරීම, කෘෂිකර්මය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (28) முதல் போக்குவரத்து சேவைகள் எவ்வாறு செயல்படும்?",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இன்று (27) நள்ளிரவு முதல் ஜூலை 10 ஆம் திகதி வரை அத்தியாவசிய சேவைகள் மாத்திரமே இயங்கும் என இலங்கை அமைச்சரவை தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (27) முதல் தனது வாகனங்களை இயக்குவது குறித்து உறுதியாக தெரியவில்லை என லங்கா தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "எரிபொருள் இருப்பின் அடிப்படையில் பேருந்துகளை இயக்கும் என தேசிய போக்குவரத்து ஆணைக்குழு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "தற்போதுள்ள நேர அட்டவணையின்படி தனது ரயில்களை இயக்குவதாக இலங்கை ரயில்வே தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "கொழும்பு பிராந்தியத்திலுள்ள அனைத்துப் பாடசாலைகளும், மேல் மாகாணத்தின் புறநகர்ப் பகுதிகளிலுள்ள பாடசாலைகளும், ஏனைய மாகாணங்களின் பிரதான நகரங்களிலுள்ள பாடசாலைகளும் ஜூலை 10 ஆம் திகதி வரை மூடப்படும்.",
        "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் திங்கட்கிழமை (27) நள்ளிரவு முதல் அத்தியாவசிய சேவைகளுக்காக டீசல் மற்றும் பெற்றோலை மாத்திரம் வழங்கவுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த சேவைகளில் துறைமுகங்கள், விமான நிலையங்கள், சுகாதாரம், உணவு விநியோகம், விவசாயம் உள்ளிட்டவை அடங்கும் என அமைச்சர் பந்துல குணவர்தன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "BREAKING: நள்ளிரவு (27) முதல் அத்தியாவசிய சேவைகள் மட்டும் செயல்படும்; அத்தியாவசிய சேவைகளுக்கு மட்டுமே CPC எரிபொருளை வழங்கும்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "செவ்வாய்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "28",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று நள்ளிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 10 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய போக்குவரத்து ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ரயில்வே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நள்ளிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துறைமுகங்கள், விமான நிலையங்கள், சுகாதாரம், உணவு விநியோகம், விவசாயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}