{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/10/cbsl-extends-amnesty-for-handing-over-dollars-above-limit/",
  "time_ut": 1657469280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "CBSL extends amnesty for handing over Dollars above limit",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CBSL extends amnesty for handing over Dollars above limit",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Minister of Finance has issued an Order under Section 8 of the Foreign Exchange Act No. 12 of 2017 extending the amnesty period to handover accumulated foreign currency over the limit of 10,000 USD.",
        "Accordingly, residents of Sri Lanka can deposit or sell the foreign currency in possession to an Authorized Dealer (A Licensed Commercial Bank or National Savings Bank) as specified in the Order, by another 14 working days up to 26th July.",
        "Previously, CBSL imposed an order reducing the amount of foreign currency retained in possession by a resident of Sri Lanka from USD 15,000 to USD 10,000 or its equivalent in other foreign currencies.",
        "Sri Lankans have right to peacefully raise their voices – Blinken"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dollars",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Order",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Section 8 of",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Authorized Dealer",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Savings Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Order",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "another 14 working days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD 15,000 to USD 10,000",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සීමාවට වඩා ඩොලර් භාරදීම සඳහා මහ බැංකුව පොදු සමා කාලයක් දීර්ඝ කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 2017 අංක 12 දරන විදේශ විනිමය පනතේ 8 වැනි වගන්තිය යටතේ ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් 10,000 සීමාවට වඩා සමුච්චිත විදේශ මුදල් භාරදීමේ සමා කාලය දීර්ඝ කරමින් මුදල් අමාත්‍යවරයා විසින් නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කර ඇත.",
        "ඒ අනුව, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පදිංචිකරුවන්ට ජුලි 26 දක්වා තවත් වැඩ කරන දින 14කින්, නියෝගයේ දක්වා ඇති පරිදි බලයලත් වෙළෙන්දෙකුට (බලපත්‍රලත් වාණිජ බැංකුවක් හෝ ජාතික ඉතිරිකිරීමේ බැංකුවක්) සන්තකයේ ඇති විදේශ මුදල් තැන්පත් කිරීමට හෝ විකිණීමට හැකිය.",
        "මීට පෙර, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පදිංචිකරුවෙකු සන්තකයේ තබාගෙන ඇති විදේශ මුදල් ප්‍රමාණය USD 15,000 සිට USD 10,000 දක්වා හෝ වෙනත් විදේශ මුදල් ඒකකවලට සමාන ලෙස අඩු කිරීමේ නියෝගයක් CBSL විසින් පනවන ලදී.",
        "සාමකාමීව හඬ නැගීමට ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ට අයිතියක් ඇත - Blinken"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩොලර්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නියෝග",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 වන වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලයලත් අලෙවි නියෝජිත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ඉතිරිකිරීමේ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නියෝග",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තවත් වැඩ කරන දින 14 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD 15,000 සිට USD 10,000 දක්වා",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வரம்பிற்கு மேல் டாலர்களை ஒப்படைப்பதற்காக CBSL பொது மன்னிப்பை நீட்டிக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 10,000 அமெரிக்க டாலர் வரம்பிற்கு மேல் குவிக்கப்பட்ட வெளிநாட்டு நாணயத்தை ஒப்படைப்பதற்கான பொது மன்னிப்பு காலத்தை நீட்டித்து 2017 ஆம் ஆண்டின் 12 ஆம் எண் அந்நியச் செலாவணிச் சட்டத்தின் பிரிவு 8 இன் கீழ் நிதியமைச்சர் உத்தரவு பிறப்பித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அதன்படி, இலங்கையில் வசிப்பவர்கள், ஜூலை 26 ஆம் தேதி வரை, மற்றொரு 14 வேலை நாட்களுக்குள், உத்தரவில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளபடி, அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்ட டீலருக்கு (உரிமம் பெற்ற வணிக வங்கி அல்லது தேசிய சேமிப்பு வங்கி) வசம் உள்ள வெளிநாட்டு நாணயத்தை டெபாசிட் செய்யலாம் அல்லது விற்கலாம்.",
        "முன்னதாக, CBSL இலங்கையில் வசிப்பவர் வசம் வைத்திருக்கும் வெளிநாட்டு நாணயத்தின் அளவை USD 15,000 இலிருந்து USD 10,000 ஆக அல்லது மற்ற வெளிநாட்டு நாணயங்களில் அதற்கு சமமானதாகக் குறைக்கும் உத்தரவை விதித்தது.",
        "அமைதியான முறையில் குரல் எழுப்ப இலங்கையர்களுக்கு உரிமை உண்டு – பிளிங்கன்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டாலர்கள்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிவு 8 இன்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க டாலர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்ட விற்பனையாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய சேமிப்பு வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேலும் 14 வேலை நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD 15,000 முதல் USD 10,000 வரை",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}