{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/පොහොට්ටුවේ-සහාය-වැඩබලන-ජනපති-රනිල්ට/11-395459",
  "time_ut": 1657892007,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පොහොට්ටුවේ සහාය වැඩබලන ජනපති රනිල්ට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Pohottuwa's support for Acting President Ranil",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "It has been decided to give the support of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna to Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe, who has been appointed as the Acting President, in the election of a Member of Parliament for the currently vacant position of President.",
        "This was decided in a discussion held by the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna group of MPs. Mr. Dallas Alahapperuma of the independent member group from the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna has also announced that he will contest for the presidency."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Pohottuwa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පොහොට්ටුවේ සහාය වැඩබලන ජනපති රනිල්ට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මේ වන විට හිස්ව ඇති ජනපතිධුරය සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙක් තෝරා පත්කර ගැනීම වෙනුවෙන් පවත්වන ඡන්ද විමසීමේදි ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සහාය වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති ලෙස පත්කර ඇති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට ලබාදිමට තිරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රී කණ්ඩායම පැවැත්වූ සාකච්ඡාවකදී මේ බව තීරණය කර තිබේ. ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සිට ස්වාධීන වූ මන්ත්‍රී කණ්ඩායමේ ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාද ජනාධිපතිධුරය සඳහා තරග කරන බවට ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පොහොට්ටුව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பொஹொட்டுவவின் ஆதரவு ஜனாதிபதி ரணிலுக்கு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தற்போது வெற்றிடமாக உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் தெரிவில், பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள திரு.ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் ஆதரவை வழங்க தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஶ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் குழு நடத்திய கலந்துரையாடலில் இது தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் சுயேச்சை உறுப்பினர் குழுவின் திரு.டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவும் ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் போட்டியிடவுள்ளதாக அறிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பொஹொட்டுவ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}