{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ඩීසල්-නැව-ජුලි-දෙවැනි-සතියේ---පෙට්‍රල්-නැව-ජුලි-අන්තිම-සතියේ/11-394958",
  "time_ut": 1656523268,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඩීසල් නැව ජුලි දෙවැනි සතියේ - පෙට්‍රල් නැව ජුලි අන්තිම සතියේ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Diesel ship in the second week of July - Petrol ship in the last week of July",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sagala Ratnayake, Chairman of the Committee appointed by Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe and Chief of Staff to the Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe has stated that a ship carrying diesel stocks is scheduled to return to Sri Lanka in the second week of July.",
        "Accordingly, 30,000 metric tons of diesel is scheduled to return to Sri Lanka between July 11-15, he said. He added that the return of the fuel consignment was due after July 22. Until then, there are no oil tankers ordered by Sri Lanka, he said.",
        "However, arrangements are being made to obtain fuel tankers to Sri Lanka before these dates, using the links with the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation, he said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Diesel",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "the second week of July - Petrol",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "the last week of",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "July",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sagala Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the second week of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 11-15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඩීසල් නැව ජුලි දෙවැනි සතියේ - පෙට්‍රල් නැව ජුලි අන්තිම සතියේ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඩීසල් තොග රැගත් නැවක් නැවත වරක් පැමිණීමට නියමිතව ඇත්තේ ජුලි මස දෙවැනි සතියේදි පමණ බව ඉන්ධන සම්බන්ධයෙන් සොයා බැලීම වෙනුවෙන් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පත්කළ කමිටුවේ සභාපති මෙන්ම අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්ය මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානි සාගල රත්නායක මහතා කියයි.",
        "මේ අනුව ඩීසල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 30000ක් රැගත් නැවත් ජුලි 11-15 අතර ලංකාවට පැමිණිමට නියමිතව ඇතැයි ඔහු පැවැසීය. පෙට්‍රල් තොග රැගත් නැවත පැමිනීමට ඇත්තේ ජුලි 22 වැනිදායින් අනතුරුව බවත් ඔහු පැවැසීය. එතෙක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඇණවුම් කළ තෙල් නැව් නොමැති බවද ඔහු පැවැසීය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීනිතග සංස්ථාවට ඇති සබඳතා උපයෝගී කරගනිමින් මෙම දිනවකවානුවලට කලින් ඉන්ධන නෞකා ලංකාවට ලබාගැනීමට කටයුතු සැලසුම් කරමින් පවතින බවත් ඔහු පැවැසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩීසල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූලි දෙවන සතිය - පෙට්රල්",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "අවසාන සතියේ",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජුලි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සාගල රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමිටුවක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි දෙවන සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 30,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 11-15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜூலை இரண்டாவது வாரத்தில் டீசல் கப்பல் - ஜூலை கடைசி வாரத்தில் பெட்ரோல் கப்பல்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜூலை இரண்டாம் வாரத்தில் டீசல் கையிருப்புகளை ஏற்றிச் செல்லும் கப்பல் இலங்கைக்கு திரும்பத் திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க மற்றும் பிரதமரின் பணிப்பாளர் பிரதானி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் நியமிக்கப்பட்ட குழுவின் தலைவர் சாகல ரத்நாயக்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதன்படி, ஜூலை 11-15 ஆம் திகதிகளுக்கு இடையில் 30,000 மெற்றிக் தொன் டீசல் இலங்கைக்கு திரும்புவதற்கு திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அவர் கூறினார். ஜூலை 22 ஆம் தேதிக்குப் பிறகு எரிபொருள் சரக்கு திரும்பப் பெறப்படும் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார். அதுவரை இலங்கையால் ஆர்டர் செய்யப்பட்ட எண்ணெய் கப்பல்கள் எதுவும் இல்லை என்றார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்துடனான தொடர்பைப் பயன்படுத்தி இந்த திகதிகளுக்கு முன்னர் எரிபொருள் தாங்கிகளை இலங்கைக்கு பெற்றுக் கொள்வதற்கான ஏற்பாடுகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டு வருவதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டீசல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை இரண்டாவது வாரம் - பெட்ரோல்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கடைசி வாரம்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சாகல ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை இரண்டாவது வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 11-15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}