{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Jacqueline-Fernandez-asks-the-authorities-to-release-her-assets-attached-by-the-ED/108-243738",
  "time_ut": 1661427431,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Jacqueline Fernandez asks the authorities to release her assets attached by the ED",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Jacqueline Fernandez asks the authorities to release her assets attached by the ED",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Actor Jacqueline Fernandez has said she was conned and manipulated by Sukesh Chandrasekhar and asked the authorities to release her assets attached by the Enforcement Directorate. The 36-year-old actor who was charged under the Prevention of Money Laundering Act said she could, at best, be accused of having received gifts from Sukesh Chandrasekhar.",
        "In April this year, ED ordered provisional attachment of her fixed deposits worth INR7.2 crore. Last week, ED also filed a charge sheet against the actor, accusing her of laundering proceeds of crime, the Hindustan Times reported.",
        "In her reply to a notice issued following the provisional attachment order before the appellate authority of PMLA in New Delhi, Jacqueline Fernandez said: “Just because she is (a) recipient of certain gifts which were forced on her for forming a connect, can’t be used to ignore the fact which the record otherwise clearly shows that she was conned by Sukesh Chandrasekhar. The approach of ED, unfortunately, seems to be highly mechanical and motivated, hence, blinded towards the fact that respondent (Jacqueline) has lost more than what can be measured in money”.",
        "HT has reviewed her response filed through lawyer Prashant Patil on August 22.",
        "Asserting that she was a victim of manipulation, for which the ED should take a humane approach, Jacqueline has said “what she has lost and suffered as a woman cannot be calculated in monetary terms”.",
        "About the FDs attached by ED, the actor said these were created through reinvestment of maturity proceeds of already existing FDs and “was her professionally earned income generated through blood and sweat and working in the industry for so long”.",
        "Jacqueline also accused ED of malafide. “What is surprising is that like the respondent (Jacqueline), some other celebrities, notably Norah Fatehi were also conned by Chandrasekhar and Fatehi and other such celebrities who received gifts from the accused, are made witnesses whereas she is sought to be dragged as an accused. This clearly shows a malafide, motivated and biased approach on the part of investigation authority which cannot be ignored,” the actor added.",
        "She said she was lured into forming a connection with Chandrasekhar, but never abetted his activities.",
        "To lure her, Jacqueline says, Chandrasekhar used Pinki Irani alias Angel (another accused) to connect with her and claimed himself to be the “nephew of Jayalalitha (former chief minister of Tamil Nadu) and owns Sun TV”.",
        "Claiming that Chandrasekhar insisted on showering her with gifts despite her repeated refusals, the Sri Lankan citizen, who moved to India to work in Bollywood, said “he would just go on rampage and if not accepted by the respondent, he would just instruct his men to leave the gifts with the watchmen or outside the gate”, adding that she never had an opportunity to check the source of these gifts.",
        "Pointing to ED’s charges against Chandrasekhar, who allegedly cheated the rich of INR200 crore by impersonating an influential person having political connections including in the Union home ministry, Jacqueline said: “the conduct of accepting gifts from a person who had impersonated himself makes her a victim and maximum a prosecution witness”.",
        "Chandrasekhar, currently lodged in Tihar prison, had given several expensive gifts including three designer bags from Gucci and Chanel; two Gucci outfits for gym wear, a pair of Louis Vuitton shoes, two pairs of diamond earrings and a bracelet of multi-coloured stones and two Hermes bracelets other than a Mini Cooper car to Fernandez, which she said she had returned.",
        "He was arrested by the Delhi Police in April 2017 in the Election Commission (EC) bribery case where it was alleged that he took money from AIADMK (Amma) leader T T V Dhinakaran to bribe EC officials in connection with a dispute over the AIADMK’s “two leaves” poll symbol.",
        "While at Tihar jail, he spoofed calls to dupe people by impersonating various senior government officers from different key departments of the Government of India.",
        "Adopting the spoof-calls modus operandi, he contacted Aditi Singh, wife of former Ranbaxy promoter Shivinder Mohan Singh, in 2020 posing as union home secretary, union law secretary, an officer from the Prime Minister’s Office (PMO), and extorted more than INR200 crore from her over a period of one year on the pretext of contribution to party funds."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ED",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Enforcement Directorate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "36-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Prevention of Money Laundering Act",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sukesh Chandrasekhar",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "April this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Hindustan Times",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sukesh Chandrasekhar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prashant Patil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Norah Fatehi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandrasekhar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fatehi",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chandrasekhar",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandrasekhar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pinki Irani",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Angel",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayalalitha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sun TV",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bollywood",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chandrasekhar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "INR200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Union",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gucci",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chanel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gucci",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Louis Vuitton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hermes",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mini Cooper",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fernandez",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Delhi Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "April 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Election Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIADMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "T T V Dhinakaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIADMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Government of India",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "modus operandi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aditi Singh",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mohan Singh",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than INR200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ED විසින් අනුයුක්ත කර ඇති ඇයගේ වත්කම් නිදහස් කරන ලෙස ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් බලධාරීන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රංගන ශිල්පිනී ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් පවසා ඇත්තේ සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර් විසින් තමාව හසුකරගෙන හසුරුවා ඇති බවත් බලාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය විසින් අනුයුක්ත කර ඇති ඇගේ වත්කම් නිදහස් කරන ලෙස බලධාරීන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටි බවත්ය. මුදල් විශුද්ධිකරණය වැලැක්වීමේ පනත යටතේ චෝදනා ලැබ සිටින 36 හැවිරිදි රංගන ශිල්පිනිය පැවසුවේ සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර්ගෙන් තෑගි ලැබුණු බවට ඇයට චෝදනා එල්ල විය හැකි බවයි.",
        "මෙම වසරේ අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී ED විසින් INR කෝටි 7.2 ක් වටිනා ඇයගේ ස්ථාවර තැන්පතු තාවකාලික ඇමුණුම් කිරීමට නියෝග කළේය. පසුගිය සතියේ, ED විසින් නළුවාට එරෙහිව චෝදනා පත්‍රයක් ද ගොනු කළ අතර, ඇය අපරාධවලින් ලැබෙන මුදල් විශුද්ධිකරණය කළ බවට චෝදනා කරමින්, හින්දුස්ථාන් ටයිම්ස් වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "නවදිල්ලියේ පීඑම්එල්ඒ හි අභියාචනා අධිකාරිය ඉදිරියේ තාවකාලික ඇමුණුම් නියෝගයෙන් පසුව නිකුත් කරන ලද දැන්වීමකට ඇයගේ පිළිතුරේ ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් මෙසේ පැවසුවාය: “ඇය (අ) සම්බන්ධතාවයක් ඇති කර ගැනීම සඳහා ඇයට බල කරන ලද සමහර තෑගි ලබන්නියක් වන නිසා, කළ හැකිය. සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර් විසින් ඇයව සම්බන්ධ කර ගත් බව වාර්තාවේ පැහැදිලිව පෙන්නුම් කරන කරුණ නොසලකා හැරීමට එය භාවිතා කළ යුතුය. ED හි ප්‍රවේශය, අවාසනාවකට මෙන්, ඉතා යාන්ත්‍රික සහ අභිප්‍රේරිත බව පෙනේ, එබැවින්, ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වූ (ජැකලින්) මුදලින් මැනිය හැකි ප්‍රමාණයට වඩා වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් අහිමි වී ඇති බවට අන්ධ විය.",
        "HT විසින් අගෝස්තු 22 වන දින නීතිඥ ප්‍රශාන්ත් පටිල් හරහා ගොනු කළ ඇයගේ ප්‍රතිචාරය සමාලෝචනය කර ඇත.",
        "ඇය හැසිරවීමේ ගොදුරක් වූ බවත්, ඒ සඳහා ED මානුෂීය ප්‍රවේශයක් ගත යුතු බවත් ප්‍රකාශ කරමින් ජැකලින් පවසා ඇත්තේ “කාන්තාවක් ලෙස ඇයට අහිමි වූ සහ දුක් වූ දේ මුදලින් ගණනය කළ නොහැකි” බවයි.",
        "ED විසින් අමුණා ඇති FD ගැන, නළුවා පැවසුවේ මේවා දැනටමත් පවතින FD වල පරිණත මුදල් නැවත ආයෝජනය කිරීම හරහා නිර්මාණය කර ඇති බවත්, “ලෙයින් සහ දහඩිය සහ මෙතරම් කාලයක් කර්මාන්තයේ වැඩ කරමින් ඇය වෘත්තීයමය වශයෙන් උපයාගත් ආදායම” බවයි.",
        "ජැකලින් ද ED malafide චෝදනා කළාය. \"පුදුමයට කරුණ නම්, වගඋත්තරකරු (ජැක්ලින්) මෙන්ම තවත් සමහර ප්‍රසිද්ධ පුද්ගලයින්, විශේෂයෙන් නෝරා ෆටේහි ද චන්ද්‍රසේකර් සහ ෆටේහි විසින් සම්බන්ධ කර ඇති අතර විත්තිකරුගෙන් තෑගි ලබාගත් වෙනත් ප්‍රසිද්ධ පුද්ගලයින් සාක්ෂිකරුවන් බවට පත් කර ඇති අතර ඇයව ඇදගෙන යාමට උත්සාහ කිරීම. චෝදනා කළා. මෙය පැහැදිලිවම පෙන්නුම් කරන්නේ විමර්ශන අධිකාරියේ පාර්ශවයෙන් නොසැලකිලිමත්, අභිප්‍රේරිත සහ පක්ෂග්‍රාහී ප්‍රවේශයක් නොසලකා හැරිය නොහැකි බවයි.",
        "චන්ද්‍රසේකර් සමඟ සම්බන්ධයක් ඇති කර ගැනීමට තමාව පොළඹවා ගත් නමුත් කිසි විටෙකත් ඔහුගේ ක්‍රියාකාරකම්වලට අනුබල නොදුන් බව ඇය පැවසුවාය.",
        "ඇයව පොළඹවා ගැනීම සඳහා, චන්ද්‍රසේකර් ඇය හා සම්බන්ධ වීමට පිංකි ඉරානි හෙවත් ඒන්ජල් (තවත් චූදිතයෙකු) යොදා ගත් බවත්, තමන් “ජයලලිතා (තමිල්නාඩුවේ හිටපු මහ ඇමතිනී) ගේ බෑණා බවත්, සන් ටීවී හිමිකරු බවත්” ප්‍රකාශ කළ බවත් ජැකලින් පවසයි.",
        "ඇය නැවත නැවතත් ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළත් චන්ද්‍රසේකර් ඇයට තෑගි බෝග දෙන ලෙස අවධාරනය කළ බව පවසමින්, බොලිවුඩයේ වැඩ කිරීමට ඉන්දියාවට ගිය ශ්‍රී ලාංකික පුරවැසියා පැවසුවේ “ඔහු කලබලයට පත්වන බවත් වගඋත්තරකරු විසින් පිළිගන්නේ නැත්නම්, ඔහු තම මිනිසුන්ට උපදෙස් දෙන බවත්ය. තෑගි මුරකරුවන් සමඟ හෝ ගේට්ටුවෙන් පිටත තැබීමට\", මෙම තෑගි වල මූලාශ්‍රය පරීක්ෂා කිරීමට ඇයට කිසි විටෙකත් අවස්ථාවක් නොලැබුණු බව පැවසුවාය.",
        "මධ්‍යම අභ්‍යන්තර කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය ඇතුළු දේශපාලන සම්බන්ධතා ඇති බලගතු පුද්ගලයෙකු ලෙස පෙනී සිටිමින් ඉන්දීය රුපියල් කෝටි 200ක ධනවතුන් වංචා කළ බව කියන චන්ද්‍රසේකර්ට එරෙහිව ED චෝදනා එල්ල කරමින් ජැකලින් මෙසේ පැවසුවාය: “තමන් ලෙස පෙනී සිටි පුද්ගලයෙකුගෙන් තෑගි පිළිගැනීමේ හැසිරීම ඇය ගොදුරක් බවට පත් කරයි. සහ උපරිම පැමිණිල්ලේ සාක්ෂිකරුවෙක්.",
        "දැනට තිහාර් බන්ධනාගාරයේ සිටින චන්ද්‍රසේකර්, Gucci සහ Chanel වෙතින් නිර්මාණ බෑග් තුනක් ඇතුළු මිල අධික තෑගි කිහිපයක් ලබා දී ඇත. Gym ඇඳුම් සඳහා Gucci ඇඳුම් දෙකක්, Louis Vuitton සපත්තු යුගලයක්, දියමන්ති කරාබු යුගල දෙකක් සහ බහු-වර්ණ ගල් වළලු දෙකක් සහ මිනි කූපර් මෝටර් රථයක් හැර වෙනත් Hermes බ්රේස්ලට් දෙකක් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් වෙත, ඇය ආපසු පැමිණි බව ඇය පැවසුවාය.",
        "ඔහු 2017 අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී දිල්ලි පොලිසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගනු ලැබුවේ මැතිවරණ කොමිසමේ (EC) අල්ලස් නඩුවේදී ඔහු ඒඩීඑම්කේ (අම්මා) නායක ටී ටී වී දිනකරන්ගෙන් මුදල් ලබාගෙන EC නිලධාරීන්ට අල්ලස් ලබා දුන් බවට චෝදනා කරමින් ඒඒඒඩීඑම්කේ “කොළ දෙක පිළිබඳ ආරවුලක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ය. ” ඡන්ද ලකුණ.",
        "තිහාර් බන්ධනාගාරයේ සිටියදී, ඔහු ඉන්දීය රජයේ විවිධ ප්‍රධාන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවල විවිධ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ රජයේ නිලධාරීන් ලෙස පෙනී සිටිමින් පුද්ගලයන් රැවටීමට ඇමතුම් වංචා කළේය.",
        "වංචා-ඇමතුම් ක්‍රියා පටිපාටිය අනුගමනය කරමින්, ඔහු 2020 දී වෘත්තීය සමිති ස්වදේශ ලේකම්, වෘත්තීය සමිති නීති ලේකම්, අගමැති කාර්යාලයේ (PMO) නිලධාරියෙකු ලෙස පෙනී සිටිමින් හිටපු Ranbaxy ප්‍රවර්ධකයෙකු වන Shivinder Mohan Singh ගේ බිරිඳ Aditi Singh අමතා INR200 කට වඩා කප්පම් ලබා ගත්තේය. පක්ෂ අරමුදල්වලට දායක වීමේ මුවාවෙන් වසරක කාලයක් තුළ ඇයගෙන් කෝටියක්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ED",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්රියාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "36 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් විශුද්ධිකරණය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර්",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දුස්ථාන් ටයිම්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රශාන්ත් පටිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෝරා ෆතේහි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රසේකර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆතේහි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රසේකර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රසේකර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිංකි ඉරානි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දේවදූතයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයලලිතා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිරු රූපවාහිනිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොලිවුඩ්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රසේකර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "INR200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gucci",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චැනල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gucci",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලුවී වුටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්මීස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිනි කූපර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිල්ලි පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017 අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැතිවරණ කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ.අයි.ඒ.ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්මා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටී ටී වී දිනකරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ.අයි.ඒ.ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ක්‍රියා පටිපාටිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අදිති සිං",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොහාන් සිං",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "INR200 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ், அமலாக்கத்துறையால் இணைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள தனது சொத்துக்களை விடுவிக்குமாறு அதிகாரிகளை கேட்டுக் கொண்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நடிகை ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ், தான் சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகரால் சூழ்ச்சி செய்யப்பட்டு சூழ்ச்சி செய்யப்பட்டதாகவும், அமலாக்க இயக்குனரகத்தால் பறிமுதல் செய்யப்பட்ட தனது சொத்துக்களை விடுவிக்குமாறு அதிகாரிகளை கேட்டுக் கொண்டதாகவும் கூறியுள்ளார். பணமோசடி தடுப்புச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்ட 36 வயதான நடிகர், சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகரிடமிருந்து பரிசு பெற்றதாகக் குற்றம் சாட்டப்படலாம் என்றார்.",
        "இந்த ஆண்டு ஏப்ரலில், அவரது 7.2 கோடி ரூபாய் மதிப்புள்ள நிலையான வைப்புகளை தற்காலிகமாக இணைக்க ED உத்தரவிட்டது. கடந்த வாரம், ED, நடிகருக்கு எதிராக குற்றப்பத்திரிகையை தாக்கல் செய்தது, அவர் குற்றத்தின் வருமானத்தை சலவை செய்ததாக குற்றம் சாட்டினார், இந்துஸ்தான் டைம்ஸ் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "புது தில்லியில் உள்ள PMLA இன் மேல்முறையீட்டு ஆணையத்தின் முன் தற்காலிக இணைப்பு உத்தரவைத் தொடர்ந்து வெளியிடப்பட்ட நோட்டீஸுக்கு ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ் அளித்த பதிலில், “அவர் (அ) ஒரு இணைப்பை உருவாக்குவதற்காக கட்டாயப்படுத்தப்பட்ட சில பரிசுகளைப் பெற்றவர் என்பதால், முடியாது. சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகரால் அவள் சம்மந்தப்பட்டாள் என்பதை பதிவு தெளிவாகக் காட்டும் உண்மையைப் புறக்கணிக்கப் பயன்படுகிறது. ED இன் அணுகுமுறை, துரதிர்ஷ்டவசமாக, மிகவும் இயந்திரத்தனமாகவும் உந்துதலுடனும் இருப்பதாகத் தெரிகிறது, எனவே, பதிலளிப்பவர் (ஜாக்குலின்) பணத்தில் அளவிடக்கூடியதை விட அதிகமாக இழந்துள்ளார் என்ற உண்மையைப் பற்றி கண்மூடித்தனமாக இருக்கிறது.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 22 அன்று வழக்கறிஞர் பிரசாந்த் பாட்டீல் மூலம் தாக்கல் செய்த பதிலை HT மதிப்பாய்வு செய்துள்ளது.",
        "தான் கையாளுதலுக்கு பலியாகிவிட்டதாகவும், அதற்காக ED மனிதாபிமான அணுகுமுறையை எடுக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் கூறிய ஜாக்குலின், \"ஒரு பெண்ணாக அவர் இழந்ததையும், கஷ்டப்பட்டதையும் பண அடிப்படையில் கணக்கிட முடியாது\" என்று கூறியுள்ளார்.",
        "ED ஆல் இணைக்கப்பட்ட FDகளைப் பற்றி, ஏற்கனவே இருக்கும் FDகளின் முதிர்வுத் தொகையை மீண்டும் முதலீடு செய்வதன் மூலம் இவை உருவாக்கப்பட்டதாகவும், \"இத்தனை காலம் இரத்தம் மற்றும் வியர்வை மற்றும் தொழிலில் பணியாற்றியதன் மூலம் அவர் தொழில் ரீதியாக சம்பாதித்த வருமானம்\" என்றும் நடிகர் கூறினார்.",
        "ஜாக்குலின் ED தவறான செயல் என்று குற்றம் சாட்டினார். \"ஆச்சரியம் என்னவென்றால், பிரதிவாதி (ஜாக்குலின்) போலவே வேறு சில பிரபலங்களும், குறிப்பாக நோரா ஃபதேஹியும் சந்திரசேகர் மற்றும் ஃபதேஹி மற்றும் குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்டவர்களிடமிருந்து பரிசுகளைப் பெற்ற பிற பிரபலங்களால் தூண்டப்பட்டனர், அதே நேரத்தில் அவரை இழுத்துச் செல்ல முயற்சிக்கிறார்கள். குற்றம் சாட்டினார். இது புலனாய்வு அதிகாரத்தின் ஒரு தவறான, உந்துதல் மற்றும் பக்கச்சார்பான அணுகுமுறையை தெளிவாகக் காட்டுகிறது, அதை புறக்கணிக்க முடியாது, ”என்று நடிகர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "சந்திரசேகருடன் தொடர்பை ஏற்படுத்திக் கொள்வதற்காக தான் ஈர்க்கப்பட்டதாகவும், ஆனால் அவனது நடவடிக்கைகளுக்கு உறுதுணையாக இருந்ததில்லை என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "அவரைக் கவர்ந்திழுக்க, சந்திரசேகர், பிங்கி இரானி என்கிற ஏஞ்சலை (மற்றொரு குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்டவர்) பயன்படுத்தி, தன்னுடன் தொடர்பு கொள்ள பயன்படுத்தினார், மேலும் தன்னை \"ஜெயலலிதாவின் (தமிழகத்தின் முன்னாள் முதல்வர்) மருமகன் என்றும், சன் டிவிக்கு சொந்தக்காரர்\" என்றும் ஜாக்குலின் கூறுகிறார்.",
        "சந்திரசேகர் பலமுறை மறுத்த போதிலும் தனக்கு பரிசுகளை வழங்குமாறு வற்புறுத்தியதாகக் கூறி, பாலிவுட்டில் பணியாற்றுவதற்காக இந்தியாவுக்குச் சென்ற இலங்கைப் பிரஜை, “அவர் வெறுமென வெறித்தனமாக நடந்து கொள்வார், பதிலளித்தவர் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளாவிட்டால், அவர் தனது ஆட்களுக்கு அறிவுறுத்துவார். பரிசுகளை வாட்ச்மேன்களிடம் அல்லது வாயிலுக்கு வெளியே விட்டுவிட வேண்டும்”, இந்த பரிசுகளின் மூலத்தை சரிபார்க்க தனக்கு ஒருபோதும் வாய்ப்பு கிடைக்கவில்லை என்று கூறினார்.",
        "மத்திய உள்துறை உள்ளிட்ட அரசியல் தொடர்புகளைக் கொண்ட செல்வாக்கு மிக்க நபராக ஆள்மாறாட்டம் செய்து 200 கோடி பணக்காரர்களை ஏமாற்றியதாகக் கூறப்படும் சந்திரசேகர் மீதான ED குற்றச்சாட்டை சுட்டிக்காட்டிய ஜாக்குலின், “தன்னை ஆள்மாறாட்டம் செய்த ஒருவரிடமிருந்து பரிசுகளைப் பெறும் நடத்தை தன்னைப் பலியாக்குகிறது. மற்றும் அதிகபட்சம் ஒரு வழக்கு சாட்சி”.",
        "தற்போது திகார் சிறையில் அடைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள சந்திரசேகர், குஸ்ஸி மற்றும் சேனலின் மூன்று டிசைனர் பைகள் உட்பட பல விலையுயர்ந்த பரிசுகளை வழங்கியுள்ளார்; உடற்பயிற்சி அணிவதற்கு இரண்டு குஸ்ஸி ஆடைகள், ஒரு ஜோடி லூயிஸ் உய்ட்டன் காலணிகள், இரண்டு ஜோடி வைரக் காதணிகள் மற்றும் பல வண்ணக் கற்கள் கொண்ட ஒரு வளையல் மற்றும் ஒரு மினி கூப்பர் காரைத் தவிர மற்ற இரண்டு ஹெர்ம்ஸ் வளையல்கள் பெர்னாண்டஸுக்கு, அவள் திரும்பி வந்ததாகச் சொன்னாள்.",
        "அ.தி.மு.க.வின் “இரண்டு இலை விவகாரம் தொடர்பாக தேர்தல் ஆணைய அதிகாரிகளுக்கு லஞ்சம் கொடுக்க அதிமுக (அம்மா) தலைவர் டி.டி.வி.தினகரனிடம் பணம் பெற்றதாகக் கூறப்பட்ட தேர்தல் கமிஷன் (இசி) லஞ்ச வழக்கில் அவர் ஏப்ரல் 2017 இல் டெல்லி போலீசாரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டார். ” வாக்கெடுப்பு சின்னம்.",
        "திகார் சிறையில் இருந்தபோது, ​​இந்திய அரசாங்கத்தின் பல்வேறு முக்கிய துறைகளைச் சேர்ந்த பல்வேறு மூத்த அரசு அதிகாரிகளைப் போல ஆள்மாறாட்டம் செய்து மக்களை ஏமாற்றுவதற்காக அழைப்புகளை ஏமாற்றினார்.",
        "ஸ்பூஃப்-அழைப்பு நடைமுறையை ஏற்று, அவர் 2020 இல் முன்னாள் ரான்பாக்ஸி விளம்பரதாரர் ஷிவிந்தர் மோகன் சிங்கின் மனைவி அதிதி சிங்கைத் தொடர்பு கொண்டு, யூனியன் உள்துறைச் செயலர், யூனியன் சட்டச் செயலர், பிரதமர் அலுவலக அதிகாரி (PMO) போன்றவற்றைக் காட்டி INR200க்கு மேல் பணம் பறித்தார். கட்சி நிதிக்கு பங்களிப்பதாக கூறி ஓராண்டில் அவரிடமிருந்து கோடி"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ED",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமலாக்க இயக்குநரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "36 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பணமோசடி தடுப்புச் சட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகர்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்துஸ்தான் டைம்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரசாந்த் பாட்டீல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நோரா ஃபதேஹி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்திரசேகர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபதேஹி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சந்திரசேகர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்திரசேகர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிங்கி இரானி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேவதை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயலலிதா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சன் டி.வி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாலிவுட்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சந்திரசேகர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய ரூபாய் 200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குஸ்ஸி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சேனல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குஸ்ஸி",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "லூயிஸ் உய்ட்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹெர்ம்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மினி கூப்பர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டெல்லி போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேர்தல் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதிமுக",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்மா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிடிவி தினகரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதிமுக",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செயல் முறை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதிதி சிங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மோகன் சிங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 ரூபாய்க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}