{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ශ්‍රීලනිප-ව්‍යවස්ථා-සංශෝධනයට:-තහනමක්-නිකුත්-කරන්නැයි-කළ-ඉල්ලීම-ඉවතට/101-619210",
  "time_ut": 1662123613,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ශ්‍රීලනිප ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනයට: තහනමක් නිකුත් කරන්නැයි කළ ඉල්ලීම ඉවතට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lankan Constitution Amendment: The request to issue a ban is dismissed",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Colombo District Judge Purnima Paranagama today (02) refused to issue an interim injunction to prevent the adoption of constitutional amendments proposed to be made in relation to the party's chairmanship at the All-Ceylon Committee meeting of the Sri Lanka Freedom Party.",
        "After considering the facts related to a petition submitted by Sri Lanka Freedom Party executive member Mr. Montague Sarachchandra, requesting to prevent the adoption of the proposed constitutional amendments related to the position of the party's chairman in the forthcoming meeting of the party's All-Ceylon Committee, the District Judge refused to issue an interim restraining order. .",
        "The Sri Lanka Freedom Party and its officials have been named as respondents in this petition presented by the executive member of the Sri Lanka Freedom Party Mr. Montague Sarachchandra.",
        "Advocate Mr. Shantha Jayawardena, who appeared for the petitioner Mr. Montagu Sarachchandra, presented the facts and informed that there are preparations to add several amendments to the party constitution in relation to the chairmanship of the Sri Lanka Freedom Party in the upcoming meeting of the All Sri Lanka Committee of the party.",
        "Also, Mr. Shantha Jayawardena, the lawyer, informed that several more amendments are to be added to the current chairman Mr. Maithripala Sirisena to \"legitimize\" his work in that position and pointed out that the amendments to be made are totally against the party's constitution.",
        "Therefore, Mr. Shanta Jayawardena, a lawyer, also requested the court to issue an order to prevent the addition of several amendments to the party constitution in the forthcoming meeting of the All Ceylon Committee.",
        "At that time, Mr. Faizer Mustafa, the President's Attorney who appeared for the Chairman of the Sri Lanka Freedom Party, Mr. Maithripala Sirisena, stood for the respondents and strongly objected to the request of the petitioners.",
        "The President's Attorney Mr. Faizer Mustafa pointed out that the court does not have the authority to consider such a request submitted to the court regarding a party's matter and asked to reject this petition at the first instance.",
        "After considering the facts of both parties, the judge refused to issue the interim order and ordered the petition to be called again on the 5th."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Purnima Paranagama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the All-Ceylon Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Montague Sarachchandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "All-Ceylon Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Montague Sarachchandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shantha Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Montagu Sarachchandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the All Sri Lanka Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shantha Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shanta Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the All Ceylon Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Faizer Mustafa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Faizer Mustafa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රීලනිප ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනයට: තහනමක් නිකුත් කරන්නැයි කළ ඉල්ලීම ඉවතට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ සමස්ත ලංකා කාරක සභා රැස්වීමේදී පක්ෂයේ සභාපති ධුරයට අදාළව සිදු කිරීමට යෝජිත ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධන සම්මත කිරීම වැළැක්වීමේ අතුරු තහනම් නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කිරීම කොළඹ දිසා විනිසුරු පූර්ණිමා පරණගම මහත්මිය අද (02) ප්‍රතික්‍ෂේප කළාය.",
        "ඉදිරියේදී පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත පක්ෂයේ සමස්ත ලංකා කාරක සභා රැස්වීමේදී පක්ෂයේ සභාපති ධුරයට අදාළව සිදු කිරීමට යෝජිත ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධන සම්මත කිරීම වැළැක්වන්නැයි ඉල්ලමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ විධායක සභික මොන්ටේගු සරච්චන්ද්‍ර මහතා විසින් ඉදිරිපත් කළ පෙත්සමකට අදාළ කරුණු සළකා බැලීමෙන් අනතුරුව දිසා විනිසුරුවරිය අදාළ අතුරු තහනම් නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කිරීම ප්‍රතික්‍ෂෙප කළාය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ විධායක සභික මොන්ටේගු සරච්චන්ද්‍ර මහතා ඉදිරිපත් කළ මෙම පෙත්සමේ වගඋත්තරකරුවන් වශයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය සහ එහි නිලධාරීන් නම් කොට ඇත.",
        "පෙත්සම්කාර මොන්ටේගු සරච්චන්ද්‍ර මහතා වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි නීතිඥ ශාන්ත ජයවර්ධන මහතා කරුණු ඉදිරිපත් කරමින් ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ සභාපති ධුරයට අදාළව පක්ෂ ව්‍යවස්ථාවට සංශෝධන කීපයක් එක් කිරීමට ඉදිරියේදී පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත පක්ෂයේ සමස්ත ලංකා කාරක සභා රැස්වීමේදී සූදානමක් ඇතැයි දැනුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "එමෙන්ම වත්මන් සභාපති මෛත්‍රිපාල සිරිසේන මහතා එම ධුරයේ කටයුතු කිරීම ”සුජාත කිරීම” සඳහා තවත් සංශෝධන කීපයක් එහි එක් කිරීමට නියමිත යැයි දැනුම් දුන් නීතිඥ ශාන්ත ජයවර්ධන මහතා සිදු කිරීමට නියමිත එම සංශෝධන පක්ෂයේ ව්‍යවස්ථාවට මුළුමනින්ම පටහැනි යැයි ද පෙන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "එහෙයින් ඉදිරියේදී පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත සමස්ත ලංකා කාරක සභා රැස්වීමේදී පක්ෂ ව්‍යවස්ථාවට සංශෝධන කීපයක් එක් කිරීම වැළැක්වීමේ නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කරන්නැයි නීතිඥ ශාන්ත ජයවර්ධන මහතා අධිකරණයෙන් ඉල්ලීමක්ද කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ සභාපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ ෆයිසර් මුස්තාෆා මහතා ඒ අවස්ථාවේදී වගඋත්තරකරුවන් වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටිමින් පෙත්සම්කරුවන්ගේ ඉල්ලීමට තරයේ විරෝධය පළකර සිටියේය.",
        "පක්‍ෂයක කරුණක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කොට ඇති මෙවැනි ඉල්ලීමක් සලකා බැලීමට අධිකරණයට බලයක් නොමැති බව පෙන්වා දුන් ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ ෆයිසර් මුස්තාෆා මහතා මුල් අවස්ථාවේදීම මෙම පෙත්සම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන්නැයි ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "දෙපාර්ශවයේ කරුණු සලකා බැලීමෙන් අනතුරුව අතුරු තහනම් නියෝගය නිකුත් කිරීම ප්‍රතික්‍ෂෙප කළ විනිසුරුවරිය මෙම පෙත්සම ලබන 05 වනදා යළි කැඳවීමට නියම කළාය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පූර්ණිමා පරණගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමස්ත ලංකා කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොන්ටේග් සරච්චන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමස්ත ලංකා කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොන්ටේග් සරච්චන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශාන්ත ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොන්ටේගු සරච්චන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමස්ත ශ්‍රී ලංකා කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශාන්ත ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශාන්තා ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමස්ත ලංකා කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆයිසර් මුස්තාෆා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆයිසර් මුස්තාෆා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தம்: தடை உத்தரவு பிறப்பிக்க கோரிக்கை நிராகரிக்கப்படுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் அகில இலங்கைக் குழுக் கூட்டத்தில் கட்சியின் தலைவர் பதவி தொடர்பில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட உத்தேசிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள அரசியலமைப்புத் திருத்தங்களை நிறைவேற்றுவதைத் தடுக்கும் வகையில் இடைக்காலத் தடையுத்தரவு பிறப்பிக்க கொழும்பு மாவட்ட நீதிபதி பூர்ணிமா பரணகம இன்று (02) மறுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் செயற்குழு உறுப்பினர் திரு.மொன்டேக் சரச்சந்திரவினால் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள மனு தொடர்பான உண்மைகளை பரிசீலித்து, கட்சியின் அகில இலங்கைக் குழுக் கூட்டத்தில் கட்சியின் தலைவர் பதவி தொடர்பான உத்தேச அரசியலமைப்புத் திருத்தங்களை நிறைவேற்றுவதைத் தடுக்குமாறு கோரி , மாவட்ட நீதிபதி இடைக்கால தடை உத்தரவு பிறப்பிக்க மறுத்துவிட்டார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் செயற்குழு உறுப்பினர் திரு.மான்டேக் சரச்சந்திரவினால் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட இந்த மனுவில் பிரதிவாதிகளாக ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி மற்றும் அதன் அதிகாரிகள் பெயரிடப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "மனுதாரர் திரு மொன்டேகு சரச்சந்திர சார்பில் ஆஜரான சட்டத்தரணி சாந்த ஜயவர்தன உண்மைகளை முன்வைத்து, எதிர்வரும் கூட்டத்தொடரில் ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் தலைவர் பதவி தொடர்பில் கட்சியின் அரசியலமைப்பில் பல திருத்தங்களைச் செய்வதற்கு ஆயத்தங்கள் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டு வருவதாகத் தெரிவித்தார். கட்சியின் அகில இலங்கை குழு.",
        "அத்துடன், தற்போதைய தலைவர் திரு மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேனவின் பணியை சட்டப்பூர்வமாக்குவதற்கு மேலும் பல திருத்தங்கள் சேர்க்கப்பட உள்ளதாக தெரிவித்த சட்டத்தரணி திரு.சாந்த ஜயவர்தன, மேற்கொள்ளப்படவுள்ள திருத்தங்கள் கட்சிக்கு முற்றிலும் எதிரானது எனவும் சுட்டிக்காட்டினார். அரசியலமைப்பு.",
        "எனவே எதிர்வரும் அகில இலங்கைக் குழுக் கூட்டத்தில் கட்சி அமைப்பில் பல திருத்தங்களைச் சேர்ப்பதைத் தடுக்கும் உத்தரவை பிறப்பிக்குமாறும் சட்டத்தரணி சாந்த ஜயவர்தன நீதிமன்றத்திடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்தார்.",
        "அப்போது, ​​ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் தலைவர் மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன சார்பில் ஆஜரான ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி பைசர் முஸ்தபா, பிரதிவாதிகள் சார்பில் ஆஜராகி மனுதாரர்களின் கோரிக்கைக்கு கடும் எதிர்ப்புத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஒரு தரப்பு விடயம் தொடர்பில் நீதிமன்றில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்ட இவ்வாறான கோரிக்கையை பரிசீலிக்க நீதிமன்றத்திற்கு அதிகாரம் இல்லை என சுட்டிக்காட்டிய ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி திரு.பைசர் முஸ்தபா, இந்த மனுவை முதலில் நிராகரிக்குமாறு கேட்டுக் கொண்டார்.",
        "இருதரப்பு உண்மைகளையும் பரிசீலித்த நீதிபதி, இடைக்கால உத்தரவை பிறப்பிக்க மறுத்து மனுவை வரும் 5ம் தேதி மீண்டும் விசாரிக்க உத்தரவிட்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பூர்ணிமா பரணகம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அகில இலங்கை குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாண்டேக் சரச்சந்திரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அகில இலங்கை குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாண்டேக் சரச்சந்திரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாந்த ஜயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாண்டேகு சரச்சந்திரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அகில இலங்கை குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாந்த ஜயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாந்தா ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அகில இலங்கை குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பைசர் முஸ்தபா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பைசர் முஸ்தபா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}