{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/‘‘22-ජනතා-පරමාධිපත්‍යයට-හානියක්‘‘/101-618557",
  "time_ut": 1661169067,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "‘‘22 ජනතා පරමාධිපත්‍යයට හානියක්‘‘",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "\"22 Damage to People's Sovereignty\"",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President's Counsel Mr. Manoharada Silva told the Supreme Court today (22) that the 22nd Constitutional Amendment Bill will curtail the powers of the Executive President and thereby harm the sovereignty of the people.",
        "09 petitions filed before the Supreme Court by nine persons including Dr. Gunadasa Amarasekara, stating that certain clauses of the 22nd Constitution Amendment Bill are contrary to the Constitution, requesting to issue an order to pass it by a special number of members and a referendum, were heard before the Supreme Court today (22). These facts were presented at the time.",
        "President's lawyer Manohara de Silva, who appeared before the Supreme Court on behalf of one of the petitioners, Colonel Sumeda Amarasinghe, said so.",
        "These petitions were taken into consideration today (22) before a Supreme Court bench consisting of Chief Justice Jayantha Jayasuriya, Mr. Buwaneka Aluvihare and Mr. Arjuna Obeysekera.",
        "Dr. Gunadasa Amarasekara, Colonel Sumeda Amarasinghe, General Secretary of the Praideh Peramuna Lawyer Nagananda Kodithuvakku, Lawyer Nuvan Bellantudawe and Sabaragamu University Senior Lecturer H. S. Nine people including Mr. Kumar have filed these petitions before the Supreme Court and the Attorney General has been named as the respondent."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Counsel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manoharada Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitutional Amendment Bill",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunadasa Amarasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution Amendment Bill",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Manohara de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sumeda Amarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayantha Jayasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buwaneka Aluvihare",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arjuna Obeysekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gunadasa Amarasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sumeda Amarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Praideh Peramuna Lawyer",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nagananda Kodithuvakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuvan Bellantudawe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘‘22 ජනතා පරමාධිපත්‍යයට හානියක්‘‘",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "22 වන ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධන පනත් කෙටුම්පත මගින් විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ බලතල කප්පාදු වන බවත් එමගින් ජනතාවගේ පරමාධිපත්‍යයට හානියක් වන බවත් ජනාධිපති නිතීඥ මනෝහරද සිල්වා මහතා ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය හමුවේ අද (22) පැවසීය.",
        "22 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධන පනත් කෙටුම්පතේ ඇතැම් වගන්ති ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවට පටහැනි බව සඳහන් කරමින් එය විශේෂ මන්ත්‍රී සංඛ්‍යාවකගේ සහ ජනමත විචාරයකින් සම්මත කර ගැනීමේ නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කරන්නැයි ඉල්ලා වෛද්‍ය ගුණදාස අමරසේකර මහතා ඇතුළු නවදෙනකු ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය හමුවේ ගොනු කර ඇති පෙත්සම් 09 ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය හමුවේ අද (22) විභාගයට ගත් අවස්ථාවේදී මෙම කරුණු ඉදිරිපත් විණි.",
        "එහිදී මෙහි පෙත්සම්කාර පාර්ශ්වයක් වන කර්නල් සුමේද අමරසිංහ මහතා වෙනුවෙන් ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය හමුවේ පෙනී සිටි ජනාධිපති නිතීඥ මනෝහර ද සිල්වා මහතා එසේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "අගවිනිසුරු ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය, බුවනෙක අලුවිහාරේ සහ අර්ජුන ඔබේසේකර යන මහත්වරුනගෙන් සමන්විත ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ විනිසුරු මඩුල්ලක් හමුවේ මෙම පෙත්සම් අද (22) සැලකිල්ලට ගැණීනි.",
        "වෛද්‍ය ගුණදාස අමරසේකර, කර්නල් සුමේද අමරසිංහ, විනිවිද පෙරමුණේ මහ ලේකම් නීතීඥ නාගානන්ද කොඩිතුවක්කු, නීතීඥ නුවන් බෙල්ලන්තුඩාවේ සහ සබරගමු විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ කථිකාචාර්ය එච්. එස්. කුමාර යන මහත්වරුන් ඇතුලු නව දෙනකු මෙම පෙත්සම් ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය හමුවේ ගොනු කරනු ලැබ ඇති අතර මෙහි වගඋත්තරකරු ලෙස නම්කර ඇත්තේ නීතිපතිවරයාය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "උපදේශක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනෝහරද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධන පනත් කෙටුම්පත",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunadasa Amarasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධන පනත් කෙටුම්පත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මනෝහර ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුමේද අමරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුවනෙක අලුවිහාරේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අර්ජුන ඔබේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gunadasa Amarasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුමේද අමරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රයිඩ් පෙරමුණේ නීතීඥ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාගානන්ද කොඩිතුවක්කු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුවන් බෙල්ලන්තුඩාවේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"22 மக்கள் இறையாண்மைக்கு கேடு\"",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "22ஆவது அரசியலமைப்புத் திருத்தச் சட்டமூலம் நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியின் அதிகாரங்களைக் குறைத்து அதன் மூலம் மக்களின் இறையாண்மைக்கு பாதிப்பை ஏற்படுத்தும் என ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி திரு மனோஹரத சில்வா இன்று (22) உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "22ஆவது அரசியலமைப்புத் திருத்தச் சட்டமூலத்தின் சில சரத்துக்கள் அரசியலமைப்புக்கு முரணானவை எனக்கூறி, அதனை விசேட அங்கத்தவர்கள் மற்றும் வாக்கெடுப்பு மூலம் நிறைவேற்ற உத்தரவிடுமாறு கோரி கலாநிதி குணதாச அமரசேகர உள்ளிட்ட ஒன்பது பேரால் உச்ச நீதிமன்றில் 09 மனுக்கள் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளன. இன்று (22) உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தில் விசாரணைக்கு வந்தது.அப்போது இந்த உண்மைகள் முன்வைக்கப்பட்டன.",
        "மனுதாரர்களில் ஒருவரான கேணல் சுமேத அமரசிங்க சார்பில் உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தில் ஆஜரான ஜனாதிபதியின் சட்டத்தரணி மனோகர டி சில்வா இதனைத் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இந்த மனுக்கள் இன்று (22) பிரதம நீதியரசர் ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய, புவனேக அலுவிஹாரே மற்றும் அர்ஜுன ஒபேசேகர ஆகியோர் அடங்கிய உச்ச நீதிமன்ற அமர்வு முன்னிலையில் பரிசீலனைக்கு எடுத்துக்கொள்ளப்பட்டது.",
        "கலாநிதி குணதாச அமரசேகர, கேணல் சுமேத அமரசிங்க, பிறைதே பெரமுனவின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் சட்டத்தரணி நாகாநந்த கொடித்துவக்கு, சட்டத்தரணி நுவன் பெல்லந்துடாவே, சப்ரகமு பல்கலைக்கழக சிரேஷ்ட விரிவுரையாளர் எச். எஸ். திரு.குமார் உட்பட ஒன்பது பேர் இந்த மனுக்களை உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தில் தாக்கல் செய்துள்ள நிலையில், சட்டமா அதிபர் பிரதிவாதியாக குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆலோசகர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனோஹரத சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்த மசோதா",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunadasa Amarasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்த மசோதா",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மனோகர டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமேத அமரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புவனேக அலுவிஹாரே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அர்ஜுன ஒபேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gunadasa Amarasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமேத அமரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரைதே பெரமுன சட்டத்தரணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாகானந்த கொடித்துவக்கு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுவன் பெல்லந்துடாவே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}