{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/31/navy-puts-35-teams-on-standby-for-flood-rescue/",
  "time_ut": 1661946720,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Navy puts 35 Teams on standby for flood rescue",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Navy puts 35 Teams on standby for flood rescue",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka Navy said it has placed 35 Navy Relief Teams on standby on Wednesday (31) to provide immediate relief to the people who may be affected by floods and landslides, in the event of a disaster situation as rains continue to pour down on many areas.",
        "On the instructions of Navy Commander Vice Admiral Nishantha Ulugetenne, the Western Naval Command has placed 26 Navy Relief Teams on standby for the Kalutara, Ratnapura, and Colombo districts.",
        "The Southern Naval Command has placed 9 Navy Relief Teams on standby for the Galle, Tangalle, and Hambantota Districts.",
        "In the backdrop of inclement weather prevailing in the island, the Navy has kept additional relief teams on standby to reach out to the groups vulnerable to the impact of flood, as needed.",
        "One-month-old infant abandoned at a motor garage with a letter",
        "Are you a victim of Cyber Crime? Police Unit ready to crackdown crime in the cyberspace"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "35",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nishantha Ulugetenne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Western Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalutara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Southern Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tangalle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One-month-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cyber Crime",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගංවතුර ගැලවීම සඳහා නාවික හමුදාව කණ්ඩායම් 35ක් සූදානම් කර ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ප්‍රදේශ රැසකට වර්ෂාව දිගටම ඇද හැලෙන බැවින් ආපදා තත්ත්වයකදී ගංවතුර සහ නායයෑම්වලින් විපතට පත් විය හැකි ජනතාවට කඩිනම් සහන සැලසීම සඳහා නාවික හමුදා සහන කණ්ඩායම් 35ක් බදාදා (31) සූදානම් කර ඇති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව පවසයි. .",
        "නාවික හමුදාපති වයිස් අද්මිරාල් නිශාන්ත උළුගේතැන්න මහතාගේ උපදෙස් පරිදි බස්නාහිර නාවික විධානය විසින් කළුතර, රත්නපුර සහ කොළඹ දිස්ත්‍රික්ක සඳහා නාවික හමුදා සහන කණ්ඩායම් 26ක් සූදානම් කර ඇත.",
        "දකුණු නාවික විධානය විසින් ගාල්ල, තංගල්ල සහ හම්බන්තොට දිස්ත්‍රික්ක සඳහා නාවික හමුදා සහන කණ්ඩායම් 9ක් සූදානම් කර ඇත.",
        "දිවයිනේ පවතින අයහපත් කාලගුණික තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් ගංවතුරෙන් විපතට පත් වූ කණ්ඩායම් වෙත අවශ්‍ය පරිදි ප්‍රවේශ වීම සඳහා නාවික හමුදාව අතිරේක සහන කණ්ඩායම් සූදානමින් තබා ඇත.",
        "ලිපියක් සමඟ මෝටර් රථ ගරාජයක දමා ගිය මාසයක් වයසැති ළදරුවා",
        "ඔබ සයිබර් අපරාධයට ගොදුරු වූවෙක්ද? සයිබර් අවකාශයේ සිදුවන අපරාධ මර්දනයට පොලිස් ඒකකය සූදානම්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නාවික",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "35",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිශාන්ත උළුගේතැන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දක්ෂිණ නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තංගල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාසයක් වයසැති",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සයිබර් අපරාධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வெள்ள மீட்புக்காக கடற்படை 35 குழுக்களை தயார் நிலையில் வைத்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பல பகுதிகளில் தொடர்ந்து மழை பெய்து வருவதால், அனர்த்தம் ஏற்பட்டால், வெள்ளம் மற்றும் மண்சரிவினால் பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடிய மக்களுக்கு உடனடி நிவாரணம் வழங்குவதற்காக 35 கடற்படை நிவாரணக் குழுக்களை புதன்கிழமை (31) தயார் நிலையில் வைத்துள்ளதாக இலங்கை கடற்படை தெரிவித்துள்ளது. .",
        "கடற்படைத் தளபதி வைஸ் அட்மிரல் நிஷாந்த உலுகேதென்ன அவர்களின் பணிப்புரையின் பேரில், மேற்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை களுத்துறை, இரத்தினபுரி மற்றும் கொழும்பு மாவட்டங்களுக்கு 26 கடற்படை நிவாரணக் குழுக்களை தயார் நிலையில் வைத்துள்ளது.",
        "தெற்கு கடற்படை கட்டளையானது காலி, தங்காலை மற்றும் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை மாவட்டங்களுக்கு 9 கடற்படை நிவாரண குழுக்களை தயார் நிலையில் வைத்துள்ளது.",
        "நாட்டில் நிலவும் சீரற்ற காலநிலையின் பின்னணியில், வெள்ளத்தால் பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடிய குழுக்களை தேவைக்கேற்ப சென்றடைய கடற்படை கூடுதல் நிவாரண குழுக்களை தயார் நிலையில் வைத்துள்ளது.",
        "கடிதத்துடன் மோட்டார் கேரேஜில் கைவிடப்பட்ட ஒரு மாத கைக்குழந்தை",
        "நீங்கள் சைபர் கிரைம் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவரா? சைபர்ஸ்பேஸ் குற்றங்களை ஒடுக்க போலீஸ் பிரிவு தயார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "35",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிஷாந்த உலுகெதென்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தங்கல்லை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாத வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சைபர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}