{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/15/pohottuwa-divided-on-support-for-ranil/",
  "time_ut": 1657891740,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Pohottuwa Divided on Support for Ranil",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Pohottuwa Divided on Support for Ranil",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); SLPP MP Madhura Withanage told News 1st that many MPs from the ruling faction are yet to decide on their support for Ranil Wickremesinghe at the election in Parliament for President.",
        "Speaking Exclusively on the Dawasa program on Sirasa TV on Friday (15) SLPP MP Madhura Withanage said the views by the SLPP General Secretary to support Ranil Wickremesinghe do NOT reflect the majority decision among SLPP MPs.",
        "“It may have been his personal view,” he said adding that no one has decided to extend their support to Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "FUTA wants Ranil to step down & NOT contest election in Parliament for President"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dawasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sirasa TV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FUTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රනිල්ට සහයෝගය මත පොහොට්ටුව දෙකඩ විය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මධුර විතානගේ News 1st වෙත ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ බොහෝ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ජනාධිපති වරණයේදී රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සහය දැක්වීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් තවමත් තීරණයක් ගෙන නොමැති බවයි.",
        "සිකුරාදා (15) සිරස රූපවාහිනියේ දවස වැඩසටහනට විශේෂ ප්‍රකාශයක් කරමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මධුර විතානගේ කියා සිටියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මහලේකම්වරයා රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහට සහය පළ කරන බවට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ බහුතර තීරණය පිළිබිඹු නොවන බවයි.",
        "“එය ඔහුගේ පෞද්ගලික මතය විය හැකියි,” ඔහු කියා සිටියේ වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට තම සහයෝගය ලබාදීමට කිසිවකු තීරණය කර නොමැති බවයි.",
        "FUTA ට අවශ්‍ය වී ඇත්තේ රනිල් ඉල්ලා අස්වීම සහ ජනාධිපතිවරණයට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් නොවීමයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dawasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරස ටී.වී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FUTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரணிலுக்கு ஆதரவாக பொஹொட்டுவா பிளவுபட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஜனாதிபதிக்கான தேர்தலில் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பது தொடர்பில் ஆளும் தரப்பின் பல பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் இன்னும் தீர்மானிக்கவில்லை என ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மதுர விதானகே நியூஸ் 1ஸ்டுக்கு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (15) சிரச தொலைக்காட்சியில் தவச நிகழ்ச்சியில் பிரத்தியேகமாக உரையாற்றிய SLPP பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மதுர விதானகே, SLPP பொதுச்செயலாளர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவை ஆதரிக்கும் கருத்துக்கள் SLPP பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் மத்தியில் பெரும்பான்மையான தீர்மானத்தை பிரதிபலிக்கவில்லை என்றார்.",
        "அது அவரின் தனிப்பட்ட கருத்தாக இருக்கலாம் எனவும், பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவிற்கு ஆதரவை வழங்குவதற்கு எவரும் தீர்மானிக்கவில்லை எனவும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "FUTA ரணில் பதவி விலக வேண்டும் மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் பாராளுமன்ற தேர்தலில் போட்டியிட வேண்டாம்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தவாசா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிரச டி.வி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FUTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}