{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130590",
  "time_ut": 1656685564,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஞானசார தேரருக்கு எதிரான வழக்கு ஆகஸ்ட்  26 ஆம் திகதிக்கு ஒத்திவைப்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The case against Gnanasara Thera has been adjourned till August 26",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "The case against Gnanasara Thera's comment that Islam is a cancer has been adjourned to August 26.",
        "Today (01) witness hearings in the case on Friday and the request put forward by Gnanasara Thera for a public apology in the case were to be considered.",
        "In view of the current situation in the country, the case has been adjourned till August 26 without being taken up for hearing as per the circular issued by the Judicial Services Commission on the 27th.",
        "A case has been registered against Gnanasara Thera before the Additional Judge (Chamber No. 3) at the Colombo Chief Magistrate's Court in response to a complaint lodged by Rigas Hajiar, a member of the Board of Trustees of Boralai Zum Aa Church in the Colombo Crime Prevention Division.",
        "Witness hearings in the case began on June 8. Accordingly the first witness of the plaintiff has testified in court.",
        "In such a situation, Gnanasara Thera's lawyers have informed the court that his client is ready to apologize publicly in court with a view to concluding the case smoothly.",
        "It is noteworthy that the case was scheduled to be heard again on July 1."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gnanasara Thera",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "August 26",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gnanasara Thera's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Islam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gnanasara Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Judicial Services Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 27th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gnanasara Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rigas Hajiar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Board of Trustees of Boralai Zum Aa Church",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Crime Prevention Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "June 8",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gnanasara Thera's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඥානසාර හිමියන්ට එරෙහි නඩුව අගෝස්තු 26 දක්වා කල් තැබේ",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉස්ලාම් දහම පිළිකාවක් බවට ඥානසාර හිමියන් කළ ප්‍රකාශයට එරෙහි නඩුව අගෝස්තු 26 වැනිදාට කල් තැබේ.",
        "අද (01) සිකුරාදා නඩුවේ සාක්ෂි විභාගය සහ නඩුව සම්බන්ධයෙන් ප්‍රසිද්ධියේ සමාව ගන්නා ලෙස ඥානසාර හිමියන් ඉදිරිපත් කළ ඉල්ලීම සලකා බැලීමට නියමිතව තිබිණි.",
        "රටේ වත්මන් තත්ත්වය හමුවේ පසුගිය 27 වැනිදා අධිකරණ සේවා කොමිෂන් සභාව නිකුත් කළ චක්‍රලේඛයට අනුව නඩුව විභාගයට නොගෙන අගෝස්තු 26 වැනිදා දක්වා කල් තැබිණි.",
        "කොළඹ අපරාධ නිවාරණ කොට්ඨාශයේ භාරකාර මණ්ඩලයේ සාමාජික රිගාස් හාජියාර් විසින් කරන ලද පැමිණිල්ලකට අනුව ඥානසාර හිමියන්ට එරෙහිව කොළඹ අගවිනිසුරු අධිකරණයේ අතිරේක මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා (කාමර අංක 3) ඉදිරියේ නඩුවක් පවරා ඇත.",
        "නඩුවේ සාක්ෂි විභාගය ජුනි 8 වැනිදා ආරම්භ විය. ඒ අනුව පැමිණිල්ලේ පළමු සාක්ෂිකරු අධිකරණය හමුවේ සාක්ෂි ලබාදී තිබෙනවා.",
        "එවැනි තත්ත්වයක් තුළ ඥානසාර හිමියන්ගේ නීතිඥවරුන් අධිකරණයට දන්වා ඇත්තේ නඩුව සාමකාමීව අවසන් කිරීමේ අරමුණින් තම සේවාදායකයා අධිකරණයේදී ප්‍රසිද්ධියේ සමාව ගැනීමට සූදානම් බවයි.",
        "මෙම නඩුව ජූලි මස 1 වැනිදා යළි විභාගයට ගැනීමට නියමිතව තිබීම විශේෂත්වයකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඥානසාර හිමි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "අගෝස්තු 26",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඥානසාර හිමියන්ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉස්ලාම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඥානසාර හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණ සේවා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඥානසාර හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිගාස් හජියාර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරලෙයි සුම් ආ දේවස්ථානයේ භාරකාර මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අපරාධ නිවාරණ කොට්ඨාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 8",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඥානසාර හිමියන්ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஞானசார தேரருக்கு எதிரான வழக்கு ஆகஸ்ட்  26 ஆம் திகதிக்கு ஒத்திவைப்பு",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "இஸ்லாம் ஒரு புற்று நோய் என ஞானசார தேரர் வெளியிட்ட கருத்துக்கு எதிராக தொடரப்பட்டுள்ள வழக்கு எதிர்வரும் ஆகஸ்ட் 26 ஆம் திகதிக்கு ஒத்தி வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இன்று (01) வெள்ளிக்கிழமை குறித்த வழக்கின் சாட்சி விசாரணைகளும்,  அவ்வழக்கில் பகிரங்க மன்னிப்பு கோர ஞானசார தேரர் சார்பில் முன் வைக்கப்பட்ட கோரிக்கையும் பரிசீலனைச் செய்யப்படவிருந்தது.",
        "இந் நிலையிலேயே நாட்டின் தற்போதைய நிலைமையை கருத்திற் கொண்டு,  நீதிச் சேவைகள் ஆணைக் குழுவினால்  கடந்த 27 ஆம் திகதி வெளியிடப்பட்ட சுற்று நிருபத்துக்கு அமைய இவ்வழக்கு விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக் கொள்ளப்படாமலேயே எதிர்வரும்  ஆகஸ்ட் 26 வரை ஒத்தி வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "கொழும்பு குற்றத் தடுப்புப் பிரிவில் பொரளை ஜும் ஆ பள்ளிவாசலின் நிர்வாக சபை உருப்பினர்  ரிகாஸ் ஹாஜியார் முன் வைத்த முறைப்பாட்டுக்கு அமைய, கொழும்பு பிரதான நீதிவான் நீதிமன்றில் மேலதிக நீதிவான் (3 ஆம் இலக்க அறை) முன்னிலையில் ஞானசார தேரருக்கு எதிராக  வழக்குப் பதிவு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த வழக்கில் கடந்த ஜூன்  8 ஆம் திகதி சாட்சி விசாரணைகள் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டன. அதன்படி முறைப்பாட்டாளர் தரப்பின் முதல் சாட்சியாளர் நீதிமன்றில் சாட்சியமளித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இவ்வாறான நிலையில், குறித்த வழக்கை சுமுகமாக முடித்துக்கொள்ளும் நோக்கில் தனது சேவை பெறுநர் நீதிமன்றில் பகிரங்க மன்னிப்பு கோர தயாராக இருப்பதாக ஞானசார தேரரின் சட்டத்தரணிகள் நீதிமன்றுக்கு அறிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இந் நிலையில் இது குறித்த விவகார வழக்கு  இன்று  ஜூலை முதலாம் திகதி மீள விசாரணைக்கு  எடுக்கப்படவிருந்தமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஞானசார தேரர்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 26",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஞானசார தேரரின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்லாம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞானசார தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதி சேவைகள் ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஞானசார தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிகாஸ் ஹாஜியார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொரளை ஜூம் ஆ தேவாலயத்தின் அறங்காவலர் சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு குற்றத்தடுப்பு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 8",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஞானசார தேரரின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}