{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ගෝඨාට-අවශ්‍ය-සුදුසු-පහසුකම්-සපුරා-අවසන්/11-396712",
  "time_ut": 1661826905,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ගෝඨාට අවශ්‍ය සුදුසු පහසුකම් සපුරා අවසන්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The necessary facilities for Gota have been completed",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna General Secretary, Member of Parliament Mr. Sagara Kariyawasam says that suitable facilities required for a former President have been arranged for Mr. Gotabhaya Rajapaksa.",
        "Accordingly, he said that Mr. Gotabaya Rajapaksa will visit Sri Lanka soon. At a press conference held yesterday (29th) at the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna headquarters, he said that he was there while answering questions from journalists.",
        "He said that Mr. Gotabaya Rajapaksa did not leave the country under a beautiful environment. Accordingly, Mr. Kariyawasam said that the necessary security and suitable facilities for a former President should be provided when he comes to Sri Lanka."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gota",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sagara Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගෝඨාට අවශ්‍ය සුදුසු පහසුකම් සපුරා අවසන්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු ජනපතිවරයෙකු අවශ්‍ය සුදුසු පහසුකම් ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට මේ වන විට පිළියෙළ කර ඇතැයි ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණු ප්‍රධාන ලේකම්, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සාගර කාරියවසම් මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව නුදුරු දිනෙක ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා මෙරටට පැමිණෙනු ඇති බවද ඔහු ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණු මූලස්ථානයෙ ඊයේ (29දා) පැවැති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී මාධ්‍ය වේදීන් විදසින් අසල ලද ප්‍රශ්න වලට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් ඔහු හේ බව පැවැසීය.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා මෙරටින් පිටව ගියේ සුන්දර පරිසරයක් යටතේ නොවන බවද ඔහු පැවැසීය. ඒ අනුව ඒ මහතා මෙරටට පැමිණීමේදී අවශ්‍ය ආරක්ෂාව හා හිටපු ජනපතිවරයෙකුට සුදුසු පහසුකම් සැපයීම කළ යුතු බවද කාරියවසම් මහතා පැවැසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨා",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோத்தாவுக்கு தேவையான வசதிகள் செய்து முடிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி ஒருவருக்குத் தேவையான வசதிகள் கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவுக்கு ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பொதுச் செயலாளர், நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் திரு.சாகர காரியவசம் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அதன்படி, திரு.கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச விரைவில் இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்யவுள்ளதாக அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் தலைமையகத்தில் நேற்று (29) இடம்பெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் ஊடகவியலாளர்களின் கேள்விகளுக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் போதே அவர் இவ்வாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "திரு.கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ அழகான சூழலில் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறவில்லை என அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். அதன்படி, முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி ஒருவர் இலங்கைக்கு வரும்போது அவருக்குத் தேவையான பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் பொருத்தமான வசதிகள் செய்து கொடுக்கப்பட வேண்டுமென திரு காரியவசம் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கிடைத்தது ஒரு",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகர காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}