{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Softlogic-launches-Walton-brand-in-Sri-Lanka/34-739247",
  "time_ut": 1661810025,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Softlogic launches Walton brand in Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Softlogic launches Walton brand in Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Softlogic Retail Ltd., a fully owned subsidiary of Softlogic Holdings PLC and one of Sri Lanka’s leading consumer electronics and furniture retail networks, recently partnered with world renowned multinational consumer electronics brand Walton to introduce the Walton brand of TVs to the Sri Lankan market.",
        "Walton is a leading electronics brand which is available in more than 40 international markets covering Europe, Asia, the Middle East and Africa. Launching the brand in Sri Lanka is one of Walton’s milestones towards achieving their vision of ‘Go Global 2030’ and becoming one of the best electronics brands by 2030.",
        "Walton Global Business Division President Edward Kim said: “We are moving ahead with a vision of becoming a global leader in the electronics industry. To reach this vision, Walton emphasises on expanding its brand presence in the global market. And thus, Walton is going to start its TV export to Sri Lanka under its own brand logo.”",
        "Softlogic Retail Ltd. Chief Executive Officer Mohammed Rizvi said: “Softlogic is immensely pleased to launch the Walton brand to the Sri Lankan market. With our diversified business eco system within the retail market, we have built a strong and loyal customer base who have come to trust us in bringing them the best brands in the world which enrich and upgrade their lifestyle. I’m sure Walton will be one such brand where our customers will be delighted with its superior product quality and affordability.”",
        "In the initial phase Softlogic plans to introduce the Walton 32-inch LED TV targeted toward the mass market segment where there is expected to be a strong demand. This would soon be followed with the larger screen LED TVs. The Walton 32-inch LED TV comes with High Definition (HD) Technology which gives high quality picture experience to viewers together with the new trendy narrow bezel design which adds a cosmetic appearance to the product.",
        "The product will be made available in over 200 Softlogic and Softlogic Max Showrooms located island-wide and also on www.mysoftlogic.lk, Softlogic’s e-commerce store. While offering the most affordable 32” LED TV in the market, Softlogic Retail has a host of attractive in-store payment plans; such as 0% interest-free instalment schemes on leading credit cards for up to 60 months, as well as up to 12-months interest-free hire purchase payment plans under Softlogic’s popular ‘Poli Free Hithata Free’ scheme.",
        "Softlogic is a local powerhouse in the Consumer Electronics and Furniture space offering a diverse range of popular leading international brands which include state-of-the-art TVs, home theatre systems, audio systems, refrigerators, washing machines, air conditioners, laptops, mobile phones, kitchen appliances, fitness equipment from some of the world’s most loved brands and a wide range of furniture under its own brand, Softlogic Furniture. Walton will be the newest addition to its world-renowned brand portfolio."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Walton",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Softlogic Retail Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Softlogic Holdings PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Walton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Walton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Walton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Europe",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Middle East",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Africa",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Walton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2030",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Walton Global Business Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Edward Kim",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Walton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Walton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Softlogic Retail Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mohammed Rizvi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Walton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Walton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Walton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "32-inch",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Walton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "32-inch",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Softlogic Max",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "www.mysoftlogic.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Softlogic",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "32",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Softlogic Retail",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "0%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "up to 60 months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12-months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Softlogic",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Consumer Electronics and Furniture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Softlogic Furniture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Walton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Softlogic විසින් Walton සන්නාමය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හඳුන්වා දෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "Softlogic Holdings PLC හි පූර්ණ අනුබද්ධිත සමාගමක් වන Softlogic Retail Ltd. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ පාරිභෝගික ඉලෙක්ට්‍රොනික උපකරණ සහ ගෘහභාණ්ඩ සිල්ලර ජාලයක් වන අතර, පසුගියදා ලොව ප්‍රකට බහුජාතික පාරිභෝගික ඉලෙක්ට්‍රොනික සන්නාමය වන Walton සමඟ හවුල් වී Walton සන්නාමය ශ්‍රී ලංකා වෙළඳපොළට හඳුන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "වෝල්ටන් යනු යුරෝපය, ආසියාව, මැදපෙරදිග සහ අප්‍රිකාව ආවරණය වන පරිදි ජාත්‍යන්තර වෙළඳපල 40 කට වැඩි ගණනක ලබා ගත හැකි ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ ඉලෙක්ට්‍රොනික සන්නාමයකි. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ සන්නාමය දියත් කිරීම වෝල්ටන්ගේ 'Go Global 2030' දැක්ම සාක්ෂාත් කර ගැනීම සහ 2030 වන විට හොඳම ඉලෙක්ට්‍රොනික සන්නාමයක් බවට පත්වීමේ සන්ධිස්ථානයකි.",
        "වෝල්ටන් ග්ලෝබල් ව්‍යාපාරික අංශයේ සභාපති එඩ්වඩ් කිම් පැවසුවේ “අපි ඉලෙක්ට්‍රොනික කර්මාන්තයේ ගෝලීය ප්‍රමුඛයා වීමේ දැක්මක් ඇතිව ඉදිරියට යනවා. මෙම දැක්ම කරා ළඟාවීම සඳහා, වෝල්ටන් ගෝලීය වෙළෙඳපොළ තුළ සිය සන්නාම පැවැත්ම පුළුල් කිරීමට අවධාරණය කරයි. මේ අනුව, වෝල්ටන් සිය සන්නාම ලාංඡනය යටතේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට රූපවාහිනී අපනයනය ආරම්භ කිරීමට නියමිතය.",
        "Softlogic Retail Ltd හි ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී Mohammed Rizvi මහතා පැවසුවේ, “Softlogic සමාගම Walton සන්නාමය ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය වෙළඳපොළට හඳුන්වා දීමට ඉමහත් සතුටට පත්වන බවයි. සිල්ලර වෙළෙඳපොළ තුළ අපගේ විවිධාංගීකරණය වූ ව්‍යාපාරික පරිසර පද්ධතිය සමඟින්, ඔවුන්ගේ ජීවන රටාව පොහොසත් කරන සහ වැඩිදියුණු කරන ලෝකයේ හොඳම සන්නාමයන් ඔවුන් වෙත ගෙන ඒමේදී අප කෙරෙහි විශ්වාසය තැබූ ශක්තිමත් සහ විශ්වාසවන්ත පාරිභෝගික පදනමක් අපි ගොඩනගා ඇත්තෙමු. වෝල්ටන් එවැනි සන්නාමයක් වනු ඇතැයි මට විශ්වාසයි, අපගේ ගනුදෙනුකරුවන් එහි උසස් නිෂ්පාදන ගුණාත්මකභාවය සහ දැරිය හැකි මිල පිළිබඳව සතුටු වනු ඇත.",
        "ආරම්භක අදියරේ දී Softlogic සමාගම විසින් Walton 32-inch LED TV හඳුන්වා දීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇත්තේ දැඩි ඉල්ලුමක් ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කරන මහා වෙළඳපල කොටස ඉලක්ක කරගනිමිනි. මෙය ඉතා ඉක්මනින් විශාල තිර LED රූපවාහිනී සමඟ අනුගමනය කරනු ඇත. වෝල්ටන් 32-අඟල් LED රූපවාහිනිය උසස් විභේදන (HD) තාක්‍ෂණයෙන් සමන්විත වන අතර එමඟින් නිෂ්පාදනයට රූපලාවන්‍ය පෙනුමක් එක් කරන නව ප්‍රවණතා පටු බෙසල් මෝස්තරය සමඟින් නරඹන්නන්ට උසස් තත්ත්වයේ පින්තූර අත්දැකීමක් ලබා දේ.",
        "දිවයින පුරා පිහිටා ඇති Softlogic සහ Softlogic Max ප්‍රදර්ශනාගාර 200කට අධික සංඛ්‍යාවකින් සහ Softlogic හි ඊ-වාණිජ්‍ය වෙළඳසැල වන www.mysoftlogic.lk වෙතින් මෙම නිෂ්පාදනය ලබා ගත හැකිය. වෙළඳපොලේ වඩාත්ම දැරිය හැකි මිලට 32” LED TV පිරිනමන අතර, Softlogic Retail සතුව ආකර්ශනීය වෙළඳසැල් තුළ ගෙවීම් සැලසුම් රාශියක් ඇත; ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ ක්‍රෙඩිට් කාඩ්පත් සඳහා මාස 60ක් දක්වා 0% පොලී රහිත වාරික යෝජනා ක්‍රම මෙන්ම Softlogic හි ජනප්‍රිය ‘පොලි ෆ්‍රී හිතට ෆ්‍රී’ යෝජනා ක්‍රමය යටතේ මාස 12ක් දක්වා පොලී රහිත කුලී මිලදී ගැනීමේ සැලසුම් වැනි.",
        "Softlogic යනු අති නවීන රූපවාහිනී, හෝම් තියටර් පද්ධති, ශ්‍රව්‍ය පද්ධති, ශීතකරණ, රෙදි සෝදන යන්ත්‍ර, වායු සමීකරණ, ලැප්ටොප්, ජංගම දුරකථන ඇතුළු ජනප්‍රිය ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ ජාත්‍යන්තර සන්නාම රාශියක් ඉදිරිපත් කරන පාරිභෝගික ඉලෙක්ට්‍රොනික හා ගෘහ භාණ්ඩ අවකාශයේ දේශීය බලාගාරයකි. දුරකථන, මුළුතැන්ගෙයි උපකරණ, ලෝකයේ වඩාත්ම ප්‍රිය කරන සන්නාමවලින් යෝග්‍යතා උපකරණ සහ තමන්ගේම සන්නාමය වන Softlogic Furniture යටතේ පුළුල් පරාසයක ගෘහභාණ්ඩ. වෝල්ටන් එහි ලෝක ප්‍රකට සන්නාම කළඹට නවතම එකතු කිරීම වනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "වෝල්ටන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Softlogic Retail Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Softlogic Holdings PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෝල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෝල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෝල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැද පෙරදිග",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රිකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෝල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2030",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෝල්ටන් ගෝලීය ව්‍යාපාරික අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එඩ්වඩ් කිම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෝල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෝල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Softlogic Retail Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොහොමඩ් රිස්වි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෝල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෝල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෝල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟල් 32",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෝල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟල් 32",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Softlogic Max",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "www.mysoftlogic.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Softlogic",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "32",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Softlogic සිල්ලර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "0%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස 60 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12-මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Softlogic",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාරිභෝගික ඉලෙක්ට්රොනික උපකරණ සහ ගෘහ භාණ්ඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Softlogic ගෘහ භාණ්ඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෝල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "Softlogic இலங்கையில் Walton வர்த்தக நாமத்தை அறிமுகப்படுத்துகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "Softlogic Retail Ltd., Softlogic Holdings PLC இன் முழுச் சொந்தமான துணை நிறுவனமும், இலங்கையின் முன்னணி நுகர்வோர் இலத்திரனியல் மற்றும் தளபாடங்கள் சில்லறை வலையமைப்பும் ஒன்று, அண்மையில் உலகப் புகழ்பெற்ற பல்தேசிய நுகர்வோர் இலத்திரனியல் வர்த்தக நாமமான Walton உடன் இணைந்து Walton வர்த்தக நாம TVகளை இலங்கை சந்தைக்கு அறிமுகப்படுத்தியது.",
        "வால்டன் ஒரு முன்னணி மின்னணு பிராண்டாகும், இது ஐரோப்பா, ஆசியா, மத்திய கிழக்கு மற்றும் ஆப்பிரிக்காவை உள்ளடக்கிய 40 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட சர்வதேச சந்தைகளில் கிடைக்கிறது. இலங்கையில் வர்த்தக நாமத்தை அறிமுகப்படுத்துவது வால்டனின் ‘Go Global 2030’ என்ற நோக்கத்தை அடைவதற்கும் 2030 ஆம் ஆண்டளவில் சிறந்த இலத்திரனியல் வர்த்தக நாமங்களில் ஒன்றாக மாறுவதற்குமான மைல்கற்களில் ஒன்றாகும்.",
        "வால்டன் குளோபல் பிசினஸ் பிரிவு தலைவர் எட்வர்ட் கிம் கூறியதாவது: எலக்ட்ரானிக்ஸ் துறையில் உலக அளவில் முன்னணியில் இருப்பதற்கான தொலைநோக்குப் பார்வையுடன் நாங்கள் முன்னேறி வருகிறோம். இந்த பார்வையை அடைய, வால்டன் உலக சந்தையில் தனது பிராண்ட் இருப்பை விரிவுபடுத்த வலியுறுத்துகிறது. இதனால், Walton தனது சொந்த வர்த்தக முத்திரையின் கீழ் இலங்கைக்கான தொலைக்காட்சி ஏற்றுமதியை ஆரம்பிக்கவுள்ளது.",
        "Softlogic Retail Ltd. இன் பிரதம நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரி மொஹமட் ரிஸ்வி தெரிவிக்கையில், “Softlogic இலங்கை சந்தையில் Walton வர்த்தக நாமத்தை அறிமுகப்படுத்துவதில் பெரும் மகிழ்ச்சியடைகிறது. சில்லறை சந்தையில் எங்கள் பல்வகைப்பட்ட வணிக சூழல் அமைப்புடன், நாங்கள் ஒரு வலுவான மற்றும் விசுவாசமான வாடிக்கையாளர் தளத்தை உருவாக்கியுள்ளோம், அவர்கள் தங்கள் வாழ்க்கை முறையை மேம்படுத்தி மேம்படுத்தும் உலகின் சிறந்த பிராண்டுகளைக் கொண்டு வந்து எங்களை நம்பி வந்துள்ளனர். எங்கள் வாடிக்கையாளர்கள் அதன் சிறந்த தயாரிப்பு தரம் மற்றும் மலிவு விலையில் மகிழ்ச்சியடையும் அத்தகைய பிராண்டாக வால்டன் இருக்கும் என்று நான் உறுதியாக நம்புகிறேன்.",
        "ஆரம்ப கட்டத்தில் வால்டன் 32-இன்ச் LED டிவியை அறிமுகப்படுத்த Softlogic திட்டமிட்டுள்ளது, அங்கு அதிக தேவை இருக்கும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது. இது விரைவில் பெரிய திரை LED TVகளுடன் பின்பற்றப்படும். வால்டன் 32-இன்ச் LED TV உயர் வரையறை (HD) தொழில்நுட்பத்துடன் வருகிறது, இது புதிய நவநாகரீக குறுகிய உளிச்சாயுமோரம் வடிவமைப்புடன் பார்வையாளர்களுக்கு உயர் தரமான பட அனுபவத்தை வழங்குகிறது, இது தயாரிப்புக்கு ஒரு ஒப்பனை தோற்றத்தை சேர்க்கிறது.",
        "நாடு முழுவதும் அமைந்துள்ள 200க்கும் மேற்பட்ட Softlogic மற்றும் Softlogic Max காட்சியறைகளிலும், Softlogic இன் இ-காமர்ஸ் கடையான www.mysoftlogic.lk இலும் தயாரிப்பு கிடைக்கும். சந்தையில் மிகவும் மலிவு விலையில் 32” LED டிவியை வழங்கும் போது, ​​Softlogic Retail பல கவர்ச்சிகரமான ஸ்டோரில் பணம் செலுத்தும் திட்டங்களைக் கொண்டுள்ளது; 60 மாதங்கள் வரை முன்னணி கிரெடிட் கார்டுகளில் 0% வட்டியில்லா தவணை திட்டங்கள், அத்துடன் Softlogic இன் பிரபலமான ‘போலி ஃப்ரீ ஹிதாட்டா ஃப்ரீ’ திட்டத்தின் கீழ் 12 மாதங்கள் வரை வட்டியில்லா வாடகைக் கட்டணத் திட்டங்கள் போன்றவை.",
        "Softlogic என்பது நுகர்வோர் எலெக்ட்ரானிக்ஸ் மற்றும் பர்னிச்சர் துறையில் உள்ள ஒரு உள்ளூர் அதிகார மையமாகும், இதில் அதிநவீன தொலைக்காட்சிகள், ஹோம் தியேட்டர் சிஸ்டம்கள், ஆடியோ சிஸ்டம்கள், குளிர்சாதனப் பெட்டிகள், வாஷிங் மிஷின்கள், ஏர் கண்டிஷனர்கள், மடிக்கணினிகள், மொபைல் போன்ற பல்வேறு பிரபலமான முன்னணி சர்வதேச பிராண்டுகளை வழங்குகிறது. தொலைபேசிகள், சமையலறை உபகரணங்கள், உலகின் மிகவும் விரும்பப்படும் சில பிராண்டுகளின் உடற்பயிற்சி உபகரணங்கள் மற்றும் அதன் சொந்த பிராண்டான சாஃப்ட்லாஜிக் ஃபர்னிச்சரின் கீழ் பரந்த அளவிலான தளபாடங்கள். வால்டன் அதன் உலகப் புகழ்பெற்ற பிராண்ட் போர்ட்ஃபோலியோவில் புதிய கூடுதலாக இருக்கும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வால்டன்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Softlogic Retail Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Softlogic Holdings PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வால்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வால்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வால்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "40க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வால்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2030",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வால்டன் குளோபல் பிசினஸ் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்வர்ட் கிம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வால்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வால்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Softlogic Retail Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முகமது ரிஸ்வி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வால்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வால்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வால்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "32-இன்ச்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "வால்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "32-இன்ச்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாஃப்ட்லாஜிக் மேக்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "www.mysoftlogic.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாஃப்ட்லாஜிக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "32",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாஃப்ட்லாஜிக் சில்லறை விற்பனை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "0%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "60 மாதங்கள் வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12-மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாஃப்ட்லாஜிக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நுகர்வோர் மின்னணுவியல் மற்றும் தளபாடங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாஃப்ட்லாஜிக் மரச்சாமான்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வால்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}