{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132121",
  "time_ut": 1658642744,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "6 மீனவர்களை விடுவிக்க கோரி காலவரையற்ற வேலைநிறுத்தம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Indefinite strike demanding release of 6 fishermen",
      "author": "Rajeeban",
      "body_lines": [
        "Rameswaram fishermen are on an indefinite strike demanding the release of 6 fishermen and the power boat in Sri Lankan jail.",
        "On the 21st, fishermen in more than 500 boats went out to sea from Rameswaram fishing port. They were fishing between Dhanushkodi-Talaimannar. At that time, the Sri Lankan Navy patrolling the area arrested a barge and 6 fishermen including Anthony and Ajith, who were fishing across the border, and imprisoned them in Sri Lanka's Vavunia jail.",
        "Subsequently, in the fishermen's consultation meeting held yesterday in Rameswaram, it was decided to go on an indefinite strike from yesterday and protest at Rameswaram bus station today (July 24) demanding the release of the 6 fishermen arrested by the Sri Lankan Navy and the barge. According to this, more than 700 barges were anchored yesterday in Rameswaram port without going for fishing. Fishermen said that this would result in a loss of revenue of more than Rs.5 crore per day."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "6",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 21st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rameswaram",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhanushkodi-Talaimannar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anthony",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rameswaram",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 700",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rameswaram",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than Rs.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ධීවරයින් 6 දෙනෙකු නිදහස් කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලමින් අඛණ්ඩ වැඩවර්ජනයක්",
      "author": "රජීබන්",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා බන්ධනාගාරයේ සිටින ධීවරයින් 6 දෙනෙකු සහ බල බෝට්ටුව නිදහස් කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා රාමේෂ්වරම් ධීවරයින් දින නියමයක් නොමැතිව වැඩ වර්ජනයක නිරත වනවා.",
        "පසුගිය 21 වැනිදා රාමේෂ්වරම් ධීවර වරායෙන් ධීවරයින් බෝට්ටු 500කට අධික ප්‍රමාණයකින් මුහුදු ගියා. ඔවුන් ධනුෂ්කොඩි - තලෙයිමන්නාරම අතර මසුන් අල්ලමින් සිටි අතර එම අවස්ථාවේදී එම ප්‍රදේශයේ මුර සංචාරයේ යෙදුණු ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් තොටුපළක් සහ දේශසීමාවෙන් එගොඩ මසුන් ඇල්ලූ ඇන්තනි, අජිත් ඇතුළු ධීවරයින් 6 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වවුනියාව බන්ධනාගාරයේ සිරකර තැබුවා.",
        "ඉන් අනතුරුව, ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව සහ තොටුපළ අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් ධීවරයින් 6 දෙනා නිදහස් කරන ලෙස බලකරමින් ඊයේ (24) රාමේෂ්වරම් ප්‍රදේශයේ පැවති ධීවර උපදේශන රැස්වීමේදී ඊයේ සිට දින නියමයක් නොමැතිව වැඩවර්ජනයක නිරත වීමටත් අද (24) රාමේෂ්වරම් බස් නැවතුම්පොළට පැමිණ විරෝධතාවයක් පැවැත්වීමටත් තීරණය කර ඇත. . මේ අනුව ඊයේ රාමේෂ්වරම් වරායේ ධීවර කටයුතු සඳහා නොගොස් තොටුපළවල් 700කට අධික ප්‍රමාණයක් නැංගුරම් ලා තිබුණා. මේ හේතුවෙන් දිනකට රුපියල් කෝටි පහකට අධික ආදායමක් අහිමි වන බව ධීවරයෝ පැවසූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "6",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "500 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමේෂ්වරම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධනුෂ්කොඩි-තලෙයිමන්නාරම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇන්තනි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමේෂ්වරම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "700 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමේෂ්වරම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 කට වඩා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "6 மீனவர்களை விடுவிக்க கோரி காலவரையற்ற வேலைநிறுத்தம்",
      "author": "Rajeeban",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை சிறையில் உள்ள 6 மீனவர்களையும், விசைப் படகையும் விடுதலை செய்ய வலியுறுத்தி ராமேசுவரம் மீனவர்கள் காலவரையற்ற வேலைநிறுத்தத்தில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர்.ட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "ராமேசுவரம் மீன்பிடித் துறைமுகத்தில் இருந்து கடந்த 21-ம் தேதி 500-க்கும் மேற்பட்ட விசைப்படகுகளில் மீனவர்கள் கடலுக்கு மீன்பிடிக்கச் சென்றனர். இவர்கள் தனுஷ்கோடி-தலைமன்னார் இடையே மீன்பிடித்துக் கொண்டிருந்தனர்.அப்போது அப்பகுதியில் ரோந்து வந்த இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் எல்லை தாண்டி மீன்பிடித்ததாகக் கூறி ஒரு விசைப்படகையும், அதில் இருந்த அந்தோணி, அஜித் உள்ளிட்ட 6 மீனவர்களையும் கைது செய்து இலங்கை வவுனியா சிறையில் அடைத்தனர்.",
        "இதையடுத்து ராமேசுவரத்தில் நேற்று முன்தினம் நடந்த மீனவர்கள் ஆலோசனைக் கூட்டத்தில், இலங்கை கடற்படை கைது செய்த 6 மீனவர்களையும், விசைப்படகையும் விடுவிக்கக் கோரி நேற்று முதல் காலவரையற்ற வேலைநிறுத்தம் செய்வது, இன்று (ஜூலை 24) ராமேசுவரம் பேருந்து நிலையத்தில் ஆர்ப்பாட்டம் செய்வது என முடிவு செய்யப்பட்டது. இதன்படி ராமேசுவரம் துறைமுகத்தில் 700-க்கும் மேற்பட்ட விசைப்படகுகள் மீன்பிடிக்கச் செல்லாமல் நேற்று நங்கூரமிட்டு நிறுத்தி வைக்கப்பட்டன. இதனால் ஒரு நாளைக்கு ரூ.5 கோடிக்கு மேல் வருவாய் இழப்பு ஏற்படும் என மீனவர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "6",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "500க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமேஸ்வரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனுஷ்கோடி-தலைமன்னார்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்தோணி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமேஸ்வரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "700க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமேஸ்வரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ.5க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}