{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/09/when-govt-resigns-new-govt-should-be-ready-pm/",
  "time_ut": 1657373400,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "When Govt resigns, new govt should be ready – PM",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "When Govt resigns, new govt should be ready – PM",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lankan Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe in a special statement to the media on Saturday (9) evening that he proposed to the President to establish an All-Party Government.",
        "He said when the existing government resigns, a new Government must be formed and it is not wise for the country go on without a Government."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Govt",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9) evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "All-Party Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ආණ්ඩුව ඉල්ලා අස්වෙන විට අලුත් ආණ්ඩුවක් සූදානම් විය යුතුයි - අගමැති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සෙනසුරාදා (9) සවස මාධ්‍ය වෙත විශේෂ ප්‍රකාශයක් කරමින් සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම සඳහා ජනාධිපතිවරයාට යෝජනා කළේය.",
        "පවතින රජය ඉල්ලා අස් වූ විට නව රජයක් පිහිටුවිය යුතු බවත් රජයක් නොමැතිව රට ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාම නුවනට හුරු නොවන බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රජය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசு ராஜினாமா செய்யும் போது, ​​புதிய அரசு தயாராக இருக்க வேண்டும் - பிரதமர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); சிறிலங்கா பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, சனிக்கிழமை (9) மாலை ஊடகங்களுக்கு வழங்கிய விசேட அறிக்கையிலேயே, சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கமொன்றை நிறுவுவதற்கு ஜனாதிபதியிடம் முன்மொழிந்துள்ளார்.",
        "தற்போதுள்ள அரசாங்கம் இராஜினாமா செய்யும் போது, ​​புதிய அரசாங்கம் அமைக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்றும், அரசாங்கம் இல்லாமல் நாடு செல்வது புத்திசாலித்தனமானதல்ல என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அரசு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9) மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனைத்து கட்சி அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}