{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84618/us-will-redouble-efforts-to-support-sri-lanka-ambassador-chung",
  "time_ut": 1661787840,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "US will redouble efforts to support Sri Lanka - Ambassador Chung",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "US will redouble efforts to support Sri Lanka - Ambassador Chung",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The United States will redouble efforts to support Sri Lanka through ongoing efforts like financing for SMEs, fertilizer and seeds for farmers, education exchange and training to strengthen public financial management, the US Ambassador in Colombo said.",
        "Ambassador Julie Chung said the US will support Sri Lanka through the International Monetary Fund (IMF) as well, if an agreement can be reached.",
        "In a tweet, the ambassador said she spoke with the Sri Lanka-USA Business Council of the Ceylon Chamber of Commerce on ways US and Sri Lankan businesses can collaborate to ensure Sri Lanka gets back on a path to prosperity.",
        "She said that US-Sri Lanka bilateral trade already supports more than 180,000 workers supplying exports to the US and contribute billions to the Sri Lankan economy.",
        "“The US will redouble efforts to support SL along this path through ongoing efforts like financing for SMEs, fertilizer & seeds for farmers, education exchange & training to strengthen public financial management, as well as support through IMF if agreement can be reached,” Ambassador Chung added."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Chung",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka-USA Business Council of",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 180,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "fertilizer &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "education exchange & training",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහය දැක්වීමේ උත්සාහය දෙගුණ කරනවා - තානාපති චුන්ග්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයින් සඳහා මූල්‍යකරණය, ගොවීන් සඳහා පොහොර සහ බීජ, අධ්‍යාපන හුවමාරුව සහ රාජ්‍ය මූල්‍ය කළමනාකරණය ශක්තිමත් කිරීම සඳහා පුහුණුව වැනි අඛණ්ඩ ප්‍රයත්නයන් හරහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය දැක්වීමේ උත්සාහයන් දෙගුණ කිරීමට එක්සත් ජනපදය කටයුතු කරන බව කොළඹ එක්සත් ජනපද තානාපතිවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "ගිවිසුමකට එළැඹිය හැකි නම් ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) හරහා ද එක්සත් ජනපදය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය දෙන බව තානාපති ජුලී චුන්ග් පැවසීය.",
        "ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් තානාපතිනිය පැවසුවේ, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව යළි සෞභාග්‍යයේ මාවතකට ගෙන ඒම සහතික කිරීම සඳහා එක්සත් ජනපද සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ව්‍යාපාරවලට සහයෝගී විය හැකි ක්‍රම පිළිබඳව ලංකා වාණිජ මණ්ඩලයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා-ඇමරිකානු ව්‍යාපාරික කවුන්සිලය සමඟ කතා කළ බවයි.",
        "එක්සත් ජනපද-ශ්‍රී ලංකා ද්විපාර්ශ්වික වෙළඳාම දැනටමත් එක්සත් ජනපදයට අපනයන සපයන කම්කරුවන් 180,000 කට වැඩි පිරිසකට සහාය වන බවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආර්ථිකයට බිලියන ගණනක් දායක වන බවත් ඇය පැවසුවාය.",
        "“එක්සත් ජනපදය කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයින් සඳහා මූල්‍යකරණය, ගොවීන් සඳහා පොහොර සහ බීජ, අධ්‍යාපන හුවමාරුව සහ රාජ්‍ය මූල්‍ය කළමනාකරණය ශක්තිමත් කිරීම සඳහා පුහුණුව මෙන්ම එකඟතාවයකට පැමිණිය හැකි නම් ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල හරහා සහය ලබා දීම වැනි අඛණ්ඩ උත්සාහයන් හරහා මෙම මාවත ඔස්සේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය දැක්වීමේ ප්‍රයත්න දෙගුණ කරයි,” තානාපති චුන්ග් එකතු කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "චුන්ග්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා-ඇමරිකා ව්‍යාපාරික කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "180,000 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොහොර &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්යාපන හුවමාරුව සහ පුහුණුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவளிக்கும் முயற்சிகளை அமெரிக்கா இரட்டிப்பாக்கும் - தூதுவர் சுங்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "SME களுக்கு நிதியுதவி, விவசாயிகளுக்கு உரம் மற்றும் விதைகள், கல்வி பரிமாற்றம் மற்றும் பொது நிதி நிர்வாகத்தை வலுப்படுத்துவதற்கான பயிற்சி போன்ற தொடர்ச்சியான முயற்சிகள் மூலம் இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதற்கான முயற்சிகளை அமெரிக்கா இரட்டிப்பாக்கும் என்று கொழும்பில் உள்ள அமெரிக்க தூதுவர் கூறினார்.",
        "ஒரு உடன்பாடு எட்டப்பட்டால், சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் (IMF) மூலமாகவும் இலங்கைக்கு அமெரிக்கா ஆதரவளிக்கும் என்று தூதுவர் ஜூலி சுங் கூறினார்.",
        "ஒரு ட்வீட்டில், தூதுவர், இலங்கை மீண்டும் செழிப்புக்கான பாதையில் செல்வதை உறுதி செய்வதற்காக, அமெரிக்க மற்றும் இலங்கை வணிகங்கள் ஒத்துழைக்கக்கூடிய வழிகள் குறித்து இலங்கை-அமெரிக்க வர்த்தக சபையுடன் இலங்கை வர்த்தக சபையுடன் பேசியதாகத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அமெரிக்கா-இலங்கை இருதரப்பு வர்த்தகம் ஏற்கனவே 180,000 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட தொழிலாளர்களை அமெரிக்காவிற்கு ஏற்றுமதி செய்வதை ஆதரிப்பதாகவும் இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரத்திற்கு பில்லியன்களை பங்களிப்பதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"எஸ்எம்இகளுக்கு நிதியுதவி, விவசாயிகளுக்கு உரம் மற்றும் விதைகள், கல்வி பரிமாற்றம் மற்றும் பொது நிதி நிர்வாகத்தை வலுப்படுத்த பயிற்சி, அத்துடன் உடன்பாடு எட்டப்பட்டால் IMF மூலம் ஆதரவு போன்ற தொடர்ச்சியான முயற்சிகள் மூலம் இந்த பாதையில் SL ஐ ஆதரிக்கும் முயற்சிகளை அமெரிக்கா இரட்டிப்பாக்கும்\" என்று தூதர் கூறினார். சுங் சேர்த்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சுங்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை-அமெரிக்க வணிக கவுன்சில்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "180,000க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உரம் &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்வி பரிமாற்றம் மற்றும் பயிற்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}