{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/චීනය-සඳ-අයිති-කරගන්න-හදනවා/1-615928",
  "time_ut": 1657071209,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "චීනය සඳ අයිති කරගන්න හදනවා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "China is trying to own the moon",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Bill Nelson, head of the US National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), accuses China of trying to take possession of the moon under their military space program.",
        "The head of NASA made this accusation in an interview with Germany's Bild newspaper. “China is preparing to send astronauts to the moon through a military space program. Not on a scientific basis. I'm sure they want to own the moon. \"If they own the moon, we (America) or any other country will not be able to go to the moon again,\" explained the head of NASA.",
        "Regarding these accusations of the head of NASA, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the country has issued a statement on behalf of the Chinese government and protested. Zhao Lijiang, spokesman for the Chinese government's foreign ministry, said that the NASA chief made a baseless and irresponsible statement.",
        "China is currently building a small space station the size of the Earth's orbit. Part by part is sent up into the air and their assembly takes place in Lahilahi. The space station is scheduled to be completed this year, after which China will land on the moon.",
        "In 2024, the American NASA is going to start a series of lunar missions called 'Artemis'. The first time a woman was sent to the moon was under the 'Artemis' lunar mission. Accordingly, there will be a competition between the United States and China for the moon landing."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Bill Nelson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the US National Aeronautics and Space Administration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NASA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NASA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bild",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "America",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "NASA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NASA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the country",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zhao Lijiang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "NASA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Earth",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lahilahi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "American",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "NASA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීනය සඳ අයිති කරගන්න හදනවා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "චීනය ඔවුන්ගේ හමුදා අභ්‍යවකාශ වැඩසටහනක් යටතේ සඳ අයිති කර ගැනීමට උත්සාහ ගන්නවා යැයි ඇමෙරිකා ‘ජාතික ගගන විද්‍යාව සහ අභ්‍යවකාශ පරිපාලනය’ හෙවත් ‘නාසා’ ආයතනයේ ප්‍රධානී බිල් නෙල්සන් චෝදනා නගයි.",
        "නාසා ප්‍රධානියා මෙසේ චෝදනා කළේ ජර්මනියේ ‘බිල්ඩ්’ පුවත්පත සමඟ සම්මුඛ සාකච්ඡාවකට එක් වෙමිනි. “චීනය සඳට ගගනගාමීන් යැවීමට සූදානම් වෙන්නේ හමුදා අභ්‍යවකාශ වැඩසටහනක් හරහායි. විද්‍යාත්මක පදනමකින් නොවෙයි. මට විශ්වාසයි ඔවුන් සඳ අයිති කර ගන්නයි හදන්නේ. ඔවුන් සඳ අයිති කර ගත්තොත් අපට (ඇමෙරිකාවට) හෝ වෙනත් රටකට හෝ යළි සඳට යන්න බැරි වේවි” යැයි නාසා ප්‍රධානියා පැහැදිලි කර ඇත.",
        "නාසා ප්‍රධානියාගේ මෙම චෝදනා සම්බන්ධයෙන් චීන රජය වෙනුවෙන් එරට විදේශ අමත්‍යාංශය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් විරෝධය දක්වා තිබේ. නාසා ප්‍රධානියා කළේ පදනම් විරහිත සහ වගකීම් විරහිතව ප්‍රකාශයක් යැයි චීන රජය වෙනුවෙන් එරට විදේශ අමාත්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක සහෝ ලිජියැං පවසා ඇත.",
        "චීනය මේ වනවිට පෘථිවි කක්ෂයේ ප්‍රමාණයෙන් කුඩා අභ්‍යවකාශ නැවැතුම්පොළක් ඉදි කරමින් පවතී. කොටසින් කොටස උඩු ගුවනට යවා ඒවා එකලැස් කිරීම ලහිලහියේ සිදුවෙයි. අභ්‍යවකාශ නැවැතුම්පොළ මෙම වසරේ ඉදිකර අවසන් කිරීමට නියමිත අතර, චීනය සඳ තරණය කරනු ඇත්තේ ඉන්පසුවය.",
        "2024 දී ඇමෙරිකාවේ නාසා ආයතනය ද 'ආටිමීස්' නමින් යළි චන්ද්‍ර මෙහෙයුම් මාලාවක් ආරම්භ කිරීමට නියමිතය. පළමු වරට කාන්තාවක සඳට යැවීම සිදුවන්නේ ද 'ආර්ටිමීස්' චන්ද්‍ර මෙහෙයුම යටතේය. ඒ අනුව ඉදිරියේ දී සඳ තරණය සඳහා ඇමෙරිකාව සහ චීනය අතරේ තරගයක් පවතිනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බිල් නෙල්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද ජාතික ගගන විද්‍යාව සහ අභ්‍යවකාශ පරිපාලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාසා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාසා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිල්ඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාසා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාසා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රටේ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zhao Lijiang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාසා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොළොවේ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලහිලාහි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාසා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நிலவை சொந்தமாக்க சீனா முயற்சிக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அமெரிக்காவின் தேசிய வானூர்தி மற்றும் விண்வெளி நிர்வாகத்தின் (நாசா) தலைவர் பில் நெல்சன், சீனா தனது ராணுவ விண்வெளி திட்டத்தின் கீழ் நிலவை கைப்பற்ற முயற்சிப்பதாக குற்றம் சாட்டியுள்ளார்.",
        "ஜேர்மனியின் பில்ட் பத்திரிகைக்கு வழங்கிய நேர்காணலில் நாசாவின் தலைவர் இந்தக் குற்றச்சாட்டை முன்வைத்துள்ளார். “ராணுவ விண்வெளித் திட்டத்தின் மூலம் நிலவுக்கு விண்வெளி வீரர்களை அனுப்ப சீனா தயாராகி வருகிறது. அறிவியல் அடிப்படையில் அல்ல. அவர்கள் சந்திரனை சொந்தமாக்க விரும்புகிறார்கள் என்று நான் நம்புகிறேன். \"அவர்கள் நிலவுக்குச் சொந்தமாக இருந்தால், நாங்கள் (அமெரிக்கா) அல்லது வேறு எந்த நாடும் மீண்டும் நிலவுக்குச் செல்ல முடியாது\" என்று நாசா தலைவர் விளக்கினார்.",
        "நாசா தலைவரின் இந்தக் குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் குறித்து அந்நாட்டு வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம் சீன அரசு சார்பில் அறிக்கை வெளியிட்டு எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவித்துள்ளது. இது குறித்து சீன அரசின் வெளியுறவுத்துறை செய்தி தொடர்பாளர் ஜாவோ லிஜியாங் கூறுகையில், நாசா தலைவர் ஆதாரமற்ற மற்றும் பொறுப்பற்ற அறிக்கையை வெளியிட்டார்.",
        "சீனா தற்போது பூமியின் சுற்றுப்பாதையில் ஒரு சிறிய விண்வெளி நிலையத்தை உருவாக்கி வருகிறது. பகுதி பகுதியாக காற்றில் அனுப்பப்பட்டு, அவர்களின் கூட்டம் லாஹிலாஹியில் நடைபெறுகிறது. விண்வெளி நிலையம் இந்த ஆண்டு முடிக்க திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளது, அதன் பிறகு சீனா நிலவில் தரையிறங்கும்.",
        "2024 ஆம் ஆண்டில், அமெரிக்க நாசா 'ஆர்டெமிஸ்' என்ற சந்திர பயணத்தைத் தொடங்க உள்ளது. 'ஆர்டெமிஸ்' சந்திர பயணத்தின் கீழ் முதல் முறையாக ஒரு பெண் நிலவுக்கு அனுப்பப்பட்டார். அதன்படி, சந்திரனில் இறங்குவதற்கு அமெரிக்காவுக்கும், சீனாவுக்கும் இடையே போட்டி நிலவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பில் நெல்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க தேசிய ஏரோநாட்டிக்ஸ் மற்றும் விண்வெளி நிர்வாகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாசா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாசா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மனி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பில்ட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாசா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாசா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாட்டின் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zhao Lijiang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாசா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூமி",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "லாஹிலாஹி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாசா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}