{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83801/tense-situation-ensues-as-troops-sweep-into-galle-face-protest-site",
  "time_ut": 1658455800,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Tense situation ensues as troops sweep into Galle Face protest site",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Tense situation ensues as troops sweep into Galle Face protest site",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Teste situation was reported early this morning (July 22) as the armed forces stormed the protest site at the Galle Face Green to clear the Presidential Secretariat and its main entrance of demonstrators.",
        "The pre-dawn raid was jointly launched by the Army, the Police and the Special Task Force (STF).",
        "Reportedly, the troops have also dismantled the tents erected in front of the Presidential Secretariat.",
        "As the troops swept into the Galle Face protest site, the protesters were asked to vacate the entrance to the Presidential Secretariat. The security forces warned the protesters that they would be arrested under provisions of emergency laws if they clash with the troops.",
        "However, tensions escalated as the troops removed the protesters from the premises. There were reports of assaults by the security forces on civilians.",
        "Nine people were placed under arrest by the police and two of them have reportedly sustained injuries.",
        "The security forces have now taken over the entrance and area surrounding the Presidential Secretariat.",
        "The military operation at the Galle Face protest site came less than 24 hours after Ranil Wickremesinghe was sworn in as the new Head of State at the parliament complex."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Galle Face",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Teste",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "early this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Galle Face Green",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Special Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "premises",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle Face",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "less than 24 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගාලු මුවදොර විරෝධතා භූමියට හමුදාව කඩා වැදීමත් සමඟ නොසන්සුන්කාරී තත්ත්වයක් ඇති විය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අද (ජූලි 22) අලුයම ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාව විසින් ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය සහ එහි ප්‍රධාන දොරටුව විරෝධතාකරුවන් ඉවත් කිරීම සඳහා ගාලුමුවදොර පිටියේ විරෝධතා ස්ථානයට කඩා වැදීමත් සමඟ ටෙස්ටි තත්ත්වය වාර්තා විය.",
        "යුධ හමුදාව, පොලිසිය සහ විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකාය (STF) එක්ව මෙම පෙරවරු වැටලීම දියත් කර ඇත.",
        "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය ඉදිරිපිට ඉදිකර තිබූ කූඩාරම් ද හමුදාව විසින් කඩා ඉවත් කර ඇති බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "ගාලු මුවදොර විරෝධතා භූමියට හමුදාව කඩා වැදීමත් සමඟ විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයට ඇතුළු වන දොරටුවෙන් ඉවත් වන ලෙස දන්වා ඇත. හමුදාව සමඟ ගැටුමක් ඇති වුවහොත් හදිසි නීති ප්‍රතිපාදන යටතේ අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා බවට ආරක්ෂක අංශ විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට අනතුරු ඇඟවීය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, භට පිරිස් විසින් විරෝධතාකරුවන් පරිශ්‍රයෙන් ඉවත් කිරීමත් සමඟ නොසන්සුන්තාව වර්ධනය විය. ආරක්ෂක අංශ සිවිල් වැසියන්ට පහරදීම් වාර්තා විය.",
        "පුද්ගලයන් 9 දෙනෙකු පොලිසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති අතර ඉන් දෙදෙනෙකු තුවාල ලබා ඇති බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයට ඇතුළු වන ප්‍රදේශය සහ ඒ අවට ප්‍රදේශය මේ වන විට ආරක්ෂක අංශ විසින් අත්පත් කරගෙන ඇත.",
        "ගාලු මුවදොර විරෝධතා භූමියේ හමුදා මෙහෙයුම සිදු වූයේ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා නව රාජ්‍ය නායකයා ලෙස පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණයේදී දිවුරුම් දී පැය 24ක් ගතවීමටත් පෙරය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ටෙස්ට්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද උදේ පාන්දර",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර පිටිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පරිශ්රය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 24 ට අඩු",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "காலி முகத்திடலில் போராட்டக்களத்திற்குள் படையினர் நுழைந்ததால் பதற்றமான சூழல் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இன்று (ஜூலை 22) அதிகாலை, ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம் மற்றும் அதன் பிரதான நுழைவாயிலில் ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களை அகற்றுவதற்காக ஆயுதப்படையினர் காலி முகத்திடலில் உள்ள போராட்டத் தளத்தை முற்றுகையிட்டதால், சோதனை நிலைமை ஏற்பட்டது.",
        "இராணுவம், பொலிஸ் மற்றும் விசேட அதிரடிப்படையினர் (STF) இணைந்து இந்த அதிகாலை சோதனையை ஆரம்பித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்திற்கு முன்பாக அமைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த கூடாரங்களையும் படையினர் அகற்றியுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது.",
        "காலி முகத்திடல் போராட்டத் தளத்திற்குள் படையினர் நுழைந்ததையடுத்து, ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் ஜனாதிபதி செயலக நுழைவாயிலை விட்டு வெளியேறுமாறு கோரப்பட்டனர். படையினருடன் மோதினால் அவசரகால சட்ட விதிகளின் கீழ் கைது செய்யப்படுவார்கள் என போராட்டக்காரர்களை பாதுகாப்பு படையினர் எச்சரித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இருப்பினும், போராட்டக்காரர்களை ராணுவத்தினர் வளாகத்தில் இருந்து அப்புறப்படுத்தியதால் பதற்றம் அதிகரித்தது. பொதுமக்கள் மீது பாதுகாப்பு படையினர் தாக்குதல் நடத்தியதாக செய்திகள் வெளியாகின.",
        "ஒன்பது பேர் பொலிஸாரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர், அவர்களில் இருவர் காயமடைந்துள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "தற்போது ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்தின் நுழைவாயில் மற்றும் அதனை சூழவுள்ள பகுதியை பாதுகாப்பு படையினர் கைப்பற்றியுள்ளனர்.",
        "புதிய அரச தலைவராக ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பாராளுமன்ற வளாகத்தில் பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்து 24 மணித்தியாலங்களுக்குள் காலி முகத்திடலில் இராணுவ நடவடிக்கை மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "காலி முகம்",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சோதனை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face Green",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறப்பு அதிரடிப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "வளாகம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி முகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 மணி நேரத்திற்கும் குறைவாக",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}