{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Parliament-to-elect-new-President-on-July-20-Speaker/342-240857",
  "time_ut": 1657544173,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Parliament to elect new President on July 20: Speaker",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Parliament to elect new President on July 20: Speaker",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Party leaders have decided to elect a new President on July 20 through a vote in Parliament in accordance with the provisions of the Constitution, Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardhane said today.",
        "He said it was decided to convene Parliament this Friday (15) and inform the House that there is a vacancy for the Presidency according to the provisions of the Constitution.",
        "“Nominations for the presidency will be called for on July 19 and a vote will be taken on July 20 to elect a new President,” he said.",
        "Party Leaders also decided to form an all-party government under the new President and take steps to continue the supply of essential services. (Ajith Siriwardana)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "July 20",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardhane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Party Leaders",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Siriwardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ජුලි 20 වැනිදා නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගනී: කථානායක",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ ප්‍රතිපාදන අනුව පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ඡන්ද විමසීමක් මගින් ජූලි 20 වැනිදා නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමට පක්ෂ නායකයින් තීරණය කළ බව කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා අද ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "මේ සිකුරාදා (15) පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කැඳවා ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ ප්‍රතිපාදන අනුව ජනාධිපති ධුරය සඳහා පුරප්පාඩුවක් පවතින බව සභාවට දැනුම් දීමට තීරණය කළ බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "\"ජූලි 19 වෙනිදා ජනාධිපති ධූරය සඳහා නාමයෝජනා කැදවන අතර නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා ජූලි 20 වෙනිදා ඡන්දය පවත්වන බව\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා යටතේ සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවා අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය සේවා සැපයීම අඛණ්ඩව සිදු කිරීමට පියවර ගැනීමට ද පක්ෂ නායකයෝ තීරණය කළහ. (අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූලි 20",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පක්ෂ නායකයන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புதிய குடியரசுத் தலைவரை ஜூலை 20ஆம் தேதி தேர்ந்தெடுக்கும் நாடாளுமன்றம்: சபாநாயகர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் பிரகாரம் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் வாக்கெடுப்பு மூலம் புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை ஜூலை 20 ஆம் திகதி தெரிவு செய்ய கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "எதிர்வரும் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (15) பாராளுமன்றத்தை கூட்டி, அரசியலமைப்பின் பிரகாரம் ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான வெற்றிடம் இருப்பதாக சபைக்கு தெரிவிக்க தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான வேட்புமனுக்கள் ஜூலை 19 ஆம் தேதி கோரப்படும், புதிய ஜனாதிபதியைத் தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதற்கான வாக்கெடுப்பு ஜூலை 20 ஆம் தேதி நடத்தப்படும்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதியின் கீழ் அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பதற்கும் அத்தியாவசிய சேவைகளை தொடர்ந்து வழங்குவதற்கு நடவடிக்கை எடுப்பதற்கும் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் தீர்மானித்துள்ளனர். (அஜித் சிறிவர்தன)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை 20",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வெள்ளிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கட்சித் தலைவர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}