{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131866",
  "time_ut": 1658303738,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "மட்டு ஆரையம்பதியில் நிலத்தைத் தோண்டி தங்கம் தேடிய 4 பேர் கைது",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "4 people were arrested for digging for gold in Madtu Arayampadi",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "Kaluvanchikudi Special Task Force has arrested and handed over 4 people who were involved in digging for gold in an abandoned land in Arayampathi Ollikkulam area of ​​Kathankudi Police Division, Batticaloa yesterday Tuesday (19) and handed them over.",
        "According to the information received by the Military Intelligence Unit, the Military Intelligence Unit along with Kalavanchikudi Special Task Force surrounded and laid siege to an abandoned land near the Garment Factory Hostel in the said area at 11.30 midnight yesterday.",
        "During this, two people from Ampara region who were engaged in digging for gold in the land, arrested 4 people including two from Arayampadi region and recovered the tools used for digging the land, shovel, shovel and call phone and handed them over to the police.",
        "The police said that steps have been taken to produce the arrested women in the court after investigation."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "4",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Madtu Arayampadi",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "​​Kathankudi Police Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Batticaloa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Military Intelligence Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Military Intelligence Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Garment Factory Hostel",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "11.30 midnight",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ampara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arayampadi",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මඩු ආරයම්පදි ප්‍රදේශයේ රත්‍රන් කැණීම් කළ පුද්ගලයින් 4 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "මඩකලපුව, කාතාන්කුඩි පොලිස් වසමේ ආරයම්පති ඔලික්කුලම් ප්‍රදේශයේ පාළු ඉඩමක රත්‍රන් කැණීමේ නිරතව සිටි පුද්ගලයින් 4 දෙනෙකු ඊයේ (19) අඟහරුවාදා (19) කලුවංචිකුඩි විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකාය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන භාර දී ඇත.",
        "හමුදා බුද්ධි අංශයට ලැබුණු තොරතුරකට අනුව හමුදා බුද්ධි අංශය කලවංචිකුඩි විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකාය සමඟ ඊයේ මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රී 11.30 ට එම ප්‍රදේශයේ ඇඟලුම් කම්හල් නේවාසිකාගාරය අසල අතහැර දමා තිබූ ඉඩමක් වටලා වටලා ඇත.",
        "මේ අතරතුර ඉඩමේ රත්‍රන් කැණීමේ නිරතව සිටි අම්පාර ප්‍රදේශයේ පුද්ගලයන් දෙදෙනකු ආරයම්පඩි ප්‍රදේශයේ දෙදෙනකු ඇතුළු 4 දෙනකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඉඩම හෑරීමට යොදාගත් උපකරණ, සවල, සවල සහ ඇමතුම් දුරකථනය සොයාගෙන පොලිසියට භාර දී ඇත. .",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් කාන්තාවන් විමර්ශනවලින් අනතුරුව අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට පියවර ගෙන ඇති බව පොලිසිය සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "4",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "මඩු ආරයම්පදි",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාතන්කුඩි පොලිස් වසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මඩකලපුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා බුද්ධි අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා බුද්ධි අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇඟලුම් කම්හල් නේවාසිකාගාරය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රී 11.30",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්පාර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරයම්පදි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மட்டு ஆரையம்பதியில் நிலத்தைத் தோண்டி தங்கம் தேடிய 4 பேர் கைது",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "மட்டக்களப்பு காத்தான்குடி பொலிஸ் பிரிவிலுள்ள ஆரையம்பதி ஒல்லிக்குளம் பிரதேசத்தில்  கைவிடப்பட்ட காணி ஒன்றில் தங்கம் தேடி நிலத்தை தோண்டும் நடவடிக்கையில் ஈடுபட்ட 4 பேரை நேற்று செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (19) நள்ளிரவு களுவாஞ்சிக்குடி விசேட அதிரடிப்படையினர் கைது செய்து ஒப்படைத்துள்ளதாக காத்தான்குடி பொலிசார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இராணுவ புலனாய்வு பிரிவினருக்கு கிடைத்த தகவல் ஒன்றிற்கமைய சம்பவதினமான நேற்று நள்ளிரவு 11.30 மணியளவில் குறித்த பகுதியிலுள்ள  ஆடைத் தொழிற்சாலை தங்குவிடுதிக்கு அருகாமையிலுள்ள  கைவிடப்பட்ட காணி ஒன்றினை களவாஞ்சிக்குடி விசேட அதிரடிப்படையினருடன் இராணுவ புலனாய்வு பிரிவினர் இணைந்து சுற்றிவளைத்து முற்றுகையிட்டனர்.",
        "இதன் போது அங்கு நிலத்தில் தங்கம் இருப்பதாக நிலத்தை தோண்டும் நடவடிக்கையில் ஈடுபட்டுக் கொண்டிருந்த அம்பாறை பிரதேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்த இருவரும் ஆரையம்பதி பிரதேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்த இருவர் உட்பட  4 பேரை கைது செய்ததுடன் நிலத்தை தோண்ட பயன்படுத்திய மண்வெட்டி, அலவாங்கு, சவல் போன் ஆயதங்களை மீட்டு பொலிசாரிடம் ஒப்படைத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இதில் கைது செய்யப்பட்டவாகளை விசாரணையின் பின்னர் நீதிமன்றில் ஆஜர்படுத்த நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிசார் தெரிவித்தனா."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "4",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "மட்டு ஆரையம்பாடி",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காத்தான்குடி பொலிஸ் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மட்டக்களப்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவ புலனாய்வு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவ புலனாய்வு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆடை தொழிற்சாலை விடுதி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நள்ளிரவு 11.30",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆரையம்பாடி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}