{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/බලශක්තිය-හා-ගුවන්-ගමන්-ගැන-රුසියා-තානාපති-සමග-සාකච්ඡාවක්/11-394898",
  "time_ut": 1656352513,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "බලශක්තිය හා ගුවන් ගමන් ගැන රුසියා තානාපති සමග සාකච්ඡාවක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Discussion with Russian Ambassador on Energy and Aviation",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Russian Ambassador Yury Materiy meets President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa The meeting took place this afternoon (27) at the President's House, Fort, Colombo.",
        "2022 marks the 65th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between Sri Lanka and Russia. Recalling the strong state ties and friendship between the two countries, the President commended Russia for its support in the process of cracking down on Kovid as well as whenever necessary.",
        "The President and Russian Ambassador to Russia Yuri Materi discussed a number of important economic areas, including Russia's growing demand for tea, tourism, fuel, coal, gas, aviation, education, trade and fertilizer."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Russian",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Energy and Aviation",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yury Materiy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fort",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 marks",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "65th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kovid",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuri Materi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බලශක්තිය හා ගුවන් ගමන් ගැන රුසියා තානාපති සමග සාකච්ඡාවක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රුසියානු තානාපති යූරි මැටේරි (Yury Materiy) මහතා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා හමුව තිබේ. හමුව අද (27) දහවල් කොළඹ, කොටුව ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ දී සිදු විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව හා රුසියාව අතර රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික සබඳතාව සඳහා 2022 දී 65 වසරක් සපිරේ. ශක්තිමත් රාජ්‍ය සබඳතාව සහ දෙරට අතර පවතින මිත්‍රත්වය සිහිපත් කළ ජනාධිපතිවරයා කොවිඩ් මර්දන ක්‍රියාවලියේ දී මෙන්ම අවැසි සෑමවිටම රුසියාවෙන් ලැබෙන සහාය පැසසුමට ලක් කළේය.",
        "තේ සඳහා රුසියාවෙන් ඇති ඉල්ලුම තවදුරටත් වර්ධනය කර ගැනීම,  සංචාරක කර්මාන්තය, ඉන්ධන,  ගල් අඟුරු, ගෑස්, ගුවන් ගමන්, අධ්‍යාපන, වෙළෙඳාම, පොහොර ඇතුළු වැදගත් ආර්ථික ක්ෂේත්‍ර ගණනාවක් පිළිබඳව ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ රුසියානු තානාපති යූරි මැටේරි මහතා අතර සාකච්ඡාවට ලක් කෙරිණ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රුසියානු",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "බලශක්ති සහ ගුවන් සේවා",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "යූරි මැටරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලකොටුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලකුණු 2022",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "65 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොවිඩ්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යූරි මැටේරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிசக்தி மற்றும் விமானப் போக்குவரத்து தொடர்பான ரஷ்ய தூதருடன் கலந்துரையாடல்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ரஷ்ய தூதுவர் Yury Materiy ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை சந்தித்துள்ளார் இந்த சந்திப்பு இன்று (27) பிற்பகல் கொழும்பு கோட்டை ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் இடம்பெற்றது.",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு இலங்கைக்கும் ரஷ்யாவுக்கும் இடையில் இராஜதந்திர உறவுகளை நிறுவி 65 ஆண்டுகள் நிறைவடைகிறது. இரு நாடுகளுக்குமிடையிலான வலுவான அரச உறவுகளையும் நட்பையும் நினைவுகூர்ந்த ஜனாதிபதி, கொவிட் நோயைக் கட்டுப்படுத்தும் நடவடிக்கைகளில் ரஷ்யாவின் ஆதரவிற்காகவும், தேவைப்படும் போதெல்லாம் பாராட்டினார்.",
        "தேயிலை, சுற்றுலா, எரிபொருள், நிலக்கரி, எரிவாயு, விமானப் போக்குவரத்து, கல்வி, வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் உரம் ஆகியவற்றுக்கான ரஷ்யாவின் வளர்ந்து வரும் தேவை உட்பட பல முக்கியமான பொருளாதாரப் பகுதிகள் குறித்து ஜனாதிபதியும் ரஷ்யாவுக்கான ரஷ்ய தூதர் யூரி மேட்டேரியும் விவாதித்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆற்றல் மற்றும் விமான போக்குவரத்து",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "யூரி மேட்டரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 மதிப்பெண்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "65வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவிட்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யூரி மேட்டரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}