{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/SLTB-TUs-threaten-to-withdraw-from-service-if-authorities-dont-respond/342-240592",
  "time_ut": 1657255303,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SLTB TUs threaten to  withdraw from service if authorities don’t respond",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SLTB TUs threaten to  withdraw from service if authorities don’t respond",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Sri Lanka Transport Board (SLTB) trade unions have decided to withdraw from all their operations from 10:00 am today if the authorities do not provide  adequate fuel for their employees to report to work.",
        "The Head of the SLTB trade unions, Nurajith Singh said their employees need to report to work early in the morning to provide the public with transportation. Most of them use their own vehicles, such as motorcycles. Due to the current fuel shortage, it has been difficult for them to report to work.",
        "However, fuel will be issued for essential service vehicles such as ambulances. As a result the trade unions have decided to withdraw from operating buses.",
        "\"We have reported this issue to the responsible authorities several months, but no one has listened. We have had practical issues when reporting for their duties as early as 4.00 am everyday. We can't travel by buses to return home. Therefore, we have to use our own vehicles,\" Nurajith Singh said.",
        "We will give up this trade union action upon getting a written approval guaranteeing that we will get fuel.",
        "However, SLTB Deputy General Manager Panduka Swarnahansa said that buses will run based on the number of employees present for duty. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SLTB",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Sri Lanka Transport Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10:00 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nurajith Singh",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "several months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Panduka Swarnahansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බලධාරීන් ප්‍රතිචාර නොදක්වන්නේ නම් සේවයෙන් ඉවත් වන බවට ලංගම TUs තර්ජනය කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයේ (ශ්‍රී ලංගම) වෘත්තීය සමිති තම සේවකයන්ට සේවයට වාර්තා කිරීමට ප්‍රමාණවත් ඉන්ධන ලබා නොදුනහොත් අද පෙරවරු 10:00 සිට සිය සියලු මෙහෙයුම්වලින් ඉවත් වීමට තීරණය කර ඇත.",
        "ලංගම වෘත්තීය සමිති ප්‍රධානී නුරාජිත් සිං පැවසුවේ මහජනතාවට ප්‍රවාහන පහසුකම් සැලසීම සඳහා තම සේවකයන් අලුයම සේවයට වාර්තා කළ යුතු බවයි. ඔවුන්ගෙන් බොහෝ දෙනෙක් යතුරුපැදි වැනි තමන්ගේම වාහන භාවිතා කරති. දැනට පවතින ඉන්ධන හිඟය හේතුවෙන් ඔවුන්ට සේවයට වාර්තා කිරීමට අපහසු වී තිබෙනවා.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් ගිලන් රථ වැනි අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය සේවා වාහන සඳහා ඉන්ධන නිකුත් කෙරේ. මේ හේතුවෙන් බස් රථ ධාවනයෙන් ඉවත් වීමට වෘත්තීය සමිති තීරණය කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "“මේ ප්‍රශ්නය අපි මාස ගණනාවක් වගකිවයුතු බලධාරීන්ට දැනුම් දුන්නත් කවුරුත් ඇහුම්කන් දුන්නේ නැහැ. හැමදාම පාන්දර 4.00ට කලින් රාජකාරියට වාර්තා කිරීමේදී ප්‍රායෝගික ගැටලු ඇතිවෙලා තියෙනවා.අපිට ගෙදර එන්න බස්වල යන්න බැහැ.ඒ නිසා අපිට අපේම වාහන පාවිච්චි කරන්න වෙනවා,\" නුරාජිත් සිං පැවසීය.",
        "ඉන්ධන ලබා දෙන බවට සහතික වී ලිඛිත අනුමැතියක් ලබා ගැනීමෙන් පසු අපි මෙම වෘත්තීය ක්‍රියාමාර්ගය අත්හරිනවා.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ශ්‍රී ලංගම නියෝජ්‍ය සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරී පණ්ඩුක ස්වර්ණහංස මහතා පැවසුවේ, රාජකාරි සඳහා පැමිණෙන සේවක සංඛ්‍යාව අනුව බස් රථ ධාවනය කෙරෙන බවයි. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලංගම",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10:00 පෙ.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුරාජිත් සිං",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාස කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පණ්ඩුක ස්වර්ණහංස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SLTB TU க்கள் அதிகாரிகள் பதிலளிக்காவிட்டால் சேவையிலிருந்து விலகுவதாக அச்சுறுத்துகின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் (SLTB) தொழிற்சங்கங்கள் தமது ஊழியர்களுக்கு பணிக்கு வருவதற்கு போதியளவு எரிபொருளை வழங்காவிட்டால், இன்று காலை 10:00 மணி முதல் தமது அனைத்து நடவடிக்கைகளிலிருந்தும் விலகுவதற்கு தீர்மானித்துள்ளன.",
        "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் தொழிற்சங்கங்களின் தலைவர் நுராஜித் சிங், பொதுமக்களுக்கு போக்குவரத்து வசதிகளை வழங்குவதற்காக தமது ஊழியர்கள் அதிகாலையில் பணிக்கு சமூகமளிக்க வேண்டுமென தெரிவித்துள்ளார். அவர்களில் பெரும்பாலானோர் மோட்டார் சைக்கிள் போன்ற சொந்த வாகனங்களைப் பயன்படுத்துகின்றனர். தற்போது நிலவும் எரிபொருள் தட்டுப்பாடு காரணமாக வேலைக்குச் செல்வதில் சிரமம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "எனினும், ஆம்புலன்ஸ் போன்ற அத்தியாவசிய சேவை வாகனங்களுக்கு எரிபொருள் வழங்கப்படும். இதனால் பேருந்துகளை இயக்குவதில் இருந்து வாபஸ் பெற தொழிற்சங்கங்கள் முடிவு செய்துள்ளன.",
        "இது குறித்து பல மாதங்களாக பொறுப்பான அதிகாரிகளிடம் புகார் தெரிவித்தும் யாரும் செவிசாய்க்கவில்லை. தினமும் அதிகாலை 4.00 மணிக்கு மேல் பணிக்கு வருவதில் எங்களுக்கு நடைமுறை சிக்கல்கள் உள்ளன. வீடு திரும்ப பஸ்சில் செல்ல முடியாது. அதனால் நாங்கள் எங்கள் சொந்த வாகனங்களைப் பயன்படுத்த வேண்டும், ”என்று நுராஜித் சிங் கூறினார்.",
        "எமக்கு எரிபொருளை பெற்றுக்கொடுக்கும் உத்தரவாதத்துடன் எழுத்து மூலமான அனுமதி கிடைத்தவுடன் இந்த தொழிற்சங்க நடவடிக்கையை கைவிடுவோம்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், கடமைக்கு வரும் ஊழியர்களின் எண்ணிக்கையின் அடிப்படையில் பஸ்கள் இயங்கும் என இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் பிரதிப் பொது முகாமையாளர் பண்டுக ஸ்வர்ணஹன்ச தெரிவித்தார். (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SLTB",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 10:00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுராஜித் சிங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பல மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாண்டுக ஸ்வர்ணஹன்சா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}