{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/29/another-sri-lankan-man-dies-while-waiting-for-fuel/",
  "time_ut": 1656499920,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Another Sri Lankan man dies while waiting for fuel",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Another Sri Lankan man dies while waiting for fuel",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Another Sri Lankan family lost their bread-winner who was at a fuel queue.",
        "A 53-year-old father of two died after he was knocked down by a lorry in Darga Town, Aluthgama while waiting for fuel last night.",
        "Report said that he was preparing to leave the filling station and head home when the tragedy struck.",
        "The driver of the Mathugama-bound lorry surrendered to the Police this morning.",
        "NO Petrol Shipment until 22nd July; 100,000 MT LP Gas available for next four months – Sagala Ratnayake",
        "‘One Country, One Law’ Task Force submits report to President"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "53-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aluthgama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mathugama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NO Petrol Shipment",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MT LP Gas",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "next four months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන බලාපොරොත්තුවෙන් සිටි තවත් ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයෙක් මිය යයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ඉන්ධන පෝලිමේ සිටි තවත් ශ්‍රී ලාංකික පවුලකට ඔවුන්ගේ පාන් දිනුම්කරු අහිමි විය.",
        "අළුත්ගම, දර්ගා නගරයේ දී ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීමට බලා සිටියදී ලොරි රථයක ගැටීමෙන් 53 හැවිරිදි දෙදරු පියෙකු ජීවිතක්ෂයට පත්වුණා.",
        "ඛේදවාචකය සිදු වූ විට ඔහු ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හලෙන් පිටවී නිවස බලා යාමට සූදානම් වෙමින් සිටි බව වාර්තාවේ.",
        "මතුගම දෙසට ධාවනය වූ ලොරි රථයේ රියදුරු අද පෙරවරුවේ පොලීසියට භාර වුණා.",
        "ජූලි 22 දක්වා පෙට්‍රල් නැව්ගත කිරීම නැත; ඉදිරි මාස හතර සඳහා මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 100,000 LP ගෑස් ලබා ගත හැකිය - සාගල රත්නායක",
        "‘එකම රටක්, එකම නීතියක්’ කාර්ය සාධක බලකාය ජනපතිට වාර්තාවක්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "53 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලුත්ගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මතුගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෙට්‍රල් නැව්ගත කිරීමක් නැත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MT LP ගෑස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි මාස හතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருளுக்காக காத்திருந்த மற்றுமொரு இலங்கையர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); மற்றுமொரு இலங்கைக் குடும்பம், எரிபொருள் வரிசையில் இருந்த தமது ரொட்டி-வெற்றியாளரை இழந்துள்ளது.",
        "அளுத்கம, தர்கா நகரில் நேற்றிரவு எரிபொருளுக்காக காத்திருந்த 53 வயதுடைய இரண்டு பிள்ளைகளின் தந்தை ஒருவர் லொறியில் மோதி உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "சோகம் ஏற்பட்டபோது அவர் எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையத்தை விட்டு வெளியேறி வீட்டிற்குச் செல்லத் தயாராகிக்கொண்டிருந்ததாக அறிக்கை கூறுகிறது.",
        "மத்துகம நோக்கிச் சென்ற லொறியின் சாரதி இன்று காலை பொலிஸில் சரணடைந்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜூலை 22 வரை பெட்ரோல் ஏற்றுமதி இல்லை; அடுத்த நான்கு மாதங்களுக்கு 100,000 MT LP எரிவாயு கிடைக்கும் – சாகல ரத்நாயக்க",
        "‘ஒரே நாடு, ஒரே சட்டம்’ பணிக்குழு ஜனாதிபதியிடம் அறிக்கை சமர்ப்பித்தது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "53 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அளுத்கம",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்துகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோல் ஏற்றுமதி இல்லை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MT LP எரிவாயு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த நான்கு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}