{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132244",
  "time_ut": 1658747097,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "பொன்னியின் செல்வனும்  இலங்கையும்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ponni's Selvan and Sri Lanka",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "Arunmozhivarman who rode on an elephant with a flute in Sri Lanka. Even though the bhikkhus requested him to be crowned as the king of this land, he left it and went across the sea to save Tamil Nadu. He traveled by ship and boat in Kodikkarai and became the emperor of the Chola Empire as Rajarajachola who ruled from Kumari in the south to Vengadam in the north.",
        "Kalki Ponni's Selvan would have solved the problem that we did not see him who lived with fame for more than a thousand years after building the world wonder Tanjore Periyar Temple. Ponniin Selvan is another name of Rajarajan.",
        "It is our duty to carry the wealth of Ponni to the next generation, which expresses the features that are ingrained in our blood as our culture. MGR to Kamal tried and failed to do that duty. Those who wanted to make Ponniyan Selvan as a yes film format were disappointed in the end. In this case, director Maniratnam has entered the field today.",
        "A few years ago, there were reports that Kalki's novel about Rajaraja Cholan had come to Sri Lanka for the shooting of Mani Ratnam. Mani Ratnam was said to have shot in Sri Lanka during the peak of Corona in India. Now the news regarding the release of the film has also arrived.",
        "In this case, let's see what is the relationship between Rajaraja Cholan and Sri Lanka, Rajaraja Cholan lived in Sri Lanka in his early years i.e. in his youth.",
        "Sri Lanka was one of their provinces during the Cholas period. Rajarajacholan's childhood name was Arunmozhivarman.",
        "When he was a child, he slipped and fell into the Ponni river. He was named Ponni's Selvan because it was believed that Ponni Nadi saved him who was swept away by the flood. Kalki wrote an epic under that name. Mani Ratnam is now making a film based on it.",
        "When Rajarajacholan lived in Sri Lanka, he traveled and lived in areas like Anuradhapuram, Polanarui, Tambullai and Sigiriya.",
        "A scene in Kalki's novel shows Sri Lanka so beautifully. Yes, it was the period when Rajarajacholan, who was then a prince, was in Sri Lanka. Vandiya Devan will come to Sri Lanka by sea from India to see him.",
        "When Vandiyathevan awoke, he was astonished by the sight that appeared in front of him and around him. The sun was rising on the eastern horizon.",
        "There the sea became a sea of ​​molten gold. Udayakumari shined with golden bangles. In front of him, in the direction the boat was going, an emerald island was visible, wrapped in blue sea. On the right side another similar green colored earth area was seen.",
        "It is not clear whether it is an island surrounded by sea on all four sides or a vast expanse of land. Looking through the two emerald territories in the distance many more such islands could be seen exemplifying the various combinations of green.",
        "Looking all around from the boat, the seven colors of the rainbow and its seven thousand mixed colors were present. All in all, the scene did not appear to be a real scene before the eyes. A master painter said, \"Here I show you what heaven looks like!\" That vow seemed like a colorful painting miracle.",
        "Vandiyadeva, who was oblivious to this sight, said, \"This is not heaven; this is Sri Lanka!\" The words fell and jolted him awake.",
        "\"This is not a paradise earth, but a heaven-like earth. For a long time, monsters in human form have been trying to make this heaven a hell,\" said Poonguzali.",
        "It is true that this paradise earth looks like hell today due to many monsters as Poonghujali said.",
        "Like Vandiyadevan, Alwarkadi comes to Sri Lanka and many incidents take place here are well described in the novel.",
        "In Sri Lanka, there are many Buddha paintings and Buddha statues in Tampullai Cave Temple. Not only that but there is a Vishnu temple adjacent to the hill. There are many Buddhist bhikkhus there. The cave is also a major tourist attraction. It is a huge stone built cave temple. Similarly, Sigiriya is a mountain hill.",
        "It looks like a lion lying on a flat surface. On top of that hill are the world famous Sigiriya Paintings. Kasiyappan is said to have painted those paintings. This is where Rajaraja Cholan's visit begins in Ponni's novel Selvan. From this Sigiriya, Rajarajacholan will come from Sigiriya along with the Chinese pilgrims as an elephant carriage, then Vandiyathevan and Alwarkadiyan from India will be standing at Dambulla.",
        "When Rajaraja Cholan from Sigiriya brings Chinese pilgrims on an elephant, his face is covered. Now we are covered with a cloth like we are covered with Korana. Only his eyes sparkle. By the light of those eyes, Alwarkadian will find out that this is Rajaraja Cholan. Scenes related to Temple Sigiriya up to Tampullai Cave are located in Ponni's Selvan.",
        "Similarly, the perahera happening in Sri Lanka is written like a movie in Thoranalang Ponni's Selvan novel, the scenes of perahera on the Anuradhapura road are similar to what we see today.",
        "Also, the scenes will be like Mandakini, who is one of the main characters of Ponni's Selvan, roaming around in the jungles of Sri Lanka. Kalki refers to Mandakini as a mute woman who cannot speak. Mandakini Devi has been protecting Raja Raja Chola from the dangers that come his way since his childhood. She likes to wear simple clothes and be in places where there are no people.",
        "Finally, Mandakini lives and dies as a woman who shows her affection for Chola's family, protecting Sundara Chola from danger until she dies. When Rajaraja Cholan was in Anuradhapuram, a wall collapsed on him. Even from that danger Mandakini will save Rajarajachola.",
        "Next, Poonguzhali and Rajarajacholan fall in love and everything happens mostly in Sri Lanka.",
        "Half of Ponni's Selvan's story takes place in Ilangi. It cannot be said that this is just a fantasy because even today there are many temples built by the Cholas in Polonnaruwa.",
        "Reading Ponni's Selvana is like watching a movie. Director Mani Ratnam has a challenge to take this as a film without diminishing this beauty.",
        "Many thought of making Ponni's Selvan and finally gave up. Even Mani Ratnam had previously wanted to make a film with Vijay and Mahesh Babu. But it was not possible..",
        "In this case, now the teaser of the movie has been released and it has received great response. The film is slated to hit the screens in September. Let's wait and see our country where Rajaraja Cholan roamed through Mani Ratnam's art.."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ponni",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Selvan",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Arunmozhivarman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kodikkarai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Chola Empire",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajarajachola",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumari",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vengadam",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kalki Ponni's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Selvan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than a thousand years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tanjore Periyar Temple",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ponniin Selvan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajarajan",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ponni",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ponniyan Selvan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maniratnam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "A few years ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalki",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mani Ratnam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mani Ratnam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Corona",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajaraja Cholan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cholas",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arunmozhivarman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ponni",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ponni Nadi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mani Ratnam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajarajacholan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapuram, Polanarui, Tambullai and Sigiriya",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kalki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajarajacholan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vandiya Devan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vandiyathevan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Udayakumari",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven thousand",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vandiyadeva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Poonguzali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poonghujali",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vandiyadevan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tampullai Cave Temple",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vishnu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sigiriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sigiriya Paintings",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kasiyappan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cholan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ponni",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Selvan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajarajacholan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vandiyathevan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alwarkadiyan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dambulla",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sigiriya",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alwarkadian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajaraja Cholan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tampullai Cave",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ponni",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thoranalang Ponni's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Selvan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mandakini",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ponni",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mandakini",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mandakini Devi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mandakini",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chola",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sundara Chola",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajaraja Cholan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapuram",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mandakini",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajarajachola",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Poonguzhali",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajarajacholan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Half",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ponni",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Selvan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ilangi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cholas",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polonnaruwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ponni",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Selvana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mani Ratnam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ponni",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mani Ratnam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vijay",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahesh Babu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "September",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajaraja Cholan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mani Ratnam's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පොන්නිගේ සෙල්වන් සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නළාවක් අතැතිව ඇතෙකු පිට නැඟුණු අරුන්මෝෂිවර්මන්. භික්ෂූන් වහන්සේ මේ බිමේ රජු ලෙස ඔටුනු පළඳවන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටියද, ඔහු එය අත්හැර තමිල්නාඩුව බේරා ගැනීමට මුහුද හරහා ගියේය. ඔහු කොඩික්කරේ ප්‍රදේශයේ නැවෙන් සහ ඔරුවෙන් ගමන් කර දකුණේ කුමාරි සිට උතුරේ වෙංගඩම් දක්වා පාලනය කළ රාජරාජචෝල නමින් චෝළ අධිරාජ්‍යයේ අධිරාජ්‍යයා බවට පත් විය.",
        "ලෝක ආශ්චර්ය තන්ජෝර් පෙරියාර් පන්සල ගොඩනගා වසර දහසකට වැඩි කාලයක් කීර්තියෙන් ජීවත් වූ ඔහු අපට නොදුටු ප්‍රශ්නය කල්කි පොන්නිගේ සෙල්වන් විසින් විසඳනු ඇත. පොන්නයින් සෙල්වන් යනු රාජරාජන්ගේ තවත් නමකි.",
        "අපේ සංස්කෘතිය ලෙස අපේ ලේ තුළට කිඳා බැස ඇති ලක්ෂණ ප්‍රකාශ කරන පොන්නිගේ ධනය මතු පරපුරට රැගෙන යාම අපේ යුතුකමකි. එම්ජීආර් සිට කමල් දක්වා එම රාජකාරිය කිරීමට උත්සාහ කර අසාර්ථක විය. පොන්නියන් සෙල්වන් ඔව් චිත්‍රපට ආකෘතියක් බවට පත් කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය වූවන් අවසානයේ බලාපොරොත්තු සුන් විය. මෙම නඩුවේදී අධ්‍යක්ෂක මනිරත්නම් අද ක්ෂේත්‍රයට පැමිණ ඇත.",
        "මීට වසර කිහිපයකට පෙර රාජරාජ චෝළන් පිළිබඳ කල්කිගේ නවකතාව මනි රත්නම්ගේ රූගත කිරීම් සඳහා ලංකාවට පැමිණි බවට වාර්තා පළ විය. ඉන්දියාවේ කොරොනා උච්චතම අවස්ථාව වන විට මනි රත්නම් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේදී රූගත කළ බව පැවසේ. දැන් චිත්‍රපටිය නිකුත් වෙන ආරංචියත් ඇවිත්.",
        "මෙම අවස්ථාවේ දී, රාජරාජ චෝළන් සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර ඇති සම්බන්ධය කුමක්දැයි බලමු, රාජරාජ චෝළන් ඔහුගේ මුල් අවදියේ එනම් තරුණ අවධියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජීවත් විය.",
        "චෝල යුගයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඔවුන්ගේ එක් පළාතක් විය. රාජරාජචෝලන්ගේ ළමා වියේ නම අරුන්මෝෂිවර්මන් ය.",
        "පොඩි කාලේ ලිස්සලා පොන්නි ගඟට වැටුණා. ඔහුට පොන්නිගේ සෙල්වන් යන නම ලැබුණේ ගංවතුරට ගසාගෙන ගිය ඔහුව පොන්නි නදී බේරා ගත් බව විශ්වාස කළ බැවිනි. කල්කි ඒ නමින් වීර කාව්‍යයක් ලිව්වා. මනි රත්නම් දැන් එය පාදක කරගෙන චිත්‍රපටයක් නිර්මාණය කරනවා.",
        "රාජරාජචෝලන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජීවත් වූ විට ඔහු අනුරාධපුරය, පොළනාරුයි, තඹුල්ලෙයි, සීගිරිය වැනි ප්‍රදේශවල සංචාරය කර වාසය කළේය.",
        "කල්කිගේ නවකතාවේ දර්ශනයක් ලංකාව කෙතරම් ලස්සනට පෙන්වයි. ඔව්, එවකට කුමාරයෙක්ව සිටි රාජරාජචෝලයන් ලංකාවේ සිටි කාලයයි. වන්දිය දේවන් ඔහු බැලීමට ඉන්දියාවේ සිට මුහුදු මාර්ගයෙන් ලංකාවට එනු ඇත.",
        "වණ්ඩියතේවන් අවදි වූ විට තමා ඉදිරියෙන් සහ අවටින් දිස් වූ දර්ශනයෙන් ඔහු විස්මයට පත් විය. නැඟෙනහිර ක්ෂිතිජයෙන් හිරු උදාවෙමින් තිබිණි.",
        "එහිදී මුහුද උණු කළ රන් මුහුදක් විය. උදයකුමාරි රන් වළලුවලින් බැබළුණාය. ඔහු ඉදිරියෙන්, බෝට්ටුව යන දිශාවට, නිල් මුහුදෙන් ඔතා ඇති මරකත දූපතක් දිස් විය. දකුණු පසින් තවත් එවැනිම කොළ පැහැති පෘථිවි ප්‍රදේශයක් දක්නට ලැබිණි.",
        "එය සතර දෙසින්ම මුහුදෙන් වට වූ දූපතක් ද නැතිනම් විශාල භූමි භාගයක් ද යන්න පැහැදිලි නැත. ඈතින් ඇති මරකත ප්‍රදේශ දෙක දෙස බලන විට හරිත වර්ණයෙන් යුත් විවිධ සංයෝජන නිදසුන් ලෙස තවත් එවැනි දූපත් රාශියක් දැකගත හැකි විය.",
        "බෝට්ටුවේ සිට වටපිට බැලූ විට දේදුන්නෙහි වර්ණ හත සහ එහි මිශ්‍ර වර්ණ හත්දහසක් දක්නට ලැබුණි. සමස්තයක් වශයෙන් ගත් කල, එම දර්ශනය ඇස් ඉදිරිපිට සැබෑ දර්ශනයක් ලෙස පෙනෙන්නට නොතිබුණි. ප්‍රවීණ චිත්‍ර ශිල්පියෙක් පැවසුවේ, \"මෙන්න මම ඔබට පෙන්වන්නේ ස්වර්ගය කෙබඳුද කියා!\" එම භාරය වර්ණවත් සිතුවම් ආශ්චර්යයක් ලෙස පෙනුණි.",
        "මේ දසුන නොදැක්කා සේ සිටි වන්දියදේව, \"මේ දෙව්ලොව නොවේ, මේ ලංකාවයි!\" වදන් බිම වැටී ඔහුව අවදි කළේය.",
        "\"මේක පාරාදීස පොළොවක් නෙවෙයි, අහසක් වගේ පොළොවක්. කාලයක් තිස්සේ මිනිස් ස්වරූපයෙන් ඉන්න රාක්ෂයෝ මේ දෙව්ලොව අපායක් කරන්න හදනවා\" පුංගුසාලි කීවාය.",
        "පූංගුජලී කීවාක් මෙන් මේ සුර පොළව අද අපායක් සේ පෙනෙන්නේ බොහෝ රාක්ෂයන් නිසා බව සැබෑය.",
        "වන්දියදේවන් මෙන්ම අල්වර්කාඩි ද ලංකාවට පැමිණෙන අතර මෙහි සිදුවන බොහෝ සිදුවීම් නවකතාවේ හොඳින් විස්තර කර ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තම්පුල්ලේ ලෙන් විහාරයේ බුද්ධ චිත්‍ර සහ බුද්ධ ප්‍රතිමා රාශියක් ඇත. ඒ විතරක් නෙවෙයි කන්දට යාබදව විෂ්ණු කෝවිලකුත් තියෙනවා. එහි බොහෝ බෞද්ධ භික්ෂූන් වහන්සේලා වැඩ සිටිනවා. ගුහාව ප්‍රධාන සංචාරක ආකර්ෂණයක් ද වේ. එය ගලින් තැනූ විශාල ලෙන් විහාරයකි. ඒ වගේ ම සීගිරිය කන්ද කන්දක්.",
        "එය පැතලි මතුපිටක් මත වැතිර සිටින සිංහයෙකු මෙන් පෙනේ. ඒ කඳු මුදුනේ ලෝක ප්‍රසිද්ධ සීගිරි චිත්‍ර තියෙනවා. එම චිත්‍ර ඇඳ ඇත්තේ කාසියප්පන් බව පැවසේ. පොන්නිගේ සෙල්වන් නවකතාවේ රාජරාජ චෝලන්ගේ සංචාරය ආරම්භ වන්නේ මෙතැනින්. මෙම සීගිරියේ සිට, රාජරාජචෝලයන් ඇත් කරත්තයක් ලෙස චීන වන්දනාකරුවන් සමඟ සීගිරියේ සිට පැමිණෙනු ඇත, එවිට ඉන්දියාවේ සිට වණ්ඩියතේවන් සහ අල්වර්කාඩියන් දඹුල්ලේ සිටගෙන සිටිති.",
        "සීගිරියේ සිට රාජරාජ චෝළන් ඇතෙකු පිට චීන වන්දනාකරුවන් රැගෙන එන විට ඔහුගේ මුහුණ වසා ඇත. දැන් අපිව කොරනවා වගේ රෙද්දකින් වහලා. ඔහුගේ ඇස් පමණක් දිදුලයි. ඒ ඇස්වල ආලෝකයෙන් අල්වාර්කාඩියන් මේ රාජරාජ චෝළන් බව සොයා ගනීවි. සීගිරි විහාරය හා සම්බන්ධ දර්ශන තම්පුල්ලේ ගුහාව දක්වා පොන්නිගේ සෙල්වන් හි පිහිටා ඇත.",
        "ඒ වගේ ම ලංකාවේ සිදුවන පෙරහැරත් තෝරනලං පොන්නිගේ සෙල්වන් නවකතාවේ චිත්‍රපටියක් වගේ ලියවිලා තියෙනවා, අනුරාධපුර පාරේ පෙරහැරේ දසුන් අද අපි දකින දේට සමානයි.",
        "ඒ වගේම පොන්නිගේ සෙල්වන්ගේ ප්‍රධාන චරිතයක් වන මන්දාකිණි ලංකාවේ කැලෑවල සැරිසරනවා වගේ දසුන්. කල්කි මන්දාකිනීව හඳුන්වන්නේ කතා කිරීමට නොහැකි ගොළු කාන්තාවක් ලෙසයි. මන්දාකිණි දේවි රාජ රාජ චෝළගේ කුඩා කල සිටම ඔහුට එන අනතුරු වලින් ඔහුව ආරක්ෂා කළාය. ඇය සරල ඇඳුම් ඇඳගෙන මිනිසුන් නොමැති ස්ථානවල සිටීමට කැමතියි.",
        "අවසානයේ මන්දාකිනී චෝළ පවුලට ආදරය දක්වන කාන්තාවක් ලෙස ජීවත් වී මිය යන්නේ සුන්දර චෝලයා මිය යන තුරුම අනතුරෙන් ආරක්ෂා කරමිනි. රාජරාජ චෝළන් අනුරාධපුරයේ සිටියදී තාප්පයක් කඩා වැටුණි. ඒ අනතුරෙන්වත් මන්දාකිණි රාජරාජචෝලව බේරගන්නවා.",
        "ඊළඟට, පූංගුෂාලි සහ රාජරාජචෝලන් ආදරයෙන් බැඳෙන අතර සෑම දෙයක්ම බොහෝ දුරට සිදුවන්නේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ය.",
        "පොන්නිගේ සෙල්වන්ගේ කතාවෙන් අඩක් සිදු වන්නේ ඉලංගි තුළය. මෙය හුදු මනඃකල්පිතයක් යැයි කිව නොහැක්කේ අදටත් පොළොන්නරුවේ චෝලයන් විසින් කරවන ලද විහාරස්ථාන රාශියක් ඇති බැවිනි.",
        "පොන්නිගේ සෙල්වනා කියවනවා කියන්නේ චිත්‍රපටියක් බැලුවා වගේ වැඩක්. මනි රත්නම් අධ්‍යක්ෂවරයාට අභියෝගයක් තියෙනවා මේ සුන්දරත්වය අඩු නොකර මේක චිත්‍රපටයක් විදියට ගන්න.",
        "ගොඩක් අය පොන්නිගේ සෙල්වන් කරන්න හිතාගෙන අන්තිමට වැඩේ අතෑරියා. මනි රත්නම්ට පවා මීට පෙර විජේ සහ මහේෂ් බාබු සමඟ චිත්‍රපටයක් කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය විය. ඒත් බැරි උනා..",
        "මේ වනවිට එම චිත්‍රපටයේ පූර්ව ප්‍රචාරක පටය නිකුත් වී ඇති අතර එයට ඉහළ ප්‍රතිචාර ලැබී තිබෙනවා. චිත්‍රපටිය සැප්තැම්බර් මාසයේදී තිරගත වීමට නියමිතයි. මනි රත්නම්ගේ කලාව හරහා රාජරාජ චෝළන් සැරිසැරූ අපේ රට බලා සිටිමු.."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පොන්නි",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "සෙල්වන්",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අරුන්මෝෂිවර්මන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kodikkarai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චෝල අධිරාජ්‍යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජරාජචෝල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාරි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙන්ගඩම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කල්කි පොන්නිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙල්වන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර දහසකට වඩා වැඩි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තන්ජෝර් පෙරියාර් පන්සල",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොන්නයින් සෙල්වන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජරාජන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොන්නි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොන්නියන් සෙල්වන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනිරත්නම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වසර කිහිපයකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කල්කි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනි රත්නම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනි රත්නම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරෝනා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජරාජ චෝලන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චෝලයන්",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරුන්මෝෂිවර්මන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොන්නි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොන්නි නදී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනි රත්නම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජරාජචෝලන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුරය, පොළනාරුයි, තඹුල්ලෙයි සහ සීගිරිය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කල්කි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජරාජචෝලන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වන්දිය දේවන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වන්දියතේවන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උදයකුමාරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හත් දහසක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වන්දියදේව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුංගුසාලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුංගුජලී",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වන්දියදේවන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුද්ධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුද්ධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තම්පුල්ලේ ලෙන් විහාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විෂ්ණු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීගිරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සීගිරි සිතුවම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාසියප්පන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චෝලන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොන්නි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙල්වන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජරාජචෝලන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "වන්දියතේවන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල්වර්කාඩියන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දඹුල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සීගිරිය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල්වර්කාඩියන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජරාජ චෝලන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තම්පුල්ලේ ගුහාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොන්නි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තොරනලං පොන්නිගෙ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙල්වන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මන්දාකිනි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොන්නි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්දාකිනි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්දාකිණි දේවි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මන්දාකිනි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චෝල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුන්දර චෝල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජරාජ චෝලන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්දාකිනි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජරාජචෝල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුංගුෂාලි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජරාජචෝලන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඩක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොන්නි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙල්වන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉලංගි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චෝලයන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොළොන්නරුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොන්නි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙල්වනා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනි රත්නම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොන්නි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනි රත්නම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහේෂ් බාබු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජරාජ චෝලන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනි රත්නම්ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பொன்னியின் செல்வனும்  இலங்கையும்",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையில் பூங்குழலியோடு  யானை மீது சவாரி செய்த அருண்மொழிவர்மன். இந்த மண்ணுக்கு மன்னனாக முடி சூட்டிக்கொள்ளுமாறு பிக்குகள் கோரிக்கை விடுத்த போதும் அதனை விட்டு தமிழ்நாட்டை காப்பாற்ற கடல் தாண்டி சென்றான். கோடிக்கரையில்  கப்பலிலும்... படகிலும்  பயணித்தவன் சோழ சாம்ராஜ்ஜியத்தின் சக்கரவர்த்தியாக மாறி  ராஜராஜசோழனாக தெற்கே குமரி முதல் வடக்கே வேங்கடம் வரை ஆட்சி புரிந்தான்.",
        "உலக அதிசயமான தஞ்சை பெரியார் கோயிலை கட்டியமைத்து ஆயிரம் வருடங்களுக்கு மேலும் , நீங்க புகழுடன் மரணத்தை கடந்து வாழும் அவனை  நாம் நேரில் காணாது தவறவிட்டோம் என்ற குறையை  கல்கி பொன்னியின் செல்வனில் தீர்த்திருப்பார். பொன்னியின் செல்வன் என்பதும் ராஜராஜனின் இன்னொரு பெயர்தான்.",
        "நமது பண்பாடு கலாசாரம் என நமது இரத்தத்தில் ஊரிப்போன அம்சங்களை பறைசாற்றும் பொன்னியின் செல்வனை அடுத்த தலைமுறைக்கு கொண்டு செல்ல வேண்டிய கடமை நம்மிடம் உள்ளது. அந்த கடமையை  எம்.ஜி.ஆர் முதல் கமல் வரை  செய்வதற்கு முயற்சித்து முடியாமல் போய்விட்டது. ஆம் திரைப்பட வடிவமாக பொன்னியன் செல்வனை உருவாக்க நினைத்தவர்களுக்கு இறுதியில் ஏமாற்றமே மிஞ்சியது.  இந்நிலையில்  இயக்குநர் மணிரத்தினம் இன்று களத்தில் இறங்கியுள்ளார்.",
        "ராஜராஜ சோழன் பற்றிய கல்கியின் நவாலை சினிமாவாக எடுக்கப்போகும் மணிரத்தினம் படப்பிடிப்புக்காக இலங்கை வந்ததாக செய்திகள் சில வருடங்களுக்கு முன்னர் வெளியாகியிருந்தன.  இந்தியாவில் கொரோனா உச்சத்தில் இருந்த காலத்தில் இலங்கையில் மணிரத்னம் படப்பிடிப்பு நடத்தியதாக கூறப்பட்டது. தற்போது படத்தின் வெளியீடு தொடர்பான செய்தியும் வந்துவிட்டது.",
        "இந்நிலையில், ராஜராஜ சோழனுக்கும்   இலங்கைக்கும் என்ன சம்பந்தம் இருக்கிறது என்று  பார்ப்போம், ராஜராஜ சோழன் ஆரம்ப காலத்தில் அதாவது இளமைக்காலத்தில்  இலங்கையில்தான்  வாழ்ந்திருக்கிறார் .",
        "சோழர்கள் காலத்தில் அவர்களின் மாகாணங்களில் ஒன்றாகவே  இலங்கை இருந்திருக்கிறது.   ராஜராஜசோழனின் சிறுவயதில்  அவரது பெயர் அருண்மொழிவர்மன்.",
        "அவர் குழந்தையாக இருக்கும்பொழுது   பொன்னி நதியில் தவறி விழுந்து விடுகிறார்.  வெள்ளத்தில் அடித்து செல்லப்பட்டவரை  காப்பாற்றியது பொன்னி நதி என கருதப்பட்டதினாலேயே,  அவருக்கு பொன்னியின் செல்வன் என்ற பெயர் உருவானது.  அந்தப் பெயரிலேயே கல்கி காவியம் படைத்தார். அதனை தழுவியே  மணிரத்தினம் இப்பொழுது  திரைப்படத்தை எடுக்கிறார்.",
        "ராஜராஜசோழன் இலங்கையில் வாழ்ந்த பொழுது அனுராதபுரம், பொலனறுவை ,தம்புள்ளை , சீகிரியா போன்ற பிரதேசங்களில் அவர் வலம் வந்திருக்கிறார் வாழ்ந்திருக்கிறார்.",
        "கல்கியின் நாவலில் ஒரு காட்சி இலங்கையை அத்தனை அழகாக காட்டுகின்றது. ஆம், அப்போது இளவரசராக இருந்த ராஜராஜசோழன் இலங்கையில் இருந்த கால கட்டம். வந்திய தேவன் இந்தியாவிலிருந்து கடல்வழி மார்க்கமாக  அவரை பார்ப்பதற்காக  இலங்கை வருவார்.",
        "‘’வந்தியத்தேவன் கண் விழித்தபோது, அவன் எதிரேயும் சுற்றிலும் தோன்றிய காட்சி அவனைப் பிரமிக்கச் செய்தது. கிழக்கே வானமுகட்டில் சூரியன் உதயமாகிக் கொண்டிருந்தான்.",
        "அங்கே கடல் உருக்கிவிட்ட தங்கக் கடலாகித் தகதகவென்று திகழ்ந்தது. உதயகுமாரி தங்கப் பட்டாடை புனைந்து கொண்டு ஜொலித்தாள். அவனுக்கு எதிரே படகு போய்க் கொண்டிருந்த திசையில் ஒரு மரகதத் தீவு நீலக் கடலாடை போர்த்துக்கொண்டு விளங்கியது. வலப்புறத்தில் அதே மாதிரி இன்னொரு பச்சை வர்ண பூமிப் பிரதேசம் காணப்பட்டது.",
        "அது நாலு புறமும் கடல் சூழ்ந்த தீவா அல்லது நீண்டு பரந்து வியாபித்துள்ள பூமிப் பிரதேசமா என்று நன்றாகத் தெரியவில்லை. இரண்டு மரகதப் பிரதேசங்களுக்கும் ஊடே பார்த்தால் தூரத்தில் அத்தகைய இன்னும் பல தீவுகள் பச்சை நிறத்தின் பல்வேறு வகைக் கலவைகளுக்கு உதாரணமாகத் தோன்றிக் கொண்டிருந்தன.",
        "படகிலிருந்தபடியே நாலுபுறமும் சுற்றிப் பார்த்தால், வானவில்லின் ஏழுவித வர்ணங்களும் அதன் ஏழாயிரம் வகைக் கலவை நிறங்களும் திகழ்ந்தன. மொத்தத்தில் அந்தக் காட்சி கண்ணெதிரே காணும் உண்மைக் காட்சியாகவே தோன்றவில்லை. ஓவியக் கலையில் தேர்ந்த அமர கலைஞன் ஒருவன், \"இதோ சொர்க்கலோகம் எப்படியிருக்கும் என்று காட்டுகிறேன்!\" என்று சபதம் பூண்டு தீட்டிய வர்ணச் சித்திர அற்புதம் போலவே தோன்றியது.",
        "இந்தக் காட்சியைக் கண்டு மெய்ம்மறந்து நினைவிழந்திருந்த வந்தியத்தேவனுடைய செவியில், \"இது சொர்க்கம் அல்ல; இது இலங்கை!\" என்ற வார்த்தைகள் விழுந்து அவனை விழிப்படையச் செய்தன.",
        "\"இது சொர்க்க பூமி அல்ல; ஆனால் சொர்க்கம் போன்ற பூமி. இந்த சொர்க்கத்தை நரகமாக்குவதற்கு மனித உருக் கொண்ட அசுரர்கள் வெகு காலமாகப் பிரயத்தனப்பட்டு வருகிறார்கள்\" என்றாள் பூங்குழலி.",
        "உண்மைதான் பூங்குழலி சொல்லியது போல பல அரக்கர்களினால் இந்த சொர்க்க பூமி இன்று நரகமாக காட்சியளிக்கின்றது.",
        "வந்தியதேவனை போலவே ஆழ்வார்கடியேனும் இலங்கை  வருவதும் இங்கு பல சம்பவங்கள் நடைபெறுவதும் நாவலில் சிறப்பாக வர்ணிக்கப்பட்டிருக்கும்.",
        "இலங்கையில் தம்புள்ளை  குகைவரை  கோயிலில் புத்தருடைய ஓவியம் , புத்தர்சிலைகள்தான் அதிகம் உள்ளன. அது மட்டும் அல்லாது விஸ்ணு ஆலயம் அருகில் மலையோடு ஒட்டி உள்ளது. அங்கு பெளத்த பிக்குகளே அதிகம் உள்ளனர். இந்த குகை ஒரு பிரதான சுற்றுலாத்தலமும் கூட.  கற்களால் அமைக்கப்பட்ட மிகப்பெரிய ஒரு குகைக்கோயில்தான்.  இதேபோல சிகிரியா என்பது மலை குன்று.",
        "தட்டையான பகுதியில் ஒரு சிங்கம் படுத்திருப்பது போல இருக்கும்.  அந்த குன்றின் மேல்தான்    உலகப் புகழ்பெற்ற சிகிரியா ஓவியங்கள் உள்ளன. காசியப்பன்தான் அந்த ஓவியங்களை வரைந்ததாக கூறப்படுகின்றது. பொன்னியின் செல்வன் நாவலில்   ராஜராஜா சோழனின் வருகை  இங்குதான் ஆரம்பமாகும். இந்த சிகிரியாவிலிருந்து சீன யாத்திரிகளோடு  யானைப் பாகனாக அவர்களை அழைத்துக்கொண்டு ராஜராஜசோழன் சிகிரியாவில் இருந்து வருவார் அப்பொழுது இந்தியாவிலிருந்து வந்த வந்தியத்தேவனும் ஆழ்வார்க்கடியானும்  தம்புள்ளையில் நின்று கொண்டிருப்பார்கள் .",
        "சிகிரியாவில் இருந்து ராஜராஜ சோழன் சீன யாத்திரிகர்களை யானையில் ஏறிக்கொண்டு யானைப் பாகனாக வரும் போது  அவரது முகம் மூடி இருக்கும். இப்பொழுது நாம் கொரானாவுக்கு மூடியிருப்பது போல துணியால் மறைத்திருப்பார்.  அவருடைய கண்கள் மட்டும் மிளிரும். அந்தக் கண்களின் ஒளியை  வைத்து ஆழ்வார்க்கடியான் இதுதான் ராஜராஜ சோழன் என்று கண்டுபிடித்து விடுவார். தம்புள்ளை குகைவரை கோயில் சிகிரியா தொடர்பில் காட்சிகள் பொன்னியின் செல்வனில் இடம் பெற்றிருக்கும்.",
        "அதுபோல இலங்கையில் நடக்கும் பெரஹரா, தோரணங்கள் பொன்னியின் செல்வன் நாவலில் திரைப்படம் போல எழுதப்பட்டிருக்கும், அனுராதபுர வீதியில் பெரஹேரா வரும் காட்சிகள் நாம் இன்று பார்ப்பது போலவே இருக்கும்.",
        "மேலும், பொன்னியின் செல்வனின் முக்கிய பாத்திரங்களில் ஒன்றாக இருக்கும் மந்தாகினி இலங்கையில் காடுகளில் சுற்றித்திரிவது போலவும் காட்சிகள் அமைந்திருக்கும். மந்தாகினியை வாய் பேச முடியாத ஊமைப்பெண் என்றே குறிப்பிடுகிறார் கல்கி. ராஜ ராஜ சோழனுக்கு சிறுவயதில் இருந்து   வரும் ஆபத்துகளிலிருந்து காக்கும் கடவுளாக மந்தாகினி தேவி வருகிறார். எளிய உடை அணிவதிலும், மக்கள் இல்லாத இடங்களிலும் இருக்க ஆசை கொள்கிறாள்.",
        "இறுதியாக சுந்தர சோழருக்கு வரும் ஆபத்திலிருந்து அவரை காத்து தான் மடியும் வரை சோழரின் குடும்பத்தின் மீதான பாசத்தினை வெளிக்காட்டும் அபலைப் பெண்ணாகவே மந்தாகினி வாழ்ந்து மடிகிறார். அனுராத புரத்தில் ராஜராஜ சோழன் இருக்கும் போது அவர் மீது சுவர் ஒன்று இடிந்து விழ போகும், . அந்த ஆபத்தில் இருந்தும்  கூட மந்தாகினிதான் ராஜராஜசோழனை காப்பாற்றுவார்.",
        "அடுத்து பூங்குழலியும் ராஜராஜசோழனும் காதல் வசப்படுவது என அனைத்தும் இலங்கையிலேயே அதிகம் நடப்பதாக இருக்கும்.",
        "இப்படி பொன்னியின் செல்வனின் பாதி கதை இலங்யைில்தான் நடக்கும். இது வெறும் கற்பனை என்று கூறிவிட முடியாது காரணம், இன்றும் சோழர்களினால் கட்டப்பட்ட சிவாலயங்கள் பல பொலன்னறுவையில் இன்றும் இருப்பது இதற்கு சான்று.",
