{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Fuel-needed-for-gem-industry-in-Ratnapura-under-QR-code-soon-Minister/108-244151",
  "time_ut": 1662044729,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Fuel needed for gem industry in Ratnapura under QR code soon: Minister",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Fuel needed for gem industry in Ratnapura under QR code soon: Minister",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Necessary measures will be taken for the delivery of fuel through Sri Lanka Transport Board (SLTB) depots for 4,000 gem miners in Ratnapura district who are engaged in the gem mining industry, Plantation Industries and Minister of Industries Minister Ramesh Pathirana said.",
        "He said this while addressing a special meeting between Ratnapura Miners, Gem Traders Association and Plantation Industries at Ratnapura yesterday.",
        "He also said that the Minister will take actions to introduce a program to obtain the fuel required for the gem industry from other petrol stations through QR code in collaboration with the Power and Energy Ministry. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ratnapura",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "under QR",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Transport Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Plantation Industries",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramesh Pathirana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura Miners",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gem Traders Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Plantation Industries",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "QR",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Power and Energy Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "QR කේතය යටතේ රත්නපුර මැණික් කර්මාන්තයට ඉන්ධන ඉක්මනින් අවශ්‍යයි: ඇමති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රත්නපුර දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ මැණික් පතල් කර්මාන්තයේ යෙදී සිටින මැණික් පතල්කරුවන් 4000ක් සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයේ (ශ්‍රී ලංගම) ඩිපෝ හරහා ඉන්ධන ලබාදීමට අවශ්‍ය පියවර ගන්නා බව වැවිලි කර්මාන්ත හා කර්මාන්ත අමාත්‍ය රමේෂ් පතිරණ මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ඔහු මේ බව කියා සිටියේ රත්නපුර පතල් කම්කරුවන්, මැණික් ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්ගේ සංගමය සහ වැවිලි කර්මාන්ත ආයතන අතර රත්නපුරයේදී ඊයේ පැවති විශේෂ හමුවකට එක්වෙමින්.",
        "මැණික් කර්මාන්තයට අවශ්‍ය ඉන්ධන අනෙකුත් ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල්වලින් QR කේතය හරහා ලබාගැනීමේ වැඩපිළිවෙළක් විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍යාංශය සමඟ එක්ව හඳුන්වාදීමට අමාත්‍යවරයා කටයුතු කරන බවද ඔහු පැවසීය. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රත්නපුරය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "QR යටතේ",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැවිලි කර්මාන්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රමේෂ් පතිරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුර පතල් කම්කරුවන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැණික් වෙළෙඳ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැවිලි කර්මාන්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "QR",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இரத்தினபுரியில் இரத்தினக்கல் தொழிலுக்கு QR குறியீட்டின் கீழ் எரிபொருள் விரைவில் தேவை: அமைச்சர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இரத்தினபுரி மாவட்டத்தில் இரத்தினக்கல் அகழ்வு தொழிலில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள 4,000 இரத்தினக்கல் சுரங்கத் தொழிலாளர்களுக்கு இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் (SLTB) களஞ்சியசாலைகள் ஊடாக எரிபொருளை வழங்குவதற்கு தேவையான நடவடிக்கைகள் எடுக்கப்படும் என பெருந்தோட்ட கைத்தொழில் மற்றும் கைத்தொழில் அமைச்சர் ரமேஷ் பத்திரன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இரத்தினபுரி சுரங்கத் தொழிலாளர்கள், இரத்தினக்கல் வர்த்தகர்கள் சங்கம் மற்றும் பெருந்தோட்டக் கைத்தொழில்களுக்கு இடையில் இரத்தினபுரியில் நேற்று இடம்பெற்ற விசேட சந்திப்பில் கலந்து கொண்டு உரையாற்றும் போதே அவர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சின் ஒத்துழைப்புடன் இரத்தினக்கல் தொழிற்துறைக்கு தேவையான எரிபொருளை QR குறியீட்டின் ஊடாக ஏனைய எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையங்களில் இருந்து பெற்றுக்கொள்ளும் வேலைத்திட்டத்தை அறிமுகப்படுத்துவதற்கு அமைச்சர் நடவடிக்கை எடுப்பதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார். (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரத்தினபுரி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "QR கீழ்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தோட்டத் தொழில்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரமேஷ் பத்திரன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி சுரங்கத் தொழிலாளர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரத்தின வியாபாரிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தோட்டத் தொழில்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "QR",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}