{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-pm-wickremesinghes-private-residence-set-on-fire-97201/",
  "time_ut": 1657382280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka PM Wickremesinghe’s private residence set on fire",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka PM Wickremesinghe’s private residence set on fire",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – A group of people gathered outside Sri Lanka Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe’s private residence has broken in and set the place on fire, the Prime Minister’s office said.",
        "Protestors had gathered outside Wickremesinghe’s residence on 5th Lane, Colombo, demanding his resignation, hours after hundreds of protestors stormed President Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s official residence demanding his resignation.",
        "“Protesters have broken into the private residence of Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe and have set it on fire,” a statement from the PM’s office said Saturday July 09 evening.",
        "Earlier in the evening, a group of journalists covering the protest were brutally assaulted by police personnel, which Wickremesinghe expressed his regret over.",
        "Sri Lanka PM regrets assault on journos, police chief to take action",
        "Protesters have attacked and set on fire the private residence of Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe. #Lka pic.twitter.com/YlaLpTJQ4V",
        "It is unclear at present who carried out the arson attack. (Colombo/Jul09/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5th Lane, Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "hundreds",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PM",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Earlier in the evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "#",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lka pic.twitter.com/YlaLpTJQ4V",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා අගමැති වික්‍රමසිංහගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ගිනි තබයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට පිටතින් රැස්ව සිටි පිරිසක් කඩා වැදී එම ස්ථානයට ගිනි තබා ඇති බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලය පවසයි.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බලකරමින් සිය ගනනක් විරෝධතාකරුවන් ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ නිල නිවසට කඩා වැදී පැය කිහිපයකට පසු විරෝධතාකරුවන් ඔහුට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බලකරමින් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ නිවස ඉදිරිපිට රැස්ව සිටියහ.",
        "\"විරෝධතාකරුවන් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට කඩා වැදී ගිනි තබා ඇත\" යනුවෙන් ජුලි 09 සෙනසුරාදා සවස අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයේ ප්‍රකාශයක් නිකුත් විය.",
        "ඊට පෙර සවස් වරුවේ විරෝධතාව ආවරණය කරමින් සිටි මාධ්‍යවේදීන් පිරිසකට පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් විසින් අමානුෂික ලෙස පහර දුන් අතර, ඒ පිළිබඳව වික්‍රමසිංහ සිය කණගාටුව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහරදීම ගැන ශ්‍රී ලංකා අගමැති කනගාටුව, පොලිස් ප්‍රධානියා පියවර ගන්න",
        "විරෝධතාකරුවන් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ප්‍රහාර එල්ල කර ගිනි තබා තිබේ. #Lka pic.twitter.com/YlaLpTJQ4V",
        "මෙම ගිනි තැබීම සිදු කළේ කවුරුන්ද යන්න දැනට පැහැදිලි නැත. (කොළඹ/ජූලි 09/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 වන පටුමග, කොළඹ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිය ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PM",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කලින් හවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": null,
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lka pic.twitter.com/YlaLpTJQ4V",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை பிரதமர் விக்ரமசிங்கேவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லம் தீ வைத்து எரிக்கப்பட்டது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கை பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்திற்கு வெளியே கூடியிருந்த மக்கள் குழுவொன்று அத்துமீறி நுழைந்து அந்த இடத்திற்கு தீ வைத்துள்ளதாக பிரதமர் அலுவலகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவை ராஜினாமா செய்யக் கோரி நூற்றுக்கணக்கான ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் அவரது உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லத்தை முற்றுகையிட்ட சில மணிநேரங்களுக்குப் பிறகு, அவர் பதவி விலகுமாறு கோரி கொழும்பு 5 வது லேனில் உள்ள விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் இல்லத்திற்கு வெளியே ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் கூடினர்.",
        "\"பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்தை போராட்டக்காரர்கள் உடைத்து தீ வைத்துள்ளனர்\" என்று பிரதமர் அலுவலகம் சனிக்கிழமை மாலை 09 மாலை வெளியிட்ட அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "முன்னதாக மாலையில், போராட்டத்தை செய்தி சேகரிக்கும் ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் குழு ஒன்று காவல்துறையினரால் கொடூரமாக தாக்கப்பட்டது, இது குறித்து விக்கிரமசிங்க வருத்தம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மீதான தாக்குதலுக்கு இலங்கை பிரதமர் வருந்துகிறார், பொலிஸ்மா அதிபர் நடவடிக்கை எடுக்க வேண்டும்",
        "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்தின் மீது ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் தாக்குதல் நடத்தி தீவைத்துள்ளனர். #Lka pic.twitter.com/YlaLpTJQ4V",
        "இந்த தீவைப்பு தாக்குதலை நடத்தியது யார் என்பது தற்போது தெரியவில்லை. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை09/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5வது லேன், கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நூற்றுக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முன்னதாக மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": null,
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lka pic.twitter.com/YlaLpTJQ4V",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}