{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lankas-runaway-ex-president-to-return-on-aug-24-report-98700/",
  "time_ut": 1660731720,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s runaway ex president to return on Aug 24: report",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s runaway ex president to return on Aug 24: report",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa who fled the country in early July following a wave of protests will be returning to Sri Lanka on August 24, a family member and former diplomat was quoted by media reports as saying.",
        "The privately owned NewsFirst network reported on Wednesday August 17 quoting ex-Ambassador to Russia Udayanga Weeratunga that Rajapaksa will return to Sri Lanka next week.",
        "Weeratunga had made this remark after giving a statement to the Criminal Investigation Department (CID) Wednesday afternoon.",
        "Former President Rajapaksa, who fled the country after protestors stormed his official residence in Colombo, is currently in Bangkok, Thailand. He arrived there on August 12 after a brief stay in Singapore.",
        "Rajapaksa resigned from the presidency after mass protests against the worst currency crisis in the history of the island’s intermediate regime central bank."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "24",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "early July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NewsFirst",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday August 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia Udayanga Weeratunga",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangkok",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පැන ගිය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා අගෝස්තු 24 වැනිදා යළි දිවයිනට: වාර්තාව",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාව විරෝධතා රැල්ලක් හේතුවෙන් ජූලි මස මුලදී රටින් පලා ගිය හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ අගෝස්තු 24 වන දින නැවත ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙන බව පවුලේ සාමාජිකයෙකු සහ හිටපු රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රිකයෙකු උපුටා දක්වමින් මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ලබන සතියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙන බව රුසියාවේ හිටපු තානාපති උදයංග වීරතුංග උපුටා දක්වමින් පුද්ගලික අයිතිය ඇති NewsFirst ජාලය අගෝස්තු 17 බදාදා වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "වීරතුංග මහතා මේ බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේ බදාදා පස්වරුවේ අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට (CID) ප්‍රකාශයක් ලබාදීමෙන් අනතුරුවය.",
        "කොළඹ පිහිටි ඔහුගේ නිල නිවසට විරෝධතාකරුවන් කඩා වැදීමෙන් පසු රටින් පලා ගිය හිටපු ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ මේ වන විට තායිලන්තයේ බැංකොක් නුවර රැඳී සිටියි. ඔහු සිංගප්පූරුවේ කෙටි නවාතැනකින් පසු අගෝස්තු 12 වැනිදා එහි පැමිණියේය.",
        "දිවයිනේ අතරමැදි පාලන තන්ත්‍රයේ මහ බැංකු ඉතිහාසයේ දරුණුතම මුදල් අර්බුදයට එරෙහිව මහජන විරෝධතාවලින් පසු රාජපක්ෂ ජනාධිපති ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "24",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NewsFirst",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 17 බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව උදයංග වීරතුංග",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැංකොක්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தப்பியோடிய இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் அதிபர் ஆகஸ்ட் 24ஆம் தேதி நாடு திரும்புவார்: அறிக்கை",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - எதிர்ப்பு அலைகளை அடுத்து ஜூலை மாத தொடக்கத்தில் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறிய இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச ஆகஸ்ட் 24 ஆம் திகதி இலங்கைக்கு திரும்பவுள்ளதாக அவரது குடும்ப உறுப்பினரும் முன்னாள் இராஜதந்திரியுமான ஊடக அறிக்கைகள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "ராஜபக்ச அடுத்த வாரம் இலங்கைக்கு திரும்புவார் என்று ரஷ்யாவுக்கான முன்னாள் தூதுவர் உதயங்க வீரதுங்கவை மேற்கோள்காட்டி ஆகஸ்ட் 17 புதன் அன்று தனியாருக்கு சொந்தமான நியூஸ்ஃபர்ஸ்ட் வலையமைப்பு செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "புதன்கிழமை பிற்பகல் குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களத்தில் (CID) வாக்குமூலம் வழங்கியதன் பின்னர் வீரதுங்க இதனைக் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "கொழும்பில் உள்ள அவரது உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லத்தை போராட்டக்காரர்கள் முற்றுகையிட்டதையடுத்து நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறிய முன்னாள் அதிபர் ராஜபக்சே தற்போது தாய்லாந்தின் பாங்காக்கில் தங்கியுள்ளார். சிங்கப்பூரில் சிறிது காலம் தங்கியிருந்த அவர் ஆகஸ்ட் 12ஆம் தேதி அங்கு வந்தார்.",
        "தீவின் இடைநிலை ஆட்சி மத்திய வங்கியின் வரலாற்றில் மிக மோசமான நாணய நெருக்கடிக்கு எதிரான வெகுஜன எதிர்ப்புகளுக்குப் பிறகு ராஜபக்சே ஜனாதிபதி பதவியை ராஜினாமா செய்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "24",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நியூஸ்ஃபர்ஸ்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 17 புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா உதயங்க வீரதுங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாங்காக்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}