{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/26/sjb-set-to-vote-against-emergency-law/",
  "time_ut": 1658836680,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SJB set to vote against Emergency Law",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SJB set to vote against Emergency Law",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The working committee of the Samagi Jana Balawegaya has decided to use their vote against the Emergency Law during the debat at the Parliament tomorrow (27).",
        "According to the Samagi Jana Balawegaya, it was unanimously decided to vote against the emergency law which is brought with the aim of suppressing the right to express opinions, the right to protest, and the right to express opinions against the issues faced by the people on a daily basis.",
        "Moreover, the Samagi Jana Balawegaya decided not to associate itself with the Government that is unleashing violence amongst the people without providing real solutions to the issues which plague them.",
        "However, the Samagi Jana Balawegaya decided to support if a committee system is enacted within the Parliament to find solutions to the issues of the people.",
        "The Parliament is set to convene tomorrow (27) and the proclamation on the state of emergency declared by the President on 17th July is set to be debated.",
        "Meanwhile, MP Tissa Attanayake emphasized that the Samagi Jana Balawegaya will not be accepting any Cabinet Ministerial positions, however will continue to function as the Opposition with the wellbeing of the people in mind.",
        "MP Rauff Hakeem, when inquired about the possible formation of an all-party Government, said that it will take a longer time to implement, in light of the 22nd Amendment, which is yet to be presented to Parliament. However, SJB MP Eran Wickramarathne said that the SJB, as a party, is ready to come forward for the formation of an all-party Government, if the present administration agrees to move into a General Election and upholds human rights.",
        "Five COVID deaths for Monday (25), over 100 cases today (26)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SJB",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Emergency Law",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Emergency Law",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17th July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet Ministerial",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rauff Hakeem",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eran Wickramarathne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "General Election",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SJB හදිසි නීතියට එරෙහිව ඡන්දය දීමට සූදානම් වෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); හෙට (27) පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ පැවැත්වෙන විවාදයේදී හදිසි නීතියට එරෙහිව ඡන්දය භාවිත කිරීමට සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ කෘත්‍යාධිකාරී මණ්ඩලය තීරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "මත ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමේ අයිතිය, විරෝධතා දැක්වීමේ අයිතිය සහ ජනතාව මුහුණ දෙන ප්‍රශ්නවලට එරෙහිව අදහස් ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමේ අයිතිය යටපත් කිරීමේ අරමුණින් ගෙන එන හදිසි නීතියට එරෙහිව ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට සමගි ජන බලවේගය විසින් ඒකමතිකව තීරණය කරන ලදී. දෛනික පදනමක්.",
        "එපමණක් නොව ජනතාව පීඩාවට පත් කරන ප්‍රශ්නවලට සැබෑ විසඳුම් ලබා නොදී ඔවුන් අතර ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය මුදාහරින රජය සමඟ සම්බන්ධ නොවී සිටීමට සමගි ජන බලවේගය තීරණය කළේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ජනතා ප්‍රශ්නවලට විසඳුම් සෙවීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව තුළ කමිටු ක්‍රමයක් සම්පාදනය කරන්නේ නම් සහය පළ කිරීමට සමගි ජන බලවේගය තීරණය කළා.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව හෙට (27) රැස්වීමට නියමිත අතර ජූලි 17 වැනි දින ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද හදිසි නීතිය පිළිබඳ ප්‍රකාශය විවාදයට ගැනීමට නියමිතය.",
        "මේ අතර, සමගි ජන බලවේගය කිසිදු කැබිනට් අමාත්‍ය ධූර භාර නොගන්නා නමුත් ජනතා සුබසිද්ධිය පෙරදැරි කරගෙන විපක්ෂය ලෙස තවදුරටත් කටයුතු කරන බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී තිස්ස අත්තනායක මහතා අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රවුෆ් හකීම් මහතා සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් කළ විමසීමකදී කියා සිටියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිත 22 වැනි සංශෝධනය සම්බන්ධයෙන් එය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට තවත් කාලයක් ගතවනු ඇති බවයි. කෙසේ වෙතත්, වත්මන් පාලනය මහ මැතිවරණයකට යාමට එකඟ වී මානව හිමිකම් ආරක්ෂා කරන්නේ නම්, සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම සඳහා පක්ෂයක් ලෙස ඉදිරිපත් වීමට SJB සූදානම් බව SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඉරාන් වික්‍රමරත්න මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "සඳුදා (25) කොවිඩ් මරණ පහක්, අද (26) රෝගීන් 100 ඉක්මවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "හදිසි නීතිය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හදිසි නීතිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැබිනට් ඇමති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රවුෆ් හකීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එරාන් වික්‍රමරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ මැතිවරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SJB அவசரச் சட்டத்திற்கு எதிராக வாக்களிக்கத் தயாராக உள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); நாளை (27) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நடைபெறும் விவாதத்தின் போது அவசரகாலச் சட்டத்திற்கு எதிராக வாக்களிக்க சமகி ஜன பலவேகயவின் செயற்குழு தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "மக்கள் எதிர்நோக்கும் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு எதிராக கருத்து வெளியிடும் உரிமை, எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவிக்கும் உரிமை, கருத்து தெரிவிக்கும் உரிமை ஆகியவற்றை நசுக்கும் நோக்கில் கொண்டு வரப்படும் அவசரகால சட்டத்திற்கு எதிராக வாக்களிக்க ஏகமனதாக தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக சமகி ஜன பலவேகய தெரிவித்துள்ளது. தினசரி அடிப்படையில்.",
        "மேலும், மக்கள் மத்தியில் நிலவும் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு உண்மையான தீர்வுகளை வழங்காமல் அவர்கள் மத்தியில் வன்முறையை கட்டவிழ்த்து விடும் அரசாங்கத்துடன் தன்னை இணைத்துக் கொள்ள வேண்டாம் என சமகி ஜன பலவேகய தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், மக்களின் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு தீர்வு காணும் வகையில் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்குள் குழு அமைப்பு நடைமுறைப்படுத்தப்பட்டால் ஆதரவளிக்க சமகி ஜன பலவேகய தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "நாடாளுமன்றம் நாளை (27) கூடவுள்ளதுடன், ஜூலை 17ஆம் திகதி ஜனாதிபதியினால் பிரகடனப்படுத்தப்பட்ட அவசரகாலச் சட்டம் மீதான விவாதம் இடம்பெறவுள்ளது.",
        "இதேவேளை, சமகி ஜன பலவேகய அமைச்சரவை அமைச்சுப் பதவிகளை ஏற்காது, எனினும் மக்களின் நலனைக் கருத்தில் கொண்டு எதிர்க்கட்சியாக தொடர்ந்தும் செயற்படும் என பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் திஸ்ஸ அத்தநாயக்க வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரவூப் ஹக்கீம், சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பது தொடர்பில் வினவியபோது, ​​22ஆவது திருத்தச் சட்டம் இன்னும் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படவுள்ள நிலையில் அதனை நடைமுறைப்படுத்துவதற்கு அதிக காலம் எடுக்கும் என தெரிவித்தார். எவ்வாறாயினும், தற்போதைய நிர்வாகம் பொதுத் தேர்தலுக்கு செல்ல இணங்கி மனித உரிமைகளை நிலைநாட்டினால், சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பதற்கு SJB ஒரு கட்சி என்ற வகையில் முன்வரத் தயாராக இருப்பதாக SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் எரான் விக்ரமரத்ன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "திங்கட்கிழமை (25) ஐந்து கோவிட் இறப்புகள், இன்று (26) 100 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட வழக்குகள்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "அவசர சட்டம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அவசர சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சரவை அமைச்சர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரவூப் ஹக்கீம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எரான் விக்கிரமரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது தேர்தல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}