{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/international/මාකෝස්-පිලිපීනයේ-නව-ජනපති-ලෙස-දිවුරුම්-දෙයි/3-395002",
  "time_ut": 1656651784,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මාකෝස් පිලිපීනයේ නව ජනපති ලෙස දිවුරුම් දෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Marcos is sworn in as the new President of the Philippines",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Ferdinand Romuildes Marcos was sworn in as the 17th President of the Philippines, pledging to prioritize food security in the country.",
        "The 64-year-old son of former President Ferdinand Marcos was sworn in at the National Museum in Manila before his 92-year-old mother Imelda and other family members.",
        "\"We prioritize the role of agriculture, the urgency of which is currently being ignored and misdirected,\" Marcos said after being sworn in as Minister of Agriculture.",
        "Over 15,000 police and security personnel have been deployed across the capital for the opening ceremony. Foreign dignitaries, diplomats and three former presidents of the Philippines, Fidel Ramos, Joseph Estrada and Gloria Macapagal-Arroyo attended.",
        "Marcos was received at the Presidential Palace by outgoing President Rodrigo Dutarte before the swearing-in ceremony.",
        "However, the Marcos administration will have to address a number of issues currently plaguing the Philippines, including rising unemployment, inflation, high debt service rates relative to gross domestic product (GDP), and rocketing gas and oil prices.",
        "Managing inflation is at the top of the list of things the president should do. Government data shows that 23.7% of the country's population of nearly 110 million lives in poverty."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Marcos",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Philippines",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ferdinand Romuildes Marcos",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "17th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Philippines",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "64-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ferdinand Marcos",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Museum",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manila",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "92-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Imelda",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Marcos",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Over 15,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Philippines",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fidel Ramos",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joseph Estrada",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gloria Macapagal-Arroyo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Marcos",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Palace",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rodrigo Dutarte",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Marcos",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Philippines",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "23.7%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly 110 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මාකෝස් පිලිපීනයේ නව ජනපති ලෙස දිවුරුම් දෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ෆර්ඩිනන්ඩ් රොමියුල්ඩෙස් මාකෝස් පිලිපීනයේ 17 වැනි ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දුන්නේ රට තුළ ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතාව ඇති කිරීමට ප්‍රමුඛත්වය දෙන බවට ප්‍රතිඥා දෙමිනි.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ෆර්ඩිනන්ඩ් මාකෝස්ගේ 64 හැවිරිදි පුත්‍රයා, ඔහුගේ 92 හැවිරිදි මව ඉමෙල්ඩා සහ අනෙකුත් පවුලේ සාමාජිකයින් ඉදිරියේ මැනිලාහි ජාතික කෞතුකාගාරයේ දිවුරුම් දෙනු ලැබීය.",
        "\"කෘෂිකාර්මික භූමිකාව, මේ වනවිට එහි නොසලකා හැරීම සහ වැරදි මඟපෙන්වීම ඉල්ලා සිටින හදිසි අවධානයට අප ප්‍රමුඛත්වය දෙනවා\" කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස තමන්ව පත් කළ මාකෝස් දිවුරුම් දීමෙන් පසු පැවසීය.",
        "සමාරම්භක උත්සවය සඳහා අගනුවර පුරා 15,000කට අධික පොලිස් සහ ආරක්ෂක නිලධාරීන් යොදවා ඇත. විදේශීය සම්භාවනීය අමුත්තන්, රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රිකයින් සහ පිලිපීනයේ හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරුන් තිදෙනෙකු වන ෆිදෙල් රමෝස්, ජෝසප් එස්ට්‍රාඩා සහ ග්ලෝරියා මැකපාගල්-අරෝයෝ සහභාගී වූහ.",
        "දිවුරුම් දීමේ උත්සවයට පෙර, ඉවත්ව යන ජනාධිපති රොද්‍රිගෝ දුතාර්තේ විසින් ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේදී මාකෝස් පිළිගත්තේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, මේ වනවිට උග්‍රවී ඇති විරැකියාව, උද්ධමනය, දල දේශීය නිෂ්පාදිතයට (GDP) සාපේක්ෂව ඉහළ ණය සේවා අනුපාතයන් මෙන්ම, රොකට් ගසන ගෑස් සහ තෙල් මිල වැනි පිලිපීනය වටකරමින් සිටින ගැටලු රැසකට මාකෝස් පරිපාලනය විසඳුම් ලබාදීමට සිදුවනු ඇත.",
        "උද්ධමනය කළමනාකරණය කිරීම ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ කළ යුතු දේ ලැයිස්තුවේ ඉහළින්ම ඇත. රටේ මිලියන 110කට ආසන්න ජනගහනයෙන් 23.7%ක් දරිද්‍රතාවයේ ජීවත් වන බව රජයේ දත්ත පෙන්වා දෙයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මාකෝස්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "පිලිපීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ferdinand Romuildes Marcos",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිලිපීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "64 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆර්ඩිනන්ඩ් මාකෝස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික කෞතුකාගාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැනිලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "92 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉමෙල්ඩා",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාකෝස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15,000 කට වඩා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිලිපීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆිදෙල් රමෝස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝසප් එස්ට්රාඩා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gloria Macapagal-Arroyo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාකෝස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොඩ්රිගෝ ඩුටාටේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාකෝස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිලිපීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "23.7%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 110 කට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிலிப்பைன்ஸின் புதிய அதிபராக மார்கோஸ் பதவியேற்றார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிலிப்பைன்ஸின் 17வது அதிபராக ஃபெர்டினாண்ட் ரோமுல்டெஸ் மார்கோஸ் பதவியேற்று, நாட்டில் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பிற்கு முன்னுரிமை அளிப்பதாக உறுதியளித்தார்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி பெர்டினாண்ட் மார்கோஸின் 64 வயதான மகன் மணிலாவில் உள்ள தேசிய அருங்காட்சியகத்தில் அவரது 92 வயதான தாய் இமெல்டா மற்றும் பிற குடும்ப உறுப்பினர்கள் முன்னிலையில் பதவியேற்றார்.",
        "\"விவசாயத்தின் பங்கிற்கு நாங்கள் முன்னுரிமை அளிக்கிறோம், அதன் அவசரம் தற்போது புறக்கணிக்கப்பட்டு தவறாக வழிநடத்தப்படுகிறது\" என்று மார்கோஸ் விவசாய அமைச்சராக பதவியேற்ற பிறகு கூறினார்.",
        "பதவியேற்பு விழாவையொட்டி தலைநகர் முழுவதும் 15,000க்கும் மேற்பட்ட போலீசார் மற்றும் பாதுகாப்பு படையினர் குவிக்கப்பட்டனர். வெளிநாட்டு பிரமுகர்கள், இராஜதந்திரிகள் மற்றும் மூன்று முன்னாள் பிலிப்பைன்ஸ் அதிபர்களான ஃபிடல் ராமோஸ், ஜோசப் எஸ்ட்ராடா மற்றும் குளோரியா மேக்பகல்-அரோயோ ஆகியோர் கலந்து கொண்டனர்.",
        "பதவியேற்பு விழாவுக்கு முன்னதாக, பதவி விலகும் அதிபர் ரோட்ரிகோ டுடார்டே, ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் மார்கோஸை வரவேற்றார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், மார்கோஸ் நிர்வாகம் தற்போது பிலிப்பைன்ஸைச் சூழ்ந்துள்ள பல பிரச்சினைகளை தீர்க்க வேண்டும், அதாவது பரவலான வேலையின்மை, பணவீக்கம், அதிக கடன்-ஜிடிபி விகிதங்கள் மற்றும் எரிவாயு மற்றும் எண்ணெய் விலைகள் விண்ணை முட்டும்.",
        "பணவீக்கத்தை நிர்வகிப்பது ஜனாதிபதியின் செய்ய வேண்டிய பட்டியலில் முதலிடத்தில் உள்ளது. நாட்டின் ஏறக்குறைய 110 மில்லியன் மக்களில் 23.7% பேர் வறுமையில் வாடுவதாக அரசாங்கத் தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மார்கோஸ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பிலிப்பைன்ஸ்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃபெர்டினாண்ட் ரோமுல்டெஸ் மார்கோஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "17வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிலிப்பைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "64 வயதானவர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபெர்டினாண்ட் மார்கோஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய அருங்காட்சியகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணிலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "92 வயதானவர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இமெல்டா",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மார்கோஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15,000க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிலிப்பைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிடல் ராமோஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜோசப் எஸ்ட்ராடா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gloria Macapagal-Arroyo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மார்கோஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோட்ரிகோ டுடார்டே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மார்கோஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிலிப்பைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "23.7%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 110 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}