{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/யாழ்ப்பாணம்/இ-போ-ச-யாழ்-சாலை-ஊழியர்கள்-இன்று-பணிப்பகிஷ்கரிப்பு/71-300986",
  "time_ut": 1658604671,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இ.போ.ச. யாழ். சாலை ஊழியர்கள் இன்று பணிப்பகிஷ்கரிப்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "E.P.C. Jaffna. Road workers strike today",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Transport Board's Jaffna. The road workers have announced that they have decided to go on strike today (24) and it has been reported that due to the shutdown of the Jaffna road, the operations of the roads connected to it will also be affected.",
        "The Jaffna Road employees made a joint announcement at a media conference held yesterday (23) at Jaffna Central Bus Station.",
        "Yesterday (22nd) at 9 o'clock in the night, both the driver and the guard of the 57-route EPO bus from Jaffna to Colombo were attacked by the employees of the Kalkamuwa Road EPO road in Thaladagama area.",
        "It has also been requested that the police immediately arrest the employees involved in the attack and take legal action.",
        "If legal action is not taken today (24) the Sri Lankan Transport Board's Jaffna Road is planning to carry out trade union protests along with Northern Regional Roads in Jaffna. The road workers had made a joint announcement yesterday. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "E.P.C. Jaffna",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Transport Board's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna Central Bus Station",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 o'clock in the night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "57",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kalkamuwa Road",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thaladagama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Transport Board's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna Road",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Northern Regional Roads",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඊ.පී.සී. යාපනය. මාර්ග සේවකයෝ අද වර්ජනය කරති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයේ යාපනය. අද (24) දින වැඩ වර්ජනයක නිරත වීමට තීරණය කර ඇති බව මාර්ග සේවකයින් නිවේදනය කර ඇති අතර යාපනය මාර්ගය වසා දැමීම හේතුවෙන් ඊට සම්බන්ධ මාර්ගවල ක්‍රියාකාරිත්වයට ද බාධා එල්ල වන බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "යාපනය මධ්‍යම බස් නැවතුම්පොළේදී ඊයේ (23) පැවැති මාධ්‍ය සාකච්ඡාවකදී යාපනය පාර සේවකයින් ඒකාබද්ධ නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කළේය.",
        "ඊයේ (22දා) රාත්‍රී 9 ට යාපනයේ සිට කොළඹ බලා ධාවනය වූ මාර්ග 57 EPO බස් රථයේ රියදුරුට සහ මුරකරුට තලදාගම ප්‍රදේශයේදී කල්කමුව පාර EPO මාර්ගයේ සේවකයන් විසින් පහර දී ඇත.",
        "පහරදීමට සම්බන්ධ සේවකයින් වහා අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන නීතිමය පියවර ගන්නා ලෙසද පොලිසියෙන් ඉල්ලා ඇත.",
        "අද (24) නීතිමය ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයක් නොගතහොත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයේ යාපනය මාර්ගය, යාපනයේ උතුරු ප්‍රාදේශීය මාර්ග ආශ්‍රිතව වෘත්තීය සමිති විරෝධතා ව්‍යාපාර ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට සැලසුම් කර තිබේ. මාර්ග සේවකයින් ඊයේ ඒකාබද්ධ නිවේදනයක් කර තිබුණා. (ඒ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඊ.පී.සී. යාපනය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය මධ්‍යම බස් නැවතුම්පොළ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාත්‍රී 9 ට",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "57",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කල්කමුව පාර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලදාගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය පාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු ප්‍රාදේශීය මාර්ග",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இ.போ.ச. யாழ். சாலை ஊழியர்கள் இன்று பணிப்பகிஷ்கரிப்பு",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் யாழ். சாலை ஊழியர்கள் இன்று (24) பணிப்பகிஷ்கரிப்பினை மேற்கொள்ள தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக அறிவித்துள்ளதுடன், யாழ் சாலை முடங்குவதால் அதனுடன் இணைந்த சாலைகளின் செயற்பாடுகளும் பாதிக்கப்படுமென தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "யாழ்ப்பாணம் மத்திய பேருந்து நிலையத்தில்நேற்று (23) இடம்பெற்ற ஊடக சந்திப்பிலேய யாழ் சாலை ஊழியர்கள் கூட்டாக அறிவித்தனர்.",
        "நேற்று முன்தினம் (22) இரவு 9 மணியளவில் யாழ்ப்பாணத்தில் இருந்து கொழும்பு நோக்கி பெறப்பட்ட 57 வழித்தட இ.போ.ச பேருந்தின் சாரதி மற்றும் காப்பாளர் இருவரும் கல்கமுவ சாலை இ.போ.ச சாலை ஊழியர்களினால் தலாதகம எனும் பகுதியில் தாக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்த தாக்குதலோடு தொடர்புபட்ட ஊழியர்களை உடனடியாக பொலிஸார் கைது செய்து சட்ட நடவடிக்கை எடுக்க வேண்டுமெனவும் கோரிக்கை விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சட்ட நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டா விட்டால் இன்றைய தினம் (24) இலங்கைப் போக்குவரத்து சபையின் யாழ் சாலை வட பிராந்திய சாலைகளுடன் இணைந்து தொழிற்சங்க போராட்டங்களை முன்னெடுக்க இருப்பதாக யாழ். சாலை ஊழியர்கள் நேற்று  கூட்டாக அறிவித்திருந்தனர். (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இ.பி.சி. யாழ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாணம் மத்திய பேருந்து நிலையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு 9 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "57",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்கமுவ வீதி",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலடகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாண வீதி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு பிராந்திய சாலைகள்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}