{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/වත්මන්-ජනාධිපතිගේ-නායකත්වය-යටතේ-දේශපාලන-ස්ථාවරත්වය-ඇතිවේවි/11-395719",
  "time_ut": 1658739235,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "වත්මන් ජනාධිපතිගේ නායකත්වය යටතේ දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වය ඇතිවේවි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "There will be political stability under the leadership of the current president",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Minister of Justice, Prison Affairs and Constitutional Reform said that under the leadership of the current President Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe, the establishment of political stability and the recovery of the economy in Sri Lanka will happen soon, and the 22nd Constitutional Amendment is being submitted to the Parliament for adoption. Lawyer Dr. Vijayadasa Rajapaksa said.",
        "The minister said this in a meeting between Thai Ambassador to Sri Lanka, Mr. Poj Hanpol, at the Ministry of Justice this morning.",
        "The Minister stated that he had the opportunity to deliver the keynote speech at the United Nations International Vesak Festival held in Thailand in 2016, and that Thailand made a great contribution when the event was held in Sri Lanka in 2017.",
        "The Minister of Justice gratefully recalled the contribution of Thailand to the economic and religious and cultural development of Sri Lanka at the present time for the re-establishment of Buddhism by returning the Buddhist Upasampa to Sri Lanka.",
        "The Ambassador said that it is hoped that the current problematic conditions in Sri Lanka will eventually lead to economic stability, and maximum diplomatic support will be provided for it."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Prison Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitutional Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vijayadasa Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thai",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poj Hanpol",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the United Nations International Vesak Festival",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Upasampa",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වත්මන් ජනාධිපතිගේ නායකත්වය යටතේ දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වය ඇතිවේවි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "වත්මන් ජනාධිපති  රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ නායකත්වය යටතේ යටතේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ  දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වය ඇතිවීම හා ආර්ථිකය යථා තත්වයට පත්වීම කඩිනමින් සිදු වනු ඇති බවත්, 22 වන ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කර සම්මත කර ගැනීමට කටයුතු කරමින් සිටින බවත් අධිකරණ, බන්ධනාගාර කටයුතු හා ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ අමාත්‍ය ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ ආචාර්ය විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තායිලන්ත තානාපති පොජ් හාන්පෝල් මහතා අතර අද පෙරවරුවේ අධිකරණ අමාත්‍යාංශයේදී පැවැති හමුවකදී අමාත්‍යවරයා මේ බව පැවැසීය.",
        "2016 වසරේ තායිලන්තයේ පැවති එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ජාත්‍යන්තර වෙසක් උත්සවයේ ප්‍රධාන දේශනය පැවැත්වීමට තමාට අවස්ථාව උදා වු බවත්, 2017 වසරේ එම උත්සවය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පැවැත්වු අවස්ථාවේ තායිලන්තය විශාල දායකත්වයක් ලබා දුන් බවත් අමාත්‍වරයා සදහන් කළේය",
        "බෞද්ධ උපසම්පදාව නැවත මෙරටට ලබාදීමට කටයුතු කරමින් බුදු දහම යළි නගා සිටුවීම සදහා මෙන්ම වර්තමානය වන විට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික හා ආගමික සංස්කෘතික සංවර්ධනය උදෙසා තායිලන්තය ලබා දෙනු ලබන දායකත්වය අධිකරණ අමාත්‍වරයා මෙහිදී කෘතවේදීව සිහිපත් කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ වර්තමානය වන විට පවතින ගැටළු සහගත තත්වයන් අවසන්ව ආර්ථික ස්ථාවරත්වය ඇති වනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කරන බවත්, ඒ සදහා රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික වශයෙන් උපරිම සහයෝගය ලබා දෙන බවත්, තානාපතිවරයා මෙහිදී පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බන්ධනාගාර කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තායි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොජ් හන්පොල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණ අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ජාත්‍යන්තර වෙසක් උත්සවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "උපසම්ප",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதியின் தலைமையில் அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மை ஏற்படும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி திரு ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் தலைமையில் இலங்கையில் அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மை மற்றும் பொருளாதாரத்தை மீட்டெடுப்பது விரைவில் நடக்கும் என்றும், 22வது அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தம் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட உள்ளதாகவும் நீதி, சிறைச்சாலை விவகாரங்கள் மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு மறுசீரமைப்பு அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்தார். பாராளுமன்றத்தை தத்தெடுப்பதற்காக.. சட்டத்தரணி கலாநிதி விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான தாய்லாந்து தூதுவர் திரு.போஜ் ஹன்போல் அவர்களுக்கிடையில் இன்று காலை நீதியமைச்சில் இடம்பெற்ற சந்திப்பிலேயே அமைச்சர் இதனைத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "2016ஆம் ஆண்டு தாய்லாந்தில் நடைபெற்ற ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் சர்வதேச வெசாக் விழாவில் தலைமை உரை ஆற்றும் வாய்ப்பு தமக்குக் கிடைத்ததாகவும், 2017ஆம் ஆண்டு இலங்கையில் இந்நிகழ்வு நடைபெற்ற போது தாய்லாந்து பெரும் பங்களிப்பை வழங்கியதாகவும் அமைச்சர் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "பௌத்த உபசம்பரை இலங்கைக்கு திருப்பியனுப்புவதன் மூலம் பௌத்தத்தை மீள ஸ்தாபிப்பதற்காக தற்போது இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார, சமய மற்றும் கலாசார வளர்ச்சிக்கு தாய்லாந்து ஆற்றிய பங்களிப்பை நீதி அமைச்சர் நன்றியுடன் நினைவு கூர்ந்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் தற்போது நிலவும் சிக்கலான நிலைமைகள் இறுதியில் பொருளாதார ஸ்திரத்தன்மைக்கு வழிவகுக்கும் என நம்புவதாகவும், அதற்கு அதிகபட்ச இராஜதந்திர ஆதரவு வழங்கப்படும் என்றும் தூதுவர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சிறை விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தாய்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "போஜ் ஹன்போல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் சர்வதேச வெசாக் விழா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நீதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "உபசம்பா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}