{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/28/gen-shavendra-silva-bestowed-mahamanya-prathapadhi-keshwara-title/",
  "time_ut": 1661690040,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Gen. Shavendra Silva bestowed ‘Mahamanya Prathapadhi-keshwara’ title",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Gen. Shavendra Silva bestowed ‘Mahamanya Prathapadhi-keshwara’ title",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Chief of Defense Staff, General Shavendra Silva declared in Kandy that he would dedicate himself for the betterment of the people of this country.",
        "The Chief of Defense Staff, General Shavendra Silva was conferred with the honorary title of 'Mahamanya Prathapadhi-keshwara' in recognition of his services.",
        "The ceremony was held with the participation of the Anunayake Theros and the leaders of the Central Sangha Council led by the Most Ven. Warakagoda Gnanarathana Thero, the Leader of the Asgiri Chapter of the Siam sect.",
        "A group of dignitaries including ambassadors were also present at this occasion.",
        "The chiefs of the Ramanna sect and the Amarapura Maha Sangha Sabha also expressed their pleasure via letters.",
        "The Chief of Defense Staff, General Shavendra Silva was awarded the honorary title by the Mahanayake Thero of the Asgiri Chapter of the Siam sect."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Shavendra Silva",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defense Staff",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shavendra Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Defense Staff",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shavendra Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahamanya Prathapadhi-keshwara'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Anunayake Theros",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Sangha Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gnanarathana Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Amarapura Maha",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Defense Staff",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shavendra Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Mahanayake Thero",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජෙනරාල් ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා මහතා විසින් ‘මහාමාන්‍ය ප්‍රතාපධි කේශ්වර’ පදවිය පිරිනමන ලදී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); මේ රටේ ජනතාවගේ අභිවෘද්ධිය වෙනුවෙන් කැපවන බව ආරක්ෂක මාණ්ඩලික ප්‍රධානී ජෙනරාල් ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා මහනුවරදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ආරක්‍ෂක මාණ්ඩලික ප්‍රධානී ජෙනරාල් ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා මහතාගේ සේවය අගයමින් ‘මහාමාන්‍ය ප්‍රතාපධි කේශ්වර’ යන ගෞරව නාමයෙන් පිදුම් ලැබීය.",
        "අතිපූජ්‍ය අනුනායක හිමිපාණන් වහන්සේ ප්‍රමුඛ මධ්‍යම මහා සංඝ සභාවේ නායක හිමිපාණන්ගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් මෙම උත්සවය පැවැත්විණි. සියම් නිකායේ අස්ගිරි පාර්ශවයේ මහා නායක වරකාගොඩ ඤාණරතන හිමි.",
        "තානාපතිවරුන් ඇතුළු සම්භාවනීය පිරිසක් ද මෙම අවස්ථාවට එක්ව සිටියහ.",
        "රාමඤ්ඤ නිකායේ සහ අමරපුර මහා සංඝ සභාවේ ප්‍රධානීන්ද සිය සතුට ලිපි මගින් ප්‍රකාශ කළහ.",
        "ආරක්‍ෂක මාණ්ඩලික ප්‍රධානී ජෙනරාල් ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා මහතාට සියම් නිකායේ අස්ගිරි පාර්ශවයේ මහානායක හිමිපාණන් විසින් ගෞරව නාමය පිරිනමන ලදී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහාමාන්‍ය ප්‍රතාපධි-කේශ්වර'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුනායක හාමුදුරුවරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්‍යම සංඝ සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඤාණරතන හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමරපුර මහා",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සභා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහානායක හාමුදුරුවෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜெனரல் சவேந்திர சில்வா ‘மஹாமான்ய பிரதாபதி-கேஸ்வரா’ என்ற பட்டத்தை வழங்கினார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இந்த நாட்டு மக்களின் முன்னேற்றத்திற்காக தன்னை அர்ப்பணிப்பதாக பாதுகாப்பு படைகளின் பிரதானி ஜெனரல் சவேந்திர சில்வா கண்டியில் அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பாதுகாப்புப் படைகளின் பிரதானி ஜெனரல் சவேந்திர சில்வாவின் சேவைகளைப் பாராட்டி 'மஹாமான்ய பிரதாபதி-கேஸ்வரா' என்ற கௌரவப் பட்டம் அவருக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "அனுநாயக்க தேரர்கள் மற்றும் மத்திய சங்கப் பேரவைத் தலைவர்கள் கலந்துகொண்ட இந்த வைபவம் அதி வணக்கத்தின் தலைமையில் இடம்பெற்றது. சியாம் பிரிவின் அஸ்கிரி பீடத்தின் தலைவர் வரகாகொட ஞானரதன தேரர்.",
        "தூதுவர்கள் உள்ளிட்ட முக்கியஸ்தர்கள் குழுவும் இந்நிகழ்வில் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "ராமண்ணா பிரிவின் தலைவர்கள் மற்றும் அமரபுர மகா சங்க சபையின் தலைவர்களும் கடிதங்கள் மூலம் தங்கள் மகிழ்ச்சியை வெளிப்படுத்தினர்.",
        "பாதுகாப்புப் படைகளின் பிரதானி ஜெனரல் சவேந்திர சில்வாவுக்கு சியாம் பிரிவின் அஸ்கிரி பீடத்தின் மகாநாயக்க தேரர்களினால் கௌரவப் பட்டம் வழங்கப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சவேந்திர சில்வா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு ஊழியர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவேந்திர சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு ஊழியர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவேந்திர சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹாமான்ய பிரதாபதி-கேஷ்வரா'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுநாயக்க தேரர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய சங்க சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞானரதன தேரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமரபுர மகா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சபா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு ஊழியர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவேந்திர சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகாநாயக்க தேரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}