{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/SL-to-get-access-to-UK-market-for-over-80-products-under-new-Trading-Scheme/108-243175",
  "time_ut": 1660655399,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SL to get access to UK market for over 80% products under new Trading Scheme",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SL to get access to UK market for over 80% products under new Trading Scheme",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka is included in the UK's new Developing Countries Trading Scheme (DCTS) which replaces the UK’s Generalized Scheme of Preferences (GSP), accessing to the UK market for over 80% of Sri Lankan export products.",
        "“The UK's new Developing Countries Trading Scheme (DCTS) is one of the most generous sets of trading preferences of any country in the world and will benefit Sri Lanka by boosting the economy and supporting jobs,” British High Commissioner Sarah Hulton said.",
        "She said that the DCTS will remove tariffs an over 150 additional products and also it will also simplify some seasonal tariffs, meaning additional and simpler access for Sri Lanka's exports to the UK.",
        "“The new scheme, which replaces UK GSP, will come into force in 2023 and the UK looks forward to future trading opportunities with Sri Lanka,” she said.",
        "According to the UK’s Department for International Trade the new Trading Scheme applies to 65 countries, offering lower tariffs and simpler rules of origin requirements for exporting to the UK."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "UK",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "over 80%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Generalized Scheme of Preferences",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 80%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sarah Hulton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "DCTS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "GSP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Department for International Trade",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "65",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නව වෙළඳ යෝජනා ක්‍රමය යටතේ 80% කට වැඩි නිෂ්පාදන සඳහා එක්සත් රාජධානියේ වෙළඳපොළට ප්‍රවේශය ලබා ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අපනයන නිෂ්පාදනවලින් 80% කට වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් සඳහා එක්සත් රාජධානියේ වෙළඳපොළට ප්‍රවේශ වන එක්සත් රාජධානියේ සාමාන්‍යකරණය වූ මනාප යෝජනා ක්‍රමය (GSP) ප්‍රතිස්ථාපනය කරන එක්සත් රාජධානියේ නව සංවර්ධනය වෙමින් පවතින රටවල වෙළඳ යෝජනා ක්‍රමයට (DCTS) ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඇතුළත් වේ.",
        "\"එක්සත් රාජධානියේ නව සංවර්ධනය වෙමින් පවතින රටවල වෙළඳ යෝජනා ක්‍රමය (DCTS) යනු ලෝකයේ ඕනෑම රටක වෙළඳ අභිරුචිවල වඩාත්ම ත්‍යාගශීලී කට්ටලයක් වන අතර ආර්ථිකය නංවාලීමෙන් සහ රැකියා සඳහා සහාය වීමෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ප්‍රතිලාභ ලැබෙනු ඇත,\" බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය මහ කොමසාරිස් සාරා හල්ටන් පැවසීය.",
        "ඩීසීටීඑස් විසින් අතිරේක නිෂ්පාදන 150කට අධික ප්‍රමාණයක තීරුබදු ඉවත් කරන බවත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව එක්සත් රාජධානියට අපනයනය කිරීම සඳහා අමතර සහ සරල ප්‍රවේශයක් ලබා දෙන සෘතුමය තීරුබදු කිහිපයක් ද සරල කරන බවත් ඇය පැවසුවාය.",
        "\"එක්සත් රාජධානියේ ජීඑස්පී වෙනුවට නව යෝජනා ක්‍රමය 2023 දී බලාත්මක වන අතර එක්සත් රාජධානිය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ අනාගත වෙළඳ අවස්ථා අපේක්ෂා කරයි,\" ඇය පැවසුවාය.",
        "එක්සත් රාජධානියේ ජාත්‍යන්තර වෙළඳ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට අනුව නව වෙළඳ යෝජනා ක්‍රමය රටවල් 65කට අදාළ වන අතර, එක්සත් රාජධානියට අපනයනය කිරීම සඳහා අඩු තීරුබදු සහ ප්‍රභවය අවශ්‍යතා පිළිබඳ සරල නීති ඉදිරිපත් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "80% ට වැඩි",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාමාන්‍ය මනාප යෝජනා ක්‍රමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "80% ට වැඩි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාරා හල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "DCTS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "150 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එස්.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්යන්තර වෙළඳ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "65",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புதிய வர்த்தகத் திட்டத்தின் கீழ் 80% க்கும் அதிகமான தயாரிப்புகளுக்கு இங்கிலாந்து சந்தைக்கான அணுகலைப் பெற SL",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஐக்கிய இராச்சியத்தின் புதிய வளரும் நாடுகளின் வர்த்தகத் திட்டத்தில் (DCTS) இலங்கை சேர்க்கப்பட்டுள்ளது, இது ஐக்கிய இராச்சியத்தின் பொதுமைப்படுத்தப்பட்ட விருப்பத்தேர்வுகளின் (GSP) 80% க்கும் அதிகமான இலங்கை ஏற்றுமதிப் பொருட்களுக்கு இங்கிலாந்து சந்தையை அணுகுகிறது.",
        "\"UK இன் புதிய வளரும் நாடுகளின் வர்த்தகத் திட்டம் (DCTS) உலகின் எந்தவொரு நாட்டினதும் தாராளமான வர்த்தக விருப்பங்களில் ஒன்றாகும், மேலும் இது பொருளாதாரத்தை உயர்த்துவதன் மூலமும் வேலைகளை ஆதரிப்பதன் மூலமும் இலங்கைக்கு நன்மை பயக்கும்\" என்று பிரிட்டிஷ் உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் சாரா ஹல்டன் கூறினார்.",
        "DCTS ஆனது 150 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட கூடுதல் பொருட்களுக்கான கட்டணங்களை நீக்கும், மேலும் இது சில பருவகால கட்டணங்களையும் எளிதாக்கும், அதாவது இலங்கையின் இங்கிலாந்துக்கு ஏற்றுமதி செய்வதற்கான கூடுதல் மற்றும் எளிமையான அணுகலைக் குறிக்கிறது.",
        "\"UK GSP ஐ மாற்றும் புதிய திட்டம், 2023 இல் நடைமுறைக்கு வரும், மேலும் இலங்கையுடன் எதிர்கால வர்த்தக வாய்ப்புகளை இங்கிலாந்து எதிர்நோக்குகிறது,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "சர்வதேச வர்த்தகத்திற்கான UKயின் திணைக்களத்தின்படி, புதிய வர்த்தகத் திட்டம் 65 நாடுகளுக்குப் பொருந்தும், UK க்கு ஏற்றுமதி செய்வதற்கு குறைந்த கட்டணங்கள் மற்றும் அசல் தேவைகளுக்கான எளிய விதிகளை வழங்குகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "யுகே",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "80%க்கு மேல்",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விருப்பங்களின் பொதுவான திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "80%க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாரா ஹல்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டி.சி.டி.எஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "150க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எஸ்.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச வர்த்தகத்திற்கான துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "65",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}