{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/චීන-නෞකාව-එන්නේ-ඉන්ධන-ලබාගන්නයි/101-617454",
  "time_ut": 1659431747,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "චීන නෞකාව එන්නේ ඉන්ධන ලබාගන්නයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The Chinese ship is coming to get fuel",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Minister of Transport, Highways and Mass Media, Dr. Bandula Gunawardena said that Foreign Minister Ali Sabri informed the President and the Cabinet that a scheduled Chinese research ship will arrive at Hambantota Port only to fulfill fuel and other needs.",
        "The Minister also mentioned that Foreign Minister Ali Sabri informed that the ship is not coming for any other purpose.",
        "The minister said this while addressing the press conference to announce the cabinet decisions held today (2) at the Government Information Department.",
        "The minister also said that President Ranil Wickramasinghe said that he would work with friendly countries including India and China to help Sri Lanka in difficult times."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Mass Media",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government Information Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීන නෞකාව එන්නේ ඉන්ධන ලබාගන්නයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "නියමිත චීන පර්යේෂණ නෞකාවක් හම්බන්තොට වරායට පැමිණෙන්නේ ඉන්ධන හා වෙනත් අවශ්‍යතා සපුරාගැනීම සඳහා පමණක් බව විදේශ අමාත්‍ය අලි සබ්‍රි මහතා ජනාධිපතිවරයාට හා කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට දැනුම් දුන් බව කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක, ප්‍රවාහන, මහාමාර්ග සහ ජනමාධ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය ආචාර්ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "එම නෞකාව වෙනත් කටයුත්තක් සඳහා පැමිණෙන එකක් නොවන බව විදේශ අමාත්‍ය අලි සබි්‍ර මහතා දැනුම් දුන් බව ද ඇමතිවරයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "අමාත්‍යවරයා මේ බව පැවසුවේ රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ දී අද (2) පැවති කැබිනට් තීරණ දැනුම්දීමේ මාධ්‍ය හමුව අමතමිනි.",
        "ඉන්දියාව, චීනය ඇතුළු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට දුෂ්කර අවස්ථාවල උදව් කරන මිත්‍ර රාජ්‍ය සමඟ මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික මට්ටමින් කරුණු දක්වා කටයුතු කරන බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා එහිදී පැවසූ බව ද ඇමතිවරයා කීවේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජන මාධ්‍ය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சீன கப்பல் எரிபொருள் பெற வருகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எரிபொருள் மற்றும் ஏனைய தேவைகளை பூர்த்தி செய்வதற்காக மாத்திரம் திட்டமிடப்பட்ட சீன ஆய்வுக் கப்பல் ஒன்று ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்திற்கு வரவுள்ளதாக வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் அலி சப்ரி ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் அமைச்சரவைக்கு அறிவித்துள்ளதாக அமைச்சரவைப் பேச்சாளர், போக்குவரத்து, நெடுஞ்சாலைகள் மற்றும் வெகுஜன ஊடக அமைச்சர் கலாநிதி பந்துல குணவர்தன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "வேறு எந்த நோக்கத்திற்காகவும் கப்பல் வரவில்லை என வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் அலி சப்ரி தெரிவித்ததாகவும் அமைச்சர் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களத்தில் இன்று (2) நடைபெற்ற அமைச்சரவை முடிவுகளை அறிவிக்கும் ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் கலந்துகொண்டு கருத்து தெரிவிக்கும் போதே அமைச்சர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கடினமான காலங்களில் இலங்கைக்கு உதவ இந்தியா, சீனா உள்ளிட்ட நட்பு நாடுகளுடன் இணைந்து செயற்படுவதாக ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தெரிவித்ததாகவும் அமைச்சர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வெகுஜன ஊடகம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}