{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/10/what-happens-after-the-president-resigns-basl-explains-process-to-elect-new-president/",
  "time_ut": 1657447680,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "What happens after the President resigns? BASL explains process to elect new President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "What happens after the President resigns? BASL explains process to elect new President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Bar Association of Sri Lanka convening a special press conference on Sunday (10) afternoon elaborated on the process that should be followed by the President, and the Prime Minister in vacating their posts.",
        "BASL President Saliya Pieris, PC told reporters that in terms of the constitution, the President must address to speaker a letter signed by him of his decision to step down, and when the position is vacant the Prime Minister would take over as acting President.",
        "“If the Prime Minister is not able to act as president, then it would the speaker who would act as president,” said the BASL President adding that the position of temporary President will be ONLY for one months.",
        "He said then within that month, the Parliament must select a successor for the remaining period of the tenure of the President who vacated his post.",
        "Commenting on the Prime Minister, the BASL President said that if the Prime Minister is to resign, he must write to the President of his decision to step down.",
        "“In Sri Lanka we had only one instance before, when President (Ranasinghe) Premadasa was assasinted on the 1st of May 1993.m D. B. Wijetunga was appointed as Acting President, and within one week the Parliament elected the new President,” he said.",
        "The Bar Association President said that Parliamentarians can elect the new President from among themselves, and the new President must be elected from among those eligible for the post.",
        "He said the process is such that the elected Member of Parliament must secure over 50% of the votes that are cast for the election of the President.",
        "“If all MPs vote, the MP elected must have 113 votes,” he said.",
        "“This country cannot have instability for a long period of time,” warned the BASL President.",
        "The Bar Association of Sri Lanka urged the President, PM, Speaker, MPs, Political Leaders to understand the gravity of the situation and they have an obligation to ensure that the transition of power is smooth.",
        "If President resigns on 13th, the transition must be done soon, and there should not be any delay, said the President of the Bar Association of Sri Lanka.",
        "“We need a smooth transition, and this is a time where all must respect the rule of law, democracy, and this is a time for national unity,” said BASL President Saliya Pieris, PC.",
        "He said that the government of national unity where all parties in government join the government, with a PM acceptable by all parties, must have a common program to address urgent economic issues..",
        "What happens after the President resigns? BASL explains process to elect new President",
        "President & PM have no moral right to remain in power; Sirisena writes 10-point letter to build Sri Lanka"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Bar Association of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10) afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saliya Pieris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "that month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 1st of May 1993.m D. B. Wijetunga",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Bar Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarians",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 50%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "113",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Bar Association of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bar Association of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saliya Pieris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "President & PM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sirisena",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු කුමක් සිදුවේද? නව සභාපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය BASL පැහැදිලි කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතීඥ සංගමය ඉරිදා (10) පස්වරුවේ විශේෂ මාධ්‍ය හමුවක් කැදවමින් ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා සිය ධුරවලින් ඉවත්වීමේදී අනුගමනය කළ යුතු ක්‍රියාදාමය පිළිබඳව විග්‍රහ කළේය.",
        "BASL සභාපති ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ සාලිය පීරිස් මාධ්‍යවේදීන් අමතමින් කියා සිටියේ ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවට අනුව ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට ගත් තීරණය සම්බන්ධයෙන් තමාගේ අත්සනින් යුත් ලිපියක් කථානායකවරයාට යොමු කළ යුතු බවත්, එම ධුරය පුරප්පාඩු වූ විට අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා වැඩ බලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස වැඩ භාර ගන්නා බවත්ය.",
        "“අගමැතිවරයාට ජනාධිපති ලෙස ක්‍රියා කිරීමට නොහැකි නම්, කතානායකවරයා ජනාධිපති ලෙස කටයුතු කරනු ඇත,” BASL සභාපතිවරයා කියා සිටියේ තාවකාලික ජනාධිපති ධුරය මාසයක් පමණක් වන බවයි.",
        "ඔහු කියා සිටියේ එම මාසය තුළ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් සිය ධුරයෙන් ඉවත් වූ ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ධූර කාලය සඳහා අනුප්‍රාප්තිකයෙකු තෝරා ගත යුතු බවයි.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා සම්බන්ධයෙන් අදහස් දක්වමින් BASL සභාපතිවරයා කියා සිටියේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට අවශ්‍ය නම් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට ගත් තීරණය ජනාධිපතිවරයාට ලිවිය යුතු බවයි.",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අපට මීට පෙර තිබුණේ 1993 මැයි 01 වැනිදා ජනාධිපති (රණසිංහ) ප්‍රේමදාස ඝාතනය වූ විට එක් අවස්ථාවක් පමණි. එම්. ඩී. බී. විජේතුංග වැඩ බලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස පත් කර සතියක් ඇතුළත පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගන්නා ලදී,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට තමන් අතරින්ම නව සභාපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගත හැකි බවත්, නව සභාපතිවරයා එම තනතුරට සුදුස්සන් අතරින් තෝරා පත් කර ගත යුතු බවත් නීතිඥ සංගමයේ සභාපතිවරයා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "තේරී පත් වූ මන්ත්‍රීවරයා ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා ප්‍රකාශ කරන ලද ඡන්දවලින් 50% කට වඩා වැඩි ප්‍රතිශතයක් ලබා ගත යුතු ක්‍රියාවලියක් බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "\"සියලු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කරන්නේ නම්, තේරී පත්වන මන්ත්‍රීවරයාට ඡන්ද 113 ක් තිබිය යුතුය,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "“මේ රට දීර්ඝ කාලයක් තිස්සේ අස්ථාවර භාවයක් තියෙන්න බෑ,” BASL සභාපති අනතුරු ඇඟවීය.",
        "තත්ත්වයෙහි බරපතලකම අවබෝධ කර ගන්නා ලෙසත්, බලය මාරුවීම සුමටව සිදු කිරීමට ඔවුන්ට වගකීමක් ඇති බවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතීඥ සංගමය ජනාධිපතිවරයා, අගමැති, කථානායක, මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්, දේශපාලන නායකයින්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා 13 වැනිදා ඉල්ලා අස්වන්නේ නම් එම සංක්‍රාන්තිය කඩිනමින් සිදු කළ යුතු බවත් ප්‍රමාද නොවිය යුතු බවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමයේ සභාපතිවරයා පවසයි.",
        "\"අපට සුමට සංක්‍රාන්තියක් අවශ්‍ය වන අතර මෙය නීතියේ ආධිපත්‍යයට, ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදයට සියලු දෙනා ගරු කළ යුතු කාලයකි, මෙය ජාතික සමගිය සඳහා කාලයකි\" යනුවෙන් BASL සභාපති ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ සාලිය පීරිස් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "සියලු පක්‍ෂ විසින් පිළිගත හැකි අගමැතිවරයකු සමඟ ආණ්‌ඩුවේ සිටින සියලුම පක්‍ෂ ආණ්‌ඩුවට එක්‌වන ජාතික සමගි රජයට හදිසි ආර්ථික ගැටලු විසඳීම සඳහා පොදු වැඩපිළිවෙළක්‌ තිබිය යුතු බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු කුමක් සිදුවේද? නව සභාපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය BASL පැහැදිලි කරයි",
        "ජනාධිපතිට සහ අගමැතිට බලයේ සිටීමට සදාචාරාත්මක අයිතියක් නැත; සිරිසේන ලංකාව හදන්න කරුණු 10ක ලිපියක් ලියයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාලිය පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එම මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993 මැයි 01 වෙනිදා.m D. B. Wijetunga",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතියක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50% ට වැඩි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "113",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාලිය පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති සහ අගමැති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරිසේන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி ராஜினாமா செய்த பிறகு என்ன நடக்கும்? புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதற்கான செயல்முறையை BASL விளக்குகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை (10) பிற்பகல் விசேட ஊடகவியலாளர் மாநாட்டை கூட்டிய ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமர் தமது பதவிகளை துறப்பதில் பின்பற்ற வேண்டிய செயற்பாடுகள் குறித்து விரிவாக விளக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "பிஏஎஸ்எல் தலைவர் சாலிய பீரிஸ், பிசி செய்தியாளர்களிடம் கூறுகையில், அரசியலமைப்பின் படி, ஜனாதிபதி பதவி விலகுவது குறித்து கையொப்பமிட்ட கடிதத்தை சபாநாயகரிடம் தெரிவிக்க வேண்டும் என்றும், அந்த பதவி வெற்றிடமானால், பிரதமர் பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியேற்பார் என்றும் கூறினார்.",
        "“பிரதமரால் ஜனாதிபதியாக செயற்பட முடியாவிட்டால், சபாநாயகரே ஜனாதிபதியாக செயற்படுவார்” என BASL தலைவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்ததாவது, தற்காலிக ஜனாதிபதி பதவி ஒரு மாத காலத்திற்கு மாத்திரமே இருக்கும்.",
        "அந்த மாதத்திற்குள், தனது பதவியை விட்டு வெளியேறிய ஜனாதிபதியின் எஞ்சிய காலத்திற்கான வாரிசை நாடாளுமன்றம் தேர்ந்தெடுக்க வேண்டும் என்றார்.",
        "பிரதமர் குறித்து கருத்து தெரிவித்த BASL தலைவர், பிரதமர் பதவி விலக வேண்டுமாயின், பதவி விலகுவது குறித்து ஜனாதிபதிக்கு கடிதம் எழுத வேண்டும் என்றார்.",
        "\"இலங்கையில் இதற்கு முன்னர் ஒரே ஒரு நிகழ்வு மட்டுமே இருந்தது, 1993 மே 1 ஆம் தேதி ஜனாதிபதி (ரணசிங்க) பிரேமதாச படுகொலை செய்யப்பட்ட போது எம். டி.பி. விஜேதுங்க பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமிக்கப்பட்டார், மேலும் ஒரு வாரத்திற்குள் பாராளுமன்றம் புதிய ஜனாதிபதியைத் தேர்ந்தெடுத்தது,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் தங்களுக்குள் இருந்து புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்ய முடியும் எனவும், புதிய தலைவர் பதவிக்கு தகுதியானவர்களில் இருந்து தெரிவு செய்யப்பட வேண்டும் எனவும் சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்க தலைவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர், குடியரசுத் தலைவரைத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கும் வாக்குகளில் 50% க்கும் அதிகமான வாக்குகளைப் பெற வேண்டும் என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"அனைத்து எம்.பி.க்களும் வாக்களித்தால், தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட எம்.பி.க்கு 113 வாக்குகள் இருக்க வேண்டும்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"இந்த நாடு நீண்ட காலத்திற்கு உறுதியற்ற தன்மையைக் கொண்டிருக்க முடியாது\" என்று BASL தலைவர் எச்சரித்தார்.",
        "நிலைமையின் தீவிரத்தை புரிந்து கொள்ளுமாறு ஜனாதிபதி, பிரதமர், சபாநாயகர், பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள், அரசியல் தலைவர்கள் ஆகியோரிடம் இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளதுடன், அதிகார மாற்றம் சுமுகமாக நடைபெறுவதை உறுதிப்படுத்த வேண்டிய கடப்பாடு அவர்களுக்கு உள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி எதிர்வரும் 13ஆம் திகதி பதவி விலகினால், விரைவில் பதவிமாற்றம் செய்யப்பட வேண்டும் எனவும், தாமதம் ஏற்படக்கூடாது எனவும் இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"எங்களுக்கு ஒரு சுமூகமான மாற்றம் தேவை, இது அனைவரும் சட்டத்தின் ஆட்சி, ஜனநாயகத்தை மதிக்க வேண்டிய நேரம், இது தேசிய ஒற்றுமைக்கான நேரம்\" என்று BASL தலைவர் சாலியா பீரிஸ், PC கூறினார்.",
        "அரசாங்கத்தில் அங்கம் வகிக்கும் அனைத்துக் கட்சிகளும் அரசாங்கத்துடன் இணையும் தேசிய ஐக்கிய அரசாங்கம், அனைத்துக் கட்சிகளாலும் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளக்கூடிய பிரதமரைக் கொண்டு, அவசரப் பொருளாதாரப் பிரச்சினைகளைத் தீர்ப்பதற்கு பொதுவான வேலைத்திட்டம் ஒன்றைக் கொண்டிருக்க வேண்டும் என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ராஜினாமா செய்த பிறகு என்ன நடக்கும்? புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதற்கான செயல்முறையை BASL விளக்குகிறது",
        "ஜனாதிபதிக்கும் பிரதமருக்கும் அதிகாரத்தில் இருக்க தார்மீக உரிமை இல்லை; இலங்கையை கட்டியெழுப்ப 10 அம்ச கடிதம் எழுதுகிறார் சிறிசேனா"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10) பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாலியா பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 1, 1993. எம் டி.பி. விஜேதுங்க",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வழக்கறிஞர் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50%க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "113",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாலியா பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி & பிரதமர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறிசேன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}