{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ග්ලයිෆොසේට්-ආනයනයට-අවසර-දෙන-ගැසට්-පත්‍රය-හෙට-පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට/1-619340",
  "time_ut": 1662378893,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ග්ලයිෆොසේට් ආනයනයට අවසර දෙන ගැසට් පත්‍රය හෙට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Gazette to allow import of glyphosate to Parliament tomorrow",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The gazette with regulations under the Import and Export (Control) Act permitting the import of glyphosate will be submitted to Parliament tomorrow (6).",
        "The Government Finance Committee has approved the gazette with regulations under the Import and Export (Control) Act allowing the import of glyphosate.",
        "The Government's Finance Committee recently considered the regulations enacted under the Import and Export (Control) Act No. 1 of 1969 regarding the permission to import glyphosate, which is used as a weed killer in the plantation sector, and after a long discussion, the committee approved it.",
        "The Parliamentary Committee on Government Finance met last (02) under the chairmanship of its Chairman, Member of Parliament (Dr.) Harsha De Silva.",
        "According to this gazette, import licenses for glyphosate will be issued subject to the recommendation of the pesticide registrar.",
        "Although the Government's Finance Committee has approved these regulations, the Chairman of the Committee has stated that the approval is subject to conditions.",
        "Mr. Harsha de Silva pointed out that further decisions should be taken after holding a wide discussion about the prepared report on the use of glyphosate in Sri Lanka's plantation crops.",
        "Minister Vidura Wickramanaya, MPs Wijitha Herath, Shehan Semasinghe, Pramitha Bandara Thennakone, Dr. Suren Raghavan, MA Sumanthiran, Harshana Rajakaruna, Chaminda Wijesiri, Anupa Pascual and Professor Ranjith Bandara participated in this discussion.",
        "Also, the officials of the Ministry of Finance, Import and Export Control Department, Ministry of Plantation Industry, Ministry of Agriculture and Pesticides Registry Office also participated in this meeting and the officials representing the Ministry of Health connected through online technology."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "tomorrow",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Import and Export (Control) Act",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Government Finance Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Import and Export (Control) Act",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Finance Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Import and Export (Control) Act No. 1 of 1969",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Parliamentary Committee on Government Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harsha De Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Government's Finance Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Harsha de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vidura Wickramanaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijitha Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shehan Semasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pramitha Bandara Thennakone",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suren Raghavan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "MA Sumanthiran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harshana Rajakaruna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaminda Wijesiri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Import and Export Control Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Plantation Industry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Agriculture and Pesticides Registry Office",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ග්ලයිෆොසේට් ආනයනයට අවසර දෙන ගැසට් පත්‍රය හෙට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ග්ලයිෆොසේට් ආනයනයට අවසර ලබාදෙන ආනයන හා අපනයන (පාලන) පනත යටතේ රෙගුලාසි සහිත ගැසට් පත්‍රය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට හෙට (6) ඉදිරිපත් කෙරේ.",
        "ග්ලයිෆොසේට් ආනයනයට අවසර ලබාදෙන ආනයන හා අපනයන (පාලන) පනත යටතේ රෙගුලාසි සහිත ගැසට් පත්‍රයට රජයේ මුදල් පිළිබද කාරක සභාවේ අනුමතිය ලැබී ඇත.",
        "වැවිලි ක්ෂේත්‍රය සදහා වල්නාශකයක් ලෙස යොදා ගන්නා ග්ලයිෆෝසේට් ආනයනයට  අවසර ලබා දීමට අදාළව 1969 අංක 1 දරන ආනයන හා අපනයන (පාලන) පනත යටතේ පනවන ලද රෙගුලාසි රජයේ  මුදල් පිළිබද කාරක සභාවේදී පසුගියදා සලකා බැලුණු අතර දීර්ඝ සාකච්ඡාවකින් අනතුරුව කාරක සභාව ඊට අනුමැතිය ලබා දුන්නේය.",
        "රජයේ  මුදල් පිළිබද පාර්ලිමේන්තු කාරක සභාව එහි සභාපති පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී (ආචාර්ය) හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන්  පසුගිය  (02) වෙනිදා රැස්විය.",
        "මෙම ගැසට් පත්‍රය අනුව පළිබෝධනාශක රෙජිස්ටාර්වරයාගේ නිර්දේශයට යටත්ව ග්ලයිෆෝසේට් සදහා ආනයන බලපත්‍ර නිකුත් කිරීම සිදුවේ.",
        "මෙම රෙගුලාසි සදහා රජයේ මුදල් කාරක සභාවේ අනුමතිය හිමිවුවද   එම අනුමැතිය ලබා දෙන්නේ  කොන්දේසි සහිතව  බවද   කාරක සභා සභාපතිවරයා මෙහිදී ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වැවිලි භෝග සම්බන්ධයෙන්  ග්ලයිෆෝසේට් භාවිතය පිළිබදව  පිළියෙල කරන ලද වාර්තාව පිළිබද පුළුල් සාකච්ඡාවක් පැවැත්වීමෙන් අනතුරුව ඉදිරි තීරණ ගතයුතු බවද  හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා මහතා  පෙන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "මෙම සාකච්ඡාවට අමාත්‍ය  විදුර වික්‍රමනායන, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන  විජිත හේරත්, ෂෙහාන් සේමසිංහ, ප්‍රමිත බණ්ඩාර තෙන්නකෝන්,  ආචාර්ය සුරේන් රාඝවන්,  එම් ඒ සුමන්තිරන්,  හර්ෂණ රාජකරුණා,  චමින්ද විජේසිරි, අනුප පැස්කුවල් සහ  මහාචාර්ය රංජිත් බණ්ඩාර යන මහත්වරු  සහභාගී වූහ.",
        "එසේම මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශය, ආනයන අපනයන පාලන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව, වැවිලි කර්මාන්ත අමාත්‍යාංශය, කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය සහ පළිබෝධනාශක රෙජිස්ටාර් කාර්යාලය යන ආයතනවල නිළධාරීන්ද මෙම රැස්වීමට සහභාගී වූ අතර සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය නියෝජනය කරමින් නිලධාරීහු  මාර්ගගත තාක්ෂණය (Online) ඔස්සේ සම්බන්ධවූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "හෙට",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ආනයන අපනයන (පාලන) පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජයේ මුදල් කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආනයන අපනයන (පාලන) පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1969 අංක 1 දරන ආනයන හා අපනයන (පාලන) පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජයේ මුදල් පිළිබඳ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජයේ මුදල් කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමිටුවක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදුර වික්‍රමනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂෙහාන් සේමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රමිත බණ්ඩාර තෙන්නකෝන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුරේන් රාඝවන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම් ඒ සුමන්තිරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂණ රාජකරුණා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චමින්ද විජේසිරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආනයන අපනයන පාලන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැවිලි කර්මාන්ත අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම හා පළිබෝධනාශක අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලියාපදිංචි කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්ය අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாளை பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு கிளைபோசேட் இறக்குமதியை அனுமதிக்கும் வர்த்தமானி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கிளைபோசேட் இறக்குமதியை அனுமதிக்கும் இறக்குமதி மற்றும் ஏற்றுமதி (கட்டுப்பாட்டு) சட்டத்தின் கீழ் ஒழுங்குகள் அடங்கிய வர்த்தமானி நாளை (6) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படவுள்ளது.",
        "க்ளைபோசேட் இறக்குமதியை அனுமதிக்கும் இறக்குமதி மற்றும் ஏற்றுமதி (கட்டுப்பாட்டு) சட்டத்தின் கீழ் ஒழுங்குமுறைகளுடன் கூடிய வர்த்தமானிக்கு அரசாங்க நிதிக் குழு அங்கீகாரம் வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "தோட்டத் துறையில் களைக்கொல்லியாகப் பயன்படுத்தப்படும் கிளைபோசேட் இறக்குமதியை அனுமதிப்பது தொடர்பாக 1969 ஆம் ஆண்டின் 1 ஆம் இலக்க இறக்குமதி மற்றும் ஏற்றுமதி (கட்டுப்பாட்டு) சட்டத்தின் கீழ் இயற்றப்பட்ட விதிமுறைகள் அண்மையில் அரசாங்கத்தின் நிதிக் குழுவில் பரிசீலிக்கப்பட்டு நீண்ட விவாதத்தின் பின்னர், குழு அதற்கு ஒப்புதல் அளித்தது.",
        "அரசாங்க நிதி தொடர்பான பாராளுமன்றக் குழு கடந்த (02) அதன் தலைவர் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் (டாக்டர்) ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா தலைமையில் கூடியது.",
        "இந்த வர்த்தமானியின் பிரகாரம் பூச்சிக்கொல்லி பதிவாளரின் சிபாரிசுக்கு உட்பட்டு கிளைபோசேட் இறக்குமதி உரிமம் வழங்கப்படும்.",
        "இந்த விதிமுறைகளுக்கு அரசின் நிதிக்குழு ஒப்புதல் அளித்துள்ள போதிலும், நிபந்தனைகளுக்கு உட்பட்டு ஒப்புதல் அளிக்கப்படும் என குழுவின் தலைவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் பெருந்தோட்டப் பயிர்களில் க்ளைபோசேட் பாவனை தொடர்பில் தயாரிக்கப்பட்ட அறிக்கை தொடர்பில் விரிவான கலந்துரையாடல்களை மேற்கொண்டு மேலதிக தீர்மானங்கள் எடுக்கப்பட வேண்டுமென திரு.ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "இந்த கலந்துரையாடலில் அமைச்சர் விதுர விக்ரமநாயக்க, பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான விஜித ஹேரத், ஷெஹான் சேமசிங்க, பிரமித பண்டார தென்னகோன், கலாநிதி சுரேன் ராகவன், எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன், ஹர்ஷன ராஜகருணா, சமிந்த விஜேசிறி, அனுபா பாஸ்குவல், பேராசிரியர் ரஞ்சித் பண்டார ஆகியோர் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "மேலும், நிதியமைச்சு, இறக்குமதி மற்றும் ஏற்றுமதி கட்டுப்பாட்டுத் திணைக்களம், பெருந்தோட்டக் கைத்தொழில் அமைச்சு, விவசாய அமைச்சு மற்றும் பூச்சிக்கொல்லிப் பதிவு அலுவலக அதிகாரிகளும் இச்சந்திப்பில் கலந்துகொண்டதுடன், சுகாதார அமைச்சின் பிரதிநிதிகள் இணையத்தள தொழில்நுட்பம் மூலம் தொடர்புகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "நாளை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இறக்குமதி மற்றும் ஏற்றுமதி (கட்டுப்பாட்டு) சட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்க நிதிக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இறக்குமதி மற்றும் ஏற்றுமதி (கட்டுப்பாட்டு) சட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிதிக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1969 இன் இறக்குமதி மற்றும் ஏற்றுமதி (கட்டுப்பாடு) சட்டம் எண்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்க நிதிக்கான பாராளுமன்றக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்கத்தின் நிதிக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விதுர விக்கிரமநாய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜித ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷெஹான் சேமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரமிதா பண்டார தென்னகோன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுரேன் ராகவன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷன ராஜகருணா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமிந்த விஜேசிறி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சித் பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இறக்குமதி மற்றும் ஏற்றுமதி கட்டுப்பாட்டு துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெருந்தோட்ட கைத்தொழில் அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வேளாண்மை அமைச்சகம் மற்றும் பூச்சிக்கொல்லிகள் பதிவு அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}