{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/26/cpstl-working-to-normalize-fuel-delivery/",
  "time_ut": 1661494560,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "CPSTL working to normalize fuel delivery",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CPSTL working to normalize fuel delivery",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st);  The Muthurajawela Terminal of Ceylon Petroleum Storage Terminals Limited did not deliver fuel to filling stations on Friday (26), but delivered fuel only for SLTB Depots.",
        "Sri Lanka began unloading a shipment of Auto Diesel that reached its shores on Thursday (25).",
        "Minister of Power and Energy Kanchana Wijesekera said the unloading of Super Diesel from a delayed shipment also commenced.",
        "Reports suggested that Ceylon Petroleum Storage Terminals Limited was working around the clock to return the distribution process to normalcy.",
        "However, Buses, school vans, and many other vehicles running on Diesel were lined up at filling stations since Friday (26) morning."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Muthurajawela Terminal of Ceylon Petroleum Storage Terminals Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Auto Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Super Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Storage Terminals Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Buses",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26) morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "CPSTL ඉන්ධන බෙදා හැරීම සාමාන්‍යකරණය කිරීමට ක්‍රියා කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); සීමාසහිත ලංකා පෙට්‍රෝලියම් ගබඩා පර්යන්තයේ මුතුරාජවෙල පර්යන්තය සිකුරාදා (26) ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් වෙත ඉන්ධන ලබා නොදුන් අතර ශ්‍රී ලංගම ඩිපෝ සඳහා පමණක් ඉන්ධන ලබා දෙන ලදී.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (25) වෙරළට ළඟා වූ ඔටෝ ඩීසල් නැව්ගත කිරීම ආරම්භ කළේය.",
        "ප්‍රමාද වූ නැව්ගත කිරීමකින් සුපර් ඩීසල් ගොඩබෑම ද ආරම්භ කළ බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "සිලෝන් පෙට්‍රෝලියම් ස්ටෝරේජ් ටර්මිනල්ස් ලිමිටඩ් බෙදාහැරීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය සාමාන්‍ය තත්ත්වයට පත් කිරීම සඳහා පැය විසිහතර පුරාම ක්‍රියා කරමින් සිටින බව වාර්තා යෝජනා කළේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, සිකුරාදා (26) උදෑසන සිටම ඩීසල්වලින් ධාවනය වන බස් රථ, පාසල් වෑන් රථ සහ තවත් වාහන රැසක් ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල්වල පෙළ ගැසී තිබුණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් ගබඩා පර්යන්තයේ මුතුරාජවෙල පර්යන්තය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔටෝ ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුපිරි ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිලෝන් පෙට්‍රෝලියම් ස්ටෝරේජ් ටර්මිනල්ස් ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26) උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "CPSTL எரிபொருள் விநியோகத்தை சீராக்க வேலை செய்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கை பெற்றோலிய சேமிப்பக முனையங்கள் லிமிடெட்டின் முத்துராஜவெல முனையம் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (26) எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையங்களுக்கு எரிபொருளை விநியோகிக்கவில்லை, ஆனால் SLTB டிப்போக்களுக்கு மட்டுமே எரிபொருளை விநியோகித்தது.",
        "இலங்கை வியாழக்கிழமை (25) தனது கரையை வந்தடைந்த ஆட்டோ டீசல் கப்பலை இறக்கத் தொடங்கியது.",
        "தாமதமான ஏற்றுமதியில் இருந்து சுப்பர் டீசலை இறக்கும் பணியும் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "சிலோன் பெட்ரோலியம் ஸ்டோரேஜ் டெர்மினல்ஸ் லிமிடெட் விநியோக செயல்முறையை இயல்பு நிலைக்கு கொண்டு வர 24 மணி நேரமும் உழைத்து வருவதாக அறிக்கைகள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், டீசலில் இயங்கும் பேருந்துகள், பள்ளி வேன்கள் மற்றும் பல வாகனங்கள் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (26) காலை முதல் எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையங்களில் வரிசையில் நின்றன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முத்துராஜவெல டெர்மினல் ஆஃப் சிலோன் பெட்ரோலியம் ஸ்டோரேஜ் டெர்மினல்ஸ் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆட்டோ டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சூப்பர் டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிலோன் பெட்ரோலியம் சேமிப்பு டெர்மினல்ஸ் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பேருந்துகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26) காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}