{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/18/public-transport-in-limbo-due-to-fuel-shortage/",
  "time_ut": 1658107140,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Public transport in limbo due to fuel shortage",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Public transport in limbo due to fuel shortage",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Sri Lanka Transport Board (SLTB) says that there is a delay in fuel delivery to several SLTB depots.",
        "The Deputy General Manager of SLTB Panduka Swarnahansa said that if fuel delivery is further delayed there will be a reduction in the number of buses in operation.",
        "Meanwhile, the Lanka Private Bus Owners’ Association says that due to the shortage of fuel the operation of private buses will be restricted today (18).",
        "The Chairman of the Lanka Private Bus Owners’ Association Gemunu Wijeratne said that if sufficient fuel is received today (18), steps will be taken to operate more buses tomorrow (19).",
        "Sri Lanka Railways says that trains will operate as usual (18)."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Sri Lanka Transport Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTB Panduka Swarnahansa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Lanka Private Bus Owners’ Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Lanka Private Bus Owners’ Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gemunu Wijeratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Railways",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන හිඟය හේතුවෙන් පොදු ප්‍රවාහනය අඩාල වී ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ලංගම ඩිපෝ කිහිපයකට ඉන්ධන ලබාදීමේ ප්‍රමාදයක් පවතින බව ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය පවසයි.",
        "ලංගම නියෝජ්‍ය සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරී පණ්ඩුක ස්වර්ණහංස මහතා පැවසුවේ ඉන්ධන බෙදා හැරීම තවදුරටත් ප්‍රමාද වුවහොත් ධාවනයේ යෙදෙන බස් රථ ප්‍රමාණයේ අඩුවීමක් සිදුවන බවයි.",
        "මේ අතර, ඉන්ධන හිඟය හේතුවෙන් අද (18) පෞද්ගලික බස් රථ ධාවනය සීමා කරන බව ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය පවසයි.",
        "අද (18) ප්‍රමාණවත් ඉන්ධන ලැබුණහොත් හෙට (19) දිනයේදී තවත් බස් රථ ධාවනය කිරීමට පියවර ගන්නා බව ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති ගැමුණු විජේරත්න මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "දුම්රිය සාමාන්‍ය පරිදි (18) ක්‍රියාත්මක වන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා දුම්රිය සේවය පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංගම පණ්ඩුක ස්වර්ණහංස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගැමුණු විජේරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දුම්රිය සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் தட்டுப்பாடு காரணமாக பொது போக்குவரத்து முடங்கியுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் பல டிப்போக்களுக்கு எரிபொருள் விநியோகம் செய்வதில் தாமதம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "எரிபொருள் விநியோகம் மேலும் தாமதமானால் சேவையில் ஈடுபடும் பஸ்களின் எண்ணிக்கை குறையும் என இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் பிரதி பொது முகாமையாளர் பண்டுக ஸ்வர்ணஹன்ச தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, எரிபொருள் தட்டுப்பாடு காரணமாக தனியார் பேருந்துகளின் சேவைகள் இன்று (18) மட்டுப்படுத்தப்படும் என இலங்கை தனியார் பேருந்து உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "போதியளவு எரிபொருள் இன்று (18) கிடைத்தால் நாளை (19) மேலதிக பஸ்களை இயக்க நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்படும் என இலங்கை தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் கெமுனு விஜேரத்ன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ரயில்கள் வழமை போன்று (18) இயங்கும் என இலங்கை ரயில்வே தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTB பண்டுக ஸ்வர்ணஹன்சா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெமுனு விஜேரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ரயில்வே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}