{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ඉන්ධන-හුටපටයෙන්-තරුණයාට-පිහි-පහර/101-615502",
  "time_ut": 1656336660,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඉන්ධන හුටපටයෙන් තරුණයාට පිහි පහර",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Young man stabbed in fuel scuffle",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A man who was attacked with a sharp weapon during an argument between two groups at the IOC petrol station in Matugama this afternoon has been admitted to hospital, Matugama Police said.",
        "The victim is a resident of Iddagoda, Deniya, Matugama, police said.",
        "The victim had been waiting in line at a petrol station near the Matugama Public Stadium when he was stabbed at around 3.30 pm, police said.",
        "The injured have been admitted to the Matugama Government Hospital with stab wounds to the abdomen, head and arms, a hospital spokesman said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IOC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matugama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matugama Police",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Iddagoda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Deniya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matugama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Matugama Public Stadium",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "around 3.30 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Matugama Government Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන හුටපටයෙන් තරුණයාට පිහි පහර",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මතුගම IOC ඉන්ධන පිරවුම් හලේ අද පස්වරුවේ දෙපිරිසක් අතර ඇතිවූ බහින්බස් වීමක් දුරදිග ගොස් තියුණු අයුධයකින් පහරකෑමට ලක්වූ පුද්ගලයකු රෝහල් ගත කළ බව මතුගම පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "මෙසේ රෝහල් ගතකර ඇත්තේ මතුගම, දෙනිය ඉද්දගොඩ ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි පුද්ගලයකු බව පොලිසිය පවසයි .",
        "පහරකෑමට ලක්වූ පුද්ගලයා ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හලේ පෝලිමේ රැදී සිට දිවා ආහාර ලබාගැනීම සඳහා මතුගම මහජන ක්‍රීඩාංගණය අසලට ගොස් සිටියදී පස්වරු 3:30 ට පමණ පිහි පහරට ලක්ව ඇතැයිද පොලිසිය පවසයි .",
        "උදරය, හිස සහ දෑත්වල කැපුම් තුවාල සහිතව, තුවාලකරු මතුගම රජයේ රෝහල වෙත ඇතුළත් කර ඇතැයි රෝහල් ප්‍රකාශකයෙක් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයි.ඕ.සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මතුගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මතුගම පොලිසිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉද්දගොඩ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙණිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මතුගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මතුගම මහජන ක්‍රීඩාංගණයේදී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.30ට පමණ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මතුගම රජයේ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் தகராறில் வாலிபர் கத்தியால் குத்தப்பட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மத்துகம, ஐஓசி எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையத்தில் இன்று பிற்பகல் இரு குழுக்களுக்கிடையில் ஏற்பட்ட வாக்குவாதத்தின் போது கூரிய ஆயுதத்தால் தாக்கப்பட்ட நபர் ஒருவர் வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக மத்துகம பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "உயிரிழந்தவர் மத்துகம, தெனியா, இத்தகொட பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்தவர் என பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "மாலை 3.30 மணியளவில் மத்துகம பொது விளையாட்டு மைதானத்திற்கு அருகில் உள்ள எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையத்தில் வரிசையில் காத்திருந்த நபர் வாள்வெட்டுக்கு இலக்காகியுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "வயிறு, தலை மற்றும் கைகளில் வெட்டுக் காயங்களுடன் காயமடைந்தவர்கள் மத்துகம அரச வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக வைத்தியசாலை பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐஓசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்துகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்துகம பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இத்தகொட",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்துகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்துகம பொது மைதானம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 3.30 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்துகம அரசு மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}